<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1096</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1096</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1096!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-01-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402565260_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-01-19">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Director of Social Welfare, and for
                matters connected
                therewith.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[6 February 1959]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402565276_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Director of Social Welfare Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402565276_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Director of Social Welfare constituted a corporation sole</heading><content>The person for the time being performing the duties of the office of Director of Social
            Welfare shall be a corporation sole, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name of the Director of Social Welfare
            Incorporated and in that name shall have perpetual succession.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402565292_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Seal of corporation and authentication thereof, and instruments executed thereunder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410867997_018" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have a common seal and the affixing of the seal shall be authenticated by the signature of the occupant of the corporation for the time being.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410868013_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any instrument purporting to be an instrument duly executed under the seal of the corporation shall be received in evidence and shall, unless the contrary is proved, be deemed to be an instrument so executed.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402565307_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Power of corporation to act as trustee, etc.</heading><content>The corporation may act as trustee of any trust created for the benefit of persons in the care of the Social Welfare Department or of any trust created in connection with the work of the said Department and may acquire, take on lease, purchase, hold, hire and enjoy any movable or immovable property and may dispose of the same.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402565307_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Power to invest trust funds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410868044_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>The corporation may invest, in accordance with the provisions of the Trustee
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>), any trust funds in the hands of
                    the corporation whether at the time in a state of investment or not:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_1_proviso">Provided that where the occupant
                    of the corporation for the time being considers it impracticable for any reason
                    whatsoever for any such trust funds to be so invested, the corporation may
                    deposit such trust funds in any bank or savings bank approved by the Chief
                    Executive either generally or in any particular case.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410868060_011" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The powers conferred on the corporation by subsection (1) are in addition to
                the powers (if any) conferred by any trust but shall apply only if and so far as a
                contrary intention is not expressed in any term of any trust, and shall have effect
                subject to any such term.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402565323_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Property of corporation to pass to its successors</heading><content>Where any property or interest therein is vested in the corporation, the same shall, unless and until otherwise disposed of by the corporation, pass and devolve to and vest in the successors from time to time of the corporation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402565354_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Certificate as to occupant of corporation</heading><content>If any question arises as to who is or was at any time the occupant of the corporation for the time being, a certificate under the hand of the Chief Secretary for Administration shall be conclusive evidence for all purposes as to the person who is or was such occupant.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402565370_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Accounts, audit and annual report</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410868107_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall keep accounts and records of all transactions in respect
                of any trust funds it administers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410868107_019" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director of Accounting Services may give such directions in writing to the
                corporation as he thinks fit with respect to the keeping of accounts and records
                referred to in subsection (1) and the corporation shall comply with any such
                direction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410868107_027" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The corporation shall prepare in relation to the trust funds it administers a
                statement of accounts of the funds for each period of 12 months ending on 31 March
                in any year, in such form as the Director of Accounting Services may require in
                writing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410868107_035" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A statement of accounts required by subsection (3) shall be signed by the
                person for the time being performing the duties of the office of the Director of
                Social Welfare and shall, unless the accounts of the trust funds the corporation
                administers have been audited by an independent accountant under <ref>section
                    24(4)</ref> of the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>), be
                submitted by the corporation to the Director of Audit not later than 30 September
                following the end of the period to which it relates, or such later date as the Chief
                Executive may allow.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410868138_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the statement of accounts is submitted to the Director of Audit under
                subsection (4), such statement of accounts and the accounts of the funds referred to
                in subsection (1) shall be audited by the Director of Audit, who shall certify the
                statement of accounts together with such report, if any, as he may think fit and
                submit the audited statement of accounts and the report thereon, if any, to the
                corporation.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410868138_013" name="6" temporalId="s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A copy of the corporation’s audited statement of accounts, together with the
                Director of Audit’s report, if any, and a report, if any, by the corporation on the
                administration of the fund during the period covered by the audited statement of
                accounts shall be laid upon the table of the Legislative Council not later than 3
                months after the audited statement of accounts and the report thereon, if any, are
                received by the corporation from the Director of Audit.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1989/20">20 of 1989 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>