<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1007</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1007</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1007!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-09-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402526479_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-09-08">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Trustees of the Chater Masonic
                Scholarship Fund.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 November 1929]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402526494_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Chater Masonic Scholarship Fund Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526510_002" name="s1A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1A"><num value="1A">1A.</num><heading>Object of Chater Masonic Scholarship Fund</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793102_011" name="1" temporalId="s1A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The objects of the Chater Masonic Scholarship Fund are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410793102_019" name="a" temporalId="s1A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to support, advance and promote education and for such purpose to grant endowments and donations to schools and tertiary institutions and to grant to students and persons pursuing studies scholarships, subsidies, bursaries, allowances, loans (whether subject to payment of interest or otherwise) and other forms of assistance (financial or otherwise) as the trustees may at their absolute discretion consider expedient;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793117_006" name="b" temporalId="s1A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to support, advance and promote all charitable activities and projects which will in the absolute opinion of the trustees be conducive to the training or education of children and young persons at their leisure times so as to develop their physical, mental and spiritual capacities that they may grow to full maturity as individuals and members of the society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793117_014" name="c" temporalId="s1A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to support and make donations to such institutions or for such purposes or objects for the advancement and promotion of education at such time or times and in such manner as the trustees may in their absolute discretion think fit; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793117_022" name="d" temporalId="s1A_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to provide funds and to make or join in the making of any administrative provisions that the trustees may at their absolute discretion deem necessary for the initiation, support, promotion or sponsoring of any projects for the advancement and promotion of education.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1995/95">95 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793133_005" name="2" temporalId="s1A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The scholarships provided under subsection (1) shall be at the University of Hong Kong, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, the City University of Hong Kong, the Hong Kong Baptist University, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology and other institutions as the trustees may think fit or any seat of higher learning situated outside Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1981/24">24 of 1981 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/100">100 of 1994 s. 10</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/95">95 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1975/72">72 of 1975 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526541_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793164_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The trustees of the Chater Masonic Scholarship Fund and their successors in
                office as hereinafter defined shall be a body corporate, hereinafter called
                        <b><i>the
                        corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name of “The Trustees of the Chater
                Masonic Scholarship Fund”, and in that name shall have perpetual succession and
                shall and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may have and
                use a common seal.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/95">95 of 1995 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793180_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Trustees shall be appointed in accordance with the by-laws of the corporation hereinafter referred to, and shall for the time being be deemed to be successors in office of the first trustees and be members of the corporation upon notice of their appointment, and of the retirement of the retiring trustees (if any) whom they have been appointed to replace, being filed with the Registrar of Companies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793180_013" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any such notice shall be signed by 2 of the continuing or retiring trustees and shall be sealed with the common seal of the corporation.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1939/33">33 of 1939</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1940/gn840">G.N. 840 of 1940</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526541_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793211_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The corporation shall have power to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410793211_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold, and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages, or tenements in Hong Kong or elsewhere;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793211_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>accept mortgages of any lands, buildings, messuages, or tenements in Hong Kong or elsewhere;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793211_028" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong or elsewhere;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793211_036" name="d" temporalId="s3_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>purchase such stocks, funds, shares or other investments or property of whatever nature and wherever situated in addition but not limited to the purchase of stocks, funds, shares or other investments or property provided for the time being in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> to the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793211_044" name="e" temporalId="s3_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>sell, convey, assign, reassign, transfer, surrender and yield up all or any of the above investments, or to reinvest the proceeds thereof in part or in whole in any of such investments;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793226_006" name="f" temporalId="s3_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>receive and accept gifts, donations, contributions or legacies and to hold or realize the same subject to any conditions attached to such gifts, donations, contributions and legacies,</content></paragraph><continued>on such terms as to the corporation may seem fit.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793226_019" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation shall have full power to direct the trustees to invest any funds in any investments listed for the time being in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> to the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1995/95">95 of 1995 s. 4</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526572_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Power to make by-laws, method of amendment and the certification and deposit thereof</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793258_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation may make by-laws for its internal management and control, and all such by-laws when agreed upon by the corporation shall be binding on every member thereof.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1975/72">72 of 1975 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793258_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Amendments to the by-laws shall be made by the trustees in general meeting, and at least 14 clear days’ written notice of the resolution to effect such amendment shall be given to each of the trustees present in Hong Kong at the time.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/95">95 of 1995 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793258_020" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A copy of the by-laws certified as correct by 2 of the trustees and sealed with the common seal of the corporation shall be deposited and filed with the Registrar of Companies, and whenever such by-laws are altered a copy thereof as altered and certified as aforesaid shall also be forthwith deposited and filed with the said Registrar.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1939/33">33 of 1939</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1940/gn840">G.N. 840 of 1940</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402526588_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><content>All deeds and other instruments requiring the corporate seal of the corporation shall be sealed in the presence of 2 of the trustees and shall be signed by 2 of the trustees.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526603_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/55">55 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>