<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1058</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1058</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1058!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-06-20</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402543358_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-06-20">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Hong Kong Society for the Protection of
                Children.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[15 August 1969]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402543373_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Society for the Protection of Children Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543389_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Chairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the
                                    Chairman of the Executive Committee of the Hong Kong Society for
                                    the Protection of Children;</def><def name="Child"><term>child</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">兒童</term>) means a
                                    person under the age of 18 years;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2006/22">22 of 2006 s.
                                                2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the
                                    constitution of the Hong Kong Society for the Protection of
                                    Children for the time being in force;</def><def name="ExecutiveCommittee"><term>Executive
                                    Committee</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">執行委員會</term>) means the
                                    Executive Committee of the Hong Kong Society for the Protection
                                    of Children established under the constitution;</def><def name="FormerBodyCorporate"><term>former body
                                    corporate</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">前法團</term>) means The
                                    Corporation of the Hong Kong Society for the Protection of
                                    Children incorporated by the Society for the Protection of
                                    Children Incorporation Ordinance 1951 (<ref href="/hk/1985/8">8
                                                of
                                                1985</ref>,
                                    Cap.
                                    1058,
                                    1964 Ed.), now repealed;</def><def name="President"><term>President</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會長</term>) means the
                                    President of the Hong Kong Society for the Protection of
                                    Children;</def><def name="Secretary"><term>Secretary</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">秘書</term>) means the
                                    Honorary Secretary of the Executive Committee;</def><def name="Society"><term>Society</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">保護兒童會</term>) means the
                                    Hong Kong Society for the Protection of Children.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402543436_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The Hong Kong Society for the Protection of Children shall be a body corporate and in
            that name shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong
            Kong and shall have, and may use, a common seal, and may from time to time break,
            change, alter and make anew the said seal as the Society may deem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543451_002" name="s3A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3A"><num value="3A">3A.</num><heading>Objects of the Society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410824068_032" name="1" temporalId="s3A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Society is established for charitable purposes.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824068_040" name="2" temporalId="s3A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The aims and objects of the Society are to provide or engage, alone or in partnership with the community, in Hong Kong or elsewhere, services or activities which promote the care, education and social development of children and their families. The objects include, but are not limited to, the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410824083_005" name="a" temporalId="s3A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to provide and operate day nurseries, day crèches, residential crèches and other centres in Hong Kong and elsewhere for the care of children and their families and to provide any other services or facilities as the Society may think fit, and to impose such charges or fees for such nurseries, crèches, centres, services and facilities provided by the Society as the Society may consider appropriate in the circumstances;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824083_013" name="b" temporalId="s3A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to educate the public regarding the care, education and social development of children and their families; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824083_021" name="c" temporalId="s3A_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to establish and support, and to aid in the establishment of, any charitable organizations, whether in or outside Hong Kong, having objects similar to those of the Society.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2006/22">22 of 2006 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543467_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of the Society</heading><leadIn>The Society shall have power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410824114_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of whatsoever nature or kind and wheresoever situate;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2006/22">22 of 2006 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824114_020" name="aa" temporalId="s4_aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><leadIn>to invest moneys in any country or territory—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410824114_028" name="i" temporalId="s4_aa_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>on deposits in, or other depositary instruments issued by, any bank;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410824114_036" name="ii" temporalId="s4_aa_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any corporation or company;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410824114_044" name="iii" temporalId="s4_aa_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>in bonds of any nature;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410824114_052" name="iv" temporalId="s4_aa_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>in any commodities; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410824114_060" name="v" temporalId="s4_aa_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>in such other investment as the Society may think fit;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2006/22">22 of 2006 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824114_067" name="ab" temporalId="s4_ab"><num value="ab">(ab)</num><content>to purchase or otherwise acquire and undertake all or any part of the property, assets, or liabilities of any charitable company, institution, society or association having objects similar to those of the Society;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2006/22">22 of 2006 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824130_006" name="ac" temporalId="s4_ac"><num value="ac">(ac)</num><content>to purchase or otherwise acquire goods and chattels of whatsoever nature or kind upon such terms as the Society may think fit;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2006/22">22 of 2006 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824130_014" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to build, rebuild, demolish, alter, vary, renew, maintain and repair any buildings, messuages or tenements acquired by the Society or in which it is interested and to effect any improvements thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824130_022" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, pledge, demise, let, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture stocks, stocks, funds, shares, securities, vessels, goods, chattels, property and assets for the time being vested in or belonging to the Society upon such terms as the Society may think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824146_006" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the Society may think fit, and subject to <ref>section 4(17)</ref> of the Summary Offences Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap228">Cap. 228</ref>), to raise money by private or public subscription;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824146_014" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to accept donations, grants or subsidies from any person or Government Authority or other body or organization;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824146_022" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to establish, support and subscribe to provident funds, pension and retirement and similar schemes for the benefit of employees of the Society and their dependants and to grant and pay pensions or gratuities to and otherwise aid, support or assist any such persons;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824146_030" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>generally to do such other acts and things as are incidental or conducive to the aims and objects of the Society.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402543498_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Vesting of property, etc. in the Society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410824192_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance all those pieces or parcels of ground specified in the second
                column of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, together with all rights, easements and
                appurtenances thereto belonging, shall vest in the Society for the unexpired residue
                of the respective terms of years created by the Crown leases or Conditions of Grant
                specified opposite thereto in the third column of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, subject
                to the payment of rent and performance of the
                covenants
                and conditions reserved by and contained in the said Crown leases and Conditions of Grant.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824208_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All debentures, stocks, funds, shares, securities, vessels, goods, chattels and
                other movable assets vested in or belonging to or held for or on behalf of or in
                trust for the former body corporate and all moneys subscribed for the purposes of
                the former body corporate and all investments of such moneys and all interest,
                income and profits arising from such investments and all securities therefor shall
                at the commencement of this Ordinance, be transferred to, vest in, belong to or be
                held for or on behalf of or in trust for the Society.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824224_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>All contractual and other rights exercisable or enforceable by the former body
                corporate shall, on the commencement of this Ordinance, be exercisable by the
                Society in place of the former body corporate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824224_013" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>On the commencement of this Ordinance, the Society shall become liable for all
                debts and liabilities and for the performance of all contractual and other
                obligations of the former body corporate.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1556089856854_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 15 August
                1969.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543514_002" name="s5A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5A"><num value="5A">5A.</num><heading>Members of Executive Committee to be indemnified</heading><content>The Society shall indemnify each member of the Executive Committee against any claim whatsoever against him arising out of, or in connection with, the performance or discharge of his duties except a claim in respect of his gross negligence, dishonesty, or fraud.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2006/22">22 of 2006 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543529_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Members</heading><content>The Society shall consist of those members of the Hong Kong Society for the
            Protection of Children who were such members immediately before the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance and of all such persons who shall continue to be members of the
            Society or who shall hereafter be admitted to membership of the Society in accordance
            with the constitution.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1556008464096_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 15 August
                1969.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543529_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Constitution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410824286_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The constitution of the Hong Kong Society for the Protection of Children in
                force immediately prior to the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance shall continue to be the constitution of the Society but the same
                may be amended or varied at any time or from time to time in accordance with the
                provisions of the constitution subject nevertheless to the provisions of this
                Ordinance relating to any matter expressly dealt with herein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824286_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The constitution shall not be amended without the consent in writing of the
                Registrar of Companies.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1556008495773_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 15 August
                1969.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543545_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410824302_019" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Society shall forward to the Registrar of Companies for registration the
                following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410824302_027" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the principal office of the Society and any change
                    thereof; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824302_035" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the constitution and any amendment thereto certified as correct
                    by the Chairman; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824302_043" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a list of the names, occupations and addresses of the President, the
                    members and the Secretary of the Executive Committee and any change therein,
                    certified as correct by the Chairman; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410824317_006" name="d" temporalId="s8_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a list of the names and addresses of the members for the time being of the
                    Society and any change therein, certified as correct by the Chairman.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824317_013" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every document required to be registered in accordance with subsection (1)
                shall be forwarded to the Registrar of Companies within 28 days of the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance or within 28 days of any change or amendment, as the case may
                be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824317_021" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Society shall pay such fees for registering any document with any public
                registry as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section 26</ref> of
                the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for the registration
                of a document with the Registrar of Companies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824317_029" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section on
                payment of such fee as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section
                    26</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for
                the inspection of documents kept by the Registrar of Companies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of
                        2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824333_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The registration of the list mentioned in subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref> shall be
                conclusive evidence of the facts mentioned in such list.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1556008569666_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 15 August
                1969.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543561_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410824364_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the Society shall be sealed in the presence of 2 members of the Executive Committee and shall also be signed by those members and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing and execution of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410824364_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Executive Committee shall be responsible for the safe custody of the common seal of the Society.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402543576_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402543592_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1058/s5">s.
                5(1)</ref>]</note><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                
                <col width="7%"></col>
                
                <col width="43%"></col>
                
                <col width="40%"></col>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Item</center>
                    </td>
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Description of
                            Property</center>
                    </td>
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Crown leases and
                            Conditions<br></br>of Grant</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">1.</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_10">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">Shaukiwan Inland Lot No. 620</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">Conditions of Grant No. 5914</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">2.</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_10">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">Kowloon Inland Lot No. 6075</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 ">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">Conditions of Grant No. 4587</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">3.</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_10">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">Kowloon Inland Lot No. 7942</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">Crown lease dated 19 October 1968</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">4.</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_10">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">2/13th undivided shares in Hung Hom
                            Inland Lot No. 401</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_left_5">
                        <p class="align_left left_indent_0">Crown lease dated 11 November 1964</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            
        </text></schedule></main></ordinance>