<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1104</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1104</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1104!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-06-02</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402572343_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-06-02">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Council of St. Paul’s Co-educational
                College.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[29 June 1962]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402572374_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Council of St. Paul’s Co-educational College Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402572374_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-06-02" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of the Council of St.
            Paul’s Co-educational College approved from time to time by its members for the time
            being in accordance with the constitution for the time being in operation;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>corporation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means the body incorporated by <ref>section
                3</ref>.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402572390_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-06-02" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The Council of St. Paul’s Co-educational College shall be a body corporate, and shall
            have the name of “The Council of St. Paul’s Co-educational College”, and in that name
            shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and
            shall have and may use a common seal.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/55">55 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402572405_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-06-02" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Power of corporation</heading><leadIn>The corporation shall have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410885267_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to manage, administer and operate St. Paul’s Co-educational College;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885267_027" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take or otherwise hold and enjoy any
                land, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and
                wheresoever situate;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1983/14">14 of 1983 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885267_035" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to acquire, by purchase or otherwise, goods and chattels of any kind or
                description;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885267_043" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong or elsewhere or in any
                Hong Kong or other government bonds or on mortgage of any land, buildings, messuages
                or tenements in Hong Kong, or in or on debentures, debenture-stocks, stocks, funds,
                shares or securities of any corporation or company carrying on business in Hong Kong
                or elsewhere;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/55">55 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885282_006" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, yield up, mortgage, demise, let,
                reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of, any land, buildings, messuages,
                tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture-stocks, stocks, funds, securities,
                vessels, goods and chattels for the time being vested in the corporation, upon such
                terms as the corporation may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885282_014" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to erect any buildings, messuages or tenements and effect any improvement
                thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885282_022" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the corporation shall think fit, and to
                raise money by public or private subscription; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885282_030" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>generally to do such other things as may appear to be incidental or conducive
                to the aims and objects of the corporation as provided by its constitution for the
                time being, or for carrying into effect the provisions of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402572405_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Members</heading><content>The corporation shall consist of such members as shall be provided by its constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402572421_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-06-02" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Existing constitution to become constitution of corporation</heading><leadIn>The constitution of the unincorporated Council of St. Paul’s Co-educational College
            in operation at the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance shall be the constitution of the corporation:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_proviso">Provided that the same may be changed or
            amended by the corporation from time to time in the manner provided by the constitution
            for the time being in operation.</proviso><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1634700404160_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 29 June
                1962.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402572421_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Registration with Registrar of Companies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410885345_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The corporation shall forward to the Registrar of Companies for registration the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410885345_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the registered office of the corporation and any change thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885345_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the constitution and any amendment thereto, certified as correct by the chairman of the corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885345_028" name="c" temporalId="s7_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a list of the names and addresses of the members of the corporation and any change therein, certified as correct by the chairman of the corporation; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410885345_036" name="d" temporalId="s7_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the name and address of any person appointed under <ref>section 8</ref> to sign deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410885345_043" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notification in accordance with subsection (1) shall be made within 28 days of any amendment or change, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410885345_051" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section, upon payment of such fees as may be payable under any enactment relating thereto.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410885345_059" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The corporation shall pay such fee for registering any document with any public registry as may be payable under any enactment relating thereto.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402572452_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Sealing of deeds</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be signed by the chairman and the secretary of the corporation or by such other person or persons as the corporation shall from time to time appoint and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402572452_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-06-02" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/55">55 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>