<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1014 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1014A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1014A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-08-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402529723_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2025-08-24">English-speaking
            Anglican
            Church
            Trust (Church Councils) Regulations</docTitle><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 215</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap1014/s9">Cap.
                1014,
                section
            9</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[18 January 1930]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section reason="inEffect" role="regulation" status="operational" id="ID_1438402529739_001" name="s1" temporalId="s1" startPeriod="2025-08-24"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Meaning of expression
                <term>church
                councils</term></heading><content>In these regulations, the expression
                <term>church
                councils</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">堂議會</term>) means the bodies constituted under that
            name by or under the
            Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 216</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402529770_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Constitution of church councils</heading><leadIn>Every church council shall consist of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410796830_019" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the incumbent or clergyman in charge;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796830_027" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the senior licensed assistant clergyman, if any;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796830_035" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>such number of lay representatives (who may be of either sex) as the annual
                church meeting may from time to time decide. Such lay representatives must be actual
                communicant members of the
                English-speaking
                Anglican Church or of a church in communion with it and not
                entered upon the electoral roll of any other church in the
                diocese.
                No candidate may be elected who has not previously consented to serve. The number
                may be altered from time to time by a resolution passed at an annual church meeting
                of the church concerned but so that the alteration shall not take effect till the
                year following the date at which it is made;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1970/ln102">L.N. 102 of
                    1970</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796846_006" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>co-opted members if the church council concerned so decides not exceeding in
                number one-fifth of the elected lay representatives and being either in holy orders
                or actual lay communicant members of the
                English-speaking
                Anglican Church of either sex or of a church in communion with
                    it;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1970/ln102">L.N. 102 of 1970</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796861_006" name="e" temporalId="s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the two lay representatives elected at the annual church meeting as members of
                the body of The Trustees of the
                English-speaking
                Anglican Church in Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1970/ln102">L.N. 102 of
                    1970</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 217</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402529801_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Election of lay representatives</heading><content>The election of lay representatives to the church council shall take place at the annual church meeting of the church concerned.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402529879_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Duration of office of lay representatives and co-opted members</heading><content>Lay representatives and co-opted members shall continue in office until the next annual church meeting unless in the meanwhile they vacate office by death, absence of six months, incapacity to act or resignation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402529895_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Filling up of casual vacancies among lay representatives
            or
            co-opted members</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 218</ref>)</sourceNote><content>In the event of death, absence for a period of six months, incapacity to act or
            resignation of any lay representative or co-opted member on a church council the
            remaining members may appoint some other qualified person to act in his or her place
            until the next annual church meeting.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402529911_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Meetings of church councils</heading><content>Meetings of church councils shall be in accordance with the rules of procedure set forth in the Appendix hereto.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402529911_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Secretary and treasurer for church councils</heading><content>Every church council shall appoint a secretary and treasurer as provided for in the rules of procedure.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402529942_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Powers of church councils</heading><leadIn>In addition to the powers conferred by the
            Ordinance,
            each church council shall have
                power—<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    219</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410796955_026" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to frame an annual budget of moneys required for the maintenance of the work of the church for which it is appointed and otherwise, and to take such steps as it thinks necessary for raising, collecting and allocating such moneys;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796970_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>jointly with the incumbent to determine the objects to which all moneys to be given or collected in the church shall be allocated, and to determine the mode of collection of all donations and the fees to be taken for marriages, burials and other services;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1970/ln102">L.N. 102 of 1970</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796970_014" name="c" temporalId="s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content><leadIn>jointly with the incumbent to appoint and dismiss and (if so authorized by the trustees in their letters of delegation) to pay the salaries of assistant chaplains, organists and subordinate officials, and to determine the conditions of the tenure of their offices or of their employment:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s8_c_proviso">Provided that no appointment or dismissal of a clergyman shall be valid unless approved in writing by the Bishop;</proviso></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796970_028" name="d" temporalId="s8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to make representation to the Bishop with regard to any matter affecting the welfare of the church concerned;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410796970_036" name="e" temporalId="s8_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><leadIn>to make regulations regarding all or any of the following matters—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410796970_044" name="i" temporalId="s8_e_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>holding of meetings of the church council and the conduct of business
                    thereat;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410796970_052" name="ii" temporalId="s8_e_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>keeping of accounts of moneys received and expended by the church
                    councils;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410796986_007" name="iii" temporalId="s8_e_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>all other matters relating to the affairs of the church
                        council:</leadIn>
                    
                </content></subparagraph><continued>Provided that no regulation shall be valid until it has been approved by an
                annual or special church meeting: And provided that no regulation shall be
                inconsistent with the provisions of the
                Ordinance,
                or with any regulation made thereunder by the
                    trustees.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                        219</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402529957_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Church councils to keep accounts</heading><content>Every church council shall furnish to the annual church meeting as provided for in <ref>regulation 17</ref> an account made up to the 31st December in the year immediately preceding such meeting setting out the income and expenditure of the church council during the year together with a statement of the funds and property, if any, remaining in its hands at the date of the account. Such account and statement having been duly audited shall together with a report upon the fabric, goods and ornaments of the church be submitted for approval at such meeting or at any adjournment thereof and the said account, statement and report if approved shall be signed by the chairman of the meeting and shall be forthwith published and affixed on or near the principal door of the church and any other conspicuous place or places in the parish at the discretion of the church council. A copy of the account, statement and report shall be furnished by the church council to the trustees.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402529973_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Keeping of registers of baptisms, marriages and burials</heading><content>Every church council shall cause to be kept proper books of registry of all baptisms and marriages solemnized in the church and of all burials performed by the clergy.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402529973_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Provision of safe for books</heading><content>Every church council shall provide a fire-proof safe for the safe custody of all books of registry belonging to the church.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402530004_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Provision of inventory</heading><content>Every church council shall provide and keep up to date an inventory of all church property for which it may be responsible.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402530020_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Erection of monuments</heading><content>A church council may, if so authorized by the trustees in the letter of delegation, and in accordance with any regulations laid down by the Bishop, permit the erection or order the removal of any monument, tablet or other memorial in the church or in the precincts thereof, but no such monument, tablet or other memorial shall be erected or removed without the previous written consent of the Bishop.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402530035_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Alterations in church or furniture</heading><content>A church council may, if so authorized by the trustees in the letter of delegation, make alterations in the church or its furniture, and may add to or renew ornaments to or in the church, but no such alteration, addition or renewal shall be made without the previous written consent of the Bishop.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402530035_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Powers of the Bishop</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410797111_011" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If any difficulty arises with respect to the conduct of any church council for
                which provision is not made in the
                Ordinance,
                or in the regulations, or in the event of a church council and an incumbent being
                unable to agree as to any matter in which their joint action is required, the Bishop
                may give such directions as may appear to him to be
                    necessary.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                        220</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797126_005" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On representation being made to the Bishop by a majority of the lay members of a church council or by one-tenth of the electors on the electoral roll, and if such representation is deemed by the Bishop to show sufficient cause for the same, the Bishop shall convene a special meeting of the church council or church meeting, and shall either take the chair himself or appoint a chairman to preside at such meeting.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center,add-toc">Electoral
                Roll</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402530067_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Electoral roll</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410797142_026" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A roll of electors shall be formed by every church council on which
                                persons claiming to be qualified electors in the church concerned
                                shall if their claim is allowed be entered and they shall remain on
                                the roll as long as their title to be qualified electors in the
                                church concerned continues.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797158_005" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The initial rolls shall be formed by the Dean for the Cathedral and
                                the Vicar of Saint Andrew’s Church, Kowloon, for Saint Andrew’s
                                Church, Kowloon, and the Vicar of Christ Church, Kowloon Tong, for
                                Christ Church, Kowloon Tong, and in the case of other churches by
                                the respective incumbents.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1970/ln102">L.N. 102 of 1970</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797158_013" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Each roll shall be kept and revised by the church council concerned
                                when it is constituted. It shall be annually revised not less than
                                twenty-eight days before the annual church meeting. Notice of such
                                revision shall be affixed at the place or places hereinafter
                                prescribed with respect to notice convening the said annual church
                                meeting fourteen days at least before such revision takes
                                place.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797173_005" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The roll shall be published by being affixed at or near the
                                principal door of the church concerned in such manner as the church
                                council (or in the case of an initial roll, as the incumbent) shall
                                appoint and except in the case of the initial roll shall be open for
                                the enrolment of new voters continuously up to fourteen days before
                                the annual church meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797173_013" name="5" temporalId="s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Qualified electors are persons of either sex of eighteen years and
                                upwards who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410797173_021" name="a" temporalId="s16_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>are baptized and are members of the
                                        Anglican
                                        Church or a Church in communion therewith;
                                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797173_029" name="b" temporalId="s16_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>do not belong to any religious body which is not in
                                        communion with the
                                        Anglican
                                        Church; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797173_037" name="c" temporalId="s16_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>are not entered upon the electoral roll of any other church
                                        in the
                                        diocese;
                                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797189_006" name="d" temporalId="s16_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>have signed the declaration set forth hereunder:</content><content><inline class="width_18"> </inline>I,<br></br>being
                                        a worshipper at [name of church]<br></br>declare that I have
                                        attained the age of eighteen years and reside at<inline class="width_80"> </inline>and am a member of the
                                        Anglican
                                        Church
                                        or a Church in communion therewith and do not belong to any
                                        religious body which is not in communion with the
                                        Anglican
                                        Church
                                        and that I am not entered upon the electoral roll of any
                                        other church in the
                                        diocese.</content><content><inline class="width_18"> </inline>Dated
                                                this<inline class="width_47"> </inline>day
                                                of<inline class="width_47"> </inline>,
                                                <inline class="width_30"> </inline>.</content><content class="align_right"><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>(Signed)
                                                <fillIn class=" width_120">.</fillIn><marker role="blank-line"></marker><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                                                221</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797189_047" name="6" temporalId="s16_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The number of qualified persons on the electoral roll shall be
                                reported each year to the
                                Bishop
                                within one month after the annual church
                                        meeting.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                                        221</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center,add-toc">Annual
        Church Meeting</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402530082_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Annual church meeting</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410797236_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>There shall be held annually in
                connexion
                with each church not later than 31st of May the annual church meeting of qualified
                and duly enrolled electors—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410797236_012" name="a" temporalId="s17_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>for receiving from the church council and considering—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410797236_020" name="i" temporalId="s17_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a copy or copies of the electoral roll;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410797236_028" name="ii" temporalId="s17_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>an annual report on its proceedings;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410797236_036" name="iii" temporalId="s17_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a statement of the financial affairs of the church;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797236_043" name="b" temporalId="s17_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for electing representatives to be members of the body of The Trustees of
                    the
                    English-speaking
                    Anglican Church in Hong
                        Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                            222</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797236_051" name="c" temporalId="s17_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>for electing the church council;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797236_059" name="d" temporalId="s17_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>for electing representatives to the Diocesan
                        Synod;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                            222</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797236_067" name="e" temporalId="s17_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>for electing sidesmen;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797236_075" name="f" temporalId="s17_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>for electing an auditor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797236_083" name="g" temporalId="s17_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>for the transaction of any other business connected with the affairs of the
                        church.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1970/ln102">L.N. 102 of 1970</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797236_090" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All the above matters shall be open to free discussion and before the report is
                proposed for adoption and it shall be open to any member of the meeting to ask any
                question about church matters or bring about a discussion of any
                matter
                of general church interest by moving a general resolution or by moving to give any
                particular recommendation to the church council in the fulfilment of its duties. The
                meeting shall have power to adjourn and to determine its own time of meeting and
                rules of procedure.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797251_005" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The meeting shall be convened by the incumbent or clergyman in charge by notice
                (in the form hereafter set forth) affixed at or near the principal door of the
                church for a period including the two Sundays immediately preceding the day of the
                meeting. The meeting shall be held in such place at such date and hour as shall be
                directed by the church council or in the absence of such direction as shall be fixed
                by the incumbent or clergyman in
                charge.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection><text class="left_indent_60"><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="370">
                <colgroup>
                    <col width="50%"></col>
                    <col width="50%"></col>
                </colgroup>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_center">Form of
                            notice<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td colspan="2" class="first_line_indent_24 left_indent_0 align_justified cellpadding_bottom_5">Notice is hereby given that the annual church meeting of the <inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_70"> </inline> church will be held at <inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_50"> </inline>on<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_50"> </inline>day the<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_50"> </inline> day of <inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_50"> </inline>,
                                <inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_30"> </inline>, at <inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_50"> </inline>o’clock in the<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_50"> </inline>noon for the purposes following, namely—</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td colspan="2">
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="a" temporalId="s17_3_a" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1649388823093_001"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the election of representatives to the board of the
                                    trustees of the
                                    English-speaking
                                    Anglican Church
                                    in
                                    Hong Kong;</content></paragraph>
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="b" temporalId="s17_3_b" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1649388823093_002"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the election of the church council;</content></paragraph>
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="c" temporalId="s17_3_c" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1649388823093_003"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the election of representatives to the Diocesan
                                    Synod;</content></paragraph>
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="d" temporalId="s17_3_d" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1649388823093_004"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the election of sidesmen;</content></paragraph>
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="e" temporalId="s17_3_e" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1649388823093_005"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the election of an auditor;</content></paragraph>
                            
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="f" temporalId="s17_3_f" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1649388823093_006"><num value="f">(f)</num><leadIn>the receiving from the church council and
                                    considering—</leadIn></paragraph>
                            
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td colspan="2">
                            
                            
                            
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="0" temporalId="s17_3_0" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1755833959444_001"><subparagraph name="i" temporalId="s17_3_0_i" id="ID_1755833959460_002"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a copy or copies of the electoral roll;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="ii" temporalId="s17_3_0_ii" id="ID_1755833959460_003"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>an annual report on its proceedings;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="iii" temporalId="s17_3_0_iii" id="ID_1755833959460_004"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a statement of the financial affairs of the
                                        church;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
                            
                            
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" name="g" temporalId="s17_3_g" class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1649388823093_010"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the transacting of any other business connected with the
                                    affairs of the
                                    church.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td colspan="2" class="left_indent_24">Dated this<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_60"> </inline>day of<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_50"> </inline> ,
                                <inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_24"> </inline>.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center">Incumbent.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
            222</ref>)</sourceNote></text><subsection id="ID_1438410797282_064" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Fifteen electors shall be a quorum at the annual or a special church meeting of
                Saint John’s Cathedral Church, of Saint Andrew’s Church, Kowloon, of Christ Church,
                Kowloon Tong, or of any other church that comes within the provisions of the
                    Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1970/ln102">L.N. 102 of
                        1970</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    222</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797282_072" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The incumbent or clergyman in charge shall be the chairman of the meeting if
                present and if not a chairman shall be chosen by and from the electors present who
                shall preside at the meeting but no clerical chairman shall have a vote (except a
                casting vote) in the election of the church council.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410797298_005" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438410797298_009" name="a" temporalId="s17_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>The candidates must either previously to the meeting by written notice to
                    the convenor thereof or at the meeting be nominated by one elector and seconded
                    by another.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797298_015" name="b" temporalId="s17_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>If more candidates are nominated than there are seats to be filled the
                    election shall take place at the meeting unless a poll is demanded by at least
                    three of the voters present at the meeting.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797298_023" name="c" temporalId="s17_6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>At every election each elector on the roll shall have as many votes as
                    there are persons to be elected but may not give more than one vote to any one
                    candidate.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797298_031" name="d" temporalId="s17_6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>Where an equality of votes renders a casting vote necessary to decide the
                    election it shall be given by the person presiding over the election.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410797298_039" name="e" temporalId="s17_6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>The result of an election shall be forthwith announced by the person
                    presiding over the election and a notice of the result shall be affixed at or
                    near the principal door of the church and the notice shall be left so affixed
                    for not less than fourteen days following the date of election.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center,add-toc">Appeals</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402530129_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-05-12" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Appeals</heading><content>Any appeal against the allowance or disallowance of enrolment on the electoral roll
            or of a vote or against the report of the result of the election shall be made in
            writing to the incumbent within seven days after the date of publication of such
            allowance or disallowance or the publication of such result as the case may be. A
            commission shall be constituted by the church council and any appeal shall be considered
            and decided by such two or more members of the commission as the commission shall
            appoint and their decision shall be final.</content></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center,add-toc">Citation</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402530145_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the
            English-speaking
            Anglican Church Trust (Church Councils) Regulations.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 223</ref>)</sourceNote></section><appendix id="ID_1438402530160_001" name="app0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="app0">
        <num value="0">Appendix</num>
        
        <note class="align_right font_size_11" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1014A/s6">regs. 6</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap1014A/s8">8</ref>]</note>
        <heading>Rules
            of Procedure
            for
            Church
            Councils</heading>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797423_020" name="s1" temporalId="app0_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1"><inline>1.</inline></num><heading>Meetings of
                church council</heading><content>Every church council shall hold not less than four meetings in each year.
                Meetings shall be convened by the chairman and if not more than four meetings are
                held they shall be at quarterly intervals as far as
                possible.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797423_036" name="s2" temporalId="app0_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2"><inline>2.</inline></num><heading>Power to call meetings</heading><content>The chairman may at any time convene a meeting of the church council. If he
                refuses or neglects to do so within seven days after a requisition for that purpose
                signed by not less than one-third of the members of the church council has been
                presented to him those members may forthwith convene a
                meeting.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797423_052" name="s3" temporalId="app0_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3"><inline>3.</inline></num><heading>Notice of meeting</heading><content>Except as provided in <ref>rule 7</ref>, at least ten clear days before any
                meeting of a church council notice thereof specifying the time and place of the
                intended meeting, and signed by or on behalf of the chairman of the church council
                or the persons convening the meeting, shall be posted at or near the principal door
                of the
                church.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797423_068" name="s4" temporalId="app0_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4"><inline>4.</inline></num><heading>Notice of motion</heading><content>Notices of motion may be sent in writing to the secretary by any member of the
                church council at any time. Not less than seven days before the meeting a notice
                thereof specifying the time and place of the meeting signed by or on behalf of the
                secretary shall be sent to every member of the church council. Such notice shall
                contain the agenda of the meeting including any motion of which notice has been
                received by the
                secretary.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797438_004" name="s5" temporalId="app0_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5"><inline>5.</inline></num><heading>Quorum and agenda</heading><content>No business shall be transacted at any meeting of a church council unless at
                least one-third of the full number of members are present thereat, and no business
                which is not specified in the agenda shall be transacted at any meeting except by
                the consent of three-quarters of the members present at the
                meeting.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797438_020" name="s6" temporalId="app0_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6"><inline>6.</inline></num><heading>Order of business</heading><content>The business of a meeting of a church council shall be transacted in the order
                set forth in the agenda unless the church council by resolution otherwise
                determines.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797438_036" name="s7" temporalId="app0_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7"><inline>7.</inline></num><heading>Short notice for emergency meetings</heading><content>In case of sudden emergency and other special circumstances requiring immediate
                action by a church council a meeting may be convened by the chairman at not less
                than three days’ notice in writing to the members of the church council concerned,
                but the quorum for the transaction of any business at such meeting shall be a
                majority of the then existing members of the church council concerned and no
                business shall be transacted at such meeting except such as is specified in the
                notice convening the
                meeting.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797438_052" name="s8" temporalId="app0_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8"><inline>8.</inline></num><heading>Place of meeting</heading><content>The meetings of a church council shall be held at such place as the church
                council may direct or in the absence of such direction as the chairman may
                direct.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797438_068" name="s9" temporalId="app0_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9"><inline>9.</inline></num><heading>Vote of majority to decide</heading><content>Subject to the foregoing rules any motion proposed by any member of a church
                council present at a meeting shall be submitted to the meeting and shall be decided
                by a majority of votes of the members present and voting
                thereon.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797454_004" name="s10" temporalId="app0_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10"><inline>10.</inline></num><heading>Casting vote</heading><content>In case of an equal division of votes the chairman of the meeting shall have a
                second or casting
                vote.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797454_020" name="s11" temporalId="app0_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11"><inline>11.</inline></num><heading>Minutes</heading><content>The names of the members present at any meeting of a church council shall be
                recorded in the minutes, and the names of those voting on each question on which a
                division is taken if the members composing either the majority or the minority so
                require shall be recorded so as to show how the vote of each member was
                    given:<proviso name="proviso" temporalId="app0_11_proviso">Provided nevertheless
                    that the vote on any question shall be by ballot if the meeting so
                    decides.</proviso></content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797454_044" name="s12" temporalId="app0_s12" class="no_header"><num value="12"><inline>12.</inline></num><heading>Adjournments</heading><content>Any meeting of a church council may adjourn its proceedings to such time as may
                be determined at such meeting and to any place authorized under <ref>rule
                8</ref>.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797454_060" name="s13" temporalId="app0_s13" class="no_header"><num value="13"><inline>13.</inline></num><heading>Secretary of council</heading><content>A church council may appoint one of its number to act as secretary of the
                church council without remuneration. If no member is appointed so to act the church
                council shall appoint some other fit person with such remuneration (if any) as it
                may think fit. The secretary shall have charge of the electoral roll and of all
                documents relating to current business of the church council. He shall be
                responsible for keeping the minutes and shall record all resolutions passed by the
                church council and shall keep the secretary of the Diocesan
                Synod
                informed as to his
                address.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 224</ref>)</sourceNote></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797470_004" name="s14" temporalId="app0_s14" class="no_header"><num value="14"><inline>14.</inline></num><heading>Treasurer of council</heading><content>A church council shall appoint one or more of its number to act as treasurer
                solely or jointly without
                remuneration.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797470_020" name="s15" temporalId="app0_s15" class="no_header"><num value="15"><inline>15.</inline></num><heading>Power to appoint committees</heading><content>A church council may appoint committees for the purposes of the various
                branches of church work in the district and may include therein persons who are not
                members of the church council. The incumbent shall be a member of all committees ex
                officio.</content></section>
        
        <section id="ID_1438410797470_036" name="s16" temporalId="app0_s16" class="no_header"><num value="16"><inline>16.</inline></num><heading>Interpretation</heading><content>Any question arising on the interpretation of these rules shall be referred to
                the Bishop and any decision given by him or by any person appointed by him on his
                behalf shall be final.</content></section>
    </appendix></main></subLeg>