<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1143</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1143</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1143!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-11-30</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402605134_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-11-30">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Spiritual Assembly of the Baha’is of
                Hong Kong and to provide for matters incidental thereto or connected
                therewith.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[17 June 1988]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402605134_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as <shortTitle>The Spiritual Assembly of the Baha’is of Hong Kong Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402605150_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Assembly"><term>Assembly</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總會</term>) means the Spiritual Assembly for the time
            being elected by the members of the Baha’i community of Hong Kong in accordance with the
            constitution;</def><def name="Company"><term>company</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公司</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">該公司</term>) means
            the company incorporated, and registered by the name 
            “The
            National Spiritual Assembly of the Baha’is of Hong Kong”, under the
            relevant Ordinance;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2015/er3">E.R. 3 of 2015</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912 &amp;
                920</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of the Assembly as
            set forth in the <ref>First Schedule</ref> and any amendments thereto made from time to
            time in accordance with such constitution;</def><def name="ContractOfEmployment"><term>contract
                of
            employment</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">僱傭合約</term>) means a contract of employment, whether
            express or implied and, if express, whether oral or in writing;</def><def name="Employee">
            <leadIn><term>employee</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">僱員</term>) means—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411040128_047" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to the company, a person who works for the company under a
                    contract of employment; and</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411040128_055" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to the Assembly, a person who works for the Assembly under a
                    contract of employment and includes a person who was, immediately before the
                        commencement<sup>#</sup>
                    of this Ordinance, a person referred to in paragraph (a);
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912 &amp;
                        920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
        </def><def name="RelevantOrdinance"><term>relevant Ordinance</term> (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關條例</term>》) means the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>)
            as in force from time to time before the commencement date* of <ref>section 2 of
                Schedule 9</ref> to the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>).
            <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912 &amp;
                920</ref>)</sourceNote></def><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1680573368090_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%" class="font_size_9">
                <colgroup>
                    <col width="3%"></col>
                    <col width="97%"></col>
                </colgroup>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td><sup xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">#</sup></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">Commencement date : 17 June 1988.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="force_orig_font">*</inline></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">Commencement date : 3 March 2014.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402605165_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><content>The Assembly shall be a body corporate under the name of “The Spiritual Assembly of the Baha’is of Hong Kong” with exclusive right to use that name in Hong Kong and in that name shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be sued and shall have and may use a common seal.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402605165_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Objects of the Assembly</heading><content>The objects of the Assembly and its members shall be to administer the affairs of the Cause of Baha’u’llah for the benefit of the Baha’is of Hong Kong according to the principles of Baha’i affiliation and administration created and established by Baha’u’llah, Founder of the Baha’i Faith, by ‘Abdu’l-Baha, its Interpreter and Exemplar, by Shoghi Effendi, its Guardian and for the Assembly and its members to carry out on behalf of themselves and their successors the sacred Trust and religious standard established by Baha’u’llah for Baha’i administrative bodies in the words: “Be ye Trustees of the Merciful One among men” and to seek the help of God and His guidance in order to fulfil that exhortation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402605181_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Powers of the Assembly</heading><leadIn>The Assembly shall have power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411040206_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire, take on lease, purchase, hold and enjoy property, movable or immovable, and sell, let or otherwise dispose of or deal with such property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040206_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to enter into any contract;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040206_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to apply for and receive sponsorships, receive gifts, whether on trust or otherwise, and act as trustee of moneys or other property vested in it on trust;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040206_036" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, shares, securities, goods or chattels vested in the Assembly on such terms as the Assembly may deem fit; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040206_044" name="e" temporalId="s5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>generally to do all such other things as may appear to be incidental or conducive to the furtherance of its objects.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402605212_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Assembly to exercise powers in accordance with the constitution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411040237_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Assembly shall be subject to the control of the constitution and shall exercise its powers in accordance with such constitution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040237_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The constitution of the Assembly may be amended at any time and from time to time in accordance with its provisions for the time being in force.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040237_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Any amendment of the constitution shall be effective upon—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411040237_028" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a copy thereof, certified by the Secretary of the Assembly or a member thereof acting as Secretary, being lodged with the Registrar of Companies; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040237_036" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>such amendment being published in the Gazette.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402605212_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><content>All documents requiring the seal of the Assembly shall be sealed with its common seal in the presence of two members of the Assembly and shall be signed by such two members and the Secretary for the time being, and such signing shall be prima facie evidence that the said seal was duly affixed and that the same is the lawful seal of the Assembly.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402605228_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Vesting of properties, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411040268_018" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>On and from the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411040268_026" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all those pieces or parcels of land specified in the <ref>Second
                        Schedule</ref> which immediately prior to the commencement of this Ordinance
                    were vested in the company together with all rights, easements and appurtenances
                    thereto shall vest in the Assembly for the unexpired residues of the respective
                    terms of years created by the Crown Leases or Conditions of Grant specified
                    opposite each such piece or parcel, subject to the payment of the rent and
                    performance and observance of the covenants and conditions reserved by and
                    contained in the said Crown Leases and Conditions of Grant, and subject to such
                    leases, tenancies, easements and other rights as may be subsisting in relation
                    to the premises upon the commencement of this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040300_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all moneys and liquidated and unliquidated claims that, immediately before
                    that commencement, were payable to or recoverable by the company shall be moneys
                    and liquidated and unliquidated claims payable to or recoverable by the
                    Assembly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040300_014" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all proceedings commenced before that commencement by the company and
                    pending immediately before that commencement shall be deemed to be proceedings
                    pending by the Assembly and all proceedings so commenced by any person against
                    the company and pending immediately before the commencement shall be deemed to
                    be proceedings pending by that person against the Assembly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040315_006" name="d" temporalId="s8_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>all contracts, agreements, arrangements and undertakings entered into with,
                    and all securities lawfully given to or by, the company and in force immediately
                    before that commencement shall be deemed to be contracts, agreements,
                    arrangements and undertakings entered into with and securities given to or by
                    the Assembly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040315_014" name="e" temporalId="s8_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the Assembly may, in addition to pursuing any other remedies or exercising
                    any other powers that may be available to it, pursue the same remedies for the
                    recovery of money and claims referred to in this section and for the prosecution
                    of actions and proceedings so referred to as the company might have done but for
                    this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040315_022" name="f" temporalId="s8_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the Assembly may enforce and realize any security or charge existing
                    immediately before that commencement in favour of the company and may exercise
                    any powers thereby conferred on the company as if the security or charge were a
                    security or charge in favour of the Assembly; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040331_006" name="g" temporalId="s8_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>all debts, money and claims, liquidated and unliquidated, that, immediately
                    before the commencement, were due or payable by, or recoverable against, the
                    company shall be debts due by, money payable by and claims recoverable against,
                    the Assembly.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040331_013" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No stamp duty shall be payable in respect of any vesting under this section of
                movable or immovable property.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1680573685209_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date : 17 June
                1988.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402605243_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving of employees of the company</heading><content>Any person who was, immediately before the
                commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance, an employee
            of the company shall, on and from that commencement, be an employee of the Assembly on
            the same terms and conditions as he was an employee of the company immediately before
            that commencement.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1680573760555_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date : 17 June
                1988.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402605259_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>References in documents to the company</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411040378_025" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>On and from the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance, a
                reference in any document to the company or an employee of the company shall be a
                reference to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411040378_033" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of the company, the Assembly; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040378_041" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of an employee of the company, an employee of the
                    Assembly.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040378_048" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Document">For the purposes of this section
                    <term>document</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">文件</term>) does not include any document which
                relates to the incorporation of the company.</def></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1680573952935_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date : 17 June
                1988.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402605259_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Dissolution of the company</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411040409_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance, the
                company shall, notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary in its constitution
                governing the winding up or dissolution of the company and notwithstanding the
                provisions of any other Ordinance, be deemed to be dissolved under <ref>section
                    291A(1)</ref> of the relevant Ordinance as if, on that commencement, the Court
                of First Instance had made an order under that section that the company be struck
                off the register and dissolved and, accordingly, the Registrar of Companies shall,
                on that commencement, or so soon thereafter as is possible, strike the company off
                the register.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040424_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the avoidance of doubt, it is hereby declared that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411040424_013" name="a" temporalId="s11_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                        912
                        &amp;
                    920</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411040424_021" name="b" temporalId="s11_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><ref>section 757</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) applies, to the company.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912 &amp;
            920</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1680574573944_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date : 17 June
                1988.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402605290_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Service of documents on the Assembly</heading><content>The Assembly shall at all times have a fixed address for service of documents on the Assembly and notice of such address or any change thereof shall be forwarded to the Registrar of Companies.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402605290_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned or referred to in this Ordinance and
            those claiming by, through, from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402605306_002" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">First
            Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1143/s2">ss. 2</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap1143/s6">6</ref>]</note><heading>Constitution</heading><section id="ID_1438411040471_048" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><content>
                <leadIn>In this constitution, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn>
                <continued class="left_indent_60">
                    <def name="Assembly"><term>Assembly</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總會</term>) means the Spiritual Assembly for
                        the time being elected by the members of the Baha’i community of Hong Kong
                        in accordance with the constitution;</def>
                    <def name="AuthorizedArea"><term>authorized
                            area</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">獲授權地區</term>) means a locality the
                        boundaries of which have been or from time to time may be defined or
                        redefined by the Assembly;</def>
                    <def name="LocalSpiritualAssembly"><term>local
                            spiritual
                        assembly</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">分區區會</term>) means the assembly elected by
                        voting members in any authorized area by the Baha’is resident therein and
                        recognized by the Assembly;</def>
                    <def name="Recognized">
                        <leadIn><term>recognized</term>
                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">認可</term>) means—</leadIn>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1438411040487_014" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to a person, recognized by the Assembly as a member
                                in good standing of the Baha’i Faith by virtue of possessing the
                                qualifications set out in <ref>paragraph 3</ref>;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1438411040487_023" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to a local spiritual assembly, recognized by the
                                Assembly as duly and validly elected by voting members from within
                                its authorized area;</content></paragraph>
                    </def>
                    <def name="Trust"><term>Trust</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">信託</term>) means the exhortation of
                        Baha’u’llah that the elected members of the Assembly shall strive to achieve
                        the exalted religious standard established by Baha’u’llah: “Be ye Trustees
                        of the Merciful One among men”;</def>
                    <def name="VotingMember"><term>voting
                            member</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有表決權成員</term>) means any person of the age
                        of 21 or over recognized by either the Assembly or a local spiritual
                        assembly, including citizens of places outside Hong Kong whose transfers to
                        the Baha’i community of Hong Kong have been recognized by the
                            Assembly.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></def>
                </continued>
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438411040487_045" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Powers of Assembly</heading><content>The Assembly, in the fulfilment of its sacred duties under this Trust, shall
                have exclusive jurisdiction and authority over all the activities and affairs of the
                Baha’i Faith throughout Hong Kong, including paramount authority in the
                administration of this Trust. It shall endeavour to stimulate, unify and co-ordinate
                the manifold activities of the local spiritual assemblies and of individual Baha’is
                in Hong Kong and by all possible means assist them to promote the oneness of
                mankind. It shall be charged with determining whether local spiritual assemblies
                shall be recognized, the scrutiny of all membership rolls, the calling of the Annual
                Meeting or special meetings and the seating of delegates to the Annual Meeting and
                their apportionment among the various electoral districts. It shall appoint all
                regional Baha’i committees and shall supervise the publication and distribution of
                Baha’i literature, the reviewing of all writings pertaining to the Baha’i Faith, the
                construction and administration of the Mashriqu’l-Adhkar and its accessory
                activities, and the collection and disbursement of all funds for the carrying on of
                this Trust. It shall decide whether any matter lies within its own jurisdiction or
                within the jurisdiction of any local spiritual assembly. It shall, in such cases as
                it considers suitable and necessary, entertain appeals from the decisions of local
                spiritual assemblies and shall have the right of final decision in all cases where
                the qualification of an individual or group for continued voting rights and
                membership in the Baha’i Faith, community or institution is in question. It shall
                furthermore represent the Baha’is of Hong Kong in all their co-operative and
                spiritual activities with the Baha’is of other lands, and shall constitute the sole
                electoral body of Hong Kong in the election of the Universal House of Justice
                provided for in the Sacred Writings of the Baha’i Faith. Above all, the Assembly
                shall ever seek to attain that station of unity in devotion to the Revelation of
                Baha’u’llah which will attract the confirmations of the Holy Spirit and enable the
                Assembly to serve the founding of the Most Great Peace. In all its deliberations and
                action the Assembly shall have constantly before it as Divine guide and standard the
                utterance of Baha’u’llah—<quotedText class="left_indent_52">“It behooveth them
                    (i.e., members of spiritual assemblies) to be the trusted ones of the Merciful
                    among men and to regard themselves as the guardians appointed of God for all
                    that dwell on earth. It is incumbent upon them to take counsel together and to
                    have regard for the interests of the servants of God, for His sake, even as they
                    regard their own interests, and to choose that which is meet and
                    seemly.”.</quotedText></content></section><section id="ID_1438411040502_012" name="s3" temporalId="sch1_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Baha’i membership</heading><content><leadIn>The Baha’is of Hong Kong, for whose benefit this Trust is established,
                    shall consist of all persons of the age of 15 years or over resident in Hong
                    Kong who are accepted by the Assembly as possessing the qualifications of Baha’i
                    faith and practice required under following standard set forth by the Guardian
                    of the Baha’i Faith—</leadIn><quotedText class="left_indent_52">“Full
                    recognition of the station of the Bab, the Forerunner, Baha’u’llah, the Author
                    and of
                    ‘Abdu’l-Baha,
                    the True Exemplar of the Baha’i religion; unreserved acceptance of, and
                    submission to, whatsoever has been revealed by their Pen; loyal and steadfast
                    adherence to every clause of ‘Abdu’l-Baha’s sacred Will; and close association
                    with the spirit as well as the form of Baha’i administration throughout the
                    world.”.</quotedText>Those residing in the area of jurisdiction of any local
                spiritual assembly recognized by the Assembly may declare their faith to, and be
                enrolled by, the local spiritual assembly; those living outside any such area of
                local Baha’i jurisdiction shall be enrolled in such manner as shall be prescribed by
                the
                Assembly.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411040502_044" name="s4" temporalId="sch1_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Composition of the Assembly</heading><content>The Assembly shall consist of nine members chosen from among the voting members
                of the Baha’i community of Hong Kong, who shall be elected by the voting members in
                the manner hereinafter provided, and who shall hold office for the term of one year,
                or until their successors are
                elected.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411040518_012" name="s5" temporalId="sch1_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Officers of the Assembly</heading><content>The officers of the Assembly shall consist of a Chairman, Vice-Chairman,
                Secretary and Treasurer and such other officers as may be found necessary for the
                proper conduct of its affairs. The officers shall be elected by a majority vote of
                the entire membership of the Assembly taken by secret
                ballot.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411040518_028" name="s6" temporalId="sch1_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Meetings and transaction of business by circulation of papers</heading><content>The first meeting of a newly-elected Assembly shall be called by the member
                elected to membership by the highest number of votes or, in case two or more members
                have received the same highest number of votes, then by the member selected by lot
                from among of those members; and this member shall preside until the permanent
                Chairman shall be chosen. All subsequent meetings shall be called by the Secretary
                of the Assembly at the request of the Chairman or, in his absence or incapacity, of
                the Vice-Chairman, or of any three members of the Assembly; provided, however, that
                the Annual Meeting of the Assembly shall be held at a time and place to be fixed by
                a majority vote of the Assembly, as hereinafter provided. The Assembly may transact
                any of its business by circulation of papers amongst members (whether any such
                member is inside or outside Hong Kong), and a resolution in writing which is
                approved in writing by not less than five members of the Assembly shall be as valid
                and effectual as if it had been passed by a meeting of the Assembly.
                </content></section><section id="ID_1438411040534_004" name="s7" temporalId="sch1_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Quorum</heading><content>Five members of the Assembly present at a meeting shall constitute a quorum,
                and a majority vote of those present and constituting a quorum shall be sufficient
                for the conduct of business, except as otherwise provided in this constitution, and
                with due regard to the principle of unity and cordial fellowship involved in the
                institution of a Baha’i spiritual assembly. The decisions and transactions of the
                Assembly shall be recorded at each meeting by the Secretary, who shall supply copies
                of the minutes to the Assembly members after each meeting, and preserve the minutes
                in the official records of the
                Assembly.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411040534_020" name="s8" temporalId="sch1_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Local spiritual assemblies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411040534_030" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Whenever in any authorized area, the number of voting members exceeds nine,
                    they shall on 21st April of any year convene and elect by plurality vote a local
                    administrative body of nine members, to be known as the Spiritual Assembly of
                    the Baha’is of that community. Every such local spiritual assembly shall be
                    elected annually thereafter upon each successive 21st April. The members shall
                    hold office for the term of one year or until their successors are elected and
                    qualified. When, however, the number of Baha’is in any such authorized area is
                    exactly nine, they shall on April 21st of any year, or in successive years,
                    constitute themselves the local spiritual assembly by joint declaration. Upon
                    the recognition of such declaration by the Secretary of the Assembly the said
                    body of nine shall become established with the rights, privileges and duties of
                    a local spiritual assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040580_006" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Each newly-elected local spiritual assembly shall at once proceed in the
                    manner indicated in <ref>paragraphs 5</ref> and <ref>6</ref> to the election of
                    its officers, who shall consist of a Chairman, Vice-Chairman, Secretary and
                    Treasurer, and such other officers as the Assembly finds necessary for the
                    conduct of its business and the fulfilment of its spiritual duties. Immediately
                    thereafter the Secretary chosen shall transmit to the Secretary of the Assembly
                    the names of the members of the newly-elected local spiritual assembly and a
                    list of its officers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040596_006" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The general powers and duties of a local spiritual assembly shall be as set
                    forth in the
                    writings
                    of Baha’u’llah, ‘Abdu’l-Baha and Shoghi Effendi.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040596_015" name="4" temporalId="sch1_s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Among its more specific duties, a local spiritual assembly shall have
                    jurisdiction of all Baha’i activities and affairs within the local community,
                    subject, however, to the exclusive and paramount authority of the Assembly as
                    defined herein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040596_024" name="5" temporalId="sch1_s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Vacancies in the membership of a local spiritual assembly shall be filled
                    by election at a special meeting of the voting members then living within that
                    authorized area duly called for that purpose by the Assembly. In the event that
                    the number of vacancies exceeds four, making a quorum of the local spiritual
                    assembly impossible, the election shall be held under the supervision of the
                    Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040612_006" name="6" temporalId="sch1_s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The business of the local spiritual assembly shall be conducted in like
                    manner as provided for the deliberations of the Assembly in <ref>paragraph
                        6</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040612_015" name="7" temporalId="sch1_s8_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The local spiritual assembly shall pass upon and approve the qualifications
                    of each member of the Baha’i community before such member shall be admitted as a
                    voting member or thereafter removed as a voting member; but where an individual
                    is dissatisfied with the ruling of the local spiritual assembly upon his status
                    as a voting member, such individual may appeal from the ruling to the Assembly,
                    which shall thereupon take jurisdiction of and finally decide the
                    case.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040627_006" name="8" temporalId="sch1_s8_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>On or before the 1st November of each year the Secretary of each local
                    spiritual assembly shall send to the Secretary of the Assembly a duly certified
                    list of the voting members of the local Baha’i community for the information and
                    approval of the Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040627_015" name="9" temporalId="sch1_s8_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>All matters arising within a local Baha’i community which are of purely
                    local interest and do not affect the interest of the Baha’i Faith in the area of
                    Hong Kong as a whole shall be under the primary jurisdiction of the local
                    spiritual assembly of that authorized area; but the decision whether a
                    particular matter involves the interest and welfare of the entire Baha’i
                    community of Hong Kong or other Baha’i communities shall rest with the
                    Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040643_006" name="10" temporalId="sch1_s8_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Any member of a local Baha’i community may appeal from a decision of his
                    local spiritual assembly to the Assembly, which shall determine whether it shall
                    take jurisdiction of the matter or leave it to the local spiritual assembly for
                    reconsideration. In the event that the Assembly assumes jurisdiction of the
                    matter, its findings shall be final.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040643_015" name="11" temporalId="sch1_s8_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>Where any dissension exists within a local Baha’i community of such
                    character that it cannot be remedied by the efforts of the local spiritual
                    assembly, this condition shall be referred by the local spiritual assembly for
                    consideration to the Assembly, whose action in the matter shall be final.
                </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040658_006" name="12" temporalId="sch1_s8_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>All questions arising between two or more local spiritual assemblies, or
                    between members of different Baha’i communities, shall be submitted to the
                    Assembly, which shall have original and final jurisdiction in all such
                    matters.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040658_015" name="13" temporalId="sch1_s8_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>The sphere of jurisdiction of a local spiritual assembly, with respect to
                    residential qualification of membership, and voting rights of a believer in any
                    Baha’i community, shall be the locality included within the authorized
                    area.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040658_024" name="14" temporalId="sch1_s8_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content>All differences of opinion concerning the sphere of jurisdiction of any
                    local spiritual assembly or concerning the affiliation of any Baha’i or group of
                    Baha’is
                    is in Hong Kong shall be referred to the Assembly, whose decision in the matter
                    shall be
                    final.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438411040658_031" name="s9" temporalId="sch1_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Annual Convention</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411040658_041" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The members of the Assembly shall be elected at an annual meeting to be
                    known as the Annual Convention of the Baha’is of Hong Kong. This Convention
                    shall be held at a time and place to be fixed by the Assembly. The Annual
                    Convention shall be composed jointly of representatives chosen by the Baha’is of
                    each authorized area, under the principle of proportionate representation, and
                    the members of the Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040674_006" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of the Annual Convention shall be given by the Assembly sixty days
                    in advance in the Annual Convention Call which sets forth the number of
                    delegates assigned to the various authorized areas in proportion to the number
                    of Baha’is resident in each
                    such
                    area, up to a total number of at least 38 delegates for the Baha’is of Hong Kong
                    or such larger number of delegates as the Assembly shall from time to time
                    establish.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040674_022" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>All delegates to the Annual Convention shall be elected by plurality vote
                    by the voting members resident in the authorized area at times and places set by
                    the Assembly. Baha’is who for illness or other unavoidable reasons are unable to
                    be present at the election in person shall have the right to transmit their
                    ballots to the meeting by mail. The meeting held in each authorized area for the
                    election of delegates shall be called by the Assembly and conducted by the
                    Baha’is present under whatever procedure may be uniformly laid down by said
                    body. Immediately after the meeting a certified report of the election
                    containing the name and address of each delegate shall be transmitted to the
                    Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040705_006" name="4" temporalId="sch1_s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>All delegates to be seated at the Annual Convention must be recognized
                    Baha’is, voting members and residents of the authorized area represented by
                    them.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040705_015" name="5" temporalId="sch1_s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The rights and privileges of a delegate may not be assigned nor may they be
                    exercised by proxy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040705_024" name="6" temporalId="sch1_s9_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The recognition and seating of delegates to the Annual Convention shall be
                    vested in the Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040705_033" name="7" temporalId="sch1_s9_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Delegates unable to be present in person at the Annual Convention shall
                    have the right to transmit their ballots for election of the members of the
                    Assembly under whatever procedure is adopted by the Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040721_006" name="8" temporalId="sch1_s9_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>If in any year the Assembly shall consider that it is impracticable or
                    unwise to assemble together the delegates to the Annual Convention, the Assembly
                    shall provide ways and means by which the annual election and the other
                    essential business of the Annual Convention may be conducted by mail.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040721_015" name="9" temporalId="sch1_s9_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>The presiding officer of the Assembly present at the Annual Convention
                    shall call together the delegates, who after roll call shall proceed to the
                    permanent organization of the meeting, electing by ballot a Chairman, a
                    Secretary and such other officers as are necessary for the proper conduct of the
                    business of the Annual Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040721_024" name="10" temporalId="sch1_s9_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>The principal business of the Annual Convention shall be consultation on
                    Baha’i activities, plans and policies, and the election of the nine members of
                    the Assembly. Members of the Assembly, whether or not elected delegates, may
                    take a full part in the consultation and discussion but only delegates may
                    participate in the election of Annual Convention officers or in the annual
                    election of the members of the Assembly. All action by the delegates, other than
                    the organization of the Annual Convention and the election of the Assembly,
                    shall constitute advice and recommendation for consideration by the Assembly,
                    final decision on all matters concerning the affairs of the Baha’i Faith in Hong
                    Kong being vested solely in that body.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040752_006" name="11" temporalId="sch1_s9_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>The general order of business to be taken up at the Annual Convention shall
                    be prepared by the Assembly in the form of an agenda, but any matter pertaining
                    to the Baha’i Faith introduced by any of the delegates may upon motion and vote
                    be taken up as part of the Convention deliberations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040752_015" name="12" temporalId="sch1_s9_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>The election of the members of the Assembly shall be by plurality vote of
                    the delegates recognized by the outgoing Assembly, i.e., the members elected
                    shall be the nine persons receiving the greatest number of votes on the first
                    ballot cast by delegates
                    present at
                    the Annual Convention and delegates whose ballots have been transmitted to the
                    Secretary of the Assembly by mail. In case, by reason of a tie vote or votes,
                    the full membership is not determined on the first ballot, then one or more
                    additional ballots shall be taken on the persons tied until all nine members are
                    elected.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040768_013" name="13" temporalId="sch1_s9_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>All business transacted at the Annual Convention shall be recorded and
                    preserved in the records of the Assembly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411040768_022" name="14" temporalId="sch1_s9_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content>Vacancies in the membership of the Assembly shall be filled by a plurality
                    vote of the delegates composing the Annual Convention which elected the
                    Assembly, the ballot to be taken by correspondence or in any other manner
                    decided upon by the
                    Assembly.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438411040768_029" name="s10" temporalId="sch1_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Power to vest in the Assembly</heading><content>Whatever functions and powers are not specifically attributed to local
                spiritual assemblies in this constitution shall be considered vested in the
                Assembly, which body is authorized to delegate such discretionary functions and
                powers as it deems necessary and advisable to the local spiritual assemblies within
                its
                jurisdiction.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411040768_045" name="s11" temporalId="sch1_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Method of selection of candidates</heading><content>In order to preserve the spiritual character and purpose of Baha’i elections,
                the practice of nominations or any other electoral method detrimental to a silent
                and prayerful election shall not prevail, so that each elector may vote for none but
                those whom prayer
                and reflection
                have inspired him to uphold.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411040783_012" name="s12" temporalId="sch1_s12" class="no_header"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Duties of members of assemblies</heading><content>Among the most outstanding and sacred duties incumbent upon those who have been
                called upon to initiate, direct and co-ordinate the affairs of the Baha’i Faith as
                members of local, regional or national spiritual assemblies are to win by every
                means in their power the confidence and affection of those whom it is their
                privilege to serve; to investigate and acquaint themselves with the considered
                views, the prevailing sentiments and the personal convictions of those whose welfare
                it is their solemn obligation to promote; to purge their deliberations and the
                general conduct of their affairs of self-contained aloofness, the suspicion of
                secrecy, the stifling atmosphere of dictatorial assertiveness and of every word and
                deed that may savour of partiality, self-centredness and prejudice; and while
                retaining the sacred right of final decision in their hands, to invite discussion,
                ventilate grievances, welcome advice, and foster the sense of inter-dependence and
                co-partnership, of understanding and mutual confidence between themselves and all
                other
                Baha’is.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411040799_004" name="s13" temporalId="sch1_s13" class="no_header"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Amendment of the constitution</heading><content>This constitution may be amended by majority vote of the Assembly at any of its
                regular or special meetings, provided that at least fourteen days prior to the date
                fixed for the said meeting a copy of the proposed amendment or amendments is mailed
                to each member of the Assembly by the Secretary.</content></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402605352_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-30" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Second
            Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1143/s8">s. 8</ref>]</note><heading>Properties
            Vested</heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="font_size_11" width="445">
                
                <col width="8%"></col>
                
                <col width="42%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="6%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="44%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p>Item</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Description</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Held Under</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p>1.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">1/720th equal and undivided share of and in
                            Kowloon Inland Lot No. 8219 and the Extension thereto</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <p class=" left_indent_12 align_justified">Conditions of Re-Grant No. 7135
                            and Conditions of Extension No. 8555</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p>2.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Lot 1703 in Lamma Demarcation District 3</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <p class=" left_indent_12 align_justified">New Grant No. 4466</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p>3.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">40/960th equal undivided shares of and in the
                            Remaining Portion of Section P of Inland Lot No. 1149 and the Remaining
                            Portion of Inland Lot No. 1149</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <p class=" left_indent_12 align_justified">Crown Lease dated 23rd July
                            1902</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </text></schedule></main></ordinance>