<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1078</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1078</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1078!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-05-05</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402556634_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-05-05">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Trustees of the Hong Kong Baptist
                Church.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[27 May 1955]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402556634_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Baptist Church Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556649_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-05" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Church"><term>church</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">教會</term>) means the Hong Kong Baptist Church;</def><def name="Committee"><term>committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">委員會</term>) means the committee elected by members of
            the church;</def><def name="Deacons"><term>deacons</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會佐</term>) means the deacons of the church;</def><def name="Members"><term>members</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會友</term>) means the adults who have been baptised in
            and admitted to the church or those transferred from other baptist churches and admitted
            to the church.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402556649_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-05" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Description and incorporation</heading><text>The trustees for the time being of the Hong Kong Baptist Church shall be a body
            corporate, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name “The Trustees of The Hong Kong
            Baptist Church”, and in that name shall have perpetual succession and shall and may sue
            and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may have and use a common seal and
            may break, alter and make anew the said seal.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402556665_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410847390_018" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate, and also invest moneys upon mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, or upon the mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation, company or person, and also to purchase, acquire and possess vessels and other goods and chattels of what nature and kind soever.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410847405_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation shall further have power by deed under its seal to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities, or vessels or other goods and chattels, which are for the time being vested in or belonging to the corporation, upon such terms as to the corporation may seem fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402556680_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Transfer of property</heading><content>The legal estate in any property whatsoever transferred to the corporation in any
            manner whatsoever shall in the event of the death of any of the trustees for the time
            being or in the
            event of any trustee ceasing to hold office as such trustee vest in the trustees for the
            time being duly appointed.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556680_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Number of trustees</heading><content>The number of the trustees shall be seven.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556696_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Vacation of office by trustee</heading><content>The office of any trustee shall be automatically vacated if such trustee shall die or shall resign his office or if a resolution be passed at a meeting of members of the church requiring the resignation of such trustee or if his term of office shall come to an end.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556712_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>New trustees; their appointment and tenure of office</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410847468_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>At the annual general meeting of members of the church held in each year, six new trustees shall be elected by members of the church as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410847468_019" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>three deacons who have been proposed by the deacons of the church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410847468_027" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>three members of the committee who have been proposed by the members of the committee.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410847468_034" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If there shall only be one clergyman or preacher then he shall be ex officio a trustee but if there shall be more than one, then the members of the church shall elect in the church during the month of January each year a presiding clergyman or preacher from among the number of clergymen or preachers, and such presiding clergyman or preacher shall be ex officio a trustee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410847483_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 7</ref>, trustees when elected shall hold office until the annual general meeting of members of the church in the following year. Trustees whose terms of office have expired shall be eligible for re-election.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402556712_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Filling casual vacancies among trustees</heading><content>If the office of a trustee be vacated other than through the expiration of the term of office then a new trustee shall be elected by the members of the church from among the class of members of the church who proposed the trustee whose office is vacated and such new trustee shall hold office until the next annual general meeting of the members of the church.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556727_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Notification of changes of trustees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410847514_018" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any change in membership of the trustees shall within three weeks of such
                change be notified in writing to the Chief Secretary for Administration and by the
                publication of a notice in the Gazette.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of
                        1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410847514_026" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No such change shall be deemed to have been made until a notification of such
                change has been published in the Gazette.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410847514_034" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The production of a copy of the Gazette containing any such notification shall
                be prima facie evidence of a change in membership of the trustees.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410847530_004" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The trustees shall when required by the Chief Executive furnish to him
                satisfactory proof of the succession, election or appointment of any new
                    trustee.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402556743_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Appointment of chairman,
            vice-chairman,
            and secretary</heading><content>The trustees when elected shall appoint a chairman, a vice-chairman, and a
            secretary from among their number.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556743_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Execution of deeds</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be sealed in the presence of three or more of the trustees, one of whom must be a trustee ex officio and shall also be signed by the three of such trustees present and such signing shall be and be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing thereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556758_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Appointment and removal of clergyman or preacher</heading><content>The members of the church may at a general meeting of the members appoint a clergyman or clergymen or preacher or preachers to perform and carry on divine worship and the services usual in the Baptist Churches and may also appoint a preacher or preachers and other officers or staff to assist the presiding clergyman or preacher to carry on all matters connected with the religious services or other affairs of the church under the immediate direction of the presiding clergyman or preacher, and may remove all or any of them.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556774_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Custody of documents</heading><content>All books, deeds, papers and other documents belonging to the church shall be under the care and custody of some one or more persons appointed by the trustees.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556774_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Power of committee to make regulations</heading><content>All regulations relating to the affairs of the church otherwise than those specifically provided for by this Ordinance shall be drawn up by a committee appointed by the members of the church for such purpose and shall be submitted to the general meeting for approval.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556790_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Regulations not binding until approved</heading><content>No regulations made by any committee under <ref>section 15</ref> shall be binding on the members of the church unless such regulations have been passed by a majority of members present and voting at a general meeting of members.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556790_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>