<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1115</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1115</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1115!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-03-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402576352_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2013-04-25">
            <content>To provide for the establishment of the Hong Kong Export Credit Insurance
                Corporation, and to define its powers and
                functions.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[23 December 1966]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438402576352_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part 1</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438402576368_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Export Credit Insurance Corporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402576414_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AdvisoryBoard"><term>Advisory Board</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">諮詢委員會</term>) means the Advisory Board established by <ref>section 10</ref>;</def><def name="Auditors"><term>auditors</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">核數師</term>) means the auditors appointed under <ref>section 25</ref>;</def><def name="Commissioner"><term>Commissioner</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總監</term>) means the Commissioner of the Hong Kong Export Credit Insurance Corporation appointed under <ref>section 6</ref>;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>Corporation</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">保險局</term>) means the Hong Kong Export Credit Insurance Corporation established by <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="FinancialYear"><term>financial year</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">財政年度</term>) means the period commencing on the 1 April in any year and ending on the 31 March in the year following, except that the period from the commencement of this Ordinance to 31 March 1967 shall be deemed to be a financial year;</def><def name="TradeWithPlacesOutsideHongKong"><term>trade with places outside Hong Kong</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">與香港以外地方進行的貿易</term>) includes any transaction (including a transaction for the rendering of a service) involving a consideration in money or money’s worth accruing from a person in the course of carrying on business or other activities outside Hong Kong to a person carrying on business in Hong Kong or to a company carrying on business or other activities outside Hong Kong which is directly or indirectly controlled by a company carrying on business or other activities in Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section></part><part id="ID_1438402576414_003" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part 2</num><heading>Establishment, Constitution, Incorporation and Business of the Corporation</heading><section id="ID_1438402576446_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Establishment of Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898620_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There is hereby established a corporation to be called the Hong Kong Export Credit Insurance Corporation which shall, in that name, be a body corporate with perpetual succession and shall be capable of suing and being sued, and subject to this Ordinance of doing and suffering all such other acts and things as bodies corporate may lawfully do and suffer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898636_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The powers, functions and duties of the Corporation under this Ordinance may be exercised or performed in its name and on its behalf by the person for the time being performing the duties of the office of Commissioner.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576446_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Official seal and authentication thereof, and instruments executed thereunder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898651_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation shall have and may use a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>common seal, the affixing of which shall be authenticated by the signature of the Commissioner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898651_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any instrument purporting to be an instrument duly executed under the seal of the Corporation shall be received in evidence and shall, unless the contrary is proved, be deemed to be an instrument so executed.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576461_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Certain contracts and instruments not required to be under seal</heading><content>Any contract or instrument which, if entered into or executed by a person not being a body corporate, would not be required to be under seal may be entered into, signed or executed on behalf of the Corporation by any person generally or specially authorized for that purpose by the Corporation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402576477_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Appointment of Commissioner</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898698_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive may appoint a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>Commissioner of the Hong Kong Export Credit Insurance Corporation, who may be a public officer seconded for the purpose, on such terms and conditions as he may think fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898698_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The appointment of any person to be the Commissioner, and the termination of his appointment, shall be notified in the Gazette.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576492_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Delegation of powers by the Corporation</heading><content>The Corporation may delegate any officer of the Corporation, or the person for the time being holding any office of the Corporation designated by it, to exercise such of its powers, except this power of delegation, or perform such of its functions and duties on its behalf as it may consider necessary.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402576492_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Acting Commissioner</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898729_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If the office of Commissioner is vacant at any time or in the event of the absence from duty of the Commissioner, the Chief Executive may appoint a person, who may be a public officer seconded for the purpose, to act as Commissioner on such terms and conditions as he may think fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898729_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person appointed to act as Commissioner by reason of a vacancy in the office of Commissioner shall hold office at the Chief Executive’s discretion, but shall not in any event continue in office for more than 1 year from the date of his appointment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898729_020" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person appointed to act as Commissioner in the event of the absence from duty of the Commissioner shall hold office during that absence, but his appointment may at any time be terminated by the Chief Executive.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402576508_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Business of the Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898745_041" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation may, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, carry on the business of insurance, being insurance under the contracts of insurance specified in subsection (2), and the business of giving guarantees under <ref>section 9B</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898761_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The contracts of insurance which the Corporation may enter into under this section are contracts of insurance with, or for the benefit of, persons carrying on business in Hong Kong, being contracts of insurance against risk of monetary loss or other monetary detriment attributable to circumstances outside the control of the person suffering the loss or detriment and resulting from failure to receive payment in connexion with, or otherwise arising out of, acts or transactions in the course of, or for the purpose of, trade with places outside Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898776_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Corporation shall not enter into contracts of insurance against risks that are normally insured with commercial insurers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898776_013" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Corporation shall pursue a policy directed towards securing revenue sufficient to meet all its expenditure properly chargeable to revenue account.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576524_002" name="s9A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s9A"><num value="9A">9A.</num><heading>Power of Corporation to enter into re-insurance agreement</heading><content>The Corporation may enter into an agreement with any person whereby such person undertakes to insure the Corporation against all or any of the liability of the Corporation under a contract of insurance entered into under <ref>section 9</ref> either before or after the commencement of the Hong Kong Export Credit Insurance Corporation (Amendment) Ordinance 1970 (<ref href="/hk/1970/58">58 of 1970</ref>).</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1970/58">58 of 1970 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402576539_001" name="s9B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s9B"><num value="9B">9B.</num><heading>Guarantees</heading><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410898807_047" name="a" temporalId="s9B_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Corporation has entered into, or proposes to enter into, a contract of insurance under <ref>section 9</ref> with, or for the benefit of, any person; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898823_006" name="b" temporalId="s9B_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>another person has advanced, or proposes to advance, moneys to the first-mentioned person for the purpose of financing, in whole or in part, the acts and transactions, which are the subject matter of the contract of insurance,</content></paragraph><continued>the Corporation may guarantee to that other person the re-payment of the whole or any part of the moneys advanced or to be advanced by him and the payment of the whole or any part of any interest or other charges that may become payable to him in respect of those moneys.</continued><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402576539_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part 3</num><heading>Advisory Board</heading><section id="ID_1438402576570_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-06-26" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Advisory Board establishment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898839_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There is hereby established an Advisory Board to advise the Corporation in the conduct of its business under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898854_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Advisory Board shall consist of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410898854_013" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="hk/2015/12">12 of 2015 s.
                        169</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898854_021" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Executive Director, Hong Kong Trade Development Council, or his representative; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898854_029" name="c" temporalId="s10_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>not more than 10 other members.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898854_036" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The members of the Advisory Board, other than
                
                the Executive Director, Hong Kong Trade Development Council—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/ln206">L.N. 206 of 1977</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1982/ln294">L.N. 294 of 1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1984/ln215">L.N. 215 of 1984</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1990/ln392">L.N. 392 of
                    1990</ref>; <ref href="hk/2015/12">12 of 2015 s.
                    169</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410898854_044" name="a" temporalId="s10_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall be appointed by the Chief Executive for a term not exceeding 3 years
                    at a time; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898854_052" name="b" temporalId="s10_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall upon appointment take an oath before a commissioner for oaths in the
                    form prescribed in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s.
                            10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898854_059" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If a member of the Advisory Board has any pecuniary interest, direct or indirect, in any contract or proposed contract or other matter, and is present at a meeting of the Board at which the contract or other matter is the subject of consideration, he shall, as soon as practicable after the commencement of the meeting of the Board, disclose to the Board the fact and the nature of his interest.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898870_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Corporation shall not be bound by the advice of the Advisory Board.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402576570_003" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part 4</num><heading>Policy of the Corporation</heading><section id="ID_1438402576586_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Policy</heading><content>The Corporation shall keep the Financial Secretary informed of the decisions of the Corporation insofar as they relate to matters of policy in relation to the conduct of its business.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402576602_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Approval of policy in respect of certain matters</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898917_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The policy pursued by the Corporation with respect to any of the following matters, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410898917_012" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the classes of contracts of insurance into which the Corporation will enter;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898917_020" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the nature and extent of the risks that may be covered under contracts of insurance entered into by the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898917_028" name="c" temporalId="s12_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the undertaking of liabilities in relation to trade with particular places;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898917_036" name="d" temporalId="s12_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the organization of the finances of the Corporation and the determination of the use to which any surpluses acquired by the Corporation are to be put;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898917_044" name="e" temporalId="s12_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the determination of the total amount of the capital and reserves required by the Corporation taking into account the sums at risk under contracts of insurance entered into by the Corporation; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898917_052" name="f" temporalId="s12_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the giving of guarantees,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>shall be subject to the approval of the Financial Secretary:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s12_1_proviso">Provided that nothing in this subsection shall prevent the Corporation, when it considers an immediate decision is required, from pursuing a policy which has not been approved by the Financial Secretary if it seeks his approval of such policy at the first available opportunity.</proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898932_004" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Nothing in subsection (1) shall be construed as—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410898932_012" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>requiring the approval of the Financial Secretary to the entering by the Corporation into a particular contract of insurance or the giving by the Corporation of a particular guarantee; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898932_020" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>empowering the Financial Secretary to determine that the Corporation shall or shall not enter into a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>particular contract of insurance or give a particular guarantee,</content></paragraph><continued>but the Corporation shall not enter into a particular contract of insurance or give a particular guarantee unless the contract or guarantee is in accordance with the policy approved by the Financial Secretary.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898932_033" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="Surplus"><leadIn><term>surplus</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">盈餘</term>) means those balances which the Corporation has in hand at the end of any financial year and which are not required to meet—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410898932_048" name="a" temporalId="s12_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>payments at that time due to be made as a result of claims under examination in respect of contracts of insurance entered into by the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898932_056" name="b" temporalId="s12_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>payments due to be made in respect of the operating expenses of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898948_006" name="c" temporalId="s12_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>provision for expenditure on capital items, on replacements of fixed assets and on amortization payments incurred by the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898948_014" name="d" temporalId="s12_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>such sums as in the opinion of the Corporation may be required to cover the unexpired risks on contracts of insurance entered into by the Corporation; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410898948_022" name="e" temporalId="s12_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>any other liabilities.</content></paragraph></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576617_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-03-28" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Extent of indemnity</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410898995_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A contract of insurance entered into by the Corporation shall specify a
                percentage as the percentage of the amount of the loss, as defined in the contract,
                to which the indemnity under the contract extends.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410898995_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The maximum percentage so specified in any contract of insurance shall not
                exceed 90 per cent or such other maximum percentage as may be prescribed by the
                Legislative Council by
                    resolution*.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1975/ln185">L.N.
                        185 of 1975</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1743567880356_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Current maximum percentage is
                95%—see <ref href="/hk/2025/ln54">L.N. 54 of 2025</ref>.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402576633_001" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part 5</num><heading>Powers of the Corporation</heading><section id="ID_1438402576633_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Powers of the Corporation</heading><leadIn>The Corporation may do, within Hong Kong or elsewhere, all things necessary or convenient to be done for and in connection with, or incidental to, the carrying on of its business and, in particular, may—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410899026_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>acquire, hold and dispose of immovable or movable property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410899026_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enter into any contract; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410899026_028" name="c" temporalId="s14_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>pay to the Government out of surpluses held by the Corporation such sums as may be determined pursuant to the policy approved in this respect by the Financial Secretary under <ref>section 12(1)</ref>.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402576664_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Provident fund scheme</heading><content>The Corporation may, with the approval of the Chief Executive, establish, manage and control, or enter into an arrangement with an insurance company or association for the establishment, management and control by such company or association, either alone or jointly with the Corporation, of a provident fund scheme for the benefit of the Commissioner and any of the officers of the Corporation, or of any specified class of officer of the Corporation, and if so required by rules governing such scheme may make contributions thereto in accordance with such rules.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402576664_003" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part 6</num><heading>Staff</heading><section id="ID_1438402576680_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Appointment of officers</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 17</ref>, the Corporation may appoint such officers as it thinks necessary.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402576695_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Terms and conditions of employment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899088_011" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The terms and conditions of employment of officers appointed by the Corporation shall be such as are determined by the Corporation with the approval of the Financial Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899088_019" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The appointment by the Corporation of an officer whose annual salary is equivalent to or exceeds that of a Senior Administrative Officer in the public service shall be subject to the approval of the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1990/5">5 of 1990 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438402576711_001" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part 7</num><heading>Finance</heading><section id="ID_1438402576711_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Corporation indemnified</heading><content>The Government shall guarantee the payment of all moneys due by the Corporation, but nothing in this section shall authorize a creditor or other person claiming against the Corporation to sue the Government in respect of his claim.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402576726_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Capital</heading><content>The Financial Secretary may pay to the Corporation from the general revenue of Hong Kong or the Development Loan Fund, in such amounts and at such times as he determines, sums of money not exceeding in the aggregate $20,000,000, and the capital of the Corporation shall consist of the amounts so paid to the Corporation.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402576773_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Loans</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899244_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Financial Secretary may, out of moneys appropriated by the Legislative Council for the purposes of this Ordinance, make advances to the Corporation of such amounts, and upon such terms and conditions with respect to repayment, payment of interest and otherwise, as the Financial Secretary may determine.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899260_005" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Corporation may borrow or otherwise raise money on such security as may be necessary, and, for that purpose, charge all or any part of the property of the Corporation, but without the prior approval of the Financial Secretary no sum shall be borrowed or otherwise raised under this subsection which itself or together with all other sums previously borrowed or otherwise raised under this subsection and still outstanding exceeds or in the aggregate exceed 5 per cent of the capital and reserves of the Corporation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576773_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Bank account</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899291_019" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation shall open and maintain an account with such bank as the Financial Secretary may approve.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899291_027" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Corporation shall pay all moneys received by it into such an account as is referred to in subsection (1).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576789_002" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Application of moneys</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899307_019" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Save as otherwise provided by this Ordinance, the moneys of the Corporation shall be applied only—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410899307_027" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in payment or discharge of the expenses, charges and liabilities incurred or undertaken by the corporation in the exercise of its powers or the performance of its functions and duties under this Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410899307_035" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in payment of the remuneration and allowances of the Commissioner.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899307_042" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Moneys of the Corporation not immediately required for the purposes of the Corporation may be invested on deposit with any bank or in such other manner as the Financial Secretary may direct.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576804_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-01-19" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Maximum liability</heading><content>The contingent liability of the Corporation under contracts of insurance shall not at any time exceed the sum of three hundred million dollars or such other sum as may be determined by the Legislative Council by resolution*.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1706065606428_001">
                        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
                        
                        
                        <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> See <ref href="/hk/1967/ln135">L.N. 135 of 1967</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1969/ln19">L.N. 19 of 1969</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1971/ln75">L.N. 75 of 1971</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1973/ln209">L.N. 209 of 1973</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1974/ln210">L.N. 210 of 1974</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1977/ln200">L.N. 200 of 1977</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1980/ln109">L.N. 109 of 1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1982/ln172">L.N. 172 of 1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1984/ln108">L.N. 108 of 1984</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/ln79">L.N. 79 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1988/ln34">L.N. 34 of 1988</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln159">L.N. 159 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1991/ln97">L.N. 97 of 1991</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln612">L.N. 612 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln37">L.N. 37 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2006/ln64">L.N. 64 of 2006</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2009/ln25">L.N. 25 of 2009</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2012/ln194">L.N. 194 of 2012</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2017/ln110">L.N. 110 of
                                2017</ref>;
                                        <ref href="/hk/2024/ln6">L.N. 6 of 2024</ref>.
                                Current
                                amount is $80,000 million—see <ref href="/hk/2024/ln6">L.N. 6 of
                                        2024</ref>.</content>
                        
                </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402576820_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Accounts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899369_004" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation shall keep proper accounts of all income and expenditure and shall maintain proper and adequate records thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899369_012" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>As soon as may be convenient after the end of each financial year, the Corporation shall cause to be drawn up, in such form as the Financial Secretary may approve, a statement of its income and expenditure during such financial year and a statement of the assets and liabilities of the Corporation on the last day thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576836_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Auditors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899400_004" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation shall with the approval of the Financial Secretary appoint auditors, who shall be entitled at any time to have access to all accounts, records and documents of the Corporation and to require such information and explanation thereon as they may think fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899400_012" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The auditors shall audit the statements drawn up under <ref>section 24(2)</ref> as soon as possible and shall make a report thereon to the Corporation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576836_003" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Access by the Director of Audit</heading><content>The Director of Audit and any public officer authorized by him shall be entitled at all reasonable times to full and free access to all accounts, records and documents of the Corporation relating directly or indirectly to the receipt or payment of moneys by the Corporation or to the acquisition custody or disposal of assets of the Corporation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402576851_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Exemption from taxation, stamp duties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899431_018" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The profits of the Corporation shall not be subject to taxation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899431_026" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of the Stamp Duty Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap117">Cap. 117</ref>), the Corporation shall not be liable to pay stamp duty in excess of $5 in respect of any instrument or document executed by or on behalf of the Corporation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/31">31 of 1981 s. 65</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402576867_001" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Annual report</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899463_004" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation shall, within a period of 6 months, or within such longer period as the Chief Executive may determine, after the end of each financial year, furnish to the Chief Executive a report of its operations during that financial year, copies of the financial statements in respect of that year drawn up under <ref>section 24(2)</ref> and a copy of the auditors’ report on those statements.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899463_012" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive shall cause to be laid on the table of the Legislative Council the reports and financial statements furnished to him pursuant to subsection (1).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402576882_001" name="P8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part 8</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438402576882_003" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Power of Chief Executive to give directions to the Financial Secretary and the Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899494_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive may give to the Financial Secretary and the Corporation such directions as he thinks fit with respect to the exercise or performance of their respective powers, functions and duties under this Ordinance, either generally or in any particular case.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899494_012" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Financial Secretary and the Corporation shall, in the exercise or performance of their respective powers, functions and duties under this Ordinance, comply with any directions given by the Chief Executive under subsection (1).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/66">66 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402576914_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Validity of insurance contracts and guarantees</heading><content>Without prejudice to the duty of the Corporation to comply with the provisions of this Ordinance, a contract of insurance entered into, or a guarantee given, by the Corporation shall not be invalidated by reason of a contravention by the Corporation of any provision of this Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402576914_003" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Secrecy</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410899525_018" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Commissioner and such other officers of the Corporation as the Corporation may require shall, before entering on the performance of their duties, take an oath before a commissioner for oaths in the form prescribed in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899525_026" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who in the performance of his functions or duty, or in the course of his employment, under or in connection with the provisions of this Ordinance has acquired, or has access to, information relating to the affairs of any person shall not, except in performance of his functions or duty, or in the course of his employment, under or in connection with the provisions of this Ordinance, communicate or make available that information to any other person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410899541_005" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person who contravenes the provisions of subsection (2) shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine at level 3 and to imprisonment for 2 years.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402576929_002" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>False statements</heading><content>Any person who wilfully makes a statement which is false or misleading in a material particular in or in connection with an application or proposal for insurance or a guarantee, or for the purposes of a claim under a contract of insurance or a guarantee, under this Ordinance shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine at level 3 and to imprisonment for 2 years.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/8">8 of 1974 s. 8</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438402576945_001" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule 1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1115/s10">s.
                10</ref>]</note><text class="align_center"><i class="not_bold">Oath or Affirmation of
            Secrecy</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_center"><i>Advisory
            Board</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">I, <fillIn class=" width_304">.</fillIn>do swear by Almighty God (or do
            solemnly and sincerely affirm and declare) that I will not, except in the performance of
            my functions as a member of the Advisory Board established by the Hong Kong Export
            Credit Insurance Corporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1115">Cap. 1115</ref>),
            communicate or make available to another person any information relating to the affairs
            of a person coming to my knowledge, or to which I have access, as a member of the
            Advisory
            Board.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_right">(Signed) <fillIn class=" width_125">.</fillIn><fillIn class="width_66"> </fillIn><br></br>In Hong Kong this <fillIn class=" width_80">.</fillIn> day of <fillIn class=" width_104">.</fillIn><br role="blank-line"></br>Before me, <fillIn class=" width_141">.</fillIn><fillIn class="width_37"> </fillIn> <br></br><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_right"><i>Commissioner for Oaths.</i><fillIn class="width_32"> </fillIn> <br></br></text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402576960_001" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule 2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1115/s31">s.
                31</ref>]</note><text class="align_center"><i class="not_bold">Oath or Affirmation of
            Secrecy</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">I,
                <fillIn class=" width_304">.</fillIn> do swear by Almighty God (or do solemnly and sincerely
            affirm and declare) that I will not, except in the performance of my functions or duty
            or in the course of my employment under or in connection with the Hong Kong Export
            Credit Insurance Corporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1115">Cap. 1115</ref>),
            communicate or make available to another person any information relating to the affairs
            of a person coming to my knowledge, or to which I have access, in the performance of my
            functions or duty or in the course of my employment under or in connection with the said
            Ordinance.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_right">(Signed) <fillIn class=" width_125">.</fillIn><fillIn class="width_66"> </fillIn><br></br>In Hong Kong this <fillIn class=" width_80">.</fillIn> day of <fillIn class=" width_104">.</fillIn><br role="blank-line"></br>Before me, <fillIn class=" width_141">.</fillIn><fillIn class="width_37"> </fillIn> <br></br><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_right"><i>Commissioner for Oaths.</i><fillIn class="width_32"> </fillIn> <br></br></text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>