<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1009</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1009</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1009!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402527025_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-04-28">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Church Body of the China Congregational
                Church in Hong Kong.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 November 1912]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402527040_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>China Congregational Church Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402527056_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793991_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The members of the church body of the China Congregational Church in Hong Kong
                shall be a body corporate under the name of “The Church Body of the China
                Congregational Church in Hong Kong”, hereinafter called
                        <b><i>the
                        corporation</i></b>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1912/43">43 of 1912</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1913/gn246">G.N.
                        246 of 1913</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793991_011" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The
                corporation by the name aforesaid shall have perpetual succession, and shall and may
                sue and be sued in all courts, and shall and may have and use a common seal, and
                may from time to time break, change, alter and make anew the said
                seal as to the corporation may seem fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1912/43">43 of 1912</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1913/gn246">G.N. 246 of 1913</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793991_025" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take,
                hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind
                soever and wheresoever situate and also to invest moneys upon mortgage of any lands,
                buildings, messuages or tenements, or upon the mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds,
                shares or securities of any corporation or company, and also to purchase, acquire
                and possess goods and chattels of what nature and kind
                soever.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410794006_004" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The corporation shall further have power by deed under its seal to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities, or goods and chattels, which are for the time being vested in or belonging to the corporation, upon such terms as to the corporation may seem fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402527071_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Register of members</heading><content>The corporation shall keep at its principal church or meeting place a register of the
            members of the China Congregational Church in Hong Kong, and shall enter in such
            register the names of all such persons as are in the opinion of the corporation proper
            persons to be admitted as members of the said church. Such book is hereinafter referred
            to as
                    <b><i>the
                    register of members</i></b>, and the persons whose names appear therein as
            members of the church.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402527087_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Filling vacancies in church body</heading><content>Upon the death or resignation or removal from office of any member of the church body aforesaid, a successor to the person so dying, retiring or being removed shall be appointed by a majority of the members of the church present at a meeting to be convened for the purpose by the corporation. The names of every person so elected shall be entered in the register of members with the date of election and particulars of the office to which such person is elected, and every such entry shall be signed by at least four members of the church body.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1912/43">43 of 1912</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1913/gn246">G.N. 246 of 1913</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402527103_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Conduct of services, etc.</heading><content>The services of the church shall be regulated and conducted by the pastor of the church for the time being in accordance with the principles of the Christian religion based upon the Old and New Testaments, and in accordance as far as possible with the practice of the Congregational Churches now in existence in Europe and America.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402527103_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Power to make regulations</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 5</ref>, the corporation may make regulations for the services of the church and the management of its property and affairs generally. All such regulations shall be laid before a meeting of the members convened for the purpose and if approved by a majority of the members present at such meeting shall be binding on the corporation and upon all members of the church. A copy of any such regulations sealed with the common seal of the corporation and countersigned by any four members of the church body shall be accepted as evidence of such regulations having been regularly made and confirmed.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1912/43">43 of 1912</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1913/gn246">G.N. 246 of 1913</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402527134_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Removal of members</heading><content>The regulations may provide for the removal from office or from membership of the church of any member of the church body or the church by the vote of at least two-thirds of the members of the church.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402527149_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Convening meetings</heading><content>Every meeting held under this Ordinance may be convened by posting a notice of the time and place for holding such meeting, and the nature of the business to be discussed, upon the door of the principal church or other meeting place of the corporation in Hong Kong on the two Sundays next preceding the date of the meeting.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402527165_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Use of seal</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be sealed with the common seal of the corporation and signed by at least four of the members of the church body for the time being.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402527181_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1950/37">37 of 1950 </ref>Schedule. Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>