<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1117 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1117A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1117A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-02-16</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402577974_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2023-02-16">The
                                    English
                                    Schools
                                    Foundation
                                    (General)
                                    Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap1117/s24">Cap.
                                                1117, section
                                    24</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted— <ref href="/hk/2023/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                                2023</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[9
                                    May 2008]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes— <ref href="/hk/2023/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402578006_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AuditCommittee"><term>Audit
                Committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">審計委員會</term>) means the committee established by the
            Board of Governors under <ref>section 9(a)</ref> of the Ordinance;</def><def name="FinanceCommittee"><term>Finance
                Committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">財務委員會</term>) means the committee established by the
            Board of Governors under <ref>section 9(b)</ref> of the Ordinance;</def><def name="RemunerationCommittee"><term>Remuneration
                Committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">薪酬委員會</term>) means the committee established by the
            Board of Governors under <ref>section 9(c)</ref> of the Ordinance.</def></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Board of
        Governors</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402578006_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Membership of Board of Governors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902193_039" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a member of the Board of Governors is absent from 3 meetings of the Board in
                succession or from half the meetings of the Board in any calendar year, and the
                Chairman of the Board receives no satisfactory explanation for the absence, the
                Chairman may declare the member’s position to be vacant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902208_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a vacancy occurs in the membership of the Board, the Board may co-opt a
                person to fill the vacancy pending the holding of an election under the Ordinance
                for membership of the Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902208_013" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If a member of the Board has given notice of his intended absence from Hong
                Kong for 3 months or more, the Board may appoint another person to act as member in
                his place during that absence; but an acting appointment so made shall cease to have
                effect on the return of the absent member to Hong Kong.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902208_021" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If a member of the Board ceases to be eligible for nomination or election as a
                member for the purposes of the provision of the Ordinance under which his nomination
                or election was made, the Chairman of the Board shall, upon the matter coming to his
                knowledge, declare the member’s position to be vacant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902224_005" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The person who is the Chairman, Vice-chairman or Treasurer of the Board may be
                removed from office by resolution of the Board approved at a meeting of the Board by
                two-thirds of the members of the Board who are eligible to vote on the
                resolution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902224_013" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The person who is the Chairman, Vice-chairman or Treasurer of the Board may
                resign his office by giving notice in writing to the Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902224_021" name="7" temporalId="s2_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Any member of the Board may resign his membership by giving notice in writing
                to the Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902224_029" name="8" temporalId="s2_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Board may invite other persons to attend meetings of the Board, in order to
                broaden the range of experience and expertise available to it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902224_037" name="9" temporalId="s2_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>In this section, a reference to a member of the Board is a reference to a
                member other than an ex officio member.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578021_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Arrangements for meetings of Board of Governors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902255_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Board of Governors shall meet at least 6 times in each academic year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902255_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Not less than 1 month before the end of each academic year, the Chairman of the Board shall publish the dates for meetings of the Board to be held in accordance with subsection (1) for the next academic year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902255_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If any 5 members of the Board request the Chairman of the Board in writing to convene a meeting of the Board, the Chairman shall call a meeting of the Board to be held on a date within 14 days of his receipt of the request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902271_005" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Chairman of the Board may at any time call a meeting of the Board by giving to the members, not less than 14 days before the meeting, notice in writing of the meeting and of the nature of the business to be transacted at the meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902271_013" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Any urgent business of the Board arising may be dealt with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902271_021" name="a" temporalId="s3_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by the Chairman of the Board in consultation with either the Vice-chairman or the Treasurer of the Board, after taking the advice of the Chief Executive Officer; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902271_029" name="b" temporalId="s3_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at a meeting of the Board convened for the purpose, to be held not less than 3 days after receipt by the members of the Board of notice in writing of the meeting and of the business in question,</content></paragraph><continued>but any decision taken by the Chairman under paragraph (a) shall be reported to the Board by the Chairman at the next meeting of the Board.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902271_042" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where for any reason a date fixed for a meeting of the Board under subsection (2) is vacated the Chairman of the Board shall fix an alternative date and shall give members notice in writing of the alternative date.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578037_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Formalities of meetings of Board of Governors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902302_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chairman of the Board shall preside at any meeting of the Board at which he is present.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902302_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In the absence of the Chairman of the Board—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902302_020" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Vice-chairman shall preside; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902302_028" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the Vice-chairman also is absent, a person elected by the members present from among their own number, in an election to be arranged by the Chief Executive Officer or his representative, shall preside,</content></paragraph><continued>and a person so presiding shall have all the powers and duties of the Chairman as regards the conduct of business at the meeting.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902302_041" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Except for matters of a minor and routine nature, which may be dealt with by circulation of information among members, all business of the Board shall be decided by a majority of votes at a meeting of the Board.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578037_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Procedure at meetings of Board of Governors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902349_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Board of Governors shall determine its own procedure, and shall make its determinations available in writing for the information of members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902349_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A formal record shall be kept of the proceedings of meetings of the Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902349_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In the case of an equality of votes the Chairman of the meeting shall have a second or casting vote.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902349_028" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In the case of an issue of confidence, the relevant officer or the Chief Executive Officer or his representative present at the meeting may be asked by a majority of the members present to leave the meeting, but an absence from a meeting under this subsection shall not affect the question of a quorum for the meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902349_036" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer may require any employee of the Foundation to be present at a meeting of the Board.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578052_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Nominating Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902380_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The term of office of a member of the Nominating Committee shall be 3 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902380_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A member of the Nominating Committee is eligible for renomination or reappointment, but no person shall serve as a member consecutively for more than 2 terms.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902380_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The members of the Nominating Committee shall elect a chairman from among their own number.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902380_028" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer shall act as secretary to the Nominating Committee.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Standing Committees of
        Board of
        Governors</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402578068_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Audit Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902395_027" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Audit Committee shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902395_035" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>up to 3 persons appointed by the Board of Governors from among the
                    independent members of the Board; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902395_043" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>up to 2 persons appointed by the members of the Committee appointed under
                    paragraph (a).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902395_050" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer and the senior finance executive of the Foundation
                may attend any meeting of the Audit Committee other than a meeting held in private
                with the external auditors of the Foundation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902395_058" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Audit Committee shall meet in private with the external auditors of the
                Foundation on at least one occasion in each year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902411_005" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In advising the Board, the Audit Committee shall, with the assistance of the
                Chief Executive Officer and the senior finance executive of the Foundation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902411_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>review the Foundation’s financial reporting processes and internal
                    controls;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902411_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>recommend persons for appointment as external auditors;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902411_029" name="c" temporalId="s7_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>advise on the scope of the audit to be carried out by the external auditors
                    and monitor the implementation of any recommendation they may make in that
                    regard;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902411_037" name="d" temporalId="s7_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>monitor and review the work of the internal audit service;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902411_045" name="e" temporalId="s7_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>review the annual financial statements of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902411_053" name="f" temporalId="s7_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>consider any audit-related matters arising from the reports of external
                    bodies;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902411_061" name="g" temporalId="s7_4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>make such recommendations to the Board as it thinks necessary to secure the
                    good corporate governance of the Foundation,</content></paragraph><continued>and for these purposes the Committee may as it thinks fit investigate any
                activity, require information from any employee of the Foundation and obtain outside
                professional advice in carrying out its activities.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902411_074" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Audit Committee shall meet at least 3 times in each academic
                year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902427_005" name="6" temporalId="s7_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If any 3 members of the Audit Committee request the chairman of the Committee
                in writing to convene a meeting of the Committee, the chairman shall call a meeting
                of the Committee to be held on a date within 14 days of his receipt of the
                request.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578099_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Finance Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902458_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Finance Committee shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902458_012" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at least one and not more than 2 persons appointed by the Board of Governors from among the independent members of the Board;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902458_020" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Treasurer of the Foundation, ex officio;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902458_028" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a School Council Chairman, who is not a member of the Board of Governors, appointed by the Board; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902458_036" name="d" temporalId="s8_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>2 persons appointed by the members of the Committee appointed under, or who are members by virtue of, paragraphs (a), (b) and (c).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902458_043" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer and the senior finance executive of the Foundation may attend meetings of the Finance Committee to assist the Committee in its work.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902458_051" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In advising the Board, the Finance Committee shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902458_059" name="a" temporalId="s8_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>prepare recommendations on long and medium term financial strategy including investments;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902473_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>recommend annually a budget;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902473_014" name="c" temporalId="s8_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>recommend annually a set of accounts;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902473_022" name="d" temporalId="s8_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>recommend and keep under review a programme of capital expenditure;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902473_030" name="e" temporalId="s8_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>receive regular monitoring reports on income and expenditure;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902473_038" name="f" temporalId="s8_3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>review and recommend annually fee levels.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578115_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Remuneration Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902489_067" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Remuneration Committee shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902489_075" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at least one and not more than 2 persons appointed by the Board of Governors from among the independent members of the Board;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902505_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a School Council Chairman, who is not a member of the Board of Governors, appointed by the Board; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902505_014" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>at least one and not more than 2 persons appointed by the members of the Committee appointed under paragraphs (a) and (b).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902505_021" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer and the senior human resources executive of the Foundation may attend meetings of the Remuneration Committee to assist the Committee in its work.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902505_029" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In advising the Board, the Remuneration Committee shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902505_037" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>keep under review the remuneration, terms and conditions of service and benefits of the employees of the Foundation, having regard to market conditions and good employment practice;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902505_045" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>appraise the financial implications of any proposed revisions to the salaries, terms and conditions of service and benefits of employees of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902505_053" name="c" temporalId="s9_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>advise the Board on revisions to its policy on remuneration, terms and conditions of service and benefits of employees of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902505_061" name="d" temporalId="s9_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>ensure that appropriate arrangements are made for consulting and communicating with employees of the Foundation in relation to matters concerning salaries, terms and conditions of service and benefits.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578115_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Membership of standing committees of Board of Governors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902536_020" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Board shall appoint one of the members of each standing committee of the Board of Governors to be the chairman of the committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902536_028" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who is an employee of the Foundation is not eligible for appointment as a member of a standing committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902536_036" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If a member of a standing committee is absent from 3 meetings of the committee in succession or from half the meetings of the committee in any calendar year, and the chairman of the committee receives no satisfactory explanation for the absence, the chairman may declare the member’s position to be vacant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902551_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a vacancy occurs in the membership of a standing committee, the committee may co-opt a person to fill the vacancy pending the appointment of a member to the committee under <ref>section 7(1)</ref>, <ref>8(1)</ref> or <ref>9(1)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902551_013" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If a member of a standing committee has given notice of his intended absence from Hong Kong for 3 months or more, the committee may appoint another person to act as member in his place during that absence; but an acting appointment so made shall cease to have effect on the return of the absent member to Hong Kong.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902551_021" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If a member of a standing committee ceases to be eligible for appointment as a member for the purposes of the provision under which he was appointed as a member, the chairman of the committee shall, upon the matter coming to his knowledge, declare the member’s position to be vacant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902567_005" name="7" temporalId="s10_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The person who is the chairman of a standing committee may resign his office by giving notice in writing to the Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902567_013" name="8" temporalId="s10_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Any member of a standing committee may resign his membership by giving notice in writing to the Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902567_021" name="9" temporalId="s10_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>A standing committee may invite other persons to attend meetings of the committee, in order to broaden the range of experience and expertise available to it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902567_029" name="10" temporalId="s10_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>The term of office of a member of a standing committee appointed under <ref>section 7(1)(b)</ref>, <ref>8(1)(d)</ref> or <ref>9(1)(c)</ref> shall be 3 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902567_037" name="11" temporalId="s10_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>An appointed member of a standing committee is eligible for reappointment as a member at the end of his first term of office, but no person shall serve as an appointed member of the same committee consecutively for more than 2 terms or 6 years, whichever is the shorter.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578130_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Proceedings of standing committees of Board of Governors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902614_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A formal record shall be kept of the proceedings of every meeting of a standing committee of the Board of Governors, and a copy of that record shall be provided to the Board as soon after the meeting as is reasonably practicable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902614_012" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Except for matters of a minor and routine nature, which may be dealt with by circulation of information among members, all business of a standing committee shall be decided by a majority of votes at a meeting of the committee; in the case of an equality of votes the chairman of the meeting shall have a second or casting vote.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902614_020" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Not less than 1 month before the end of each academic year, the chairman of each standing committee shall publish the dates for meetings of the committee for the next academic year (but nothing in this section shall preclude the calling or holding of a meeting under any other provision of this Regulation).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902629_005" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The chairman of a standing committee may at any time call a meeting of the committee by giving to the members, not less than 14 days before the meeting, notice in writing of the meeting and of the nature of the business to be transacted at the meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902629_013" name="5" temporalId="s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Each standing committee shall report to the Board of Governors at least once in each year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902629_021" name="6" temporalId="s11_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where for any reason a date fixed for a meeting of a standing committee under subsection (3) is vacated the chairman of the committee shall fix an alternative date and shall give members notice in writing of the alternative date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902629_029" name="7" temporalId="s11_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>In relation to matters not otherwise provided for in this Regulation, the Board of Governors shall determine the procedure of the standing committees and shall make its determinations available in written form for the information of the members of the committees.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Chief Executive
        Officer’s Advisory
        Committees</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402578146_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Committee of Principals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902661_042" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Committee of Principals shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902661_050" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Principal of each school of the Foundation that provides primary or
                    secondary education; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902661_058" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not more than 3 persons elected by the Principals of schools of the
                    Foundation that provide nursery or kindergarten education only from among their
                    own number.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902676_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 12(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, matters that
                affect the interests of Principals of schools of the Foundation include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902676_013" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the development of an educational vision and strategy for the Foundation
                    and the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902676_021" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the execution of the Foundation’s education strategy within the schools of
                    the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902676_029" name="c" temporalId="s12_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the curriculum, teaching and learning strategies and assessment and
                    reporting procedures of schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902676_037" name="d" temporalId="s12_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the performance management and professional development of all staff within
                    the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902676_045" name="e" temporalId="s12_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the promotion of the welfare, standards of behaviour and quality of
                    education of students of schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902676_053" name="f" temporalId="s12_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the maintenance and development of effective communication with parents of
                    students of schools of the Foundation, alumni of those schools and the wider
                    community;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902676_061" name="g" temporalId="s12_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the securing of a clear and coherent identity and collaborative culture
                    across the schools of the Foundation.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578146_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Committee of School Council Chairmen</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902739_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Committee of School Council Chairmen shall comprise the Chairman of each of the School Councils.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902739_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 12(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, matters that affect the interests of Chairmen of School Councils of schools of the Foundation include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902739_020" name="a" temporalId="s13_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the governance and strategic development of the Foundation and schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902739_028" name="b" temporalId="s13_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the distribution and management of funding and the capital programme;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902739_036" name="c" temporalId="s13_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the development and management of the staff of schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902739_044" name="d" temporalId="s13_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the development of effective communications with parents and the wider community.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578162_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Committee of Parents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902770_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Committee of Parents shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902770_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Chairmen of the Parent Teacher Associations;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902770_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>one parent member of each of the School Councils, elected by the parent members of the School Council from among their own number; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902770_028" name="c" temporalId="s14_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the parent members of the Board of Governors.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902770_035" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 12(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, matters that affect the interests of parents of students of schools of the Foundation include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902770_043" name="a" temporalId="s14_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the welfare, conduct and quality of education of students at schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902770_051" name="b" temporalId="s14_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the admission of students to schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902770_059" name="c" temporalId="s14_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the effectiveness of communication between the Foundation, the Principals and staff of schools of the Foundation and the parents of students of those schools;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902770_067" name="d" temporalId="s14_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>financial matters affecting the parents of students at schools of the Foundation, including fee levels and the value for money offered by those schools.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902770_074" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="ParentMember">In this section,
                    <term>parent
                    member</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">家長成員</term>), in relation to a School Council,
                means a member of the School Council elected pursuant to <ref>section
                    14(1)(b)(iii)</ref> of the Ordinance.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578177_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Committee of Teaching Staff</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902832_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Committee of Teaching Staff shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902832_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>2 members of the staff of each school of the Foundation, other than a special school, that provides secondary education, elected by the members of the teaching staff of the school; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902832_020" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>one member of the staff of each school of the Foundation that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410902832_028" name="i" temporalId="s15_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>provides primary education only; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410902832_036" name="ii" temporalId="s15_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>is a special school that provides primary or secondary education,</content></subparagraph><continued>elected by the members of the teaching staff of the school.</continued></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902832_048" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 12(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, matters that affect the interests of members of the teaching staff of schools of the Foundation include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902848_005" name="a" temporalId="s15_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the development of an educational vision and strategy for the Foundation and the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902848_013" name="b" temporalId="s15_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the curriculum, teaching and learning strategies and assessment and reporting procedures of schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902848_021" name="c" temporalId="s15_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the promotion of the welfare, standards of behaviour and quality of education of students of schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902848_029" name="d" temporalId="s15_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the professional development and performance management of the teaching staff of schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902848_037" name="e" temporalId="s15_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the securing of a clear and coherent identity and collaborative culture across the schools of the Foundation.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578193_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Committee of Support Staff</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902879_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Committee of Support Staff shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902879_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>2 members of the staff of each school of the Foundation, other than a
                    special school, that provides secondary education, elected by the members of the
                    support staff of the school; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902879_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>one member of the staff of each school of the Foundation that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1674807781964_001" name="i" temporalId="s16_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>provides primary education only; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1674807781965_002" name="ii" temporalId="s16_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>is a special school that provides primary or secondary
                        education,</content></subparagraph><continued>elected by the members of the support staff of the school.</continued></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902879_047" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 12(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, matters that affect the interests of members of the support staff of schools of the Foundation include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410902879_055" name="a" temporalId="s16_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the day-to-day administrative processes within the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902879_063" name="b" temporalId="s16_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the operation of school libraries within the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902879_071" name="c" temporalId="s16_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the work of school nurses within the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902879_079" name="d" temporalId="s16_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the educational role of Educational Assistants within the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902879_087" name="e" temporalId="s16_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the care and security of school buildings within the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902895_006" name="f" temporalId="s16_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the professional development and performance management of support staff of the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410902895_014" name="g" temporalId="s16_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the securing of a clear and coherent identity and collaborative culture across the schools of the Foundation.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578193_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Meetings of advisory committees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902910_067" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Each advisory committee of the Chief Executive Officer shall elect a chairman from among the members of the committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902910_075" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A formal record shall be kept of the proceedings of every meeting of an advisory committee, and a copy of that record shall be provided to the Board of Governors as soon after the meeting as is reasonably practicable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902926_005" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>All business of an advisory committee shall be decided by a majority of votes at a meeting of the committee; in the case of an equality of votes the chairman of the meeting shall have a second or casting vote.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902926_013" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In circumstances of the unavoidable absence of a member of an advisory committee from a meeting of the committee, an alternate may attend the meeting with the agreement of the chairman of the committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902926_021" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The agenda for each meeting of an advisory committee shall be as agreed between the chairman of the committee and the Chief Executive Officer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902926_029" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The term of office of an elected member of an advisory committee shall be 2 years; an elected member is eligible for re-election at the expiry of his term of office, but no person shall serve as an elected member of the same committee consecutively for more than 3 terms.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">School
        Councils</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402578208_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Membership of School Councils</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410902957_011" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a member of a School Council is absent from 3 meetings of the Council in
                succession or from half the meetings of the Council in any calendar year, and the
                chairman of the Council receives no satisfactory explanation for the absence, the
                chairman may declare the member’s position to be vacant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902957_019" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a vacancy occurs in the membership of a School Council, the Council may
                co-opt a person to fill the vacancy pending the holding of an election under the
                Ordinance for membership of the Council.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902957_027" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If a member of a School Council has given notice of his intended absence from
                Hong Kong for 3 months or more, the Council may appoint another person to act as
                member in his place during that absence; but an acting appointment so made shall
                cease to have effect on the return of the absent member to Hong Kong.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902973_005" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If a member of a School Council ceases to be eligible for election or
                appointment as a member for the purposes of the provision of the Ordinance under
                which he was elected or appointed as a member, the chairman of the Council shall,
                upon the matter coming to his knowledge, declare the member’s position to be
                vacant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902973_013" name="5" temporalId="s18_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The members of a School Council may elect a vice-chairman from among their own
                number.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902973_021" name="6" temporalId="s18_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The person who is the chairman or vice-chairman of a School Council may resign
                his office by giving notice in writing to the Council.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902973_029" name="7" temporalId="s18_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The person who is the chairman of a School Council may be removed from office
                by resolution of the Board of Governors approved at a meeting of the Board by
                two-thirds of the members of the Board who are eligible to vote on the
                resolution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410902988_005" name="8" temporalId="s18_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Any member of a School Council may resign his membership by giving notice in
                writing to the Council.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578224_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Meetings of School Councils</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410903004_052" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Each School Council shall meet at least 3 times in each academic year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903019_005" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any 3 members of a School Council request the chairman of the Council in writing to convene a meeting of the Council, the chairman shall call a meeting of the Council to be held on a date within 14 days of his receipt of the request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903019_013" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A formal record shall be kept of the proceedings of every meeting of a School Council, and a copy of that record shall be provided to the Board of Governors as soon after the meeting as is reasonably practicable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903019_021" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Except for matters of a minor and routine nature, which may be dealt with by circulation of information among members, all business of a School Council shall be decided by a majority of votes at a meeting of the Council; in the case of an equality of votes the chairman of the meeting shall have a second or casting vote.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903019_029" name="5" temporalId="s19_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Not less than 1 month before the end of each academic year, the chairman of each School Council shall publish the dates for meetings of the Council for the next academic year (but nothing in this section shall preclude the calling or holding of a meeting under any other provision of this Regulation).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903035_005" name="6" temporalId="s19_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The chairman of a School Council may at any time call a meeting of the Council by giving to the members, not less than 14 days before the meeting, notice in writing of the meeting and of the nature of the business to be transacted at the meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903035_013" name="7" temporalId="s19_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Each School Council shall report regularly to the Chief Executive Officer and the Board of Governors.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903035_021" name="8" temporalId="s19_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer may nominate a representative to attend a meeting of a School Council on his behalf.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903035_029" name="9" temporalId="s19_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>A School Council may invite other persons to attend meetings of the Council, in order to broaden the range of experience and expertise available to it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903035_037" name="10" temporalId="s19_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>A School Council may invite students of the school to attend its meetings as observers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903051_005" name="11" temporalId="s19_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>Where for any reason a date fixed for a meeting of a School Council under subsection (5) is vacated the chairman of the Council shall fix an alternative date and shall give members notice in writing of the alternative date.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Parent Teacher
        Associations</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402578224_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Functions of Parent Teacher Associations</heading><leadIn>In the performance of its functions under the Ordinance, a Parent Teacher
            Association of a school of the Foundation may in particular—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903082_019" name="a" temporalId="s20_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>seek to facilitate the discussion between the parent members and teacher members
                of the Association of matters relating to the education offered by the school
                including but not limited to—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410903082_027" name="i" temporalId="s20_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the school’s curriculum;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410903082_035" name="ii" temporalId="s20_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the quality of education provided at the school;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410903082_043" name="iii" temporalId="s20_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the assessment of, and school reports on, students of the school;
                    and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410903082_051" name="iv" temporalId="s20_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>the behaviour of students of the school;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903082_058" name="b" temporalId="s20_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by agreement with the Principal of the school, organize extra-curricular and
                other supporting activities for students of the school;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903082_066" name="c" temporalId="s20_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>raise funds to support the Association and the school and, in consultation with
                the Principal, decide how to use the money raised;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903082_074" name="d" temporalId="s20_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>engage in such other activities related to that function as the members of the
                Association and the Principal may decide.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402578271_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Membership fees of Parent Teacher Associations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410903113_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A fee
                        (<b><i>membership
                        fee</i></b>)
                for membership as a parent member of the Parent Teacher Association of a school of
                the Foundation shall be payable in respect of each academic year by the parent, or
                by both parents jointly, of a student of a school of the Foundation and, except as
                provided in subsection (2), a separate membership fee shall be payable by such
                parent or parents in respect of each child who is a student of a school of the
                Foundation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903113_012" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In the case of a parent or parents having more than one child as a student at the same school of the Foundation, only a single membership fee is payable in respect of those students.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903129_005" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Board of Governors may determine a maximum amount that may be fixed by a Parent Teacher Association as the membership fee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903129_013" name="4" temporalId="s21_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The membership fee for an academic year payable in respect of a student becomes payable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903129_021" name="a" temporalId="s21_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the time at which the school fee for the first month of the academic year becomes payable in respect of that student; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903129_029" name="b" temporalId="s21_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the student is admitted to a school during the course of the academic year, at the time at which the school fee for the first month following the student’s admission to the school becomes payable.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903129_036" name="5" temporalId="s21_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Membership fees paid are non-returnable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903129_044" name="6" temporalId="s21_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The parent or parents of any child applying for a place at a school of the Foundation shall be informed in writing of the requirements of the foregoing provisions of this section.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578286_002" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Committees of Parent Teacher Associations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410903160_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>There shall be for the Parent Teacher Association of each school of the Foundation a committee comprising the following members—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903160_012" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>one of the parent members of the Association, other than a parent who is also an employee of the Foundation, elected by the Association to be its chairman;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903160_020" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not less than 2 other members, at least one of whom shall be a parent member of the Association, elected by the Association; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903160_028" name="c" temporalId="s22_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Principal of the school, ex officio.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903160_035" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The term of office of the elected members of a committee of a Parent Teacher Association shall be 1 year; no person shall serve as an elected member consecutively for more than 6 terms.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903160_043" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If an elected member of the Parent Teacher Association of a school of the Foundation ceases to have a child at the school, the committee of the Association shall, upon the matter coming to its knowledge, declare a vacancy in its membership.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903175_005" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a vacancy occurs in the membership of a committee of a Parent Teacher Association, the committee may co-opt a member of the Association to fill the vacancy pending the holding of an election for membership of the committee.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578302_001" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Meetings of Parent Teacher Associations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410903191_012" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any Parent Teacher Association may invite members of the community to join the Association as honorary members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903191_020" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Parent Teacher Association of a school of the Foundation may invite students of the school to join the Association as student members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903191_028" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An honorary member or a student member of a Parent Teacher Association shall not be entitled to vote at meetings of the Association; no membership fee shall be payable by an honorary member or a student member.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903207_005" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>At any meeting of the Parent Teacher Association of a school of the Foundation, each family shall have one vote irrespective of the number of children they have in the school.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Miscellaneous</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402578302_003" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Vice-chairman of Foundation may act as Chairman</heading><content>If for any reason the person who is the Chairman of the Foundation is unable to
            perform the duties of the Chairman, the person who is the Vice-chairman of the
            Foundation may act as the Chairman in his place and shall, while acting, have all the
            powers and duties of the Chairman.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402578318_002" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Consultation and communication between Chief Executive Officer and staff on employment issues</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410903238_004" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer shall establish procedures to consult and communicate with the employees of the Foundation on matters of remuneration, terms and conditions of service and benefits.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903238_012" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Association of Professional Teachers in English Schools Foundation Schools or the Support Staff Association of the English Schools Foundation has nominated representatives from among its members to communicate with the Chief Executive Officer on behalf of the Association, then, for the purposes of subsection (1), any consultation or communication by the Chief Executive Officer with those representatives shall be regarded as consultation or communication with every member of the Association.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903253_005" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The agenda for any meeting between the Chief Executive Officer and any representative of either of the Associations mentioned in subsection (2) shall be as agreed by the Chief Executive Officer and the Chairman of the Association.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578318_004" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Appeals Panel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410903269_004" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chairman of the Appeals Panel shall convene the Panel as and when an issue of appeal arises.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903269_012" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Appeals Panel may take advice from a member of the legal profession who is independent of the Foundation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578333_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Code of conduct</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410903285_012" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Board of Governors shall issue a code
                        (<b><i>code
                        of
                conduct</i></b>)
                setting out standards of conduct to be observed by the members of the Board, the
                School Councils and any committee provided for under the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903285_020" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every person who becomes a member of the Board, a School Council or a committee provided for under the Ordinance shall be provided with a copy of the code of conduct and shall be asked to affirm in writing that he agrees to abide by it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903285_028" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The code of conduct shall require the members of the Board, a School Council and any committee provided for under the Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903285_036" name="a" temporalId="s27_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>annually and in writing, to declare to the Board, School Council or committee (as the case may be) of which they are a member any pecuniary or personal interest, direct or indirect, that may have a bearing on their role as such member, or to state that they have no such interest; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903300_006" name="b" temporalId="s27_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>at any meeting of the Board, School Council or committee (as the case may be)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410903300_014" name="i" temporalId="s27_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to declare any pecuniary or personal interest relating to an item on the agenda for the meeting; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410903300_022" name="ii" temporalId="s27_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to abstain from voting on any matter in which they have a pecuniary interest and to speak on such matter only at the specific invitation of the chairman of the meeting.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903300_028" name="4" temporalId="s27_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Board of Governors shall keep a record of all declarations of interest made under subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref> by its members and shall permit the record to be inspected by the public at any reasonable time.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402578349_001" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Election of parent members to the Board of Governors under <ref>section 6(1)(b)</ref> or (c) of the Ordinance</heading><content><ref>Schedule 1</ref> has effect as regards the election of parents of students of schools of the Foundation as members of the Board of Governors under <ref>section 6(1)(b)</ref> or (c) of the Ordinance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402578364_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Transitional arrangements</heading><content>The arrangements set out in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> shall have effect.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402578364_003" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1117A/s28">s. 28</ref>]</note><heading>Election
            of
            Parent Members
            to
            the Board
            of Governors
            under
            <ref>Section
                6(1)(b)</ref>
            or
            (c) of
            the
            Ordinance</heading><crossHeading class="align_center ">Secret
            ballot</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903378_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_s1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Elections shall be conducted by way of a secret postal
                ballot.</content></section><crossHeading>Elections
            to be managed by Chief Executive
            Officer</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903378_028" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_s2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The election process shall be managed by the Chief Executive
                Officer.</content></section><crossHeading>Notice
            of
            election</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903378_044" name="s3" temporalId="sch1_s3"><num value="3">3.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410903378_049" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer shall give notice of an election
                            (<b><i>Election
                            Notice</i></b>)
                    specifying a date not less than 1 month from the giving of the notice as the
                    date for the return of ballot papers to the
                    Foundation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903378_055" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Election Notice shall be given in such manner as the Chief Executive
                    Officer may decide and, without limiting the discretion of the Chief Executive
                    Officer in that regard, may be given—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903378_064" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by notices placed in the schools of the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903378_073" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by notice in writing sent to each parent; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903378_082" name="c" temporalId="sch1_s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by notification published on the website of the Foundation or the
                        websites of schools of the
                        Foundation.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading>Nomination
            of
            candidates</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903378_096" name="s4" temporalId="sch1_s4"><num value="4">4.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410903378_101" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive Officer shall send to each parent in writing a notice
                    inviting the nomination of candidates, together with a copy of the form for
                    nomination of candidates
                            (<b><i>Nomination
                            Form</i></b>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903394_006" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A person who is eligible for election as a member shall be regarded as
                    validly nominated as a candidate for an election if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903394_015" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the nomination has been proposed by a parent and seconded by a parent,
                        both of whom have signed the Nomination Form;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903394_024" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Nomination Form has been signed by the nominated person confirming
                        his or her willingness to stand as a candidate; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903394_033" name="c" temporalId="sch1_s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Nomination Form has been returned to the Chief Executive Officer by
                        5 p.m. on the date specified in the notice sent under subsection (1) as the
                        closing date for nomination of candidates.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903394_041" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of <ref>section 6(1)(c)</ref> of the Ordinance (which
                    provides for the election of a person from among the parents of students with
                    special educational needs of schools of the Foundation), a parent shall be
                    regarded as eligible to stand for election if the parent’s child has been
                    assessed by the child’s school as being a student with special educational
                    needs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903409_006" name="4" temporalId="sch1_s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A candidate for nomination may submit to the Chief Executive Officer,
                    together with the completed Nomination Form, a personal statement comprising
                    details of the candidate’s relevant experience and a statement of what the
                    candidate believes he or she could contribute to the Foundation as a member of
                    the Board of Governors, for use for the purposes of <ref>section
                    5(2)(c)</ref>.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading>Ballot</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903409_021" name="s5" temporalId="sch1_s5"><num value="5">5.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410903409_026" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Ballot papers shall be sent to parents by post.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903409_032" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Included with the ballot papers shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903409_041" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>instructions for the completion of the ballot paper and its return to
                        the Foundation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903409_050" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>envelopes addressed to the Foundation and marked “Parent Ballot” for
                        enclosing returned ballot papers; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903425_007" name="c" temporalId="sch1_s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of any candidate who has submitted a personal statement
                        under <ref>section 4(4)</ref>, a copy of the personal statement or
                        information extracted from it.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903425_015" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Each of the parents of a child, to a maximum of two, shall be entitled to
                    vote.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903425_024" name="4" temporalId="sch1_s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Parents having children at more than one school shall be entitled to vote
                    once for each school attended by their children.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903425_033" name="5" temporalId="sch1_s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Each set of parents shall have only one set of votes per school
                    irrespective of the number of children they have in the school.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903425_042" name="6" temporalId="sch1_s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Each ballot paper shall have provision for a parent to vote for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903425_051" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s5_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>6 candidates standing for election under <ref>section 6(1)(b)</ref> of
                        the Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903425_060" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s5_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>one candidate standing for election under <ref>section 6(1)(c)</ref> of
                        the
                        Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading>Ballot
            counting</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903425_074" name="s6" temporalId="sch1_s6"><num value="6">6.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410903425_079" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Returned ballot papers received by the Foundation shall remain sealed in
                    their envelopes and be kept in a secure place until the counting of
                    votes.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903441_006" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The counting of votes shall take place as soon after 12 noon on the date
                    specified under <ref>section 3(1)</ref> as is practicable; ballot papers
                    received after that time shall be disregarded.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903441_015" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The internal auditor of the Foundation shall be responsible for opening the
                    envelopes and managing the count.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903441_024" name="4" temporalId="sch1_s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The candidates may be present during the
                    count.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading>Results</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903441_039" name="s7" temporalId="sch1_s7"><num value="7">7.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410903441_044" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The winning candidate or candidates shall be decided by the number of votes
                    cast; in the event of an equality of votes, the winning candidate shall be
                    decided by the drawing of lots.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903441_050" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The result shall be announced by the internal auditor of the Foundation
                    through notices placed in the schools and on the website of the Foundation and
                    the websites of schools of the Foundation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903441_059" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If fewer candidates are nominated than there are vacancies, those nominated
                    shall be deemed to have been
                    elected.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading>Vacancies</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438410903441_074" name="s8" temporalId="sch1_s8"><num value="8">8.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410903456_001" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a vacancy remains after the holding of an election, or a casual vacancy
                    occurs, the Board may co-opt a parent to fill the vacancy until an election is
                    held.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903456_007" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An election to fill a casual vacancy may be deferred until the start of the
                    next academic
                    year.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading>Interpretation,
            etc.</crossHeading><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/er1">E.R. 1 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438410903456_022" name="s9" temporalId="sch1_s9"><num value="9">9.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410903456_027" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="Parent">In this <ref>Schedule</ref>, unless the context otherwise
                    requires,
                        <term>parent</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">家長</term>) means a parent of a student of a
                    school of the Foundation.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410903456_032" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any communication required or permitted to be sent to a parent in writing
                    or by post may be sent by post addressed to the billing address held by the
                    Foundation.</content></subsection></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402578380_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
      2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1117A/s29">s.
        29</ref>]</note><heading>Transitional
      Arrangements</heading><section id="ID_1438410903534_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_s1"><num value="1">1.</num><leadIn>As at the
          commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Regulation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410903534_022" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a person who immediately before that commencement was a member of the committee of
          the Parent Teacher Association of a school of the Foundation for the purposes of
            <ref>regulation 15</ref>.9 of the repealed Regulations and was the Chairman of that
          committee shall be deemed to be the Chairman of the committee of the Parent Teacher
          Association of that school for the purposes of paragraph (a) of <ref>section 22(1)</ref>
          of this Regulation, pursuant to an election held in accordance with that
          paragraph;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410903550_007" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a person who immediately before that commencement was a member of the committee of
          the Parent Teacher Association of a school of the Foundation for the purposes of
            <ref>regulation 15</ref>.9 of the repealed Regulations, other than the Chairman of that
          committee, shall be deemed to be a member of the committee of the Parent Teacher
          Association of that school for the purposes of paragraph (b) of <ref>section 22(1)</ref>
          of this Regulation, pursuant to an election held in accordance with that
          paragraph.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438410903565_004" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_s2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The term of office of a person deemed to be a member of the committee of a Parent
        Teacher Association under <ref>section 1</ref> shall be the period beginning with the
        commencement of this Regulation and ending with the first election of a person to that
        membership position under <ref>section 22</ref> of this Regulation (and for the purpose of
        any such first election the membership position shall be regarded as being
        vacant).<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1438410903581_004" name="s3" temporalId="sch2_s3"><num value="3">3.</num><def name="RepealedRegulations">In this <ref>Schedule</ref>,
          <term>repealed
          Regulations</term>
          (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已廢除規例</term>》) means Regulations made under the Ordinance
        and in effect immediately before the
          commencement<sup>#</sup>
        of The English Schools Foundation (Amendment) Ordinance 2008 (<ref href="/hk/2008/5">5 of
          2008</ref>).</def></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1675043100670_001">
      
      <content>
        <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="245" class="font_size_9">
          <colgroup>
            <col width="3%"></col>
            <col width="97%"></col>
          </colgroup>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td colspan="2">Editorial Note:</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="force_orig_font">*</inline></td>
              <td>Commencement date: 9 May 2008.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><sup>#</sup></inline></td>
              <td>Commencement date: 18 April 2008.</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </content>
      
      
    </editorialNote></schedule></main></subLeg>