<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1025</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1025</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1025!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402533530_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-04-28">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of The Hong Kong Chinese Christian Churches
                Union.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[4 June 1948]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402533545_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Chinese Christian Churches Union Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533561_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="BoardOfDirectors"><term>board
                of
            directors</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">董事會</term>) means the board of directors who have the
            power of management and control of the affairs of the Union in accordance with the
            constitution;</def><def name="Chairman,Vicechairman"><term>chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) and
                <term>vice-chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">副主席</term>) mean the chairman and vice-chairman of the
            board of directors;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會章</term>) means the rules or regulations governing the
            Union for the time being in force together with any amendment thereto made from time to
            time in accordance with such rules or regulations;</def><def name="TheHongKongChineseChristianChurchesUnion,TheUnion"><term>The
                Hong Kong Chinese Christian Churches
            Union</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">香港華人基督教聯會</term>) or
                <term>the
                Union</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">聯會</term>) means the representatives of such Chinese
            Christian Churches in Hong Kong as are or shall be members of the Union in accordance
            with the constitution.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section><section id="ID_1438402533577_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Appointment of chairman and vice-chairman</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410803647_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Whenever any person is appointed to the office of chairman and whenever any person is appointed to the office of vice-chairman such persons shall, within three weeks after their respective appointments or within such further time as may be allowed by the Chief Secretary for Administration, furnish to the Chief Secretary for Administration satisfactory evidence of their respective appointments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803647_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A notification in the Gazette under the hand of the Chief Secretary for Administration that such evidence has been furnished to the Chief Secretary for Administration by such persons shall be conclusive evidence of such appointments.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of 1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533577_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Proof of membership of the Union and proof of the constitution</heading><leadIn>A certificate under the hand of the chairman, or in his absence from Hong Kong, of
            the vice-chairman—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803678_005" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that any person therein named is a member of the Union; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803678_013" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that any rules or regulations annexed to such certificate are the
                constitution,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be accepted for all purposes as sufficient proof of the fact that such
            person is a member of the Union, or that the constitution was duly made and is in
            force.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438402533592_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Incorporation. Powers of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410803694_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Union shall be a body corporate under the name of “The Hong Kong Chinese
                Christian Churches Union”, hereinafter referred to as
                        <b><i>the
                        corporation</i></b>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803694_019" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation by the name aforesaid shall have perpetual succession, and
                shall and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong, and shall and may have and
                use a common seal, and may break, change, alter and make anew the said seal as to
                the corporation may seem fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803694_027" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take,
                hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind
                soever and wheresoever situate in Hong Kong, and also to invest moneys upon mortgage
                of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, or upon the mortgages, debentures,
                stocks, funds, shares or securities of any corporation or company, and also to
                purchase, acquire and possess goods and chattels of what nature and kind
                    soever.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803710_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The corporation shall further have power by deed under its seal to grant, sell,
                convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise,
                reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages,
                tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities, or goods and
                chattels which are vested in or belong to the corporation, upon such terms as to the
                corporation may seem fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533608_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Seal</heading><text>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall
            be sealed therewith in the presence of the chairman, or in his absence from Hong Kong,
            of the vice- chairman, and shall also be signed by the chairman, or by the
            vice-chairman. The seal shall be kept in the custody of the chairman, or in his absence
            from Hong Kong, in the custody of the vice-chairman.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533623_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Internal management of the Union</heading><content>All matters of internal management of the Union, including any amendment of the constitution, shall be settled and carried out in accordance with the constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533623_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>