<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1133</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1133</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1133!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402602326_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-05-19">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of The Methodist Church, Hong
                Kong.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[23 December 1983]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402602342_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as <shortTitle>The Methodist Church, Hong Kong, Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402602357_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Conference"><term>Conference</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總議會</term>) means a Conference of the delegates of the
            members of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong, as defined in the constitution;</def><def name="ConferenceCommittee"><term>Conference
                Committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總議會委員會</term>) means a sub-committee under the control
            of the Standing Committee set up by the Corporation in accordance with the
            constitution;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>Constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of The Methodist
            Church, Hong Kong, for the time being in force;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>Corporation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means the body incorporated by <ref>section
                3</ref>;</def><def name="StandingCommittee"><term>Standing Committee</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">常務委員會</term>) means the governing body of the Corporation set up by the Corporation
            in accordance with the constitution; <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R.
                    2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TheMethodistChurchHongKong"><term>The
                Methodist Church, Hong
            Kong</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">香港基督敎循道衞理聯合敎會</term>)
            means The Methodist Church, Hong Kong, referred to in <ref>section
            3</ref>.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of
            2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402602357_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Description and Incorporation</heading><content>There is hereby established a body corporate having for its members the delegates of the members of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong, specified in <ref>section 6</ref> and which shall have the name “THE METHODIST CHURCH, HONG KONG” and in<inline class="width_3"> </inline>that name shall have perpetual succession and shall and may sue and be sued in all courts and tribunals in Hong Kong and shall have and may use a common seal, and may from time to time, break, change, alter and make anew the said seal as the Corporation may deem fit.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402602373_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2005-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of the Corporation</heading><leadIn>The Corporation shall have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411032515_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to establish, manage, administer and operate any church, school, clinic, hospital, welfare centre, or educational or charitable institution as the Corporation may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032531_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take or otherwise hold and enjoy any land, buildings, messuages or tenements of whatsoever nature or kind and wheresoever situate;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2005/17">17 of 2005 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032531_014" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to acquire, by purchase or otherwise, goods and chattels of whatsoever nature or kind;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032531_022" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank or finance company in Hong Kong or outside Hong Kong or in any government bonds or on mortgage of any land, buildings, messuages, or tenements of whatsoever nature or kind and wheresoever situate, or in or on debentures, debenture-stocks, funds, shares or securities of any corporation or company in Hong Kong or outside Hong Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2005/17">17 of 2005 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032531_030" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, yield up, mortgage, demise, let, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of, any land, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture-stocks, stocks, funds, shares, securities, vessels, goods or chattels for the time being vested in the Corporation, upon such terms as the Corporation may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032546_006" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to act as custodian trustee or manager of any property or fund for any charitable purpose;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032546_014" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to accept gifts, donations and endowments for all or any of the purposes of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032546_022" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>to subscribe to and to grant donations for any charities or educational purposes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032546_030" name="i" temporalId="s4_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to develop either alone or jointly with other or others and turn to account any land acquired by the Corporation or in which it is interested and in particular by laying out and preparing the same for building purposes, constructing, altering, pulling down, decorating, maintaining, fitting up, and improving buildings, and by planting, paving, draining, farming, cultivating and letting on building lease or building agreement, and by advancing money to and entering into contracts and arrangements of all kinds with builders, developers, contractors, land investment companies, land mortgage companies, building estate companies, banks, financiers, owners, lessees, tenants and others, in such manner or on such terms and conditions as the Corporation may deem fit or expedient and to make applications and obtain orders under the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap. 7</ref>), and to agree and pay such compensation as the Tribunal within the meaning of that Ordinance may recommend or order;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2002/32">32 of 2002 s. 40</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032593_006" name="j" temporalId="s4_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the Corporation may deem fit, and to raise money by public or private subscription; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032593_014" name="k" temporalId="s4_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>generally to do such other things as may appear to be incidental or conducive to the aims and objects of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402602388_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Vesting of Property</heading><leadIn>On the
            commencement^
            of this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411032624_028" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all those pieces or parcels of ground specified in the second column of Parts I,
                II and IV of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, together with all rights,
                easements and appurtenances thereto belonging, shall vest in the Corporation without
                any conveyance or assignment for the unexpired residue of the respective terms of
                years created by the Crown leases, conditions of sale, conditions of grant,
                conditions of exchange, conditions of regrant and new grant specified opposite
                thereto in the third column of Parts I,
                II and IV of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, subject to payment of the
                rent and performance of the covenants and conditions reserved by and contained in
                the said Crown leases, conditions of sale, conditions of grant, conditions of
                exchange, conditions of regrant and new grant and subject also to such mortgages,
                charges, leases, tenancies and other agreement (if any) and upon such trusts,
                conditions and stipulations, as may be subsisting in relation to such premises upon
                the commencement of this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032671_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/7">7 of 1997 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032671_014" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>the Corporation shall succeed to all other property, right, privileges,
                obligations and liabilities within Hong Kong of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411032671_022" name="i" temporalId="s5_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>Methodist Missionary Trust Association;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411032671_030" name="ii" temporalId="s5_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>The Hong Kong Chinese District of the Methodist Church (United
                    Kingdom);</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411032687_007" name="iii" temporalId="s5_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>The Methodist Church, Hong Kong District (Property Holding),
                    Limited;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411032687_015" name="iv" temporalId="s5_c_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>The Methodist Church Hong Kong (Wei Li Kung Hui);</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411032687_023" name="v" temporalId="s5_c_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>The Wesleyan Methodist Missionary Trust Association;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411032687_031" name="vi" temporalId="s5_c_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>Bishop W. Angie Smith, Sidney R. Anderson, Judith L. Hawks, Yolay Young,
                    Pau-Waung Yang, Chen Kuan Yu and Jack Y. H. Yuen, Trustees of The Methodist
                    Church, Hong Kong District.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1632715877713_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><sup>^</sup> Commencement date: 23 December 1983.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402602404_001" name="s5A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5A"><num value="5A">5A.</num><heading>English Speaking Methodist Church</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411032718_039" name="1" temporalId="s5A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All that piece or parcel of ground specified in the second column of Part III of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, together with all rights, easements and appurtenances thereto belonging, shall be deemed to have vested in the Corporation on 1 September 1988 without any conveyance or assignment for the unexpired residue of the term of years created by the Crown lease specified opposite thereto in the third column of Part III of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, subject to payment of the rent and performance of the covenants and conditions reserved by and contained in the said Crown lease and subject also to such mortgages, charges, leases, tenancies and other agreements (if any) as may be subsisting in relation to such premises on 1 September 1988.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411032749_005" name="2" temporalId="s5A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Corporation shall be deemed to have succeeded to all other property, rights, privileges, obligations and liabilities within Hong Kong of “The Hong Kong English District of the Methodist Church, United Kingdom” (also known as English Speaking Methodist Church) on 1 September 1988.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/7">7 of 1997 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402602404_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Members of the Corporation</heading><leadIn>The delegates of the members of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong, shall consist of the following persons—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411032780_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all ordained ministers and missionaries for the time being of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032780_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all deacons and deaconesses and district workers appointed by The Methodist Church, Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032780_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all delegates for the time being of each local church of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong, elected by each such local church in accordance with the constitution;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032780_036" name="d" temporalId="s6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a member of the Standing Committee who held office immediately preceding the annual conference of the Corporation of any one year, shall be a member of the Corporation during the year commencing from such annual conference immediately prior to which he held office as a member of the Standing Committee whether he may or may not be a member of the Corporation under paragraph (a), (b) or (c) of this section;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032796_006" name="e" temporalId="s6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the delegates of any Conference Committee for any one year, elected by that particular Conference Committee to represent it at the annual conference for the immediate following year, shall be a member of the Corporation during the year commencing from the said annual conference.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402602420_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Proof of Membership</heading><content>A certificate under the hand of the President of the Corporation, or in his absence from
            Hong Kong, of the
            Vice-President
            of the Corporation that any person specified in <ref>section 6</ref> is a member of the
            Corporation shall be accepted for all purposes as sufficient proof of the fact that such
            person is a member of the Corporation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402602435_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Seal of the Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411032827_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The seal of the Corporation shall not be affixed to any deed, document or instrument except by the authority of a resolution of the Standing Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411032827_019" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the Corporation shall be sealed with the seal of the Corporation and signed by either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411032827_027" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any two of the President of the Corporation, the Vice-President of the Corporation, the Secretary of the Corporation and the Treasurer of the Corporation; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411032843_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any one of the persons named in paragraph (a) of this subsection and any three members of the Standing Committee.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/7">7 of 1997 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411032843_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The seal shall be kept in the custody of the President, or in his absence from Hong Kong, in the custody of the Vice-President.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402602451_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Management and exercise of powers of the Corporation</heading><content>The business of the Corporation shall be managed by the Standing Committee and all the powers of the Corporation shall be exercisable by the Standing Committee except so far as this Ordinance or the constitution otherwise requires.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402602466_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Existing constitution to become constitution of the Corporation</heading><content>The existing constitution of the unincorporated “The Methodist Church, Hong Kong” shall be the constitution of the Corporation, but the same may be changed or amended at any time and from time to time in accordance with its provisions for the time being in force.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402602466_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of any other person except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by, from or under them.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2005/17">17 of 2005 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402602482_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1133/s5">ss. 5</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap1133/s5A">5A</ref>]<sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/7">7 of 1997 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></note><part id="ID_1438411032936_031" name="PI" temporalId="sch0_PI" class="no_header"><num value="I"><inline>Part
                    I</inline></num><heading>Property
                Hitherto
                Held
                for “The Trustees of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong District” or “The Methodist
                Church, Hong Kong District”
                (“Wei
                Li Kung
                Hui”)
                by:—</heading><heading></heading><section class="no_header" id="ID_1506326735170_001" name="sA" temporalId="sch0_PI_sA"><num value="A"><inline>(A)</inline></num><leadIn>“The
                    Methodist Church, Hong Kong District (Property Holding),
                        Limited”<b class="font_size_14"></b></leadIn><continued>which
                    has also been described as<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued><continued>“The
                    Methodist Church, (Property Holding) Limited”<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued><continued>“The
                    Methodist Church (Property Holding), Limited”<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued><continued>“The
                    Methodist Church, Hong Kong District (Property Holding)
                        Limited”<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">and</inline></crossHeading><continued>“The
                    Methodist Church Hong Kong District (Property Holding)
                        Limited”<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued></section><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="446" class="repeat_header">
                    
                    <col width="10%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="58%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="32%"></col>
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Item<br></br>No.</span></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Descriptions of
                                    Property</span></th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_10 valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Crown Lease/Conditions of Sale/Conditions of Grant/Conditions
                                    of Exchange/Conditions of Regrant/New Grant</span></th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_15"></th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>1.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT one equal
                                undivided sixteenth part or share of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel
                                of ground situate lying and being at Kowloon, Hong Kong and
                                registered in the Land Office as SUBSECTION THREE OF SECTION B OF
                                KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER SIX THOUSAND AND EIGHTEEN And of and in
                                the messuages erections and building erected thereon known as BLOCK
                                “D” of KIMBERLEY MANSION TOGETHER with the exclusive right and full
                                privilege to the possession use occupation and enjoyment of the
                                whole of the FOURTEENTH FLOOR of the said Block “D” of Kimberley
                                Mansion which said Fourteenth floor of the said Block “D” is shown
                                on the plan marked No. 2 annexed to an Indenture of Assignment dated
                                the 19th day of April 1967 and registered in the Land Office by
                                Memorial No. 581413 and thereon coloured Pink.</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 24th day of November 1955.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT one equal
                                undivided sixteenth part or share of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel
                                of the ground situate lying and being at Kowloon, Hong Kong and
                                registered in the Land Office as SUBSECTION FIVE OF SECTION B OF
                                KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER SIX THOUSAND AND EIGHTEEN And of and in
                                the messuages erections and building erected thereon known as BLOCK
                                “E” of KIMBERLEY MANSION TOGETHER with the exclusive right and full
                                privilege to the possession use occupation and enjoyment of the
                                whole of the FOURTEENTH FLOOR of the said Block “E” of Kimberley
                                Mansion which said Fourteenth floor of the said Block “E” is shown
                                on the plan marked No. 2 annexed to an Indenture of Assignment dated
                                the 19th day of April 1967 and registered in the Land Office by
                                Memorial No. 581414 and thereon coloured Pink.</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 24th day of November 1955.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>3.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT one equal
                                undivided sixteenth part or share of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel
                                of ground situate lying and being at Kowloon, Hong Kong and
                                registered in the Land Office as SUBSECTION FIVE OF SECTION B OF
                                KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER SIX THOUSAND AND EIGHTEEN And of and in
                                the messuages erections and building erected thereon known as BLOCK
                                “E” of KIMBERLEY MANSION TOGETHER with the exclusive right and full
                                privilege to the possession use occupation and enjoyment of the
                                whole of the ROOF of the said Block “E” of Kimberley Mansion which
                                said Roof of the said Block “E” is shown on the plan marked No. 3
                                annexed to an Indenture of Assignment dated the 8th day of September
                                1967 and registered in the Land Office by Memorial No. 596193 and
                                thereon coloured Pink.</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 24th day of November 1955.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>4.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title and interest of and in ALL THAT One equal undivided
                                Sixtieth part or share of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel of ground
                                situate at Kowloon, Hong Kong and registered in the Land Office as
                                KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER EIGHT THOUSAND TWO HUNDRED AND THIRTY FIVE
                                And of and in the messuages or tenements and other erections and
                                buildings known as “SUNLIGHT GARDEN” at No. 2 Man Wan Road Waterloo
                                Hill Together with the full right and privilege to hold use occupy
                                and enjoy ALL THAT FLAT “C” on the SEVENTEENTH FLOOR of the said
                                “SUNLIGHT GARDEN” Together with CAR PARK SPACE NO. 30 (which said
                                Flat and Car Park Space are more particularly shown and coloured
                                Pink on the Plans annexed to an Indenture of Assignment dated the
                                4th day of November 1965 and registered in the Land Office by
                                Memorial No. 510358).</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Sale No. 7299.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>5.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THOSE Two equal
                                undivided one hundred and thirtieth parts or shares of and in ALL
                                THAT piece or parcel of ground registered in the Land Office as THE
                                REMAINING PORTION OF SUB<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">SECTION 1</ref>
                                OF SECTION A OF INLAND LOT NO. 2836 And of and in the messuage
                                erections and buildings thereon known as LAKESIDE BUILDING Together
                                with ALL THAT the right to the exclusive use occupation and
                                enjoyment of ALL THOSE FLATS A and B on the EIGHTH FLOOR of the said
                                LAKESIDE BUILDING as shown and coloured Pink on the Plans annexed to
                                an Indenture of Assignment dated the 24th day of February 1967 and
                                registered in the Land Office by Memorial No. 572478.</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 22nd day of May 1930.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>6.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THOSE two equal
                                undivided eighty-eighth parts or shares of and in ALL THOSE pieces
                                or parcels of ground situate at Kowloon, Hong Kong and registered in
                                the Land Office as THE REMAINING PORTION OF KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO.
                                1462 and THE REMAINING PORTION OF KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 2361 AND of
                                and in the messuages erections and buildings thereon known as KIU
                                KIN MANSION Nos. 566, 566A, 568 and 568A Nathan Road TOGETHER with
                                the right to the exclusive use and enjoyment of ALL THOSE Portions
                                of the SIXTH FLOOR of the said Kiu Kin Mansion (which said Portions
                                are shown and coloured Pink on the plan annexed to an Indenture of
                                Assignment dated the 25th day of October 1967 and registered in the
                                Land Office by Memorial No. 603074 and are known as 6th floor of
                                Nos. 566 and 568 Nathan Road).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 29th day of October 1931, Crown Lease dated
                                the 27th day of October 1930.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>7.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT one equal
                                undivided eighty-eighth part or share of and in ALL THOSE pieces or
                                parcels of ground situate at Kowloon, Hong Kong registered in the
                                Land Office as THE REMAINING PORTION OF KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 1462
                                and THE REMAINING PORTION OF KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 2361 and of and
                                in the messuages erections and buildings thereon known as KIU KIN
                                MANSION Nos. 566, 566A, 568 and 568A Nathan Road TOGETHER with the
                                right to the exclusive use and enjoyment of ALL THAT portion of the
                                TWELFTH FLOOR of the said Kiu Kin Mansion (which said Portion is
                                shown and coloured Pink on the plan annexed to an Indenture of
                                Assignment dated the 23rd day of July 1965 and registered in the
                                Land Office by Memorial No. 500002) and is known as No. 568 Nathan
                                Road Twelfth floor.</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 29th day of October 1931, Crown Lease dated
                                the 27th day of October 1930.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>8.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title and interest of and in ALL THAT one equal undivided one
                                hundred and ninety-first part or share of and in ALL THAT piece or
                                parcel of ground situate at Kwun Tong, Kowloon, Hong Kong and
                                registered in the Land Office as KWUN TONG INLAND LOT NO. 399 And of
                                and in the messuages erections and buildings thereon known as “TSAP
                                KING MANSION” at Kwun Tong TOGETHER with the full and exclusive
                                right and privilege to hold use occupy and enjoy ALL THAT FLAT “G”
                                on the SECOND FLOOR of the said Tsap King Mansion which is more
                                particularly shown and coloured Pink on the Plan annexed to an
                                Indenture of Assignment dated the 24th day of December 1969 and
                                registered in the Land Office by Memorial No. 714969.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Sale No. 8241.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>9.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title and interest of and in ALL THOSE THREE equal undivided
                                THIRTY-FOURTH parts or shares of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel of
                                ground situate lying and being at Fung Wong Village, Kowloon, Hong
                                Kong and registered at the Land Office as NEW KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO.
                                5024 and of and in the messuages or tenements and
                                other erections and buildings thereon known as “WAH CHUNG MANSION”
                                NOS. 8, 10, 10A, 12, 12A and 14 WAN FUNG STREET TOGETHER with the
                                sole and exclusive right and privilege to the possession use
                                occupation and enjoyment of ALL THOSE the FLATS C, D and F on the
                                FIRST FLOOR of the said WAH CHUNG MANSION which Flats are also known
                                as FIRST FLOORS of NOS. 8, 10 and 10A WAN FUNG STREET and are more
                                particularly shown on the Floor Plans annexed to an Indenture of
                                Assignment dated the 17th day of March 1971 and registered in the
                                Land Office by Memorial No. 812184 and thereon coloured Pink.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Grant No. 9179.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>10.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title benefit and interest of and in ALL THOSE four equal
                                undivided seventy fourth parts or shares of and in ALL THAT piece or
                                parcel of ground situate lying and being at Kwun Tong, Kowloon, Hong
                                Kong and known and registered in the Land Office as KWUN TONG INLAND
                                LOT NO. 313 and of and in the messuages erections and buildings
                                thereon known as “CHUNG HING HOUSE” TOGETHER with the sole and
                                exclusive right and privilege to hold use occupy and enjoy ALL THOSE
                                FLATS “M”, “N”, “O”
                                AND “P” on the FIRST FLOOR of the said CHUNG HING
                                HOUSE as shown on the plans annexed to an Indenture of Assignment
                                dated the 27th day of October 1966 and registered in the Land Office
                                by Memorial No. 559589 and thereon coloured Pink respectively.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Sale No. 7542.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>11.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title benefit and interest of and in ALL THOSE three equal
                                undivided seventy fourth parts or shares of and in ALL THAT piece or
                                parcel of ground situate lying and being at Kwun Tong, Kowloon, Hong
                                Kong and known and registered in the Land office as KWUN TONG INLAND
                                LOT NO. 313 and of and in the messuages erections and buildings
                                thereon known as “CHUNG HING HOUSE” TOGETHER with the sole and
                                exclusive right and privilege to hold use occupy and enjoy ALL THOSE
                                FLATS “F”, “G” AND “H” on the FIRST FLOOR of the said CHUNG HING
                                HOUSE as shown on the Plans annexed to an Indenture of Assignment
                                dated the 27th day of September 1966 and registered in the Land
                                Office by Memorial No. 555078 and thereon coloured Pink
                                respectively.</td>
                            <td>
                                <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Conditions of Sale No.
                                    7542.</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>12.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title benefit and interest of and in ALL THOSE six equal
                                undivided sixty sixth parts or shares of and in ALL THOSE pieces or
                                parcels of ground situate lying and being at Kowloon, Hong Kong and
                                known and registered in the Land Office respectively as SECTION A OF
                                NEW KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 2141 and THE REMAINING PORTION OF NEW
                                KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 2141 and of and in the messuages erections
                                and buildings thereon known as “FAT TSEUNG BUILDING” Nos. 290 and
                                292 Castle Peak Road and Nos. 7C, 7D and 7E Fat Tseung Street
                                TOGETHER with the sole and exclusive right and privilege to hold use
                                occupy and enjoy ALL THAT the FIRST FLOOR of the said No. 290 Castle
                                Peak Road as shown on the Plan annexed to an Indenture of Assignment
                                dated the 1st day of June 1966 and registered in the Land Office by
                                Memorial No. 536848 and thereon coloured Pink.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Exchange No. 3527.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>13.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THOSE nine equal
                                undivided 103rd parts or shares of and in ALL THOSE pieces or
                                parcels of ground registered in the Land Office as THE REMAINING
                                PORTION OF INLAND LOT NO. 5411, THE REMAINING PORTION OF INLAND LOT
                                NO. 5410, THE REMAINING PORTION OF INLAND LOT NO. 5409, THE
                                REMAINING PORTION OF INLAND LOT NO. 5408, THE REMAINING PORTION OF
                                INLAND LOT NO. 5407, THE REMAINING PORTION OF INLAND LOT NO. 5406
                                which said pieces or parcels of ground with their abuttals and
                                dimensions are more particularly delineated and described on the
                                Block Plan No. 1 annexed to an Indenture of Assignment dated the
                                15th day of November 1968 and registered in the Land Office by
                                Memorial No. 653340 and thereon coloured Yellow And of and in all
                                messuages erections and buildings thereon known as “SANG CHEONG
                                BUILDING” Nos. 427, 429, 431, 433, 435 and 437 Queen’s Road West as
                                regards the ground floors and Flats A, B, C, D, E, F, G and H of No.
                                427 Queen’s Road West as regards the upper floors Together with the
                                exclusive right to the use occupation and enjoyment of ALL THOSE
                                FLATS A, B, C, D, E, F, G and H on the FIRST FLOOR of the said No.
                                427 Queen’s Road West which is shown on the Plan No. 2 annexed to
                                the said Indenture of Assignment Memorial No. 653340 and thereon
                                coloured Pink.</td>
                            <td>Six several Crown Leases all dated the 1st day of June 1939.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>14.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title and interest of and in ALL THOSE two equal undivided two
                                thousand and ninety fourth parts or shares of and in ALL THAT piece
                                or parcel of ground registered in the Land Office as THE REMAINING
                                PORTION OF SECTION A OF SHAU KEI WAN INLAND LOT NO. 738 and THE
                                REMAINING PORTION OF SHAU KEI WAN INLAND LOT NO. 738 And of and in
                                the messuage erections and buildings thereon known as TAI ON
                                BUILDING Together with ALL THAT the right to the exclusive use
                                occupation and enjoyment of ALL THOSE SHOPS NOS. 117 and 118 on the
                                FIRST FLOOR of the said Tai On Building (which said shops are shown
                                and coloured Pink on the plan annexed to an Indenture of Assignment
                                dated the 21st day of July 1970 and registered in the Land Office by
                                Memorial No. 753452).</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Exchange No. 8669.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>15.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THOSE four equal
                                undivided thirty-second parts or shares of and in ALL THOSE pieces
                                or parcels of ground registered in the Land Office as SUB<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">SECTION 1</ref>
                                OF SECTION G OF HUNGHOM INLAND LOT NO. 239, SUB<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">SECTION 2</ref>
                                OF SECTION G OF HUNGHOM INLAND LOT NO. 239 and THE REMAINING PORTION
                                OF SECTION G OF HUNGHOM INLAND LOT NO. 239 and of and in the
                                building thereon known as Nos. 7 AND 8 WA FUNG STREET, HUNGHOM and
                                collectively known as GOOD RICH MANSION (衡豐樓) TOGETHER with the full
                                and exclusive right and privilege to hold use occupy and enjoy ALL
                                THOSE OFFICES “A” AND “B” on the FIRST FLOOR of the said GOOD RICH
                                MANSION (which said offices are more particularly shown and
                                delineated on the Floor Plan annexed to an Indenture of Assignment
                                dated the 16th day of March 1972 and registered in the Land Office
                                by Memorial No. 875345 and thereon coloured Pink).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 4th day of February 1903.</td>
                        </tr>
                        
                        <tr>
                            <td>16.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO.
                                9093<br></br>(Waterloo Road).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 10th day of March 1970.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>17.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">DEMARCATION DISTRICT
                                NO. 2 LOT No. 643, MUI WO, LANTAU.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Grant No. 4521.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>18.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title and interest of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel of
                                ground registered in the Land Office as INLAND LOT NO. 7643 and
                                situate at North Point, Hong Kong and of and in the buildings
                                thereon known as No. 19 Cheung Hong Street.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Grant No. 6252.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>19.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">KWAI CHUNG TOWN LOT NO.
                                269<br></br>(Kwai Chung, Tsuen Wan, New Territories).</td>
                            <td>New Grant No. 5175.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>20.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title benefit and interest of and in ALL THOSE twelve equal
                                undivided 246th parts or shares of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel
                                of ground situate lying and being at Kowloon, Hong Kong and
                                registered in the Land Office as KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 7728 which
                                said piece or parcel of ground with its abuttals and dimensions is
                                more particularly delineated on the plan annexed to an Indenture of
                                Assignment dated the 1st day of February 1967 and registered in the
                                Land Office by Memorial No. 576226 and thereon coloured yellow and
                                of and in the messuages erections and buildings thereon known as
                                “METROPOLE BUILDING” TOGETHER with the exclusive right and privilege
                                to the use occupation and enjoyment of (1) ALL THAT the SEVENTH
                                FLOOR of the said METROPOLE BUILDING as shown coloured Pink on the
                                said plan and (2) those parts of the external walls of the said
                                METROPOLE BUILDING between the seventh floor level and the eighth
                                floor level.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Regrant No. 6291.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>21.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">KWAI CHUNG TOWN LOT NO.
                                253<br></br>(Kwai Chung, New Territories).</td>
                            <td>New Grant No. 5018.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>22.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT piece or
                                parcel of ground registered in the Land Office as</td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10 cellpadding_left_10">CHEUNG CHAU
                                    INLAND<br></br><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_15"> </inline>LOT NO. 1A,</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 28th day of December 1914.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10 cellpadding_left_25">1A
                                EXTENTION, and</td>
                            
                            <td>New
                                Grant No. 1006 SALE NO. 682.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10 cellpadding_left_25">1A
                                FURTHER EXTENTION</td>
                            
                            <td>New Grant No. 1038 SALE NO. 711.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">TOGETHER with the
                                messuage erections and buildings, thereon known as NO. 7 PEAK ROAD
                                CHEUNG CHAU.</td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>23.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title benefit and interest of and in ALL THOSE five equal
                                undivided 2133rd parts or shares of and in ALL THAT piece or parcel
                                of ground situate lying and being at Kwun Tong, Kowloon, Hong Kong
                                and known and registered in the Land Office as KWUN TONG INLAND LOT
                                NO. 363 which said piece or parcel of ground with its abuttals and
                                dimensions is more particularly delineated and described on the
                                Block Plan “A” annexed to an Assignment registered in the Land
                                Office by Memorial No. 521462 and thereon coloured Brown and of and
                                in the messuages erections and buildings thereon now known as “HING
                                TAT MANSION (興達大廈)” of Nos. 335, 335A, 337, 339, 339A, 341, 341A,
                                343, 343A, 345, 345A, 347, 347A, 349, 349A, 351 and 351A Ngau Tau
                                Kok Road and Nos. 1, 3 and 5 Tung Ming Street TOGETHER with the sole
                                and exclusive right and privilege to hold use occupy and enjoy ALL
                                THAT the SIXTH FLOOR of the said No. 349A Ngau Tau Kok Road
                                (formerly known as Flat “M” on the Sixth floor of the said HING TAT
                                MANSION) which said Flat is more particularly delineated and
                                described on the Floor Plan “B” annexed to the said Assignment
                                Memorial No. 521462 and thereon coloured Pink.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Sale No. 7514.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>24.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title and interest of and in ALL THOSE sixteen equal undivided
                                nine hundred and sixtieth parts or shares of and in ALL THAT piece
                                or parcel of ground situate at Kwun Tong, Kowloon and registered in
                                the Land Office as NEW KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER FIVE THOUSAND FOUR
                                HUNDRED AND TWENTY And of and in the messuages or tenements and
                                other erections and building thereon known as “KING HING COURT” No.
                                38 Kung Lok Road Together with the full right and privilege to hold
                                use occupy and enjoy ALL THOSE UNITS being FLAT NO. 4 on the SEVENTH
                                FLOOR and CAR PARKING SPACE NO. 46 on the GROUND FLOOR of the said
                                KING HING COURT (which said Units are more particularly shown and
                                coloured Pink on the respective plans annexed to an Indenture of
                                Assignment dated the 12th day of September 1977 and registered in
                                the Land Office by Memorial No. 1425461.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Sale No. 10148.</td>
                        </tr>
                        
                        <tr>
                            <td>25.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT the estate
                                right title and interest of and in ALL THAT one equal undivided 66th
                                part or share of and in ALL THOSE pieces or parcels of ground
                                registered in the Land Office as SUBSECTIONS FOUR AND FIVE OF
                                SECTION E OF INLAND LOT NO. 2366 AND THE EXTENTION THERETO And of
                                and in the building thereon known as MIDO APARTMENTS at King’s Road
                                North Point Hong Kong TOGETHER with the sole and exclusive right and
                                privilege to hold use occupy and enjoy ALL THAT FLAT NO. “B” on the
                                SEVENTH FLOOR of the said Mido Apartments which said Flat is shown
                                and coloured Pink on the Plan annexed to an Assignment registered in
                                the Land Office by Memorial No. 353271.</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Sale No. 1143.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>26.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT one equal
                                undivided twenty second part or share of and in ALL THOSE pieces or
                                parcels of ground situate lying and being at Victoria Hong Kong and
                                known and registered in the Land Office respectively as THE
                                REMAINING PORTION OF SECTION E OF INLAND LOT NO. 67, THE REMAINING
                                PORTION OF SECTION A OF INLAND LOT NO. 67, THE REMAINING PORTION OF
                                SECTION A OF INLAND LOT NO. 68, THE REMAINING PORTION OF SUB<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">SECTION 2</ref>
                                OF SECTION A OF INLAND LOT NO. 67 and THE REMAINING PORTION OF
                                    SUB<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">SECTION
                                    2</ref> OF SECTION A OF INLAND LOT NO. 68 and of and in the
                                building thereon known as NOS. 29 AND 31 CAINE ROAD TOGETHER with
                                the full and exclusive right and privilege to hold use occupy and
                                enjoy ALL THAT FLAT NO. B on the EIGHTH FLOOR of the said building
                                NOS. 29 and 31 CAINE ROAD (which said Flat is more particularly
                                shown and delineated on the Plan annexed to an Indenture of
                                Assignment dated the 26th day of March 1970 and registered in the
                                Land Office by Memorial No. 739812 and thereon coloured Pink and is
                                also known as the Eighth Floor of No. 31 Caine Road).</td>
                            <td>Two several Crown Leases both dated the 27th day of August
                                1853.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </text><section class="no_header" id="ID_1506326735186_002" name="sB" temporalId="sch0_PI_sB"><num value="B"><inline class="not_bold">(B)<b class="font_size_14"></b></inline></num><leadIn>“Bishop W.
                    Angie Smith, Sidney R. Anderson, Judith L. Hawks, Yolay Young, Pau-Waung Yang,
                    Chen Kuan Yu and Jack Y. H. Yuen, Trustees of The Methodist Church, Hong Kong
                        District”<b class="font_size_14"></b></leadIn></section><text>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="446" class="repeat_header">
                    
                    <col width="10%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="58%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="32%"></col>
                    
                    
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Item<br></br>No.</span></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Descriptions of
                                    Property</span></th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_10 valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Conditions of Grant</span></th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_15"></th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>1.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">INLAND LOT NO.
                                7690<br></br>(Upper Cheung Hong Street).</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Grant No. 6658.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </text></part><text><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><part id="ID_1438411033030_009" name="PII" temporalId="sch0_PII" class="no_header"><num value="II"><inline>Part
                    II</inline></num><heading><inline>Property
                    Hitherto
                    Held
                    for The Hong Kong Chinese District of
                    The
                    Methodist Church (United
                    Kingdom)
                    (“Tsun
                    To
                    Kung
                    Wool”)
                    by:—</inline></heading><section class="no_header" id="ID_1506326735186_003" name="sA" temporalId="sch0_PII_sA"><num value="A"><inline>(A)</inline></num><leadIn>“Methodist Missionary Trust
                        Association”<b class="font_size_14"></b></leadIn><continued>which
                    has also been described and known as<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued><continued>“The
                    Methodist Missionary Trust Association” and<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued><continued>“Methodist Trust
                        Association”<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued></section><text>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="446" class="repeat_header">
                    
                    <col width="10%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="58%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="32%"></col>
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Item<br></br>No.</span></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Descriptions of
                                    Property</span></th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_10 valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Crown Lease/Conditions of Grant/New Grant</span></th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_15"></th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>1.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO.
                                6090<br></br>(Gascoigne Road, Kowloon).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 2nd day of April 1970.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO.
                                7068<br></br>(Gascoigne Road, Kowloon).</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Grant No. 5668.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>3.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">THE REMAINING PORTION
                                OF INLAND LOT NO. 7724<br></br>(North Point).</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Grant No. 6819.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>4.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO.
                                9606<br></br>(Junction
                                of Sheung Shing Street
                                
                                and
                                Sheung Lok Street, Ho Man Tin, Kowloon).</td>
                            <td>Conditions of Grant No. 9400.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>5.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT one equal
                                undivided forty-seventh part or share of and in ALL THOSE pieces or
                                parcels of ground situate at Kowloon, Hong Kong and registered
                                respectively in the Land Office as KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER THREE
                                THOUSAND FOUR HUNDRED AND SIX, KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER THREE
                                THOUSAND FOUR HUNDRED AND SEVEN, KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER THREE
                                THOUSAND FOUR HUNDRED AND EIGHT and KOWLOON INLAND LOT NUMBER THREE
                                THOUSAND FOUR HUNDRED AND NINE And of and in all messuages erections
                                and buildings thereon Nos. 588, 586, 584 and 582 Shanghai Street
                                Together with the exclusive right to the use occupation enjoyment
                                rents and profits of the THIRD FLOOR of the said building No. 588
                                Shanghai Street.</td>
                            <td>Three several Crown Leases all dated the 17th day of July 1934 in
                                respect of Kowloon Inland Lots Nos. 3406, 3407 and 3408. Another
                                Crown Lease dated the 13th day of July 1934 in respect of Kowloon
                                Inland lot No. 3409.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>6.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">ALL THAT one equal
                                undivided 63rd part or share of and in ALL THOSE pieces or parcels
                                of ground registered in the Land Office respectively as THE
                                REMAINING PORTION OF SECTION B OF KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 1698 and
                                THE REMAINING PORTION OF KOWLOON INLAND LOT NO. 1698 And of and in
                                the messuages erections and buildings thereon known as KA SING
                                BUILDING (Nos. 61, 63, 63A, 65 and 67 Shanghai Street and 1A Min
                                Street) TOGETHER with the full and exclusive right to the use
                                occupation and enjoyment of ALL THAT the EIGHTH FLOOR of the said
                                No. 63 SHANGHAI STREET (which said Floor is more particularly shown
                                and delineated on the floor Plan annexed to an Indenture of
                                Assignment dated the 1st day of February 1972 and registered in the
                                Land Office by Memorial No. 871294 and thereon coloured Pink).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 22nd day of January 1931.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>7.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">RURAL BUILDING LOT NO.
                                542<br></br>(No. 51 Barker Road).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 4th day of June 1969.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>8.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">LANTAO PEAK LOT NO.
                                26<br></br>(Lantao Peak) (Tai Tung Shan or Mui Wo Peak).</td>
                            <td>New Grant No. 1831 (C.S.O. 42/4126/1933).</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </text><section class="no_header" id="ID_1506326735186_004" name="sA" temporalId="sch0_PII_sA"><num value="A"><inline class="not_bold">(B)<b class="font_size_14"></b></inline></num><leadIn>“The
                    Wesleyan Methodist Missionary Trust Association”<b class="font_size_14"></b></leadIn><continued>which
                    has also been described and known as “The Wesleyan Methodist Trust
                        Association”<b class="font_size_14"></b></continued></section><text>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="446" class="repeat_header">
                    
                    <col width="10%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="58%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="32%"></col>
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Item<br></br>No.</span></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Descriptions of
                                    Property</span></th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_10 valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Crown Lease</span></th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_15"></th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>1.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">INLAND LOT NO.
                                3775<br></br>(at the JUNCTIONS of Hennessy Road Fenwick Street and
                                Johnston Road, Victoria).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 16th day of February 1937.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">CHEUNG CHAU INLAND LOT
                                NO. 34.</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 25th day of January 1921.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </text></part><part id="ID_1438411033046_017" name="PIII" temporalId="sch0_PIII" class="no_header"><num value="III"><inline>Part
                    III</inline></num><heading><inline>Property
                    Hitherto
                    Held
                    for The Hong Kong English District of The Methodist Church, United Kingdom (also
                    known as English Speaking Methodist Church) by:—<br></br>The Wesleyan Methodist
                    Missionary Trust Association<br></br>until 23 December 1983 and the Corporation
                    until 1 September
                    1988</inline><inline class="not_bold"></inline></heading><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/7">7 of 1997 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><text>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="446" class="repeat_header">
                    
                    <col width="10%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="58%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="32%"></col>
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Item<br></br>No.</span></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Description
                                    of Property</span></th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_10 valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Crown Lease</span></th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_15"></th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>1.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">THE REMAINING PORTION
                                OF INLAND LOT NO. 1316<br></br>(No. 271 Queen’s Road East, Hong
                                Kong).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 17th day of March 1893.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </text></part><part id="ID_1438411033046_081" name="PIV" temporalId="sch0_PIV" class="no_header"><num value="IV"><inline>Part
                    IV</inline></num><heading><inline>Property
                    Hitherto
                    Held
                    for The Methodist Church (United Kingdom) by:—<br></br>The Wesleyan Methodist
                    Missionary Trust
                    Association</inline></heading><text>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="446" class="repeat_header">
                    
                    <col width="10%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="58%"></col>
                    
                    <col width="32%"></col>
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Item<br></br>No.</span></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Description
                                    of Property</span></th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_10 valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Crown Lease</span></th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th class="valign_bottom"></th>
                            <th class="valign_bottom">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </th>
                            <th class="cellpadding_right_15"></th>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>1.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">INLAND LOT NO.
                                2616<br></br>(Johnston Road).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 19th day of June 1930.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">
                                <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2.</td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_10">INLAND LOT NO.
                                3646<br></br>(Anton Street, Hong Kong).</td>
                            <td>Crown Lease dated the 15th day of April 1937.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </text></part></schedule></main></ordinance>