<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1181</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1181</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1181!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-01-27</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402638362_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-01-27">
            <content>An Ordinance to continue the body corporate called The Executive Committee of
                The Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Hospital as a body corporate under the corporate
                name of the Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Charity Foundation (雅麗氏何妙齡那打素慈善基金會), to
                provide for the constitution, powers, duties, work and activities of the Alice Ho
                Miu Ling Nethersole Charity Foundation (雅麗氏何妙齡那打素慈善基金會), and to repeal the Alice Ho
                Miu Ling Nethersole Hospital Incorporation
                Ordinance.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[23 May 2008]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of
                        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><section id="ID_1438402638378_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Charity Foundation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402638378_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Purposes</heading><leadIn>The purposes of this Ordinance are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411110671_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to continue in existence as a body corporate The Executive Committee of The Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Hospital under the corporate name of the Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Charity Foundation (雅麗氏何妙齡那打素慈善基金會); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110687_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to provide for the constitution and functions of the Foundation.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402638409_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="BoardOfGovernors"><term>Board
                of
            Governors</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">董事局</term>) means the Board of Governors of the
            Foundation provided for and referred to in <ref>section 7</ref>;</def><def name="Chairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the person holding the office of
            Chairman of the Board of Governors for the time being;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the articles of constitution of the
            Foundation referred to in <ref>section 5</ref>;</def><def name="Foundation"><term>Foundation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">基金會</term>) means the Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole
            Charity Foundation (雅麗氏何妙齡那打素慈善基金會) referred to in <ref>section 4</ref>;</def><def name="Functions"><term>functions</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">職能</term>) includes powers, duties, work and
            activities;</def><def name="Governor"><term>governor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">董事</term>), subject to <ref>section 7(2)</ref>, means a
            governor of the Board of Governors for the time being appointed in accordance with the
            constitution;</def><def name="HonoraryTreasurer"><term>Honorary
                Treasurer</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">義務司庫</term>), subject to <ref>section 7(2)</ref>, means
            the Honorary Treasurer of the Board of Governors for the time being appointed in
            accordance with the constitution;</def><def name="RepealedOrdinance"><term>repealed
                Ordinance</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已廢除條例</term>) means the Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole
            Hospital Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1072">Cap. 1072</ref>) repealed
            under <ref>section 12</ref>;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of
            2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TheExecutiveCommittee"><term>The Executive Committee</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">執行委員會</term>) means The Executive Committee of The Alice Ho
            Miu Ling Nethersole Hospital incorporated under the repealed Ordinance.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of
            2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402638424_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Incorporation of Foundation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411110749_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The body corporate incorporated under <ref>section 3</ref> of the repealed Ordinance as The Executive Committee of The Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Hospital is preserved and continues in existence as a body corporate under the corporate name of the Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Charity Foundation (雅麗氏何妙齡那打素慈善基金會).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110749_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporate identity and the rights and obligations of the body corporate referred to in subsection (1) are not affected by the repeal by this Ordinance of the repealed Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110749_020" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Foundation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411110749_028" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has perpetual succession under its corporate name;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110749_036" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has and may use a common seal; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110749_044" name="c" temporalId="s4_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>is capable of suing and being sued in its corporate name.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402638424_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Constitution of Foundation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411110781_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The constitution of the Foundation shall be such as the Board of Governors may
                adopt after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110781_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The constitution may from time to time be amended in accordance with the
                constitution for the time being in force.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1659603159652_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 23 May
                2008.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402638440_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Members of Foundation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411110796_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall be members of the Foundation consisting of such class or classes as shall be provided in the constitution for the time being in force.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110796_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Board of Governors may from time to time admit any persons to be the members of the Foundation subject to and in accordance with the constitution for the time being in force.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402638440_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Board of Governors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411110812_019" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>There shall be a Board of Governors of the Foundation consisting of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411110812_027" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>such number of governors as not exceeding the maximum number of governors
                    provided in the constitution for the time being in force; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110812_035" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an Honorary Treasurer.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110812_042" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The members and the Honorary Treasurer of The Executive Committee immediately
                before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance shall be the first governors and the first Honorary Treasurer who
                shall hold the offices as respectively held by them in The Executive Committee
                immediately before the commencement of this Ordinance but otherwise subject to and
                in accordance with the constitution of the Foundation adopted by the Board of
                Governors in pursuance of the provisions of <ref>section 5(1)</ref>.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1659603230079_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 23 May
                2008.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402638456_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Powers of Foundation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411110843_027" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Foundation shall have power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411110843_035" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>to operate, manage and supervise the operation and management of non-profit-making hospitals, clinics, medical institutions, community health centres, social services centres and homes for aged people and dementia for—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411110843_043" name="i" temporalId="s8_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the care, treatment and comfort (whether physically, psychologically or spiritually) of those who are weak, sick or aged or are in need of assistance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411110859_007" name="ii" temporalId="s8_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the promotion of, and the education of the community in, the awareness of health care and prevention of diseases;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411110859_015" name="iii" temporalId="s8_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the training of doctors, nurses, midwives and other allied health staff;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411110859_023" name="iv" temporalId="s8_1_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>the promotion and the practice of the teachings of Jesus Christ in the service of people in need; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411110859_031" name="v" temporalId="s8_1_a_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the demonstration of the Christian belief in the wholeness of man, his body and spirit; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110859_038" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to operate, manage and supervise the operation and management of non-profit-making child care centres, play centres, nurseries and kindergartens for the care and education of young children.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110859_045" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Foundation shall also have power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411110859_053" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate, and also to invest moneys upon any lands, buildings and any debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, corporation or company and also upon mortgage of any lands and buildings, and also to purchase and acquire all goods and chattels of what nature or kind soever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110874_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares, securities, goods and chattels vested in the Foundation on such terms as the Foundation may seem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110874_014" name="c" temporalId="s8_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to accept grants, donations and subsidies as the Board of Governors may consider expedient and to make grants, donations and subsidies to such charities and charitable institutions or purposes on such terms and conditions as the Board of Governors may consider expedient; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411110890_006" name="d" temporalId="s8_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to conduct any businesses, matters or things for the furtherance of or incidental to the fulfilment of its objects as set out in the constitution.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110890_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (1) and (2), the powers conferred by those subsections shall only be exercised for the purpose of endowing, supporting, maintaining, carrying on or otherwise promoting the work of the Foundation as specified in the constitution.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402638456_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Seal</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the Foundation shall be sealed with its common seal in the presence of 2 governors and shall also be signed by them and such signing shall be taken as sufficient prima facie evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402638471_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Internal management</heading><content>All matters of internal management of the Foundation including any amendment of the constitution shall be settled and carried out in accordance with the constitution for the time being in force.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402638502_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Properties</heading><content>All properties of and vested in The Executive Committee shall be vested in the
            Foundation as from the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1659603432146_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 23 May
                2008.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402638502_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-24" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Repeal</heading><content>The Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Hospital Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1072">Cap. 1072</ref>) is repealed.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402638518_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411110983_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to any vested or contingent gift or disposition, made
                either before or after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, by will, deed, testamentary disposition, or in any other manner
                for the benefit of The Executive Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411110983_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A gift or disposition to which this section applies is to be construed for all
                purposes after the commencement of this Ordinance as if the gift or disposition were
                expressed to be for the benefit of the Foundation, and a receipt given by the
                Chairman or the Honorary Treasurer on behalf of the Foundation shall be a sufficient
                discharge to any person making a payment or otherwise acting in respect of such a
                gift or disposition in accordance with this subsection.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1659603501334_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 23 May
                2008.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402638518_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2008-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of any other person except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by, from or under them.</content></section></main></ordinance>