<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1164</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1164</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1164!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-02-16</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402624525_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-02-16">
      <content>An Ordinance
        to
        make provision for the incorporation of Hong Kong St. John Ambulance and for matters
        incidental thereto or connected
        therewith.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
    </longTitle><commencementNote>[27 June 1997]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2023/er1">E.R. 1 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><preamble id="ID_1438402624540_001" name="preamble" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="preamble" startPeriod="2023-02-16"><heading>Preamble</heading><recital>WHEREAS—<paragraph id="ID_1438411077428_013" name="a" temporalId="preamble_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the St. John Ambulance Association is a foundation of an Order formerly
                    designated the Grand Priory of the Order of the Hospital of St. John of
                    Jerusalem in England (hereinafter referred to as the <b><i>Order</i></b>) which
                    was duly incorporated by a Charter granted on 14 May 1888, by Her Late Majesty
                    Queen Victoria, and now designated the Grand Priory in the British Realm of the
                    Venerable Order of the Hospital of St. John of Jerusalem by virtue of a Charter
                    granted on 12 June 1926, by His Late Majesty King George V;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077443_007" name="b" temporalId="preamble_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the Order since its incorporation has had 3 foundations, to wit—</leadIn><continued class="left_indent_96">The St. John Ophthalmic Hospital at
                    Jerusalem;</continued><continued class="left_indent_96">The St. John Ambulance Association;
                    and</continued><continued class="left_indent_96">The St. John Ambulance Brigade;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077443_035" name="c" temporalId="preamble_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the year 1884 a Branch of the said St. John Ambulance Association was
                    established in Hong Kong (hereinafter referred to as the
                    <b><i>Branch</i></b>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077443_043" name="d" temporalId="preamble_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in the year 1916 a District of the St. John Ambulance Brigade was
                    established in Hong Kong (hereinafter referred to as the
                    <b><i>District</i></b>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077443_051" name="e" temporalId="preamble_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>in the year 1949 a Council of the Order was established in Hong Kong
                    (hereinafter referred to as the <b><i>old Council</i></b>) charged with the
                    governance of the activities of the Order in Hong Kong in accordance with the
                    commands and regulations given by the Chapter-General of the Order from time to
                    time;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077459_007" name="f" temporalId="preamble_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>it is now considered desirable that the old Council, the Branch and the
                    District should be fully merged and from the commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance be incorporated and
                    exist as one single entity and be managed in accordance with the provisions of
                    this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077459_015" name="g" temporalId="preamble_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>in view of the change of sovereignty in 1997 as provided by the
                    Sino-British Joint Declaration on the question of Hong Kong, it is also
                    considered desirable that the old Council, the Branch and the District should
                    exist as an independent corporation in Hong Kong as from the commencement of
                    this Ordinance.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph></recital><enactingFormula>
            
            
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2023/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula></preamble><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1675062191003_002">
        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
        <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 27 June
            1997.</content>
    </editorialNote><part id="ID_1438402624540_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438402624556_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong St. John Ambulance Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624572_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Association"><term>Association</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">救傷會</term>) means the St. John Ambulance Association in
            Hong Kong which forms part of the Corporation;</def><def name="Brigade"><term>Brigade</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">救傷隊</term>) means the St. John Ambulance Brigade in
            Hong Kong including all ambulances, nursing, dental and cadet divisions of the Brigade
            in Hong Kong which forms part of the Corporation;</def><def name="Chairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the Chairman of the Council;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>Constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the Constitution of Hong Kong St. John
            Ambulance;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>Corporation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means the Hong Kong St. John Ambulance
            incorporated under <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="Council"><term>Council</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">理事會</term>) means the Council of the Corporation;</def><def name="Institution"><term>Institution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">前機構</term>) means the old Council, the Branch and the
            District referred to in the Preamble and which before the
                commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance were governed
            by, existed and carried on their activities pursuant to the provisions of the Order of
            St. John Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1047">Cap. 1047</ref>);</def><def name="President"><term>President</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會長</term>) means the President of the
            Corporation;</def><def name="Secretary"><term>Secretary</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">秘書</term>) means the Secretary of the Council;</def><def name="ViceChairmen"><term>Vice-Chairmen</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">副主席</term>) means the Vice-Chairmen of the
            Council.</def><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1663827405045_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 27 June
                1997.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402624572_003" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Hong
            Kong
            St.
            John
            Ambulance</heading><section id="ID_1438402624587_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><content>The old Council, the Branch and the District are hereby incorporated as a body corporate
            and shall have the corporate name of Hong Kong St. John Ambulance (香港聖約翰救護機構)
            (hereinafter referred to as the
                    <b><i>Corporation</i></b>),
            with the sole and exclusive right to use that name in Hong Kong, and by that name shall
            have perpetual succession, and shall and may sue and be sued in all courts, and shall
            and may have and use a common seal, and may from time to time break, change, alter and
            make anew the said seal as the Corporation may deem fit.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624587_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Objects of the Corporation</heading><leadIn>The objects of the Corporation are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411077615_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to continue, promote and encourage ambulance service in all its aspects;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077615_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to promote and encourage all works of humanity and charity for the relief of distress, suffering, sickness and danger without any distinction as to race, class or creed, and the extension of the principle and spirit of the Corporation embodied in its motto “FOR THE SERVICE OF MANKIND”;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077615_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to render aid to the sick, wounded, disabled, injured or suffering;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077615_036" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to promote, encourage and co-ordinate contacts and co-operation between the Corporation and other organizations with the same or similar aims and objects;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077615_044" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to send representatives to attend any meeting or conference regarding any matter or matters connected with any of the objects of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077615_052" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to organize and promote lectures and instruction courses to the general public in respect of matters related to nursing and first aid services and to issue certificates and testimonials therefor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077630_005" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to receive and accept donations, endowments, gifts of money, land, hereditaments, houses, buildings, stocks, shares, securities and other properties movable or immovable, real or personal, whatsoever and wheresoever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077630_013" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>to maintain fraternal relationship with the Order and its various Foundations and affiliated organizations worldwide;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077630_021" name="i" temporalId="s4_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>generally to do or pursue all such deeds, acts, matters or things that are helpful or incidental to the attainment of any one or more of the above objects.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402624618_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Powers of the Corporation</heading><leadIn>Subject to this Ordinance, the Council may on behalf of the Corporation do or pursue all such deeds, acts, matters or things as are necessary, incidental or conducive to the attainment or better carrying out of the objects of the Corporation, and, in particular, but without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing, may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411077662_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>acquire, accept lease of, purchase, take, hold or enjoy any property, lands, proprietory interests in land, buildings, messuages or tenements of whatsoever nature or kind and wheresoever situate, movable or immovable or demolish any buildings, messuages or tenements or develop, redevelop, sell, let, dispose of or otherwise deal with any such property as aforesaid on such terms as the Council may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077662_013" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>invest money in or upon mortgage, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation, company or person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077662_021" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>purchase, acquire and possess any ambulance or other vehicles, any medical and first aid equipment, medicine and other goods and chattels of whatsoever nature or kind;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077662_029" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>enter into any contract, agreement and memorandum of whatsoever nature or kind;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077677_006" name="e" temporalId="s5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>by deed under its seal grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer, or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities, ambulances or other goods and chattels which are for the time being vested in or belong to the Corporation upon such terms as the Corporation may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077677_014" name="f" temporalId="s5_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>borrow money, mortgage or charge property or assets of the Corporation or give undertakings on behalf of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077677_022" name="g" temporalId="s5_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>apply for and receive sponsorships, donations and gifts, whether on trust or otherwise, and act as trustee of monies or other property vested in the Corporation on trust;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077677_030" name="h" temporalId="s5_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>appoint and remove any employee of the Corporation and fix the amount of remuneration of such employee and auditors of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077693_006" name="i" temporalId="s5_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>utilize money and funds of the Corporation for any matter or matters relating to or in connection with any or all of the objects of the Corporation or which in the opinion of the Council is advisable in the general interest of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077693_014" name="j" temporalId="s5_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>do or pursue all other matters reasonably incidental or conducive to the furtherance of the Corporation’s objects.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402624634_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Vesting of property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411077724_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>At and from the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411077724_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all those pieces or parcels of land specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>
                    and all other property and assets which immediately prior to the commencement of
                    this Ordinance were vested in the Executive Officers of the old Council or the
                    Institution together with all rights, easements and appurtenances thereto shall
                    be vested in the Corporation and in respect of all those pieces or parcels of
                    land specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, the same shall be vested in the
                    Corporation for the unexpired residue of the respective terms of years created
                    by the Crown Leases, Conditions of Grant or other documents specified opposite
                    each such piece or parcel of land thereto and subject to the payment of rent and
                    the performance and observance of the covenants and conditions reserved by and
                    contained in the said Crown Leases, Conditions of Grant or other documents and
                    subject to such leases, tenancies, easements and other rights as may be
                    subsisting in relation to such lands upon the commencement of this
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077771_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all money and claims, liquidated and unliquidated, which immediately before
                    the commencement of this Ordinance were payable to or recoverable by the
                    Institution shall be money and claims payable to or recoverable by the
                    Corporation;<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077771_014" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all legal and court proceedings commenced before the commencement of this
                    Ordinance by or against the Institution and pending immediately before the
                    commencement of this Ordinance shall be deemed to be proceedings commenced by or
                    against the Corporation and the Corporation shall have the right to carry on the
                    conduct of such proceedings in the name of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077771_022" name="d" temporalId="s6_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>all contracts, agreements, arrangements and undertakings entered into with,
                    and all securities lawfully given to or by the Institution and in force
                    immediately before the commencement of this Ordinance shall be deemed to be
                    contracts, agreements, arrangements and undertakings entered into with, and
                    securities given to or by the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077786_006" name="e" temporalId="s6_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the Corporation may, in addition to pursuing any other remedies or
                    exercising any other powers that may be available to it, pursue the same
                    remedies for the recovery of money and claims referred to in this section and
                    for the prosecution of actions and proceedings so referred to as the Institution
                    might have done but for this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077786_014" name="f" temporalId="s6_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the Corporation may enforce and realize any security or charge existing
                    immediately before the commencement of this Ordinance in favour of the
                    Institution and may exercise any powers thereby conferred on the Institution as
                    if the security or charge were a security or charge in favour of the
                    Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077802_006" name="g" temporalId="s6_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>all debts, money and claims, liquidated and unliquidated, which immediately
                    before the commencement of this Ordinance were due or payable by, or recoverable
                    against the Institution shall be debts due, money payable by and claims
                    recoverable against the
                    Corporation.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411077802_013" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All property, investments and money vested in the Corporation shall be managed
                and controlled by the Council in accordance with the provisions of the
                Constitution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411077802_021" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438411077802_025" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>The production of a Government Printer’s copy of this Ordinance shall, for
                    all purposes, be conclusive evidence of the vesting and transfer of any property
                    and liabilities of the Institution in the Corporation in accordance with the
                    provisions of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077802_031" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of paragraph (a)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411077802_039" name="i" temporalId="s6_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any deed or other document made or executed on or after the
                        commencement of this Ordinance, whereby the Corporation or the Institution,
                        whether alone or jointly with any other person, conveys or transfers, or
                        purports to convey or transfer, to any person (whether for consideration or
                        not), or applies to be registered as the holder or proprietor of, any
                        property held by the Institution immediately before the commencement of this
                        Ordinance, whether alone or jointly with any other person, shall be
                        sufficient evidence that the interest of the Institution in that property is
                        deemed to be vested in the Corporation under this Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411077833_007" name="ii" temporalId="s6_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>where there is any other transaction or purported transaction by the
                        Institution or the Corporation on or after the commencement of this
                        Ordinance in connection with, or in relation to, any property or liabilities
                        which are the property or liabilities of the Institution immediately before
                        that commencement, it shall be deemed in favour of any other party to the
                        transaction, or any person claiming through or under him, that the
                        Corporation has full power and authority for that transaction as if the
                        property or liabilities were deemed to be vested in it under this
                        Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411077849_007" name="iii" temporalId="s6_3_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a certificate given by or on behalf of the Corporation at any time that
                        any property or liability specified in the certificate (which property or
                        liability immediately before the commencement of this Ordinance is the
                        property or liability of the Institution) is or, as the case may be, is not,
                        deemed to be vested in the Corporation under this Ordinance, shall be
                        conclusive evidence for all purposes of the fact so certified;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411077849_015" name="iv" temporalId="s6_3_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>in this paragraph
                            <term>convey</term>
                        includes mortgage, charge, lease, assent, vest by way of vesting declaration
                        or vesting instrument, disclaim, release or otherwise assure.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077849_022" name="c" temporalId="s6_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>The Corporation shall register or cause to be registered in the Land
                    Registry a Government Printer’s copy of this Ordinance in respect of the vesting
                    of the properties of the Institution in the
                    Corporation.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411077864_005" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The vesting in the Corporation of an interest in land by virtue of this
                Ordinance shall not—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411077864_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>constitute the acquisition, assignment, transfer or parting with possession
                    of that interest for the purposes of <ref>section 53(4)(a)</ref> or (7)(a) of
                    the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap.
                        7</ref>); or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2004/16">16 of 2004 s. 16</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077864_021" name="b" temporalId="s6_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>operate so as to merge any leasehold interest in the reversion expectant on
                    it; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077864_029" name="c" temporalId="s6_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>constitute an assignment, transfer, devolution, parting with possession,
                    dealing with or other disposition of that interest for the purposes of any
                    provision contained in any instrument concerning or affecting that interest;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077864_037" name="d" temporalId="s6_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>operate as a breach of covenant or condition against alienation;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077864_045" name="e" temporalId="s6_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>give rise to any forfeiture, damages or other right of action; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411077864_053" name="f" temporalId="s6_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>invalidate or discharge any contract or security.</content></paragraph></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1663827419519_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 27 June
                1997.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402624650_001" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Council</heading><section id="ID_1438402624650_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Council’s role and power</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411077942_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Council shall be the supreme governing body of the Corporation and is charged with the governance, management and control of all business and activities of the Corporation in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance and the Constitution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411077958_004" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The business of the Corporation shall be managed by the Council which may exercise all the powers and privileges vested in the Corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411077958_012" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance and the Constitution, the Council may, by resolution passed by a majority of votes at its meetings held from time to time, make, alter or repeal such regulations or rules of the Corporation, including regulations or rules of the Council, the Association and the Brigade in force from time to time, as it may at its discretion deem necessary or desirable for governing, regulating and monitoring the affairs and activities of the Corporation including but not limited to the appointment, removal or conduct of any or all of the members, officers and office-bearers of the Council, the Association or the Brigade.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438402624665_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>General
            Provisions</heading><section id="ID_1438402624681_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Amendment of the Constitution</heading><content>Subject to the terms and provisions of this Ordinance and the Constitution, the Council may from time to time amend the Constitution and any amendments made thereto shall be filed with the Registrar of Companies within the time limit set out in the Constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624696_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411078005_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All documents requiring the seal of the Corporation shall be sealed
                                with its common seal in the presence of the Chairman or one of the
                                Vice-Chairmen and shall be signed by either one of them and
                                countersigned by a member of the Council, and such signing shall be
                                prima facie evidence that the said seal was duly affixed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078020_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any document purporting to be executed in accordance with
                                subsection (1) shall, unless the contrary is proved, be deemed to
                                have been duly executed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078020_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438411078020_017" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>All books and other documents which would, before the
                                                commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>
                                        of this Ordinance, have been evidence in respect of any
                                        matter for or against the Institution shall be admissible in
                                        evidence in respect of the same matter for or against the
                                        Corporation.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411078020_023" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="Documents">In this section
                                                <term>documents</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">文件</term>) has the same
                                        meaning as in <ref>section 46</ref> of the Evidence
                                        Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap. 8</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/2">2 of 1999 s.
                                                6</ref>)</sourceNote></def></paragraph></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1663827431445_001">
                        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
                        <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 27
                                June 1997.</content>
                </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402624696_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Service of documents on the Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411078052_036" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation shall at all times have a registered address on its letterhead for service of documents on the Corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078052_044" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of the registered address or any change thereof shall be filed with the Registrar of Companies.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402624712_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Awards in recognition of services</heading><content>In order to give recognition to any person who has made outstanding contribution to the work of the Corporation, the President or the Chairman may, on the recommendation of the Council, make an award to that person.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624728_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Distribution of badges, tokens, emblems and devices</heading><leadIn>No person, except with the authority of the Council shall distribute, sell or expose for sale—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411078083_019" name="a" temporalId="s12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any badge, token, emblem or device in whatsoever form or material specifically adopted for the use of the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411078083_027" name="b" temporalId="s12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any badge, token, emblem or device in whatsoever form or material containing the words “Hong Kong St. John Ambulance” or the Chinese characters “香港聖約翰救護機構” or “St. John Ambulance Association” or the Chinese characters “聖約翰救傷會” or “St. John Ambulance Brigade” or the Chinese characters “聖約翰救傷隊” or any similar token or emblem.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402624728_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Unauthorized possession of badges, tokens, emblems and devices</heading><leadIn>No person shall, except with the authority of the Council or with other lawful authority or reasonable excuse, have in his possession—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411078114_012" name="a" temporalId="s13_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any badge, token, emblem or device specifically adopted by the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade for use by the members thereof; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411078114_020" name="b" temporalId="s13_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any badge, token, emblem or device containing the words “Hong Kong St. John Ambulance” or the Chinese characters “香港聖約翰救護機構” or “St. John Ambulance Association” or the Chinese characters “聖約翰救傷會” or “St. John Ambulance Brigade” or the Chinese characters “聖約翰救傷隊”.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402624743_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Unauthorized possession of devices resembling badges</heading><leadIn>No person shall, without lawful authority or reasonable excuse, have in his possession—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411078130_027" name="a" temporalId="s14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any device which so closely resembles any badge, token, emblem or device specifically adopted by the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade for use by the members thereof as to lead to the belief that the device in question is such badge, token, emblem or device; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411078130_035" name="b" temporalId="s14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any badge, token, emblem or device containing any words or characters which so closely resemble any words or characters ordinarily used to describe any member of the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade as to be calculated to deceive or mislead members of the general public.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402624759_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Wrongful exercise of authority</heading><content>No member of the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade shall, by virtue of his wearing, carrying, bearing, possessing, showing and displaying any badge, token or emblem of the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade or otherwise, enforce or exercise authority or attempt to do so otherwise than in accordance with the authority given, delegated or conferred upon him by the provisions of the Constitution, regulations or rules of the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624774_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Unauthorized organizations</heading><content>No person shall form, or work in connection with, or be a member of any organization which without the authority of the Council, claims or purports to be Hong Kong St. John Ambulance, the Association or the Brigade or any organization (other than the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade) which uses the title “Hong Kong St. John Ambulance” or “香港聖約翰救護機構”, “St. John Ambulance Association” or “聖約翰救傷會” or “St. John Ambulance Brigade” or “聖約翰救傷隊” or any title in any language, with or without additional words or characters, which so closely resembles either the title of “Hong Kong St. John Ambulance” or “香港聖約翰救護機構”, “St. John Ambulance Association” or “聖約翰救傷會” or “St. John Ambulance Brigade” or “聖約翰救傷隊” as to be calculated to deceive or mislead members of the general public or any organization which, by the use of any such titles or otherwise, without due authority, purports or claims to be connected with the Corporation, the Association or the Brigade.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624790_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Uniform and equipment of the Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411078208_003" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All uniforms and equipment issued to members of the Branch, the District, the Association or the Brigade are deemed to be the property of the Corporation and every such member on resigning or being dismissed from the Association or the Brigade or otherwise ceasing to be a member thereof shall forthwith deliver up the uniform and equipment issued to him to the officer in charge of his division or section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078208_011" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All badges, emblems, insignia and equipment issued to officers of the Branch, the District, the Association or the Brigade are deemed to be the property of the Corporation and every officer upon resigning or being dismissed from the Association or the Brigade or otherwise ceasing to be an officer thereof shall forthwith deliver up to his superior officer all badges, emblems, insignia and equipment issued to him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078223_005" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person other than a member or officer of the Association or the Brigade shall wear or use any uniform or equipment of the Association or the Brigade.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402624790_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Offence and penalty</heading><content>Any person who contravenes the provisions of <ref>section 12</ref>, <ref>13</ref>, <ref>14</ref>, <ref>15</ref>, <ref>16</ref> or <ref>17</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine at level 3.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624806_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Members to be indemnified</heading><content>Every Council member, office-bearer and officer of the Corporation shall be indemnified by the Corporation against all loss, costs and liability for any act, deed or matter done for and on behalf of the Corporation for which he is sued in his personal name or capacity.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402624806_004" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other person except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402624821_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Transitional</heading><section id="ID_1438402624837_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Institution to be dissolved and transitional matters</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411078286_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Immediately before the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance, the
                Institution shall be deemed for all purposes to have been dissolved and subject to
                the provisions of this Ordinance, all rights, powers, privileges, duties,
                obligations, property, money and assets of whatsoever nature and description vested
                in, conferred upon or held by the Institution shall immediately be transferred to,
                vested in and conferred upon the Corporation or its duly authorized
                representatives.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078286_012" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who was, immediately before the commencement of this Ordinance, an
                employee of the Institution shall, on and from the day of the commencement of this
                Ordinance, be an employee of the Corporation with the same benefits and on the same
                terms and conditions as he may have enjoyed immediately before the commencement of
                this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078301_005" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>All members of the old Council and all office-bearers and officers of the
                Institution shall, on and from the day of the commencement of this Ordinance, become
                members of the Council, office-bearers and officers of the Corporation and, subject
                to the provisions of the Constitution, shall occupy the same ranks and positions and
                shall exercise the same rights, powers and privileges and shall have the same duties
                and obligations as each of them may have had or held immediately before the
                commencement of this Ordinance and shall for the avoidance of doubt be deemed to
                have been appointed by the Council on the date when each of them was first appointed
                by the old Council or the Institution but if such person had subsequently been
                reappointed by the old Council or the Institution, he shall be deemed to have been
                appointed by the Council on the date when he was last reappointed by the old Council
                or the Institution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078332_005" name="4" temporalId="s21_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The regulations and rules of the Branch and the District in force before the
                commencement of this Ordinance shall, to the extent that the same are not
                inconsistent with the provisions of this Ordinance and the Constitution, continue to
                be valid and binding on all members of the Association and the Brigade.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411078348_005" name="5" temporalId="s21_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Regulations of the old Council are repealed.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1663827442155_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 27 June
                1997.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402624852_001" name="s22" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="omitted" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2023/er1">E.R. 1 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438402624852_003" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-02-16" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1164/s6">s. 6</ref>]</note><heading>Lands Vested
            in
            the Institution
            prior
            to
            the
                Commencement<inline class="force_orig_font not_bold">*</inline>
            of
            this
            Ordinance</heading><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="repeat_header">
                
                <col width="7%"></col>
                
                <col width="60%"></col>
                
                <col width="5%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="28%"></col>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Property
                                descriptions<br></br> </center>
                        </td>
                        
                        <th></th>
                        
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Documents of
                                title</center>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">1.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_4 first_line_indent_0">2 Macdonnell Road, the
                            Remaining Portion of Inland Lot No. 7253</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">Crown Lease
                            dated
                            24 October 1968</p>
                        
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">2.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_4 first_line_indent_0">2 Tai Hang Road, the Remaining
                            Portion of Inland Lot No. 3687</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">Crown Lease
                            dated
                            19 November 1936</p>
                        
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">3.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_4 first_line_indent_0">104 Waterloo Road, Kowloon
                            Inland Lot No. 10974</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">Conditions of Grant No. 12001</p>
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">4.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_4 first_line_indent_0">Fanling Sheung Shui Town Lot
                            No. 111 </p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">New Grant No. 12450</p>
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">5.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_4 first_line_indent_0">Princess Margaret Road
                            Ambulance Depot</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">Crown Land Permit No.
                            KW
                            K0642</p>
                        
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">6.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_4 first_line_indent_0">St. John Hospital, Cheung Chau
                            Lot No. 789 and the Extension Thereto</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">New Grant No. 1793</p>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">New Grant No. 1982</p>
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">7.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_4 first_line_indent_0">St. John War Memorial at Wong
                            Nei Chong Gap Road</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_0">Licence dated 3 December 1992; Licence Agreement
                            No.
                            DLO/HW NH-0073</p>
                        
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1675058981635_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 27 June
                1997.</content>
        </editorialNote></schedule></main></ordinance>