<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1050</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1050</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1050!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-05-05</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402541798_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-05-05">
            <content>To incorporate trustees capable of holding property and empowered to administer
                two trust funds known as The Chater (Cathedral) Endowment Fund and The Chater (St.
                Andrew’s Church) Endowment Fund for the purpose of assisting in the maintenance of
                St. John’s Cathedral and St. Andrew’s Church in Hong Kong.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[27 June 1941]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><preamble id="ID_1438402541845_001" name="preamble" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="preamble" startPeriod="2022-05-05"><heading>Preamble</heading><recital>WHEREAS by two several Deeds of Trust dated the 24th day of April, 1920, and the
            29th day of April, 1925, made between the late Sir Catchick Paul Chater of the one part
            and trustees therein mentioned of the other part the said Sir Catchick Paul Chater
            created two funds each of the amount of $250,000.00 to be known as “The Chater
            (Cathedral) Endowment Fund” and “The Chater (St. Andrew’s Church) Endowment Fund”
            respectively which said funds he gave to the said trustees to be possessed by them upon
            trust to apply the income thereof in assisting in the maintenance of St. John’s
            Cathedral Church and St. Andrew’s Church in Hong Kong and augmenting the stipends of the
            Clergy for the time being holding the respective offices of Chaplain or Assistant
            Chaplain of the said Cathedral and Incumbent or Curate of the said
            Church:</recital><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><recital>AND WHEREAS it is deemed expedient that the said funds should be vested in an
            incorporated body which may administer the same for the purposes declared in the said
            two deeds of trust:</recital></preamble><section id="ID_1438402541845_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Chater (Cathedral and St. Andrew’s) Endowment Funds Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541860_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-05" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The trustees of The Chater (Cathedral) Endowment Fund and the trustees of The Chater
            (St. Andrew’s) Endowment Fund and their successors in office shall be a body corporate,
            hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name “The Trustees of the Chater
            (Cathedral and St. Andrew’s) Endowment Funds”, and by that name shall have perpetual
            succession and shall and may sue or be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may
            have and use a common seal and the said seal may break, change, alter and make anew as
            to the said corporation may seem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541891_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><content>The said corporation shall administer the funds and securities now respectively representing and hereafter so to represent The Chater (Cathedral) Endowment Fund and The Chater (St. Andrew’s Church) Endowment Fund in accordance with the provisions and directions that are contained regarding the same in two several deeds of trust dated the 24th day of April, 1920, made between the late Sir Catchick Paul Chater of the one part and Newton John Stabb and John Scott Harston of the other part and the 29th day of April, 1925, made between the said Sir Catchick Paul Chater of the one part and the said John Scott Harston and Arthur Howard Barlow of the other part and shall have the same powers and authorities over such funds and securities as are mentioned and contained in the said two deeds of trust.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541907_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-05" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Appointment of trustees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410818311_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the event of the death or retirement from the office of trustee of the
                Chater (Cathedral and St. Andrew’s) Endowment Funds of any trustee the survivor or
                remaining one of them shall have power by writing under his hand to appoint a
                successor to the office of a trustee of the Chater (Cathedral and St. Andrew’s)
                Endowment Funds in the place of the one so dying or retiring from that office and
                any person so appointed shall be deemed to be a trustee of the Chater (Cathedral and
                St. Andrew’s) Endowment Funds.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410818311_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>When any person is appointed to the office of a trustee of the Chater
                (Cathedral and St. Andrew’s) Endowment Funds such person shall within three weeks
                after his appointment or within such further time as may be allowed by the Chief
                Executive furnish to the Chief Executive satisfactory evidence of his
                appointment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410818327_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A notification in the Gazette under the hand of the Chief Secretary for
                Administration that such evidence has been furnished to the Chief Executive by such
                person shall be conclusive evidence of such appointment.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of
                        1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1966/13">13 of 1966 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541923_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the said corporation shall be sealed in the presence of the trustees for the time being of the said funds and signed by them and such signing shall be and be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing thereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541954_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-05" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>