<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" identifier="/hk/cap1183!en" xml:lang="en"><meta><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1183</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><docName>Cap. 1183</docName><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1183!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main><longTitle startPeriod="2025-05-22" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955313_001" name="longTitle" temporalId="longTitle">An Ordinance to make provision for the incorporation of the Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals and for related matters.</longTitle><commencementNote>[8 November 2024]</commencementNote><enactingFormula>
            
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2025/er1">E.R. 1 of
                        2025</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
            
            
        </enactingFormula><part startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955485_002" name="P1" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part 1</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955485_003" name="s1" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals Ordinance.</content></section><section startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955500_004" name="s2" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance—</leadIn><def name="Constitution"><term>Constitution</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution and bye-laws of the Institute referred to in <ref>section 10</ref> for the time being in force;</def><def name="GeneralCouncil"><term>General Council</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">理事會</term>) means the General Council of the Institute established under <ref>section 7</ref>;</def><def name="Institute"><term>Institute</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">學會</term>) means the “Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals” incorporated by <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="Member"><term>member</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會員</term>) means a person whose name is currently included in the Register;</def><def name="President"><term>President</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會長</term>) means the person referred to as President of the Institute in <ref>section 7</ref> and any person acting as President in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution;</def><def name="Register"><term>Register</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">名冊</term>) means the Register of members of the Institute kept in accordance with the Constitution;</def><def name="Secretary"><term>Secretary</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">秘書</term>) means the honorary secretary of the Institute appointed under the provisions of the Constitution;</def><def name="Year"><term>year</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">年度</term>) means the financial year of the Institute commencing and ending on such dates each year in accordance with the Constitution except that the period from the incorporation of the Institute to 31 March next thereafter is to be considered as a financial year.</def></section></part><part startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955610_005" name="P2" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part 2</num><heading>Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals</heading><section startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955610_006" name="s3" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation of Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals</heading><subsection id="ID_1731295955610_007" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals is to become a body corporate and is to be known as “Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals” which in that name is to have perpetual succession and is to be capable of suing and being sued and, subject to this Ordinance, of doing and suffering all such other acts and things as bodies corporate may lawfully do and suffer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955625_008" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Institute is to have a common seal which is not to be affixed except pursuant to a resolution of the General Council, and unless provided otherwise in the Constitution, in the presence of a member of the General Council and of the Secretary, or such other person appointed in his or her place by the General Council, each of whom is to sign his or her name.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955625_009" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any document purporting to be duly executed under the common seal of the Institute authenticated in accordance with subsection (2) is to be received in evidence and is, unless the contrary is proved, to be considered as a document so executed.</content></subsection></section><section startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955641_010" name="s4" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Objects of Institute</heading><leadIn>The objects of the Institute are, subject to this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1731295955641_011" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to promote, develop and maintain a qualification system for environmental professionals in Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955641_012" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to meet the current and future environmental expertise needs of Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955641_013" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to support the development of the environmental industry in Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955641_014" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to maintain a register as specified in <ref>section 9</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955641_015" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to promote continuous professional development of environmental professionals to meet the changing needs of the society and the environment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955657_016" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to facilitate the exchange of ideas, knowledge and information between environmental professionals on current and emerging environmental-related challenges and risks, technologies, regulations, policies and stakeholder expectations by means of meetings or publications;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955688_017" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to promote the advancement of environmental knowledge across different professional and industry sectors for the betterment of the environment of Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955688_018" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>to maintain the integrity and status of the environmental professionals and to represent them both to the public and to the Government;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955703_019" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>to provide links between industry and the local governmental bodies and other organizations to ensure that environmental professionals remain dynamic and relevant to both industry and the society; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955703_020" name="j" temporalId="s4_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>to do all such other things as are incidental or conducive to the attainment of the above objects as the General Council may consider appropriate.</content></paragraph></section><section startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955703_021" name="s5" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Powers of Institute</heading><leadIn>Subject to this Ordinance, the General Council may, on behalf of the Institute, do all such things as are necessary for, or incidental or conducive to the better carrying out of the objects of the Institute, and, in particular, but without prejudice to the generality of this Ordinance, may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1731295955719_022" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>acquire, take on lease, purchase, hold and enjoy any property and sell, let or otherwise dispose of any property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955719_023" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enter into any contract;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955719_024" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>provide appropriate amenities for members;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955719_025" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>employ staff;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955719_026" name="e" temporalId="s5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>provide residential accommodation for staff and visiting guests;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955735_027" name="f" temporalId="s5_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>provide or contribute to pensions for staff;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955735_028" name="g" temporalId="s5_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>act as trustee in relation to pension schemes and funds for scholarships and prizes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955735_029" name="h" temporalId="s5_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>borrow money in such manner and on such securities or terms as the General Council considers appropriate or expedient;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955735_030" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>apply for and receive any grant in aid for the functions of the Institute on such conditions as the General Council considers appropriate or expedient; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955735_031" name="j" temporalId="s5_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>invest the funds of the Institute in such manner and to such extent as the General Council considers appropriate or expedient.</content></paragraph></section><section startPeriod="2024-11-08" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955750_032" name="s6" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Vesting of property</heading><content>On the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance, the Institute is to succeed to all property, rights, privileges,
            obligations and liabilities of the unincorporated Hong Kong Institute of Qualified
            Environmental Professionals.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1731568993137_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 8 November
                2024.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955750_033" name="P3" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part 3</num><heading>General Council</heading><section startPeriod="2024-11-08" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955750_034" name="s7" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Establishment of General Council</heading><subsection id="ID_1731295955766_035" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There is established a General Council to be known as the “General Council of
                Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955766_036" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>At the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, the General Council is to consist of the persons holding the
                offices of President, Vice-President, Honorary Secretary and Honorary Treasurer of
                the unincorporated Hong Kong Institute of Qualified Environmental Professionals
                immediately before the commencement of this Ordinance, and all other persons who
                were members of the general council of the unincorporated Hong Kong Institute of
                Qualified Environmental Professionals immediately before the commencement of this
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955782_037" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The persons specified in subsection (2) are to hold office until the election
                of officers and members of the General Council at the first annual general meeting
                of the Institute or otherwise in accordance with the provisions of the
                Constitution.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1731569012969_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 8 November
                2024.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955782_038" name="s8" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Powers of General Council</heading><content>The management of the Institute is to be vested in the General Council and all the powers of the Institute are to be vested in and exercisable by the General Council except so far as this Ordinance or the Constitution otherwise requires.</content></section></part><part startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955797_039" name="P4" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part 4</num><heading>Membership and Constitution</heading><section startPeriod="2024-11-08" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955797_040" name="s9" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Membership</heading><leadIn>The members of the Institute are to be those persons whose names are included in the
            Register, being—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1731295955797_041" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all the members of the unincorporated Hong Kong Institute of Qualified
                Environmental Professionals at the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955813_042" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>other persons elected to membership in accordance with the
                Constitution.</content></paragraph><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1731569029582_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 8 November
                2024.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section startPeriod="2024-11-08" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955828_043" name="s10" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Existing constitution to become Constitution of Institute</heading><subsection id="ID_1731295955828_044" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The constitution and bye-laws of the unincorporated Hong Kong Institute of
                Qualified Environmental Professionals at the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance are to be adopted as the Constitution of the Institute.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955828_045" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Within 14 days after the commencement of this Ordinance, the President is to
                deliver to the Registrar of Companies for registration a copy of the Constitution
                adopted under subsection (1), certified by the President as being a true
                copy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955828_046" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Constitution may be amended by the Institute at any time in accordance with
                its provisions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955828_047" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>It is not necessary to publish the Constitution or any amendment of it in the
                Gazette.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1731569051777_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 8 November
                2024.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part startPeriod="2024-11-08T00:00:00" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955844_048" name="P5" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part 5</num><heading>General Provisions</heading><section startPeriod="2024-11-08" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955844_049" name="s11" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Particulars to be delivered to Registrar of Companies</heading><subsection id="ID_1731295955844_050" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Within 14 days after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, the President is to deliver to the Registrar of Companies for
                registration—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1731295955844_051" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the Institute;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955844_052" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a list containing the names and addresses of the members of the General
                    Council; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1731295955844_053" name="c" temporalId="s11_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the name and address of the Secretary.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955844_054" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Within 14 days after the Constitution has been amended at any time under
                    <ref>section 10</ref>, the President is to deliver to the Registrar of Companies
                for registration a copy of the Constitution as amended, certified by the President
                as being a true copy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955860_055" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Within 14 days following any change in any of the particulars required by
                subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref>, (b) or (c) to be delivered to the Registrar of
                Companies, the President is to deliver notice of change to the Registrar of
                Companies for registration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955860_056" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Not later than 6 months after the end of each year, a statement of income and
                expenditure during that year and of the assets and liabilities of the Institute on
                the last day of that year prepared in accordance with the Constitution, and the
                report of the auditors made under the Constitution are to be delivered by the
                President to the Registrar of Companies for registration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955860_057" name="5" temporalId="s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section on
                payment of such fees as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section
                    26</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for
                the inspection of a document under <ref>section 45(3)</ref> of that
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1731295955860_058" name="6" temporalId="s11_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Institute is to pay such fees for registering any document under this
                Ordinance as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section 26</ref>
                of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) as if the
                Institute were a company not having a share capital.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1731569065076_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 8 November
                2024.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section startPeriod="2024-11-08" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1731295955860_059" name="s12" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of any other person except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by, from or under them.</content></section></part></main></ordinance>