<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1084</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1084</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1084!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-08-10</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402560783_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-08-10">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Mother Superior of the Congregation of
                Our Lady of Charity of the Good Shepherd of Angers at Hong
                Kong.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[14 October 1955]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2023/er3">E.R. 3 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402560783_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Congregation of Our Lady of Charity of the Good Shepherd of Angers at Hong Kong Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402560799_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-08-10" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The Mother Superior of the Congregation of Our Lady of Charity of the Good Shepherd of
            Angers at Hong Kong shall be a corporation sole, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name of “The Mother Superior of the
            Congregation of Our Lady of Charity of the Good Shepherd of Angers at Hong Kong”, and by
            that name shall and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may
            have and use a common seal.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402560814_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Powers
            of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410853973_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take,
                hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind
                soever and wheresoever situate, and also to invest moneys upon mortgage of any
                lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, or upon the mortgages, debentures, stocks,
                funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation, or company
                and also to purchase, acquire and possess goods and chattels of what nature and kind
                soever and also to borrow or raise monies with or without security.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410853988_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation shall further have power by deed under its seal to grant, sell,
                convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise,
                reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, debentures, stocks,
                funds, shares or securities, or any goods and chattels whatsoever which are for the
                time being vested in or belonging to the corporation, upon such terms as to the
                corporation may seem fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402560830_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Property transferred to corporation to pass to successors</heading><content>The legal estate in any property whatsoever transferred to the corporation in any manner whatsoever shall in the event of the death of the Mother Superior of the Congregation of Our Lady of Charity of the Good Shepherd of Angers at Hong Kong for the time being or in the event of her ceasing to hold office as such Mother Superior pass to her successor in such office when appointed.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402560830_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><content>All deeds and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be sealed in the presence of the person who is for the time being Mother Superior of the Congregation of Our Lady of Charity of the Good Shepherd of Angers at Hong Kong or of her attorney duly authorized and such deeds and instruments and all other documents, instruments and writings requiring the signature of the corporation shall be signed by such Mother Superior or her attorney.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402560846_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Appointment of Mother Superior</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410854051_011" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Whenever any person is appointed to the office of Mother Superior of the
                Congregation of Our Lady of Charity of the Good Shepherd of Angers at Hong Kong such
                person shall within three weeks after her appointment or within such further time as
                may be allowed by the Chief Executive furnish to the Chief Executive satisfactory
                evidence of her appointment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410854051_019" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A notification in the Gazette under the hand of the Chief Secretary for
                Administration that such evidence has been furnished to the Chief Executive by such
                person shall be conclusive evidence of such appointment.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of
                        1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402560861_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>