<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1023 sub. leg. B</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1023B</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1023B!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-02-02</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402533140_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2023-02-02">Ocean
            Terminal (Parking and Waiting) By-laws</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap1023/s3">Cap. 1023, section
                3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[23 June 1972]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402533155_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These by-laws may be cited as the Ocean Terminal (Parking and Waiting) By-laws.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533155_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2023-02-02" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these by-laws, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="CarPark"><term>car
                park</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">停車場</term>) means the car park on the 62 feet and 72
            feet principal datum levels and the taxi quay at the 33 feet principal datum level of
            the Ocean Terminal being Kowloon Permanent Pier 83 and also means the ramps and
            entrances thereto;</def><def name="Driver"><term>driver</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">司機</term>) includes any person who is in charge of a
            vehicle;</def><def name="Fee"><term>fee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">費用</term>) means the sum payable to the company for the
            use of the car park;</def><def name="OceanTerminal"><term>Ocean
                Terminal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">海運大廈</term>) means that part of the company’s pier in
            Kowloon known as Kowloon Permanent Pier 83;</def><def name="OfficialOfTheCompany"><term>official
                of the
            company</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公司職員</term>) includes any person employed as a car park
            attendant at the car park;</def><def name="ParkingPermit"><term>parking
                permit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">泊車許可證</term>) means a ticket other than a pass issued
            to each driver who uses the car park;</def><def name="Pass"><term>pass</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">通行證</term>) means a monthly or quarterly pass issued in
            accordance with <ref>by-law 9(2)</ref>;</def><def name="Vehicle"><term>vehicle</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車輛</term>) means any mechanically propelled vehicle
            intended or adopted for the use on roads.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402533187_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Use of car park</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802898_025" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The driver of a vehicle in respect of which a pass has been issued shall, upon entering and leaving the car park and at any other time when requested to do so by an official of the company, produce the pass for inspection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802898_033" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any driver who proposes to use the car park otherwise than in accordance with a pass shall upon entering the car park obtain a parking permit in respect of his vehicle and shall at any time thereafter upon request by an official of the company produce such parking permit for inspection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802914_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>On leaving the car park a driver to whom a parking permit has been issued shall surrender such parking permit to an official of the company.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802914_013" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>No person shall park any vehicle or cause or permit any vehicle to wait on the
                taxi quay on the 33 feet principal datum level in contravention of any sign or lines
                erected or delineated at or on such taxi quay for the direction of vehicles or for
                the designation of the type or class of vehicle which may be parked on such taxi
                quay or any park
                thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802914_021" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>No vehicle shall be parked or allowed to wait in the car park for more than 7 days unless by prior agreement with the company.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533202_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2023-02-02" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Duties of drivers within car parks</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802945_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The driver of a vehicle who uses or proposes to use the car park and any person who enters or proposes to enter the park shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>obey all lawful directions given to him by an official of the company;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>obey all signs and signals within the car park which are applicable to him; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on demand made by an official of the company give his name and address to
                    such
                    official.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802945_035" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The driver of a vehicle who uses the car park shall not—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_043" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>sound any warning instrument therein except in an emergency;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_051" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>park the vehicle in such a manner that it protrudes over any line indicating the space in which the vehicle is to be parked;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_059" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>park the vehicle in any part of the car park other than within the lines indicating the space in which a vehicle is to be parked;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_067" name="d" temporalId="s4_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>park any vehicle in any space marked “reserved” unless he is expressly authorized to do so by the company; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802945_075" name="e" temporalId="s4_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>remove the vehicle from the car park unless the fee has been paid or a pass relating to the vehicle has been produced to an official of the company.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802961_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Paragraph
                    (2)(e)</ref>
                shall not apply to the drivers of vehicles using the taxi quay at the 33 feet
                principal datum level of the Ocean Terminal.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of
                2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802961_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>No driver shall park in the car park a vehicle which is, or is likely to be, in such condition as to be a danger to any person or other vehicle in the car park or which carries any goods or article likely to cause any such danger.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533202_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Duties of persons in the car park</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802992_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Upon parking a vehicle in the car park the driver and all passengers in the vehicle shall leave the car park as soon as practicable by the exits provided.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802992_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall remain in the car park after he has been lawfully ordered by an official of the company to leave.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802992_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If any person is in possession of a pass which is altered, defaced or otherwise mutilated, he shall immediately surrender it to an official of the company.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802992_028" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>No person shall smoke in any part of the car park.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802992_036" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>No person shall, without lawful authority, tamper with or interfere with a vehicle in the car park.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533218_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2023-02-02" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Loss of parking permit</heading><content>If a driver fails to produce a parking permit, the driver shall before removal of
            the vehicle from the car park pay a fee calculated from
            7 a.m. on
            the day on which the vehicle entered the car park.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533249_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Conduct and duties of attendants</heading><content>At 8 o’clock each morning an attendant on duty in the car park shall enter in a register, the registration mark of every motor vehicle in the car park at such time and, in the case of a motor vehicle exhibiting a valid pass, that fact, and shall date and sign such register and such register shall be retained at the car park for not less than 4 months from the date thereof and, in the calculation of any fees payable under these by-laws, such register completed and signed by an attendant shall be prima facie evidence that the motor vehicles whose registration marks are recorded in the register were in the car park at the date and time set forth on the register.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533265_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Removal and sale of vehicles upon contravention of by-laws</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410803039_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any vehicle appears to have been parked or allowed to wait in contravention of these by-laws, any official of the company may seize and remove the vehicle to any part of the car park or the company’s premises, or if it is not practicable so to remove it, to any other place of safety which the official of the company thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803054_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any vehicle removed under paragraph (1) may be detained by the company until—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803054_013" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>there is paid to the company a removal charge of 50 dollars and a storage charge calculated at the same rate as would be payable if the vehicle had been properly parked in the car park during the period for which it was left in the car park or detained under this paragraph; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803054_021" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the vehicle is released by order of a court.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803054_028" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a vehicle is detained under this by-law the company shall forthwith give notice in writing thereof to the owner, if he can be found, and if the vehicle is not claimed within 3 months after the date on which such notice is sent or, if notice cannot be given, after the date of detention, the company may sell the vehicle by public auction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803070_005" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The company may apply the proceeds of a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>sale under paragraph (3) in payment of any parking fees, removal fee, storage charges and other sums due to or expenses incurred by the company in respect of the vehicle, and shall pay the balance of the proceeds to the owner of the vehicle. If such owner cannot be found after the expiry of 12 months from the date of such sale any such balance shall become the property of the company.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533296_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Fees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410803101_043" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The fees payable for the use of the several parts of the car park shall be in accordance with notice prominently displayed by the company in respect of each part thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803117_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The company may, upon application by any person, issue a monthly or quarterly pass to such person upon such terms as the company may see fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533296_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Weight limit of vehicles entering the car park</heading><content>Save with the permission of an official of the company, no person shall drive into the car park a vehicle of a weight unladen exceeding 1 1/2 tons or a vehicle with a seating capacity for more than 7 persons.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533327_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Prohibition of entry</heading><leadIn>The company may by such signs prominently displayed at, in and outside the car park prohibit, as the company may from time to time think fit—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803132_019" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the entry of vehicles to the car park or any part thereof; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803132_027" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the entry of persons into the car park or any part thereof.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402533343_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Attendants</heading><content>Every person employed by the company as an attendant at the car park shall wear such uniform or badge as shall be sufficient to identify him to members of the public using the car park.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533343_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2023-02-02" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Offences</heading><content>Any person who contravenes any of the provisions of <ref>by-law 3</ref>,
                <ref>4</ref>, <ref>5</ref> or <ref>6</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall
            be liable on conviction to a fine
            at
            level 1.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>