<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1024</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1024</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1024!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402533358_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-09-29">
            <content>To incorporate the Hong Kong Tuberculosis, Chest and Heart Diseases
                Association.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1980/9">9 of 1980 s.
            2</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[3 February 1967]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><preamble id="ID_1438402533374_002" name="preamble" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="preamble" startPeriod="2022-09-29"><heading>Preamble</heading><recital class="first_line_indent_-36 left_indent_36">WHEREAS—<subsection id="ID_1438410803179_076" name="1" temporalId="preamble_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>the former Hong Kong Anti-Tuberculosis Association was incorporated by
                    Ordinance in 1948 with its main purpose to combat tuberculosis in Hong
                    Kong:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803195_005" name="2" temporalId="preamble_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>since that time many organizations throughout the world, also established
                    for the purpose of combating tuberculosis, have extended the scope of their
                    activities to include all diseases of the chest and heart:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803195_012" name="3" temporalId="preamble_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>the former Association being desirous of likewise extending the scope of
                    its activities and of making changes in its constitution:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803195_019" name="4" temporalId="preamble_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>it is considered expedient to make provision accordingly by
                    legislation:</content></subsection></recital></preamble><section id="ID_1438402533389_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Tuberculosis, Chest and Heart Diseases Association Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/9">9 of 1980 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533405_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Association"><term>Association</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">協會</term>) means the Hong Kong Tuberculosis, Chest and
            Heart Diseases Association incorporated under <ref>section 3</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/9">9 of 1980 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Board"><term>Board</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">董事會</term>) means the Board of Directors established
            under the Constitution;</def><def name="Chairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the Chairman of the Board;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>Constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會章</term>) means the Constitution of the Association
            for the time being in force, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance relating to any
            matter expressly dealt with in this Ordinance;</def><def name="FormerAssociation"><term>former
                Association</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">前防癆會</term>) means the Hong Kong Anti-Tuberculosis
            Association established under the repealed Hong Kong Anti-Tuberculosis Association
            Incorporation Ordinance<inline class="width_3"> </inline>(Cap.
            1024,
            1964 Ed.).</def></section><section id="ID_1438402533405_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-29" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation of Association</heading><text>The Hong Kong Tuberculosis, Chest and Heart Diseases Association shall be a body
            corporate and in that name shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be sued in
            all courts in Hong Kong and shall have, and may use, a common seal, and may from time to
            time break, change, alter and make anew the said seal as the Association may deem
            fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/9">9 of 1980 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41
                of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533436_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Objects of the Association</heading><leadIn>The objects of the Association are each and every of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803288_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to carry on and continue the work and activities hereto before carried on by the Association;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803288_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to promote, encourage, or undertake research and experimental work on the prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and any other aspects of the diseases and malfunctions of the chest, heart and lung, and to publish the findings of such work;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803288_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to establish and operate hospitals, clinics, or such other institutions and to provide rehabilitation and medical treatment for those suffering or have suffered from diseases or malfunctions of the chest, heart or lung;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803288_036" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>to provide medical, convalescent, or rehabiliatory services generally for the benefit of the community of Hong Kong, and in the following institutions—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410803288_044" name="i" temporalId="s4_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the Ruttonjee Hospital;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410803288_052" name="ii" temporalId="s4_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the Freni Memorial Convalescent Home;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410803304_007" name="iii" temporalId="s4_d_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the Grantham Hospital; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410803304_015" name="iv" temporalId="s4_d_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>any other hospitals, clinics, infirmaries or other establishments managed by the Association;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803304_022" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to establish, maintain, support, and operate hospitals, clinics, infirmaries, homes for the aged, convalescent centres or any other similar establishments;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803304_030" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to establish, maintain, conduct, or operate, and to assist, financially or otherwise, any other charitable activities or institutions with all or any of its objects similar to those of the Association;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803304_038" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to provide social and cultural services for the Hong Kong community;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803304_046" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>to promote the general welfare of the people of Hong Kong, and in particular, in the furtherance of health and the relief of distress and sickness;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803304_054" name="i" temporalId="s4_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to promote and extend the objects of the Association overseas; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803304_062" name="j" temporalId="s4_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>to establish and maintain affiliations with overseas organizations in the promotion and furtherance of the objects of the Association.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1988/43">43 of 1988 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533436_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Powers of the Association</heading><leadIn>The Association shall have power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803366_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire by purchase, lease or otherwise and to hold, possess and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, goods, chattels and other property of whatsoever nature or kind, and wheresoever situate;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/74">74 of 1974 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803366_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to build, rebuild, alter, vary, renew, maintain and repair any buildings, messuages or tenements and to effect any improvement thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803366_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank or upon mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, or upon the mortgage, debentures, debenture stocks, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation or company or such other investment as the Board may think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803382_006" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, pledge, demise, let, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture stocks, stocks, funds, shares, securities, vessels, goods, chattels, property and assets for the time being vested in or belonging to the Association upon such terms as the Association may think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803382_014" name="e" temporalId="s5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the Association may think fit, and, subject to <ref>section 4(17)</ref> of the Summary Offences Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap228">Cap. 228</ref>), to raise money by public or by private subscription;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803382_022" name="f" temporalId="s5_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to accept donations, grants or subsidies from any person or Government authority or other body or organization;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803398_006" name="g" temporalId="s5_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to establish, support and subscribe to provident funds, pension, retirement and similar schemes for the benefit of employees of the Association and their dependants and to grant and pay pensions or gratuities to and otherwise aid, support or assist any such persons;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1979/ln20">L.N. 20 of 1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803398_014" name="h" temporalId="s5_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>generally to do such other acts and things as are incidental or conducive to the objects of the Association as provided by this Ordinance and the Constitution.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402533452_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-29" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Vesting of property, etc. of former Association</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410803429_011" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The following properties, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803429_019" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all that piece or parcel of ground known and registered in the Land
                    Registry as Aberdeen Inland Lot No. 159;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803429_027" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all that piece or parcel of ground known and registered in the Land
                    Registry as Inland Lot No. 7206;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803429_035" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all that piece or parcel of ground known and registered in the Land
                    Registry as Inland Lot No. 7254,</content></paragraph><continued>together with all erections and buildings thereon and together with all
                rights, easements and appurtenances thereto belonging vested in the former
                Association shall from the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance be vested in the Association absolutely subject to and with the
                benefit of the respective Conditions of Grant under which the same are held from the
                    Government.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803429_048" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1980/9">9 of 1980 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803444_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>All debentures, stocks, funds, shares, securities, vessels, goods, chattels and
                other movable assets vested in or belonging to or held for or on behalf of or in
                trust for the former Association and all moneys subscribed for the purposes of the
                former Association and all investments of such moneys and all interest, income and
                profits arising from such investments and all securities therefor shall, at the
                commencement of this Ordinance, be transferred to, vest in, belong to or be held for
                or on behalf of or in trust for the Association.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803444_013" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>All contractual and other rights exercisable or enforceable by the former
                Association shall, at commencement of this Ordinance, be exercisable and enforceable
                by the Association in place of the former Association.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803460_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>On the commencement of this Ordinance, the Association shall become liable for
                all the debts and liabilities and for the performance of all the contractual and
                other obligations of the former Association.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1643079432235_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 3 February
                1967.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533467_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Membership of Association</heading><content>The Association shall consist of the persons who were ordinary or life members of the former Association under the constitution thereof referred to in <ref>section 8</ref> and of all such persons who shall continue to be members or who shall be admitted to membership of the Association in accordance with the Constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533483_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Constitution of Association</heading><content>The constitution of the former Association as approved and adopted at the Annual General Meeting of the former Association held on 28 October 1966 shall be deemed to be the Constitution of the Association but the same may be amended or replaced by the Association at any time or from time to time in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533483_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-29" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Registration with the Registrar of Companies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410803507_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Association shall forward to the Registrar of Companies for registration the
                following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803507_019" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the principal office of the Association and any
                    change thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803507_027" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the Constitution and any amendment thereto certified as correct
                    by the Chairman; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803522_006" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a list of the names, occupations and addresses of the members of the Board
                    and of the officers of the Association and any change therein, certified as
                    correct either by the Chairman alone or by any one other member of the Board and
                    the Secretary.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803522_013" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every document required to be registered in accordance with subsection (1)
                shall be forwarded to the Registrar within 28 days of the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance or within 28 days of any change or amendment, as the case may
                be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803522_021" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A fee of $5 shall be payable for registering any document under this
                section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803522_029" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section on
                payment of such fee as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section
                    26</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for
                the inspection of documents kept by the Registrar of Companies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of
                        2012 ss.
                        912
                        &amp;
                    920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803538_005" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The registration of the list mentioned in subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref> shall be
                conclusive evidence of the facts contained in such list.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1643354409312_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 3 February
                1967.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533499_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Sealing and signing of documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410803554_020" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the Association shall be sealed in the presence of 2 members of the Board and shall also be signed by those members and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing and execution of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410803569_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Board shall be responsible for the safe custody of the common seal of the Association.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533514_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-29" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>