<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1158</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1158</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1158!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-10-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402616179_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-05-19">
            <content>An Ordinance to continue the body corporate known as The Church Body of the
                Chinese Anglican Church in Hong Kong under the name of the Church Body of the Hong
                Kong Sheng Kung Hui, to provide for the constitution, powers and duties of the
                Church Body of the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui, and to repeal the Chinese Anglican
                Church Body Incorporation Ordinance.</content>
            <content>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[26 February 1999]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1999/ln55">L.N. 55 of 1999</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of
                        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><section id="ID_1438402616194_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438411062966_004" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Church Body of the Hong Kong
                    Sheng Kung Hui Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411062966_012" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616210_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Chancellor"><term>Chancellor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法律顧問</term>) means the Chancellor of the Province of
            the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui appointed under the Constitution and Canons;</def><def name="ChurchBody"><term>Church
                Body</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">管業委員會</term>) means the Church Body of the Hong Kong
            Sheng Kung Hui constituted under <ref>section 5</ref>;</def><def name="ConstitutionAndCanons"><term>Constitution
                and
            Canons</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">憲章及規則</term>) means the Constitution and Canons of the
            Province of the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui referred to in the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui
            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1157">Cap. 1157</ref>);</def><def name="ExecutiveCommittee"><term>Executive
                Committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">執行委員會</term>) means the Executive Committee of the
            Church Body provided for and referred to in <ref>section 7</ref>;</def><def name="FinancialYear"><term>financial
                year</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">財政年度</term>) means each period of 12 months ending on
            31 March;</def><def name="Functions"><term>functions</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">職能</term>) includes powers, duties, work and
            activities;</def><def name="GeneralSynod"><term>General
                Synod</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總議會</term>) means the General Synod of the Province of
            the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui;</def><def name="Province"><term>Province</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">教省</term>) means the Province of the Hong Kong Sheng
            Kung Hui established and constituted by the Constitution and Canons.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402616210_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Purposes</heading><leadIn>The purposes of this Ordinance are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411063013_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to continue in existence as a body corporate The Church Body of the Chinese Anglican Church in Hong Kong under the corporate name of the Church Body of the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui (香港聖公會管業委員會);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063013_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to provide for the constitution and functions of the Church Body; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063013_028" name="c" temporalId="s3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to enable property to be held by the Church Body.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402616226_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Incorporation of Church Body</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063029_041" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The body corporate established and constituted under <ref>sections 2</ref> and <ref>4</ref> of the Chinese Anglican Church Body Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1012">Cap. 1012</ref>) as The Church Body of the Chinese Anglican Church in Hong Kong is preserved and continues in existence as a body corporate for the purposes of this Ordinance under the corporate name of the Church Body of the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui (香港聖公會管業委員會).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063044_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporate identity and the rights and obligations of the body corporate referred to in subsection (1) are not affected by the repeal by this Ordinance of the Chinese Anglican Church Body Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1012">Cap. 1012</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063044_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Church Body—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411063044_021" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has perpetual succession under its corporate name;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063044_029" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has and may use a seal; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063044_037" name="c" temporalId="s4_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>is capable of suing and being sued in its corporate name.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616241_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Constitution of Church Body</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063076_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Church Body has the following members—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411063076_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Archbishop of the Province;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063076_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Chancellor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063076_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Archdeacon of each Diocese within the Province;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063076_036" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the General Secretary of the General Synod;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063076_044" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>6 persons elected by and as representatives of the General Synod; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063076_052" name="f" temporalId="s5_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>2 persons in respect of each Diocese within the Province, elected by and as representatives of the Synod of that Diocese.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063076_059" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Archbishop of the Province is the chairman of the Church Body and the Chancellor is the deputy chairman.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616241_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Powers of Church Body</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063091_073" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Church Body may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411063091_081" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>acquire, hold, grant any interest in, or any kind of licence in relation to, or otherwise dispose of, land, and acquire, hold or dispose of other property of any description;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063107_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>make contracts or other agreements;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063107_014" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>invest moneys on deposit with any bank, or upon mortgage of property in Hong Kong, or in debentures, stocks, funds, shares, or securities of any government, corporation or company, or in such other investment as the Executive Committee thinks proper;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063107_022" name="d" temporalId="s6_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>receive and expend moneys;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063107_030" name="e" temporalId="s6_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>employ such persons and engage or appoint such consultants, advisers, or agents as the Executive Committee considers necessary upon such terms and conditions as that Committee thinks appropriate;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063107_038" name="f" temporalId="s6_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>accept donations, grants or subsidies from any persons or government authority or other body or organization, and in particular accept any gift of property, whether subject to any special trust or not, for the benefit of the Church Body;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063122_006" name="g" temporalId="s6_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>undertake and execute any trusts which may seem directly or indirectly conducive to the carrying out of any of the purposes of the Church Body; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063122_014" name="h" temporalId="s6_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>subject to this Ordinance, do or suffer all such acts and things as bodies corporate may in general lawfully do or suffer.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063122_021" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Without affecting the generality of the powers in subsection (1), the Church Body has power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411063122_029" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>either alone or jointly with other persons, to improve, develop, redevelop and turn to account any land belonging to the Church Body or in which the Church Body has or may acquire a sufficient interest by reconstructing, altering and demolishing buildings and by constructing new buildings of any kind;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063122_037" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to obtain vacant possession by any lawful means of any land belonging to the Church Body or in which the Church Body has or may acquire a sufficient interest and of any buildings on such land;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063138_006" name="c" temporalId="s6_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to pay compensation to occupiers vacating any land or buildings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063138_014" name="d" temporalId="s6_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to borrow or raise or secure the payment of money in such manner as the Church Body thinks proper for the purpose of developing any land belonging to the Church Body or in which the Church Body has or may acquire a sufficient interest and for payment of compensation to occupiers for vacating any such land or any buildings on that land;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063138_022" name="e" temporalId="s6_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to lay out and prepare land for building purposes, to let land on building leases and to enter into building agreements, and for such purposes to apply to any tribunal or court or authority for any order, licence, permission, or exemption that may be required.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616257_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Executive Committee of Church Body</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063232_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The governing body responsible for the management of the affairs of the Church Body is the Executive Committee which shall, in accordance with the regulations, be constituted from amongst the constituent members of the Church Body.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063232_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Except as provided in the regulations, the Executive Committee may determine its own procedure.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616272_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Delegation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063247_019" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Executive Committee may by resolution delegate any of its functions, other than the power to delegate, to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411063263_005" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Chancellor; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063263_013" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any specified member or members of the Executive Committee.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063263_020" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Executive Committee has delegated a function under this section, the Executive Committee may give directions or provide guidelines to the delegate with respect to the exercise of that function.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063263_028" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A delegation under this section does not prevent the concurrent performance by the Executive Committee of the function delegated.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063263_036" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a person purports to act in accordance with a delegation under this section, that person is presumed, unless the contrary is shown, to be acting in accordance with the terms of the delegation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063278_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>An act or thing done by a delegate under a delegation under this section has the same force and effect as if it had been done by the Executive Committee.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616272_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Use of seal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063294_065" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The seal of the Church Body shall be affixed only with the authority of a resolution of the Executive Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063294_073" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The seal of the Church Body shall be authenticated by the signatures of the Chancellor and one other member of the Executive Committee, or, if the Chancellor is absent from Hong Kong or is otherwise unavailable to authenticate the seal, by the signatures of the General Secretary of the General Synod and any member of the Executive Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063310_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any deed, document or instrument purporting to be duly executed under the seal of the Church Body shall be received in evidence in any court and shall, unless the contrary is proved, be presumed to have been so executed.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616288_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Accounts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063325_027" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Executive Committee shall cause proper accounts and records to be kept of all the financial transactions of the Church Body and shall, as soon as practicable after the end of each financial year, cause a statement of the accounts of the Church Body to be prepared for that financial year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063325_035" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A statement of accounts prepared under subsection (1) must include an income and expenditure account and a balance sheet.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616304_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-01" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Audit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063341_033" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Executive Committee shall, as soon as practicable after the end of each
                financial year, submit the statement of the accounts prepared for that year as
                required by <ref>section 10</ref> to a certified public accountant (practising)
                (appointed for the purpose by the Executive Committee) for audit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063356_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The certified public accountant (practising) shall prepare a report on the
                accounts and send the report to the Executive Committee which shall, as soon as
                practicable, send a copy of the report and a copy of the statement of accounts to
                the Standing Committee of the General Synod.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1660875449858_001" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="CertifiedPublicAccountantpractising"><term>certified public accountant (practising)</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">執業會計師</term>) has the meaning given by <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the
                Accounting and Financial Reporting Council Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap588">Cap.
                    588</ref>).<inline class="width_3"></inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2022/ln66">L.N. 66 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2004/23">23 of 2004 s. 56</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402616304_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Evidentiary provision</heading><leadIn>A certificate under the signature of the Archbishop of the Province or, if the Archbishop is absent from Hong Kong or is otherwise not available to sign a certificate, under the signature of the Chancellor, that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411063388_005" name="a" temporalId="s12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the person named in the certificate is the Chancellor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063388_013" name="b" temporalId="s12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the persons named in the certificate are the persons constituting the Church Body or the persons constituting the Executive Committee; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411063388_021" name="c" temporalId="s12_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the regulations attached to the certificate are the regulations of, and properly made by, the General Synod under this Ordinance,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be accepted for all purposes as sufficient evidence of the facts stated in the certificate.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438402616319_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063403_018" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The General Synod may, by resolution passed by the majority of its constituent members, make regulations for the administration of the Church Body and the control of its expenditure, the management of its property of all kinds and the performance generally of the Church Body’s functions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063403_026" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The General Synod may, by resolution passed by the majority of its constituent members, amend or revoke any regulations made under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063403_034" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Regulations made by the General Synod under this section are to be held by the Chancellor and are to be available for inspection at reasonable times.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063419_005" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The regulations are not to be regarded as subsidiary legislation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402616350_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Repeal</heading><content>The Chinese Anglican Church Body Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1012">Cap. 1012</ref>) is repealed.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402616350_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-19" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411063450_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to any vested or contingent gift or disposition, made
                either before or after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, by will, deed, testamentary disposition, or in any other manner
                for the benefit of The Church Body of the Chinese Anglican Church in Hong
                Kong.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411063450_012" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A gift or disposition to which this section applies is to be construed for all
                purposes after the commencement of this Ordinance as if the gift were expressed to
                be for the benefit of the Church Body, and a receipt given by the Chancellor on
                behalf of the Church Body shall be a sufficient discharge to any person making a
                payment or otherwise acting in respect of such a gift or disposition in accordance
                with this subsection.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1646804610849_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 26 February
                1999.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402616366_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1999-02-26" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Savings</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>