<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1087</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1087</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1087!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-12-22</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402561376_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-22">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the members of the Society for the Relief
                of Disabled
                Children.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[2 March 1956]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402561392_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Society for the Relief of Disabled Children Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402561423_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Committee"><term>committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">委員會</term>) means the committee of The Society for the
            Relief of Disabled Children;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of The Society for
            the Relief of Disabled Children approved from time to time by its members for the time
            being.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402561423_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The members of the Society for the Relief of Disabled Children shall be a body
            corporate, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name “The Society for the Relief of
            Disabled Children”, and in that name shall have perpetual succession and shall and may
            sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may have and use a common seal,
            and may from time to time, break, change, alter and make anew the said seal as the
            corporation may deem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402561438_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><leadIn>The corporation shall have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410859714_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to establish, operate, manage or maintain such homes, clinics and other
                institutions for disabled children or for the curing and rehabilitating of disabled
                children as it may think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859714_027" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take or otherwise hold and enjoy any
                lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and
                wheresoever situate;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859714_035" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to acquire, by purchase or otherwise, goods and chattels of what nature or kind
                soever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859714_043" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong or elsewhere in the world
                or in any government bonds or on mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or
                tenements in Hong Kong or elsewhere in the world, or in or on debentures,
                debenture-stocks, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any corporation or company
                carrying on business in Hong Kong or of any foreign corporation carrying on business
                elsewhere in the world;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1973/46">46 of 1973 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41
                        of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859729_006" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, yield up, mortgage, demise, let,
                reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of, any lands, or buildings, messuages,
                tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture-stocks, funds, securities, vessels,
                goods and chattels for the time being vested in the corporation, upon such terms as
                the corporation may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859729_014" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to erect any buildings, messuages or tenements and effect any improvement
                thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859745_006" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the corporation shall think fit, and to
                raise money by public or private subscription; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859745_014" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>generally to do such other things as may appear to be incidental or conducive
                to the aims and objects of the corporation as provided by its constitution, or the
                purposes aforesaid or any of them.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402561454_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Members</heading><content>The corporation shall consist of such members as shall be provided by its constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402561454_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Existing constitution to become constitution of corporation</heading><content>The existing constitution of the unincorporated Society for the Relief of Disabled Children shall be the constitution of the corporation, but the same may be changed or amended at any time and from time to time in accordance with its provisions for the time being in force.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402561470_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Registration with Registrar of Companies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410859792_011" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The corporation shall forward to the Registrar of Companies for registration the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410859792_019" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the registered office of the corporation and any change thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859792_027" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the constitution and any amendment thereto, certified as correct by the chairman of the committee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859792_035" name="c" temporalId="s7_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a list of the names and addresses of the members of the committee, and any change therein, certified as correct by the chairman of the committee; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410859792_043" name="d" temporalId="s7_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the name and address of any person appointed under <ref>section 8</ref> to sign deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410859792_050" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notification in accordance with subsection (1) shall be made within twenty-eight days of any amendment or change, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410859807_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410859807_013" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A fee of five dollars shall be payable for registering any document under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410859807_021" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A fee of one dollar shall be payable for inspecting the documents filed with the Registrar of Companies under this Ordinance.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402561485_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Sealing of deeds</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be signed by the chairman and the secretary of the committee or by such other person or persons as the corporation shall from time to time appoint and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402561501_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>