<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1155</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1155</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1155!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-10-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402614728_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-10-13">
            <content>An Ordinance to provide for the deemed transfer to and vesting in The Christian
                and Missionary Alliance, a Colorado corporation, of all immovable property in Hong
                Kong of The Christian and Missionary Alliance, a New York corporation; and for other
                related purposes.</content>
            <content>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[5 May 1992]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><preamble id="ID_1438402614744_001" name="preamble" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="preamble" startPeriod="2022-10-13"><heading>Preamble</heading><recital class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">WHEREAS—<paragraph id="ID_1438411060486_045" name="a" temporalId="preamble_a" class="left_indent_60 first_line_indent_-24"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>The Christian and Missionary Alliance was prior to the merger hereinafter
                    mentioned a non-profit making religious corporation organized under the Laws of
                    the State of New York having its national office in New York, the United States
                    of America (hereinafter called
                            <b><i>CMA,
                            New
                    York</i></b>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060502_007" name="b" temporalId="preamble_b" class="left_indent_60 first_line_indent_-24"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in accordance with the relevant provisions in Colorado Revised Statutes,
                    Laws of the State of Colorado and effective from 5 May 1992, CMA, New York was
                    merged with a newly formed Colorado corporation, The Christian and Missionary
                    Alliance of Colorado (Colorado Non-profit Corporation) with the latter as the
                    survivor after the merger;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060502_015" name="c" temporalId="preamble_c" class="left_indent_60 first_line_indent_-24"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>simultaneously with the said merger the name of The Christian and
                    Missionary Alliance of Colorado (Colorado Non-profit Corporation) was changed to
                    The Christian and Missionary Alliance (hereinafter called
                            <b><i>CMA,
                            Colorado</i></b>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060502_023" name="d" temporalId="preamble_d" class="left_indent_60 first_line_indent_-24"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>prior to the said merger, CMA, New York was the registered owner of certain
                    immovable property in Hong Kong, whether as sole owner or as co-owner with
                    others; or otherwise had a beneficial interest in the same or holding the same
                    in a fiduciary capacity;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060502_031" name="e" temporalId="preamble_e" class="left_indent_60 first_line_indent_-24"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>it is expedient to deem the transfer to and vesting in CMA, Colorado of all
                    immovable property in Hong Kong of CMA, New York.</content></paragraph></recital><sourceNote class="left_indent_36 align_left">(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></preamble><section id="ID_1438402614775_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-13" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title and commencement</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411060533_004" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance may be cited as <shortTitle>The Christian and Missionary Alliance (Transfer of Hong Kong Immovable Property) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411060533_012" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This Ordinance shall have retrospective effect and shall be deemed to have come into operation and become effective for all purposes on 5 May 1992.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402614790_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411060548_019" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="CMAColorado"><term>CMA,
                    Colorado</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">科羅拉多宣道會</term>) means The Christian and Missionary
                Alliance, a non-profit corporation organized and existing under the Laws of the
                State of Colorado in the United States of America with its national office in
                Colorado;</def><def name="CMANewYork"><term>CMA,
                    New
                York</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">紐約宣道會</term>) means The Christian and Missionary
                Alliance, a non-profit corporation previously organized and existed under the Laws
                of the State of New York in the United States of America;</def><def name="EffectiveDay"><term>effective
                    day</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">生效日期</term>) means 5 May 1992;</def><def name="ImmovableProperty"><term>immovable
                    property</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">不動產</term>) means land in Hong Kong whether covered
                by water or not, any estate, right, interest or easement in or over such land
                (whether legal or equitable, present or future, actual or contingent), the whole or
                part of an undivided share in land and things attached to such land or permanently
                fastened to anything attached to such land and all liabilities, if any, pertaining
                thereto.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411060564_004" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any reference in this Ordinance to the immovable property of CMA, New York is a reference to the immovable property situated in Hong Kong to which CMA, New York was immediately prior to the said merger entitled (whether beneficially or in any fiduciary capacity) wherever in Hong Kong such immovable property is situated.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411060564_012" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any body politic or corporate and any other person or persons whose rights are affected by any of the provisions of this Ordinance shall be deemed to be mentioned herein.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402614806_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Recognition of transfer to and vesting in CMA, Colorado of immovable property of CMA, New York</heading><content>On the effective day, the immovable property of CMA, New York shall be deemed for the purpose of Hong Kong law to have been transferred to, and vested in, CMA, Colorado to the intent and effect that CMA, Colorado shall succeed to the immovable property of CMA, New York as if in all respects CMA, Colorado were the same person in law as CMA, New York.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402614822_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Trust property and wills</heading><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of <ref>section 3</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411060611_033" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any immovable property deemed to have been transferred to and vested in CMA, Colorado by virtue of this Ordinance which immediately before the effective day was held by CMA, New York, whether alone or jointly as co-owner with any other person or persons, as trustee or custodian trustee of any trust deed, settlement, covenant, agreement or will (whether originally so appointed or not, and whether appointed under hand or seal, or by order of any court), or as executor of the will, or administrator of the estate, of a deceased person or as judicial trustee appointed by order of any court, or in any other fiduciary capacity, shall, on and from the effective day, be held by CMA, Colorado alone or, as the case may be, jointly as co-owner with such other person or persons, in the same capacity upon the trusts, and with and subject to the powers, provisions and liabilities, applicable thereto respectively;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060658_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any existing instrument or order of any court under or by virtue of which any immovable property became vested in CMA, New York in any such fiduciary capacity as is referred to in paragraph (a) (including in the case of a will any grant of probate thereof), and any provision in such instrument or order, or any existing contract or arrangement, for the payment to, or retention by, CMA, New York of remuneration for its services in any such fiduciary capacity, shall, on and from the effective day, be construed and have effect, so far as the context permits, as if for any reference therein to CMA, New York there were substituted a reference to CMA, Colorado; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060673_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>no testamentary gift shall be adeemed by reason only of the operation of any of the provisions of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402614837_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Supplementary provisions</heading><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing provisions but subject to any provision of this Ordinance to the contrary effect, every contract or instrument relating to any of the immovable property to which CMA, New York is a party (whether in writing or not) shall have effect on and from the effective day as if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411060704_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>CMA, Colorado had been a party thereto instead of CMA, New York;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060704_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for any reference (however worded and whether express or implied) to CMA, New York there were substituted, as respects anything done or to be done on or after the effective day, a reference to CMA, Colorado; and;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060704_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any reference (however worded and whether express or implied) to the president or to any president, director, secretary, lawful attorney, officer or employee of CMA, New York was, as respects anything done or to be done on or after the effective day, a reference to the president of CMA, Colorado or, as the case may require, to such president, director, secretary, lawful attorney, officer or employee of CMA, Colorado as CMA, Colorado may appoint for that purpose or, in default of appointment, to the president, director, secretary, lawful attorney, officer or employee of CMA, Colorado who corresponds as nearly as may be to the first-mentioned president, director, secretary, lawful attorney, officer or employee.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402614853_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-13" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Evidence: title deeds and documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411060751_011" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All title deeds and other documents which would, before the effective day, have been evidence in respect of the immovable property or any part thereof for or against CMA, New York shall be admissible in evidence in respect of the same matter for or against CMA, Colorado.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411060751_019" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Documents">In this section
                    <term>documents</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">文件</term>) has the same meaning as in <ref>section
                    46</ref> of the Evidence Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap. 8</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/2">2 of 1999
                        s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402614868_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-13" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Evidence of vesting</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411060767_026" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The production of a Government Printer’s copy of this Ordinance shall, for all purposes, be conclusive evidence of the vesting of any of the immovable property of CMA, New York in CMA, Colorado in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411060782_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411060782_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any document made or executed on or after the effective day, whereby CMA, Colorado or CMA, New York, whether alone or jointly with any other person, conveys or transfers, or purports to convey or transfer, to any person (whether for consideration or not), or applies to be registered as the owner of, any of the immovable property held by CMA, New York immediately before the effective day, whether alone or jointly with any other person, shall be sufficient evidence that the interest of CMA, New York in that property is deemed to be vested in CMA, Colorado under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060798_006" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where there is any other transaction or purported transaction by CMA, Colorado or CMA, New York on or after the effective day in connection with, or in relation to any of the immovable property held by CMA, New York immediately before that day, it shall be deemed in favour of any other party to the transaction, or any person claiming through or under him, that CMA, Colorado has full power and authority for that transaction as if the relevant property or properties in question were deemed to be vested in it under this Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060814_006" name="c" temporalId="s7_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><def name="Convey">in this section
                        <term>convey</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">轉易</term>) includes assign, mortgage, charge,
                    lease, assent, vest by way of vesting declaration or vesting instrument,
                    disclaim, release or otherwise assure.</def></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402614868_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2004-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Interests in land</heading><leadIn>The deemed vesting in CMA, Colorado of an interest in immovable property by virtue of this Ordinance shall not—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411060829_027" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>constitute a purchase conveyance or creation of that interest for the purposes of <ref>section 4(1)</ref> or <ref>27(1)</ref> of the Stamp Duty Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap117">Cap. 117</ref>); or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2004/16">16 of 2004 s. 16</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060829_035" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>constitute an assignment, transfer, devolution, parting with possession, dealing with or other disposition of that interest for the purposes of any provision contained in any instrument concerning that interest; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060845_006" name="c" temporalId="s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>give rise to any forfeiture; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060845_014" name="d" temporalId="s8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>invalidate or discharge any contract or security; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411060845_022" name="e" temporalId="s8_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>operate so as to merge any leasehold interest in the reversion expectant on it.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402614884_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-13" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>