<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1055</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1055</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1055!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-08-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402542999_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-15">
            <content>To amend the law relating to the incorporation of the Zetland Hall
                Trustees.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[29 September 1922]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402543015_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Zetland Hall Trustees Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543030_001" name="s1A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1A"><num value="1A">1A.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Trustees"><term>trustees</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受託人</term>) means the Zetland Hall Trustees
            incorporated by <ref>section 2</ref>.</def><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543046_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Incorporation of trustees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410823241_025" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The persons who have been certified by the secretary of the Zetland Hall Trustees by statutory declaration made by him and filed with the Registrar of Companies on 21 April 1949, to be the elected representatives of the lodges specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> together with the persons who shall from time to time be certified in the same manner by the secretary of the Zetland Hall Trustees as being the elected representatives of other lodges, the names of which shall be from time to time added to those specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> in manner provided by subsection (2) and their successors in office as hereinafter defined shall be a body corporate and shall have the name “The Zetland Hall Trustees”, and by that name shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may have and use a common seal.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1949/20">20 of 1949 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823288_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In addition to the lodges specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> it shall be lawful for the trustees to invite any other lodge hereafter established in Hong Kong in accordance with the English, Scottish or Irish Constitutions to have its name added to those appearing in the <ref>Schedule</ref> and upon the acceptance of such invitation to nominate such lodge accordingly; and such nomination shall be made in writing under the hand of the chairman of the trustees and shall be filed with the Registrar of Companies. Notice of the addition of the name of any such lodge to the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall be given by the trustees in the Gazette within 14 days of the making of the nomination which shall thereupon take effect as if the name of the lodge so nominated had been included in the <ref>Schedule</ref> originally.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1949/20">20 of 1949 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823319_005" name="2A" temporalId="s2_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><content>Where any lodge specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> so requests in writing, the trustees shall, by notice published in the Gazette within 21 days of the receipt of such request, delete the name of the lodge from the <ref>Schedule</ref>; and shall forthwith notify the Registrar of Companies of such deletion.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823319_013" name="2B" temporalId="s2_2B"><num value="2B">(2B)</num><content>Where the name of a lodge is deleted from the <ref>Schedule</ref> under subsection (2B), the trustees shall repay to the lodge the sum of $5,000 if in the opinion of the trustees this can be done without undue detriment to the trustees.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823319_021" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The trustees shall have full power to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate in Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1949/20">20 of 1949 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823334_005" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The trustees shall also have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410823334_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>to invest their funds not immediately required in any—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410823334_021" name="i" temporalId="s2_4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>securities of
                        the
                        government of any place outside Hong
                        Kong;
                            or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 232</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410823334_029" name="ii" temporalId="s2_4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>investments listed for the time being in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> to the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823334_036" name="b" temporalId="s2_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by deed under their common seal to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender,
                    exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise
                    dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures,
                    stocks, funds, shares or securities, or other goods and chattels whatsoever,
                    which are for the time being vested in or belonging to the trustees;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62
                            of 1977 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s.
                            2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of
                        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823350_006" name="c" temporalId="s2_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold, and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages, or tenements in Hong Kong or elsewhere;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823350_014" name="d" temporalId="s2_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to accept mortgages of any lands, buildings, messuages, or tenements in Hong Kong or elsewhere;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823350_022" name="e" temporalId="s2_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong or elsewhere;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823350_030" name="f" temporalId="s2_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to purchase such stocks, funds, shares or other investments or property of whatever nature and wherever situated in addition but not limited to the purchase of stocks, funds, shares or other investments or property provided for the time being in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> to the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823350_038" name="g" temporalId="s2_4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to employ and pay for such professional or other staff or assistant as the trustees may deem requisite in the discharge of the duties of the trustees including assistance from a partner of a trustee or from a person who is a director or shareholder of a company which is a trustee,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>on such terms as the trustees may think fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823366_011" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823366_019" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The trustees shall also have full power to receive and accept gifts, donations, contributions and legacies and to hold or realize the same in their absolute discretion subject to any conditions attached to such gifts, donations, contributions or legacies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1955/47">47 of 1955 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543061_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Successors in office</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410823412_028" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If at any time any of the lodges specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> or whose names shall have been added thereto in manner hereinbefore provided shall wish to appoint a new representative in succession to or in substitution for the representative specified in the statutory declaration referred to in <ref>section 2</ref> it shall be lawful for the said lodge so to do and the said new representative shall be deemed to be a trustee in succession to or in substitution for the said former representative upon the filing with the Registrar of Companies of a certificate of the fact of such election certified under the hand of the secretary of the Zetland Hall Trustees.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1949/20">20 of 1949 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823444_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The power of electing a new representative shall apply in the case of persons elected under subsection (1) in the same way as it applies in the case of the persons specified in the statutory declarations referred to in <ref>section 2(1)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1939/33">33 of 1939</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1940/gn840">G.N. 840 of 1940</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402543077_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Use of property</heading><content>The trustees shall manage and maintain a hall or halls, to be used, occupied and enjoyed as a meeting place for the members of the lodges the names of which appear in the <ref>Schedule</ref> or which shall have been from time to time added thereto in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 2</ref>, and may permit the said hall or halls to be used, occupied and enjoyed as a meeting place for the members of other masonic lodges, chapters and bodies, and may at their discretion furnish and equip such hall or halls.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1949/20">20 of 1949 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543093_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Fees and rents for use of property</heading><content>The trustees may charge such fees, rents and charges for the use of the properties of the trustees as may seem expedient to the trustees.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543093_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Apportionment of surplus funds</heading><content>The trustees may from time to time give and pay over in equal shares to the lodges specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> together with other lodges whose names have from time to time been added to the <ref>Schedule</ref> in manner provided in <ref>section 2</ref> any funds not required for the purposes of the maintenance or development of the properties of the trustees.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1949/20">20 of 1949 s. 6</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543108_002" name="s6A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s6A"><num value="6A">6A.</num><heading>Distribution of assets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410823506_018" name="1" temporalId="s6A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If at any time the trustees are of the opinion that they can no longer serve any purpose for the benefit of freemasonry in Hong Kong and that such position is likely to remain unchanged in the then foreseeable future, the trustees shall convert into money such of their assets as they are able.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823506_026" name="2" temporalId="s6A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>After such conversion the trustees
                shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410823522_005" name="a" temporalId="s6A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>pay to each lodge then listed in the <ref>Schedule</ref> the sum of
                    HK$5,000; but if the funds of the trustees are insufficient for this purpose the
                    trustees shall pay the entire funds to the lodges in equal shares; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823522_013" name="b" temporalId="s6A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>divide any balance of the funds that may remain after such payments among
                    the English, Scottish and Irish Constitutions according to the proportion in
                    which those constitutions are represented by the lodges then listed in the
                        <ref>Schedule</ref> and pay the shares thus found to the respective District
                    Treasurers.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543124_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Meetings of trustees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410823537_041" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The secretary shall convene a general meeting of trustees during the month of May in each year at which the trustees shall elect from among their own number a chairman and a deputy chairman who shall hold office until the conclusion of the general meeting in the next succeeding year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823553_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Other meetings may be convened by the secretary or any trustee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823553_013" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Five trustees personally present shall be a quorum for the purposes of any meeting of the trustees.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823553_021" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The chairman of the trustees shall preside at any meeting of the trustees, but if the chairman is absent, any such meeting shall be presided over by—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410823553_029" name="a" temporalId="s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the deputy chairman; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823553_037" name="b" temporalId="s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the absence of the deputy chairman a trustee elected from among those present at the meeting.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823553_044" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>All questions arising at any meeting of the trustees shall be decided by the majority of votes cast and in the event of an equality of votes the chairman of the trustees or other person presiding shall have a casting as well as a deliberative vote.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823553_052" name="6" temporalId="s7_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content><leadIn>Not less than 14 days’ notice shall be given of any meeting and any trustee may, upon giving not less than 7 days’ written notice to the secretary, appoint a proxy to speak and vote for him at that meeting:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_6_proviso">Provided that such proxy shall have previously been generally or specifically approved in open lodge by the lodge by whom such trustee was appointed.</proviso></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543124_003" name="s7A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7A"><num value="7A">7A.</num><heading>Appointment of officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410823584_026" name="1" temporalId="s7A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The trustees shall from time to time appoint a secretary and a treasurer who shall fill their respective positions until a replacement has been appointed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823584_034" name="2" temporalId="s7A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>At the general meeting referred to in <ref>section 7(1)</ref> the treasurer shall present audited accounts in respect of the year ended on the previous 31 December.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543139_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410823600_026" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the trustees shall be sealed by one of the trustees and signed by not less than 3 of the trustees.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823600_034" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All documents which are required by law to be signed by the trustees shall be signed by 3 of the trustees.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543155_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Fees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410823615_033" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The trustees shall pay such fees for registering any document with any public
                registry as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section 26</ref> of
                the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for the registration
                with the Registrar of Companies of a document.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410823631_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section upon
                payment of such fee as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section
                    26</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for
                the inspection of a document.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1995/96">96 of 1995 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                912 &amp;
                920</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543171_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of
            the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic
            or corporate or of any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and
            those claiming by, from or under them.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2024/21">21 of 2024 s. 78</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402543171_003" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1055/s2">s.
                2</ref>]<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Zetland Lodge No. 525 E.
            C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Victoria Lodge No.
            1026 E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Perseverance
            Lodge No. 1165 E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">United Service Lodge No. 1341 E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Corinthian Lodge of Amoy No. 1806 E.
            C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Foo Chow Lodge No.
            1912 E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Lodge Star of
            Southern China No. 2013 E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">University Lodge No. 3666 E.
            C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Swatow Lodge No. 3705
            E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Cathay Lodge No.
            4373 E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Royal Sussex
            Lodge No. 501 E. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">St.
            Andrew in the Far East Lodge No. 493 S. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Lodge St. John No. 618 S.
            C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Naval and Military
            Lodge No. 848 S. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Eastern Scotia Lodge No. 923 S. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Erin Lodge No. 463 I. C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Shamrock Lodge No. 712 I.
            C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">Emerald Lodge No. 883
            I.
            C.</content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">Rotarian Lodge of Hong Kong No. 9378 E.
                C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">The Lodge of Lu Pan No. 9387 E.
                C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">St. Paul’s Lodge No. 9718 E.
                C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">Sino Lusitano Lodge of Macau No. 897 I.
                C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">Lodge St. David No. 903 I.
                C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">Baden Powell Lodge No. 929 I.
                C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">Hong Kong &amp; Far East District Grand
            Stewards Lodge No. 9879 E. C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">Club Lodge No. 9880 E. C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><content class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12">Harriers Lodge No. 9882 E.
                C.<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    233</ref>)</sourceNote></content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1977/62">62 of 1977 s. 9</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1983/gn3423">G.N.
                3423 of 1983</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>