<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1035</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1035</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1035!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-09-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402536431_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-09-08">
            <content>To provide for the holding of the property and funds now held by or vested in
                the trustees for the time being of the will and codicil of Granville Sharp,
                deceased, and the funds of the trustees of the War Memorial Nursing Home and for the
                administration of the said property and funds for maintaining, endowing, supporting,
                carrying on or otherwise promoting subject to the provisions of this Ordinance a
                hospital in substitution for the Matilda Hospital and the War Memorial Nursing Home
                as heretofore constituted and to be called the “Matilda and War Memorial
                Hospital”.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[7 October 1949]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><preamble id="ID_1438402536447_001" name="preamble" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="preamble" startPeriod="2022-09-08"><heading>Preamble</heading><recital class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">WHEREAS in pursuance of the Will and Codicil
            of Granville Sharp, deceased, hereinafter referred to as
                    <b><i>the
                    testator</i></b>, who died on the 16th day of August, 1899, and of a scheme
            approved by the Supreme Court in Action No. <ref href="/hk/1904/46">46 of 1904 </ref>and
            of an order of the said court made on the 7th day of March, 1923, the residue of the
            estate of the testator was applied to the erection and maintenance of a hospital called
            the “Matilda Hospital” for British, American and European patients as provided in the
            said scheme:</recital><recital class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">AND WHEREAS by the War Memorial Nursing Home
            Trustees Ordinance 1923 (<ref href="/hk/1923/14">14 of 1923</ref>), the trustees of the
            War Memorial Nursing Home and their successors in office, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    nursing home trustees</i></b>, were incorporated as a body corporate and the
            property of the War Memorial Nursing Home was vested in the said trustees to be
            administered in accordance with the constitution provided by the said Ordinance for the
            institution and maintenance of the Hong Kong War Memorial Nursing Home:</recital><recital class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 ">AND WHEREAS in order to ensure the
            continuance of the objects for which the said Matilda Hospital was instituted and to
            make provision for a nursing home or hospital to fulfil the purpose for which the War
            Memorial Nursing Home was instituted it is deemed expedient that all lands, buildings,
            messuages or tenements, funds and endowments held by the trustees of the will and
            codicil of the testator and all the funds and endowments held by the nursing home
            trustees should be vested in one incorporated body and that the same may be administered
            for the purposes and subject to the provisions of an Ordinance:</recital></preamble><section id="ID_1438402536447_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Matilda and War Memorial Hospital Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402536463_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="BoardOfGovernors,Board"><term>board
                of
            governors</term>
            or
                <term>board</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">董事會</term>) means the board of governors referred to in
                <ref>section 4</ref> and specified in article 7 of the constitution;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the articles of constitution referred
            to in <ref>section 4</ref> and specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>corporation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means the Matilda and War Memorial Hospital
            named and incorporated in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="NursingHomeTrustees"><term>nursing
                home
            trustees</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">護理院受託人</term>) means the trustees appointed in
            accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3</ref> of the War Memorial Trustees
            Ordinance 1923 (<ref href="/hk/1923/14">14 of 1923</ref>);</def><def name="Trustees"><term>trustees</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受託人</term>) means the trustees of the will and codicil
            of Granville Sharp, deceased.</def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536478_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Description and incorporation</heading><content>A hospital to be named the “Matilda and War Memorial Hospital” is hereby incorporated as a body corporate and as the “Matilda and War Memorial Hospital” shall have perpetual succession and shall and may sue or be sued in all courts and shall have and may use a common seal and may break, change, alter and make anew the said seal.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402536494_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Constitution and board of governors</heading><content>The articles of constitution specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall be binding upon the corporation and a board of governors shall be appointed in accordance with the constitution the members of which shall be deemed to be the members of the corporation after notice of their appointment has been filed with the Registrar of Companies.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402536509_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410808452_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to do any of the following acts, namely, to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate, and also to invest moneys upon mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, or upon the mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation or company, and also to purchase, acquire and possess goods and chattels of what nature and kind soever, and so that by virtue of the powers conferred by this subsection any investment or other property may be acquired whether or not it is producing or is expected to produce income.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410808483_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>The corporation shall further have power to do any of the following acts, namely, to borrow or raise money and to give securities for the repayment thereof, to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities, and to enter into any contract or arrangement of any kind as the corporation may think fit:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_2_proviso">Provided that the powers conferred by this section shall only be exercised for the purpose of endowing, supporting, maintaining, carrying on or otherwise promoting the work of the corporation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402536525_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Seal and sealing</heading><content>All deeds and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be sealed in the presence of 2 members of the board of governors and shall be signed by 2 members of the board of governors.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536541_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Internal management and amendment of constitution</heading><content>All matters of internal management of the corporation including any amendment of the constitution shall be settled and carried out in accordance with the constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402536556_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Vesting of property</heading><content>The property and assets of whatsoever description hitherto vested in the Hong Kong Bank Trustee Limited as custodian trustee for the corporation are hereby transferred to and vested in the corporation.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536572_001" name="s9" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 ss.
                6 &amp;
                7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536587_001" name="s10" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 ss.
                6 &amp;
                7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536619_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402536634_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1035/s2">ss. 2</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap1035/s4">4</ref>]</note><heading>Articles
            of
            Constitution<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><section id="ID_1438410808577_049" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These articles shall be cited as the articles of constitution
                of
                the Matilda and War Memorial
                Hospital.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410808577_065" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these articles, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Hospital"><term>Hospital</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">醫院</term>) means
                the Matilda and War Memorial Hospital;</def><def name="MatildaHospital"><term>Matilda Hospital</term> means the hospital erected and
                maintained in pursuance of the will and codicil of Granville Sharp, deceased, and a
                scheme approved by the Supreme Court in Action No. <ref href="/hk/1904/46">46 of
                    1904 </ref>and by an order of the said court made on the 7th day of March,
                1923;</def><def name="Ordinance"><term>Ordinance</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">條例</term>)
                means the Matilda and War Memorial Hospital Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1035">Cap.
                    1035</ref>);</def><def name="WarMemorialHospital"><term>War Memorial Hospital</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">戰爭紀念醫院</term>) means the hospital specified in the War
                Memorial Nursing Home Trustees Ordinance 1923 (<ref href="/hk/1923/14">14 of
                    1923</ref>).</def></section><section id="ID_1438410808592_028" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Title of Hospital</heading><content>The Hospital shall be called the Matilda and War Memorial
                Hospital.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410808592_044" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Objects of Hospital</heading><leadIn>The objects of the Hospital shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410808592_062" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in continuation of the work and traditions of the Matilda and War Memorial
                    Hospital and in memory of Matilda Lincolne Sharp, resident of Hong Kong from
                    1858 to 1893, and in continuation also of the work and traditions of the War
                    Memorial Nursing Home (first established after the Great War of 1914-18 as a
                    memorial to those residents of Hong Kong who saw active service in that
                    War)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410808592_071" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to provide in Hong Kong the facilities and services of a hospital or
                        hospitals and of a nursing home or nursing homes;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410808608_008" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_s4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to provide in Hong Kong medical and surgical treatment and aid or any
                        other assistance and all kinds of medical, surgical, dental and nursing care
                        and all remedies and requisites in case of accident or illness and to do so
                        either gratuitously or in return for such payment as may from time to time
                        be authorized by the board of governors;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410808608_017" name="iii" temporalId="sch0_s4_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>to provide facilities for training in medicine, surgery, dentistry,
                        nursing and hospital work and all kinds of medical, surgical, nursing and
                        dental care;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410808608_026" name="iv" temporalId="sch0_s4_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>to provide facilities for and to promote (and join in promoting)
                        research into and investigation of diseases and their causes, diagnosis,
                        treatment and cure and research aimed at the progressive elimination of
                        diseases and the promotion of good health among all members of the
                        community;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808624_006" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to raise funds and to accept and administer subscriptions, gifts and
                    bequests for all or any of the foregoing objects or for other purposes which in
                    the opinion of the board of governors can conveniently be carried into effect by
                    the Hospital as part of or in conjunction or
                    connexion
                    with its work in Hong Kong and without derogation from the generality of the
                    foregoing to continue the administration and application of all such funds and
                    all
                    gifts
                    that have been made or may hereafter be made to the Hospital (including among
                    the gifts that have been made a gift of
                    ￡50,000
                    sterling made by Mr. Haakon J. Wallem in memory of Sir Vandeleur M. Grayburn)
                    and to administer and apply the same together with any other funds which may be
                    or be made available for the purposes of the Hospital or for similar purposes
                    and so that the care and facilities provided by the Hospital may be made
                    available without charge or in return for such payment and on such terms
                    generally in all respects as the board of governors in their absolute discretion
                    think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808670_007" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>generally to do all things which the board of governors consider reasonably
                    necessary or expedient for, or conducive or incidental to, the carrying out of
                    all or any of the objects aforesaid.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808670_021" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Supreme control of Hospital</heading><content>The supreme control, government and management of all the property and affairs
                of the Hospital shall be vested in the board of
                governors.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410808670_037" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Powers of board of governors</heading><leadIn>The board of governors may exercise all such powers and do all such acts and
                things as the corporation may do but without prejudice to the general powers
                conferred upon them it is hereby expressly declared that they shall have the
                following powers, that is to say, power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410808670_055" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to appoint and at their discretion dismiss or suspend such medical
                    superintendents, doctors, matrons, secretaries, nursing sisters, paramedical
                    staff, nurses, housekeepers or other officers and servants whether appointed for
                    permanent, temporary or special services as they may from time to time think fit
                    and to determine their powers and duties and make provision for the remuneration
                    of and payment of pensions and gratuities to such
                    persons
                    including the provision of pensions and other benefits for any spouse or
                    dependants of any such person; <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21
                            of 1984 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808686_007" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to appoint any person or persons (whether incorporated or not) to accept
                    and hold in trust for the corporation any property belonging to the corporation
                    or in which it is interested or for any other purpose and to execute and do all
                    such deeds and things as may be requisite in relation to any such trust and to
                    provide for the remuneration of the trustee or trustees;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808686_016" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to institute, conduct, defend, compound or abandon any legal proceedings by
                    or against the corporation or its officers or otherwise concerning the affairs
                    of the corporation and also to compound or allow for payment or satisfaction of
                    any debts due or any claims or payments by or against the corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808702_007" name="d" temporalId="sch0_s6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to refer any claims or demands by or against the corporation to arbitration
                    and observe and perform the awards;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808702_016" name="e" temporalId="sch0_s6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to make and give receipts, releases and other discharges for money payable
                    to the corporation and for the claims and demands of the corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808702_025" name="f" temporalId="sch0_s6_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to determine who shall be entitled to sign on the corporation’s behalf
                    bills, notes, receipts, acceptances, endorsements, cheques, releases, contracts
                    and documents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808702_034" name="g" temporalId="sch0_s6_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>save as herein provided to make, vary and repeal such orders, by-laws,
                    regulations and rules as the governors may from time to time think fit in
                    relation to the said Hospital and its conduct and management and as to their own
                    duties and procedure and proceedings and in any affairs relating to the said
                    Hospital;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808717_007" name="h" temporalId="sch0_s6_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>to enter into all such negotiations and contracts and execute and do all
                    such acts, deeds and things in the name and on behalf of the corporation as they
                    may consider expedient for or in relation to any of the matters aforesaid or
                    otherwise for the purpose of the corporation; <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808717_016" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s6_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>at any time and from time to time by power of attorney and under the
                    corporation’s seal or by an instrument in writing delegate any of their powers
                    and appoint any person or persons to be the attorney or attorneys of the
                    corporation for such purposes and with such powers, authorities and discretions
                    not exceeding those vested in the board of governors and subject to such
                    conditions as the governors may from time to time think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808733_007" name="j" temporalId="sch0_s6_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>to appoint any committee or committees consisting of such member or members
                    of their own body or otherwise as they may think fit and to delegate any of
                    their powers to such committee or committees and to prescribe the functions,
                    duties and powers thereof and to revoke any delegation and to determine all or
                    any such functions, duties and powers; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808733_016" name="k" temporalId="sch0_s6_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>to exercise all or any of the foregoing powers so far as they are
                    applicable in relation to liabilities or obligations whether legal or moral
                    previously incurred by the trustees or by the nursing home trustees and to
                    assume responsibility for payments by way of gratuities, pensions or otherwise
                    for services rendered to the Matilda Hospital or the War Memorial Hospital and
                    to charge such payments to the funds of the corporation and generally at the
                    discretion of the board to sanction new payments in respect of services
                    previously rendered to the Matilda Hospital or the War Memorial
                    Hospital.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438410808748_004" name="s7" temporalId="sch0_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Constitution of board of governors</heading><leadIn>The board of governors shall consist of the following persons—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410808748_022" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>one member who and whose successors shall be appointed by the Chairman for
                    the time being of The Hongkong and Shanghai Banking Corporation;
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1989/ln333">L.N. 333 of
                        1989</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808764_007" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>one member who and whose successors shall be appointed by the Chairman and
                    Senior Managing Director for the time being of Jardine, Matheson &amp; Co.,
                    Limited;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808764_016" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>one member who and whose successors shall be appointed by the senior
                    resident executive for the time being in Hong Kong of the Swire Group of
                    Companies;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808764_025" name="d" temporalId="sch0_s7_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>one member who shall be appointed by the senior resident executive for the
                    time being in Hong Kong of the Wallem Group of Companies;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808764_034" name="e" temporalId="sch0_s7_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>2 registered medical practitioners to be appointed by the board of
                    governors;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808764_043" name="f" temporalId="sch0_s7_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>not more than 2 other members who and whose successors shall be chosen by
                    the board of governors with a view to having on the board (so far as possible)
                    persons who are drawn, in conjunction with other members of the board of
                    governors, from the principal communities and sections of society in Hong
                    Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808764_052" name="g" temporalId="sch0_s7_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>a person to represent the religious communities of Hong Kong who shall be
                    chosen by the board of governors.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808780_012" name="s8" temporalId="sch0_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Board of governors. Tenure of office</heading><leadIn>Each member of the board of governors shall hold office—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410808780_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>until he submits his resignation in writing to the board of governors;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808780_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>until he is removed from office by notice in writing given to the board of
                    governors by his appointor.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808780_053" name="s8A" temporalId="sch0_s8A" class="no_header"><num value="8A">8A.</num><heading>Appointment of alternates</heading><paragraph id="ID_1438410808780_063" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s8A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Any member of the board of governors may appoint any person previously
                    approved in writing by the board of governors to be an alternate or substitute
                    member of the board of governors to act in his place or stead and such appointee
                    whilst he holds office as an alternate member of the board of governors shall be
                    entitled to notice of meetings of the board of governors and to attend and vote
                    thereat accordingly but he shall ipso facto vacate office if and when the
                    appointor vacates office as a member of the board of governors or removes the
                    appointee as his alternate or substitute. <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/ln4">L.N. 4 of 1991</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808795_007" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s8A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Any appointment or removal under paragraph (a) shall be effected by notice
                    in writing under the hand of the member of the board of governors making the
                    same.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808795_016" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s8A_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>One person may act as alternate or substitute member of the board of
                    governors for more than one member of the board of governors and while he is so
                    acting shall be entitled to a separate vote for each member he is representing
                    and if he is himself a member of the board of governors his vote or votes as an
                    alternate or substitute member shall be in addition to his own vote.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808811_012" name="s9" temporalId="sch0_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Monthly meeting of board</heading><content>The board of governors shall once in every 3 months and may as often as they
                think fit meet together for the dispatch of business and any 2 governors may by
                notice in writing to the chairman of the board of governors or to the duly appointed
                secretary or secretaries require a meeting to be called at any time. The board of
                governors may in their discretion reimburse any travelling expenses necessarily
                incurred by any member of the board of governors in attending any meeting of the
                board of governors.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1965/ln26">L.N. 26 of 1965</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808811_036" name="s10" temporalId="sch0_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Quorum</heading><content>At any meeting of the board of governors, a quorum shall be constituted by 4
                members of the board.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1965/ln24">L.N. 24 of 1965</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/ln4">L.N. 4 of
                1991</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808811_060" name="s10A" temporalId="sch0_s10A" class="no_header"><num value="10A">10A.</num><heading>Resolution in writing</heading><content>A resolution in writing signed by all members of the board of governors shall
                be as effective for all purposes as a resolution of the board of governors passed at
                a meeting. A written notification of confirmation of such resolution in writing sent
                by a member of the board of governors shall be deemed to be his signature to such
                resolution in writing for the purposes of this article. A resolution in writing may
                consist of several documents, each signed by one or more members of the board of
                governors.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1991/ln4">L.N.
                    4 of
                1991</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808826_012" name="s11" temporalId="sch0_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Appointment of treasurer and secretary</heading><content>The board of governors may appoint a treasurer of the Hospital who shall be an
                honorary officer and may appoint from outside their own members a secretary or
                secretaries of the Hospital who shall perform such duties and receive such
                remuneration as the board from time to time may
                determine.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410808826_028" name="s12" temporalId="sch0_s12" class="no_header"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Minutes</heading><leadIn>The board of governors shall cause minutes to be made in books provided for the
                purpose—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410808826_046" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of all appointments of officers made by the board;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808826_055" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>of all the resolutions and proceedings at all meetings of the board and of
                    the committees appointed by
                    them.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438410808826_061" name="s13" temporalId="sch0_s13" class="no_header"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Books, accounts and audit</heading><content>The board of governors shall cause proper books or accounts to be kept of all
                receipts and payments and the accounts of the corporation shall be balanced and the
                financial state of the corporation shall be ascertained under the superintendence of
                the board once in every year as at 31 December in every year and the balance sheet
                showing the financial state of the corporation as on that date in each year shall be
                prepared. The profit and loss account and balance sheet shall be audited by an
                auditor or by auditors appointed by the board and a copy of such account and balance
                sheet fully audited shall within 7 days after the date of the certificate of the
                auditors thereon be sent by the board to the Chief Executive.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808842_012" name="s14" temporalId="sch0_s14" class="no_header"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Annual general meeting of board</heading><content>A meeting of the board of governors shall be held not later than 30 June in
                each year and shall be called the annual general meeting and at such meeting a
                report of all the affairs of the Hospital with a statement of property belonging to
                the Hospital and a full account of all the receipts and expenditure of the Hospital
                for the year and a balance sheet drawn up as at 31 December preceding shall be
                presented and at such meeting the auditors for the ensuing year shall be appointed.
                After the conclusion of each annual general meeting a special meeting shall be held
                at which the members appointed to replace the members retiring from the board shall
                take office and the board shall elect from among their own members a chairman and
                deputy chairman and such other officers as they may consider necessary for the
                ensuing year.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808858_012" name="s15" temporalId="sch0_s15" class="no_header"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Custody of moneys received</heading><content>All moneys received for the purpose of being applied towards acquiring
                additional land or erecting buildings for the Hospital or for paying off any debt
                incurred for any such purpose shall on being received be paid to the corporation for
                and on behalf of the board.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808858_036" name="s16" temporalId="sch0_s16" class="no_header"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Investment of surplus moneys</heading><content>All moneys at any time standing to the credit of the general account which
                shall not be required for current expenses shall be paid to the corporation and any
                investment from time to time held by the corporation may be sold and the proceeds
                thereof invested in other
                investments as
                and when the board shall direct.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1965/ln25">L.N. 25 of 1965</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808858_068" name="s17" temporalId="sch0_s17" class="no_header"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Cheques</heading><content>Cheques shall be drawn under the order of the board of governors and shall be
                signed by such person or persons in such manner as the board may from time to time
                determine.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808858_092" name="s18" temporalId="sch0_s18" class="no_header"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Appointment of medical and nursing staff</heading><content>The
                board of governors shall be at liberty to appoint for the Hospital a resident
                medical officer or superintendent who shall be registered as a medical practitioner
                in Hong Kong. He shall exercise such functions as the board directs and receive such
                remuneration as the board may from time to time determine. The board may appoint
                other medical or technical officers for service in the Hospital either for whole or
                part time and either in an honorary capacity or for such remuneration and on such
                terms as the board may from time to time determine. The board shall also be at
                liberty to appoint for the Hospital a matron who shall have such qualifications as
                are necessary to be registered in Part I of the register of nurses maintained under
                the Nurses Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap164">Cap. 164</ref>). She shall
                have such functions and receive such remuneration as the board may from time to time
                determine. The board shall also appoint an adequate number of registered nurses and
                enrolled nurses (as defined in the Nurses Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap164">Cap. 164</ref>)), all of whom shall be duly qualified to
                perform such duties as may be prescribed by the board or by the resident medical
                officer, the superintendent of the Hospital or the matron from time to
                time.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808889_012" name="s19" temporalId="sch0_s19" class="no_header"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Private medical attendants</heading><content>Any patient in the Hospital may be attended by his own medical attendant on the
                condition that he be so attended at his own expense and without any liability on the
                part of the corporation or of the board of governors or any member of the staff of
                the Hospital
                in respect of
                any act of commission or omission of the medical attendant attending such
                patient.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410808889_036" name="s20" temporalId="sch0_s20" class="no_header"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Rules for admission to Hospital</heading><content>Except as herein otherwise provided the board of governors shall have the sole
                right of making rules for and deciding as to the suitability of any applicant for
                admission to the Hospital and as to the continuance in the Hospital of any patient
                who may have been admitted and to decide and regulate the fees and charges to be
                paid by them. In urgent cases the admission of patients shall be in the discretion
                of the resident medical officer or superintendent, or, in his absence, of the
                matron, who shall as far as possible in the circumstances act in accordance with
                such rules as may be made by the
                board.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410808904_004" name="s21" temporalId="sch0_s21" class="no_header"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Power to exclude certain patients</heading><content>No lunatic or person suffering from any disease which in the opinion of the
                resident medical officer or superintendent, or, in his absence, of the matron, may
                be a source of danger or otherwise prejudicial to other patients, may (except in
                case of necessity) be admitted or retained as a
                patient.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410808904_020" name="s22" temporalId="sch0_s22" class="no_header"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Appointment of sub-committees</heading><paragraph id="ID_1438410808904_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s22_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>The board of governors shall have power to appoint sub-committees with such
                    terms of reference and powers as the board of governors may from time to time
                    prescribe.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808904_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s22_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Each sub-committee shall consist of not less than 3 members of the board of
                    governors one of whom shall be appointed by the board of governors as the
                    convener thereof.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808904_048" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s22_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>The meetings of a sub-committee shall be convened by its convener and if
                    the convener shall not be present within 15 minutes after the time appointed for
                    holding the meeting the members of the sub-committee may stand the meeting
                    adjourned or may elect one of the members present to act as convener of that
                    meeting in which event the meeting shall proceed.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808920_007" name="d" temporalId="sch0_s22_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>A quorum of each sub-committee shall be such number of its members as the
                    board of governors may prescribe but, in any event, at least 2 of its
                    members.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410808920_016" name="e" temporalId="sch0_s22_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>A resolution in writing signed by all the members of a sub-committee for
                    the time being in Hong Kong (not being less than the number required to
                    constitute a quorum) shall be an effective resolution of such sub-committee for
                    all purposes.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/21">21 of 1984 s.
                8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438410808920_030" name="s23" temporalId="sch0_s23" class="no_header"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Power of board to amend, etc. Constitution. Procedure</heading><content>The board of governors shall have power to repeal, replace or amend these
                articles or any of them:<proviso name="proviso" temporalId="sch0_23_proviso">
                    <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438410808920_056" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s23_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a resolution authorizing any such repeal, replacement or amendment
                            shall have been passed by the majority of not less than three-fourths of
                            the members of the board; and</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438410808920_065" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s23_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>consent in writing thereto shall have been given by the Chief
                                Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                </proviso></content></section></schedule></main></ordinance>