<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1008</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1008</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1008!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-09-22</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402526869_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-09-22">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Society of Boys’
                Centres.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[10 April 1981]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402526884_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Society of Boys’ Centres Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526900_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-22" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Chairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the Chairman for the time being of the
            Executive Committee;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of the Society for
            the time being in force;</def><def name="ExecutiveCommittee"><term>Executive
                Committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">執行委員會</term>) means the Executive Committee of the
            Society;</def><def name="ExistingSociety"><term>existing
                society</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">原有扶幼會</term>) means the Society of Boys’ Centres
            existing immediately prior to the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance;</def><def name="Society"><term>Society</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">扶幼會</term>) means the Society of Boys’ Centres
            incorporated by <ref>section 3</ref>.</def><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1642475980420_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 10 April
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526915_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><content>The Society of Boys’ Centres shall be a body corporate and in that name shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall have, and may use, a common seal.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526915_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-22" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers</heading><leadIn>The Society shall have power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410793616_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands,
                buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever
                situate in Hong Kong, to invest moneys on deposit in any bank or upon mortgage of
                any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements in Hong Kong or in the debentures,
                debenture stock, stock, funds, shares or securities of any corporation
                or
                company carrying on business in Hong Kong and to purchase and acquire movable
                property of whatsoever nature or kind;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793632_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to build, rebuild, demolish, alter, vary, renew, maintain and repair any buildings, messuages or tenements acquired by the Society or in which the Society has acquired an interest and to effect any improvements thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793632_014" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, transfer, exchange, partition, surrender, yield up, charge, mortgage, pledge, reassign, release, demise, let or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture stock, stock, funds, shares, securities, and movable property for the time being vested in or belonging to the Society upon such terms as the Society may think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793648_006" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the Society may think fit and, subject to
                    <ref>section
                    4(17)</ref>
                of the Summary Offences Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap228">Cap. 228</ref>), to raise
                money by private or public subscription;
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of
                2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793648_014" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to accept donations, grants or subsidies from any person or Government Authority or other body or organization;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793648_022" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to establish, support and subscribe to provident funds, pension and retirement and similar schemes for the benefit of employees of the Society and their dependants and to grant and pay pensions or gratuities to and otherwise aid, support or assist any such persons;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793648_030" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>generally to do such other acts and things as are incidental or conducive to the aims and objects of the Society.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402526947_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-22" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Vesting of property, etc. in the Society</heading><leadIn>On the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410793679_043" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all that piece or parcel of ground known and registered in the Land Registry as
                New Kowloon Inland Lot No. 5458 together with all erections and buildings thereon
                and all rights, easements and appurtenances thereto belonging vested in The Society
                of Boys’ Centres Trustees Incorporated, incorporated under the Registered Trustees
                Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap306">Cap. 306</ref>), shall vest in the
                Society for the unexpired residue of the term of years created by the Conditions of
                Grant No. 10147 under which the same is held from the Government subject to payment
                of the rent and performance of the covenants and conditions reserved by and
                contained in the said Conditions of Grant;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793710_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all those beneficial rights and interests of The Society of Boys’ Centres
                Trustees Incorporated in all that piece or parcel of ground known and registered in
                the Land Registry as New Kowloon Inland Lot No. 5197 and in portions of the building
                erected thereon, which said piece or parcel of ground and building are held by the
                Hong Kong Housing Society, incorporated under the Hong Kong Housing Society
                Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1059">Cap. 1059</ref>), in trust for the
                said Society of Boys’ Centres Trustees Incorporated and others under a Crown lease
                dated 1 August 1969 for the unexpired residue of the term of years created thereby
                subject to the payment of the rent and performance of the covenants and conditions
                reserved by and contained in the said Crown lease, shall vest in the Society
                    absolutely;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793741_006" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all those beneficial rights and interests of the said Society of Boys’ Centres
                Trustees Incorporated in all that piece or parcel of ground known and registered in
                the Land Registry as Kowloon Inland Lot No. 8243 and in portions of the building
                erected thereon, which said piece or parcel of ground and building are held by the
                said Hong Kong Housing Society in trust for the said Society of Boys’ Centres
                Trustees Incorporated and another body under a Crown lease dated 15 December 1969
                for the unexpired residue of the term of years created thereby subject to the
                payment of the rent and performance of the covenants and conditions reserved by and
                contained in the said Crown lease, shall vest in the Society absolutely;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993
                        s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793757_006" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>all investments and movable property vested in or belonging to or held for or
                on behalf of or in trust for the existing society shall be transferred to vest in,
                belong to or be held for or on behalf of or in trust for the Society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793772_006" name="e" temporalId="s5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>all contractual and other rights exercisable or enforceable by or on behalf of
                the existing society shall be exercisable and enforceable by the Society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793772_014" name="f" temporalId="s5_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the Society shall become liable for all debts and liabilities and for the
                performance of all contractual and other obligations of the existing
                society.</content></paragraph><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1642476455590_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 10 April
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526962_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-22" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Office-bearers and members</heading><content>The Society shall consist of those office-bearers and members of the existing
            society who were such office-bearers and members immediately before the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance and of all persons who shall hereafter be admitted to membership of
            the Society in accordance with its constitution.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1642476514953_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 10 April
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526978_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-22" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Constitution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793835_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The constitution of the existing society in force immediately prior to the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance shall be the constitution of the Society, and, subject to this
                Ordinance, may be amended at any time or from time to time in accordance with the
                provisions of the constitution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793835_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The constitution shall not be amended without the consent in writing of the
                Registrar of Companies.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1642476559831_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 10 April
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526978_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-22" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793850_019" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Society shall forward to the Registrar of Companies for registration the
                following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410793866_005" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the principal office of the Society and of any
                    change therein;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793866_013" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the constitution and any amendment thereto certified as correct
                    by the Chairman; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410793866_021" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a list of the names, occupations and addresses of the Chairman and members
                    of the Executive Committee and any change therein, certified as correct by the
                    Chairman.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793866_028" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every document required to be registered in accordance with subsection (1)
                shall be forwarded to the Registrar of Companies within 28 days of the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance or within 28 days of any change or amendment, as the case may
                be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793866_036" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Society shall pay such fees for registering any document under this section
                as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section 26</ref> of the
                Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for the registration of
                a document required to be registered under that Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                        912
                        &amp;
                    920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793882_005" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person may inspect any document registered under this section on payment of
                such fee as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section 26</ref> of
                the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for inspecting a
                document kept by the Registrar of Companies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                        912
                        &amp;
                    920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793882_013" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The list or any change therein registered under subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref>
                shall be prima facie evidence of the facts mentioned therein.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1642476602896_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 10 April
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402527009_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410793913_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the Society shall be sealed in the presence of 2 members of the Executive Committee and shall be signed by those members, and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents or other instruments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410793913_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Executive Committee shall be responsible for the safe custody of the common seal of the Society.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402527025_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-22" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the
                                    rights of the Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong
                                    Kong Special Administrative Region under the Basic Law and other
                                    laws or the rights of any body politic or corporate or any other
                                    persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those
                                    claiming by, from or under
                                    them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s.
                                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>