<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1007 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1007A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1007A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-09-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402526619_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2022-09-08">Chater
            Masonic Scholarship Fund By-laws</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap1007/s4">Cap.
                1007,
                section
            4</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 November 1929]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline>Citation</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402526650_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1"><b>1.</b></num><content>These by-laws may be cited as the Chater Masonic Scholarship Fund
                        By-laws.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline>Constitution</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402526666_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2"><b>2.</b></num><content>The fund shall be known as the “Chater Masonic Scholarship Fund”.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526681_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3"><b>3.</b></num><content>The fund shall consist of the existing fund in the hands of the honorary treasurer
            and such further contributions as shall be made by masonic bodies and
            individuals.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline>Government</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402526697_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4"><b>4.</b></num><content>The trustees shall consist of such brethren as shall be elected by the lodges and
            chapters contributing to the funds of the corporation and of trustees for life as
            hereinafter provided. Each Lodge shall elect one brother to be a trustee and every
            individual brother contributing not less than $500 shall by virtue of such contribution
            become a trustee for life. Any vacancy or vacancies of elected trustees occurring
            through death, incapacity, retirement or prolonged absence from Hong Kong may be filled
            by the Lodge or other masonic body. Any representative of a Lodge shall not be deemed a
            trustee until the notice referred to in <ref>section 2</ref> of the Ordinance including
            his name as a trustee has been filed with the Registrar of Companies.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1949/gna149">G.N.A. 149 of 1949</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/55">55 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402526728_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5"><b>5.</b></num><content>The trustees shall appoint annually from among themselves a president and a
            vice-president. At all meetings the president shall preside, or in his absence the
            vice-president, or in the absence of both the senior past master present.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526744_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6"><b>6.</b></num><content>The trustees shall appoint annually an honorary treasurer who must be a subscribing
            member of a Lodge in Hong Kong, who shall collect all sums due to the corporation and
            keep an accurate account of all moneys received and disbursed to be presented at each
            meeting. He shall also carry out the duties of secretary to the trustees.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526775_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7"><b>7.</b></num><content>The trustees shall also appoint one or more auditors (who shall not be trustees) to
            audit the accounts and present a statement at the annual meeting.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline>Funds</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402526806_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8"><b>8.</b></num><content>All contributions shall be paid to the honorary treasurer and shall by him
                        be placed to the credit of the corporation in a local bank or invested as
                        the trustees may deem advisable.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526806_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9"><b>9.</b></num><content>No payment on account of the corporation shall be made without the order of the
            trustees, payment on petty cash account excepted, for which latter purpose the trustees
            may place such sum as they think fit at the disposal of the honorary treasurer, who
            shall furnish a correct account of all such payments at each meeting of the trustees.
            All cheques shall be signed by the honorary treasurer.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline>Scholarship</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402526822_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10"><b>10.</b></num><content>A scholarship shall be granted to the person selected by the trustees for
                        one year only in the first instance, but such scholarship shall be renewable
                        yearly at the discretion of the trustees.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402526837_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11"><b>11.</b></num><content>In the event of there being more than one candidate qualified to receive the
            benefits of this endowment, the trustees shall make the award mainly on the result of a
            matriculation or equivalent examination but shall also take into consideration the
            character of the candidate and the financial position of the candidate’s
            family.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1949/gna149">G.N.A. 149 of 1949</ref>)</sourceNote></section><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline>Meetings</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402526853_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12"><b>12.</b></num><content>The annual meeting of the trustees shall be held not later than the month
                        of May in every year when the report of the trustees and the audited
                        statement of accounts made up to the 31st December of the previous year
                        shall be presented and any business of the previous year discussed, after
                        which, the accounts and report being passed, the trustees shall proceed with
                        the appointment of the officers for the ensuing year and discuss any
                        business having reference to the corporation which may be brought before the
                        meeting. Emergency meetings may be called at any time by the president or in
                        his absence by the vice-president, or in the absence of both, by the senior
                        past master.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline>Quorum</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402526853_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2022-09-08" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13"><b>13.</b></num><content> At all meetings three trustees shall form a quorum.</content></section></main></subLeg>