<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 606</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>606</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap606!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-08-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403519012_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-08">
            <content>An Ordinance to adjust the pay, and the amount of certain allowances, payable
                to certain civil servants and officers of the Independent Commission Against
                Corruption and certain other public officers whose pay or allowance amount is
                determinable, or (for pay) determinable and adjustable, in accordance with or by
                reference to a civil service pay scale or the Independent Commission Against
                Corruption Pay Scale or adjustable in accordance with or by reference to adjustments
                made to such a
                scale.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[24 December 2009]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
            2022</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><sourceNote class="align_left left_indent_36">(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403519012_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            1</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403519012_005" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Public Officers Pay Adjustment Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403519027_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413727099_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance—</leadIn><def name="Allowance"><term>allowance</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">津貼</term>) means any remuneration, other than pay,
                payable to a public officer;</def><def name="CivilServant"><term>civil
                    servant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公務員</term>) means a public officer employed by the
                Government on civil service terms of appointment at a civil service rank;</def><def name="CivilServicePayScale"><term>civil
                    service pay
                scale</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公務員薪級表</term>) means a pay scale specified in
                    <ref>Part 1</ref> of the <ref>Schedule</ref> between the points on that scale
                specified in that Part (both points inclusive);</def><def name="HospitalAuthorityCivilServant"><term>Hospital
                    Authority civil
                servant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">醫院管理局公務員</term>) means a civil servant serving in
                the Hospital Authority whose pay is determined in accordance with a point on a
                Hospital Authority pay scale;</def><def name="HospitalAuthorityPayScale"><term>Hospital
                    Authority pay
                scale</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">醫院管理局薪級表</term>) means a pay scale specified in
                    <ref>Part 3</ref> of the <ref>Schedule</ref> between the points on that scale
                specified in that Part (both points inclusive);</def><def name="ICACOfficer"><term>ICAC
                    officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">廉署人員</term>) means a public officer who is an
                officer within the meaning of the Independent Commission Against Corruption
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap204">Cap. 204</ref>);</def><def name="ICACPayScale"><term>ICAC
                    pay
                scale</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">廉署人員薪級表</term>) means the pay scale specified in
                    <ref>Part 2</ref> of the <ref>Schedule</ref> between the points on that scale
                specified in that Part (both points inclusive);</def><def name="OperativeDate"><inline class="force_orig_font"><inline class="not_bold">*</inline></inline><term>operative
                    date</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">實施日期</term>) means the first day of the month
                immediately following the month during which this Ordinance commences;</def><def name="Pay"><term>pay</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">薪酬</term>) means any remuneration payable to a
                public officer as salary, wages, a consultancy fee or an honorarium;</def><def name="PayScale"><term>pay
                    scale</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">薪級表</term>) means a civil service pay scale, a
                Hospital Authority pay scale or the ICAC pay scale.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727115_039" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the rules (however expressed) by which adjustments may be made to the pay,
                or to the amount of an allowance, payable to a public officer refer to civil service
                pay increases as the factor or one of the factors by which the pay or the amount of
                the allowance is adjustable, then for the purposes of this Ordinance, the reference
                to civil service pay increases must be taken for a public officer to whom
                    <ref>section 8</ref> applies to be a reference to adjustments made to a civil
                service pay scale.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1660890634672_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>
                Operative date: 1 January 2010.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403519043_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Pay point and pay adjustment rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413727177_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If the adjustment of a point on a pay scale by this Ordinance results in a dollar value for that point of an amount that is not a multiple of $5, the resulting dollar value must be rounded up to the nearest $5.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727177_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the adjustment (with any required rounding up) of a point on a pay scale by this Ordinance results in a dollar value for that point of an amount that is less than $48,700, the resulting dollar value must be increased to $48,700.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727177_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the adjustment of the pay payable to the Director of Audit under <ref>section 7</ref> or to a public officer under <ref>section 8</ref> results in a dollar value that is not a multiple of $5, the resulting dollar value must be rounded up to the nearest $5.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403519043_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Non-application to judicial officers</heading><leadIn>This Ordinance does not apply to the pay or allowances payable to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413727208_020" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a person holding a judicial office specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Judicial Officers Recommendation Commission Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap92">Cap. 92</ref>); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413727224_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any other judicial officer appointed by the Chief Executive or by the Chief Justice.</content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403519043_005" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            2</num><heading>Adjustment
            of
            Pay</heading><section id="ID_1438403519058_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Civil servants</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413727255_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the operative date each civil service pay scale is adjusted by reducing the dollar value of each point on the scale by 5.38%.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727255_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The pay payable to a civil servant in accordance with a civil service pay scale as adjusted under subsection (1) is payable with effect from the beginning of the operative date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727255_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>On the operative date each Hospital Authority pay scale is, in its application to a Hospital Authority civil servant and not otherwise, adjusted by reducing the dollar value of each point on the scale by 5.38%.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727271_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The pay payable to a Hospital Authority civil servant in accordance with a Hospital Authority pay scale as adjusted in its application to him or her under subsection (3) is payable with effect from the beginning of the operative date.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403519058_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>ICAC officers paid in accordance with ICAC pay scale</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413727302_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the operative date the ICAC pay scale is adjusted by reducing the dollar value of each point on the scale by 5.38%.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727302_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The pay payable to an ICAC officer in accordance with the ICAC pay scale as adjusted under subsection (1) is payable with effect from the beginning of the operative date.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403519074_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Director of Audit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413727318_019" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the operative date the pay payable to the Director of Audit is adjusted by reducing it by 5.38% and the pay as so adjusted is payable with effect from the beginning of that date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727333_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section has effect despite anything to the contrary in <ref>section 4A</ref> of the Audit Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap122">Cap. 122</ref>) or in any order made under that section.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403519074_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Other public officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413727364_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to a public officer to whom a monthly pay of more than $48,400 is payable immediately before the operative date and who is not a civil servant, an ICAC officer covered by <ref>section 6(2)</ref> or the Director of Audit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727364_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the pay payable to the public officer is determinable in accordance with or by reference to, directly or indirectly, a point on a civil service pay scale or on the ICAC pay scale, then from the beginning of the operative date, the pay is to be determined in accordance with or by reference to the dollar value of that point as reduced by <ref>section 5(1)</ref> or <ref>6(1)</ref>, as the case requires.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727380_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the pay payable to the public officer is adjustable in accordance with or by
                reference to, directly or indirectly, adjustments made to a civil service pay scale
                or the ICAC pay scale, then to the extent that it is so adjustable, on the day of
                the first adjustment to the pay that is to be made on or after the operative date,
                the pay is to be adjusted in accordance with or by reference to the rate of
                adjustments made to that scale by <ref>section 5(1)</ref> or <ref>6(1)</ref>, as the
                case requires, and the pay as so adjusted is payable with effect from the beginning
                of that
                day.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727396_005" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If the pay payable to the public officer is determinable and adjustable in accordance with or by reference to, directly or indirectly, a point on a civil service pay scale or on the ICAC pay scale, then from the beginning of the operative date, the pay is to be determined and adjusted in accordance with or by reference to the dollar value of that point as reduced by <ref>section 5(1)</ref> or <ref>6(1)</ref>, as the case requires.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403519090_002" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            3</num><heading>Adjustment
            of
            Allowances</heading><section id="ID_1438403519090_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Allowances determinable in accordance with or by reference to pay point or points</heading><content>If the amount of an allowance payable to a public officer is determinable in accordance with or by reference to, directly or indirectly, a point, or more than one point, on a civil service pay scale or on the ICAC pay scale, then from the beginning of the operative date and in so far as the allowance is payable for or attributable to any period beginning on or after that date, the amount is to be determined in accordance with or by reference to the dollar value of that point, or those points, as reduced by <ref>section 5(1)</ref> or <ref>6(1)</ref>, as the case requires, with the result rounded up to the next dollar.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403519090_006" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Allowances adjustable in accordance with or by reference to pay scale adjustments</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413727489_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If the amount of an allowance payable to a public officer is adjustable in
                accordance with or by reference to, directly or indirectly, adjustments made to a
                civil service pay scale or the ICAC pay scale, then to the extent that it is so
                adjustable, on the day of the first adjustment to the amount of the allowance that
                is to be made on or after the operative date, the amount is to be adjusted in
                accordance with or by reference to the rate of adjustments made to that scale by
                    <ref>section 5(1)</ref> or <ref>6(1)</ref>, as the case requires, with the
                result rounded up to the next
                dollar.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413727505_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The adjusted allowance is payable with effect from the beginning of the day on which the adjustment is made in so far as it is payable for or attributable to any period beginning on or after that day.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403519105_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            4</num><heading>General Provisions
            and
            Repeals</heading><section id="ID_1438403519105_004" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Future adjustments</heading><content>This Ordinance does not prohibit or affect any other adjustment being made to the pay, or to the amount of any allowance, payable to a public officer on or after the operative date or with effect from the operative date or any later date including, for the Director of Audit, by an order made under <ref>section 4A</ref> of the Audit Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap122">Cap. 122</ref>).</content></section><section id="ID_1438403519121_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Express authority for adjustments</heading><content>The contract of employment of any public officer is varied so as to expressly authorize the adjustments made by this Ordinance to the pay, or to the amount of any allowance, payable to the public officer.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403519121_003" name="s13" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="omitted" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403519121_005" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap606/s2">s.
                2</ref>]</note><heading>Pay
            Scales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><part id="ID_1438413727614_017" name="P1" temporalId="sch0_P1"><num value="1">Part
                1</num><heading>Civil
                Service Pay
                Scales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><paragraph class="left_indent_0" id="ID_1594880132633_001" name="0" temporalId="sch0_P1_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438413727614_036" name="1" temporalId="sch0_P1_0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Master Pay Scale—point 34 (33A) to point
                        49</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413727614_044" name="2" temporalId="sch0_P1_0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>Police Pay Scale—point 36 to point
                        59</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413727614_052" name="3" temporalId="sch0_P1_0_3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>General Disciplined Services (Commander) Pay Scale—point 1 to
                        point 4</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413727614_060" name="4" temporalId="sch0_P1_0_4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>General Disciplined Services (Officer) Pay Scale—point 20 to
                        point 39</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413727614_068" name="5" temporalId="sch0_P1_0_5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>Directorate Pay Scale—point D1 to point
                        D8</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413727614_076" name="6" temporalId="sch0_P1_0_6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>Directorate (Legal) Pay Scale—point DL1 to point
                        DL6<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph></paragraph></part><part id="ID_1438413727614_081" name="P2" temporalId="sch0_P2"><num value="2">Part
                2</num><heading>ICAC Pay
                Scale<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><content>Independent Commission Against Corruption Pay Scale—point 28 to
                point 48<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></part><part id="ID_1438413727630_009" name="P3" temporalId="sch0_P3"><num value="3">Part
                3</num><heading>Hospital
                Authority Pay
                Scales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><paragraph class="left_indent_0" id="ID_1594880132634_002" name="0" temporalId="sch0_P3_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438413727630_028" name="1" temporalId="sch0_P3_0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Hospital Authority General Pay Scale—point 34 to point
                        56</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413727630_036" name="2" temporalId="sch0_P3_0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>Hospital Authority Management Pay Scale—point 9 to point 46</content></paragraph></paragraph></part></schedule></main></ordinance>