<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1177</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1177</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1177!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-10-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402637457_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2020-10-08">
            <content>An Ordinance to provide for the vesting in Citibank (Hong Kong) Limited
                (花旗銀行(香港)有限公司) of the undertakings of the Hong Kong branch of Citibank, N.A. and for
                other related
                purposes.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[3 June 2005]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er5">E.R. 5 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><preamble id="ID_1438402637473_001" name="preamble" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="preamble" startPeriod="2020-10-08"><heading>Preamble</heading><recital>WHEREAS—<paragraph id="ID_1438411106927_006" name="a" temporalId="preamble_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Citibank (Hong Kong) Limited (花旗銀行(香港)有限公司) (hereinafter called
                            <b><i>Citibank (Hong
                            Kong)</i></b>)
                    is a company incorporated under the laws of Hong Kong having its registered
                    office in Hong Kong and is a bank authorized under the Banking Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411106927_014" name="b" temporalId="preamble_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Citibank, N.A. (花旗銀行) (hereinafter called
                            <b><i>Citibank</i></b>)
                    is a national banking association organized under the laws of the United States
                    having its principal place of business in the State of New York and is a bank
                    authorized under the Banking Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>)
                    carrying on the business of banking in Hong Kong and elsewhere;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411106927_022" name="c" temporalId="preamble_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>Citibank operates that part of its business which constitutes the retail
                    banking business in Hong Kong through a branch in Hong Kong (hereinafter called
                            <b><i>Citibank, Hong Kong Branch</i></b>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411106927_030" name="d" temporalId="preamble_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>Citibank (Hong Kong) is a wholly owned subsidiary of Citibank and is a
                    member of the Citibank group of companies of which Citigroup Inc. is the
                    ultimate holding company;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411106943_007" name="e" temporalId="preamble_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>for the better conduct of the businesses of Citibank (Hong Kong) and
                    Citibank, it is expedient that the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch
                    which constitute the retail banking business of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in
                    Hong Kong be merged into, and succeeded by, Citibank (Hong Kong) and that such
                    merger and succession should occur by means of a transfer of the undertakings of
                    Citibank, Hong Kong Branch which constitute the retail banking business of
                    Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in Hong Kong to Citibank (Hong Kong);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411106943_015" name="f" temporalId="preamble_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>in view of the extent of the contractual and other legal relationships
                    affecting the conduct of the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch which
                    constitute the retail banking business of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in Hong
                    Kong, it is expedient that the said undertakings be transferred to Citibank
                    (Hong Kong) by this Ordinance without interference with the conduct and
                    continuity of the business of Citibank, Hong Kong
                    Branch.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content><sourceNote class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph></recital></preamble><section id="ID_1438402637488_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Citibank (Hong Kong) Limited (Merger) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402637504_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411106990_018" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the subject or context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AppointedDay"><term>appointed
                    day</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指定日期</term>) means such day as may be appointed
                pursuant to <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="BankingOrOtherFinancialServices"><term>banking
                    or other financial
                services</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">銀行或其他財務服務</term>) includes the taking of deposits,
                the provision of payment and remittance services, the provision of facilities for
                the purchase or sale of foreign currencies, securities or other financial
                instruments and the incurring of financial exposure mentioned in <ref>section
                    81(2)</ref> of the Banking Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap.
                155</ref>);</def><def name="Citibank"><term>Citibank</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">花旗</term>) means Citibank, N.A. (花旗銀行);</def><def name="CitibankHongKong"><term>Citibank
                    (Hong
                Kong)</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">花旗(香港)</term>) means Citibank (Hong Kong) Limited
                (花旗銀行(香港)有限公司);</def><def name="CitibankHongKongBranch"><term>Citibank,
                    Hong Kong
                Branch</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">花旗香港分行</term>) means Citibank acting through each
                of the places in Hong Kong at which Citibank carries on business;</def><def name="CorporateBankingBusiness"><leadIn><term>corporate
                        banking
                    business</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公司銀行業務</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411107005_040" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the business carried on by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch for the provision of banking or other financial services to companies but does not include such services so provided as part of its retail banking business; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107005_048" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all existing property and liabilities of whatsoever nature as recorded in or created by any of the books and records of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch that are kept in respect of the corporate banking business of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Customer"><term>customer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">客戶</term>) means any person having a banking
                account or other dealing, transaction or arrangement with Citibank, Hong Kong
                Branch;</def><def name="DataProtectionPrinciples"><term>data
                    protection
                principles</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">保障資料原則</term>) means the data protection principles
                set out in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap486">Cap. 486</ref>);</def><def name="ExcludedPropertyAndLiabilities"><leadIn><term>excluded
                        property and
                    liabilities</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">除外財產及法律責任</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411107021_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the common seal of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107021_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>documents required to be kept by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch pursuant to the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>) as in force from time to time before the commencement date* of <ref>section 2 of Schedule 9</ref> to the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) and other applicable law;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; 920)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107021_042" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any liability recorded in the books of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch as being due to Citibank under the caption “Profit/Loss Awaiting Remittance”; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107021_050" name="d" temporalId="s2_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>all existing property, reserves and liabilities of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch of whatsoever nature as recorded in or created by any of the books and records of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch which relate in whole or in part to the corporate banking business, the private banking business or any other businesses of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch other than to the retail banking business;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Existing"><term>existing</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">現有</term>) means existing, outstanding or in force
                immediately prior to the appointed day;</def><def name="Liabilities"><term>liabilities</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法律責任</term>) means duties and obligations of every
                description (whether present or future, actual or contingent);</def><def name="PrivacyCommissioner"><term>Privacy
                    Commissioner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">私隱專員</term>) means the Privacy Commissioner for
                Personal Data established under <ref>section 5(1)</ref> of the Personal Data
                (Privacy) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap486">Cap. 486</ref>);</def><def name="PrivateBankingBusiness"><leadIn><term>private
                        banking
                    business</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">私人銀行業務</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411107037_033" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the business carried on by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch for the provision of banking or other financial services to individuals who are considered by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch to be of high net worth but does not include such services so provided as part of its retail banking business; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107052_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all existing property and liabilities of whatsoever nature as recorded in or created by any of the books and records of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch that are kept in respect of the private banking business of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Property"><term>property</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">財產</term>) means property and assets of every
                description wheresoever situate and rights of every description (whether present or
                future, actual or contingent) including, without limitation, rights as beneficiary
                under trust or nominee arrangements and includes property held on trust or in a
                fiduciary capacity and security interests, benefits and powers of every
                description;</def><def name="RetailBankingBusiness"><leadIn><term>retail
                        banking
                    business</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">零售銀行業務</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411107052_027" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the business carried on by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch for the provision of banking or other financial services to individuals, firms, partnerships, unincorporated businesses or companies and acting as an insurance agent within the meaning of the Insurance Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap41">Cap. 41</ref>) which do not form part of the corporate banking business, the private banking business or any other businesses of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107068_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all existing property and liabilities of whatsoever nature as recorded in or created by any of the books and records of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch that are kept in respect of the retail banking business of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch;</content></paragraph></def><def name="SecurityInterest"><term>security
                    interest</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">抵押權益</term>) includes a mortgage or charge (whether
                legal or equitable and whether fixed or floating), debenture, bill of exchange,
                promissory note, guarantee, lien, pledge (whether actual or constructive),
                hypothecation, hypothec, assignment by way of security, indemnity, right of set-off,
                flawed asset arrangement, agreement or undertaking, right of compensation or
                undertaking, any standard security, any assignation or disposition ex facie absolute
                and any agreement or other deed, instrument or document qualifying the same, any
                bond and disposition or assignation in security, any bond of cash credit, any bond
                of cash credit and disposition or assignation in security, any assignation in
                security, any real right or burden of whatever kind in the nature of a security and
                any other deed, document, conveyance, instrument, arrangement or means (in each case
                made, granted, arising or subsisting under any applicable law) for securing the
                payment or discharge of any debt or liability and also includes any agreement or
                undertaking (in each case, whether in writing or not) to give or execute any of the
                foregoing whether upon demand or otherwise or other means (in each case made,
                granted, arising or subsisting under any applicable law) for securing the payment or
                discharge of a debt or liability (whether present or future, actual or
                contingent);</def><def name="Subsidiary"><term>subsidiary</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附屬公司</term>) has the meaning given by <ref>section
                    15</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for
                the purposes of that Ordinance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; 920)</sourceNote></def><def name="Undertakings"><term>undertakings</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">業務</term>) means the businesses and all existing
                property, reserves and liabilities of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch of whatsoever
                nature as recorded in or created by any of the books and records of Citibank, Hong
                Kong Branch (other than any excluded property and liabilities).</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; 920)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438411107130_018" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any reference in this Ordinance to property or liabilities of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch is a reference to property or liabilities (other than the excluded property and liabilities) to which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch is immediately prior to the appointed day entitled or subject (whether beneficially or in any fiduciary capacity), wherever such property or liabilities are situated or arise and whether or not capable of being transferred or assigned by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, and whether Citibank, Hong Kong Branch is entitled to such property or subject to such liabilities under the laws of Hong Kong or under the laws of any country, territory or place outside Hong Kong.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107146_005" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any body politic or corporate and any other person or persons whose rights are affected by any of the provisions of this Ordinance shall be deemed to be mentioned herein.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1591585277732_001"><content>Editorial Note:</content><content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement
                date:
                3 March 2014.</content></editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402637520_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Notice of appointed day</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411107224_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The directors of Citibank (Hong Kong) may appoint a day for the purposes of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107224_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Citibank (Hong Kong) and Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall give joint notice in the Gazette stating the day so appointed save that, in the event that such day proves not to be the appointed day for any reason, Citibank (Hong Kong) and Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall give joint notice in the Gazette to that effect and shall again give joint notice in the Gazette stating the next day so appointed or, as the case may be, the day which was the appointed day.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637520_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Vesting of the undertakings in Citibank (Hong Kong)</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411107255_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the appointed day the undertakings shall, by virtue of this Ordinance and without further act or deed, be transferred to, and vest in, Citibank (Hong Kong) to the intent that Citibank (Hong Kong) shall succeed to the undertakings as if in all respects Citibank (Hong Kong) were the same person in law as Citibank, Hong Kong Branch.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107255_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the transfer and vesting of any property and liabilities is governed otherwise than by the laws of Hong Kong, Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall, if Citibank (Hong Kong) so requires, so soon as is practicable after the appointed day, take all necessary steps for securing the effective transfer and vesting thereof in Citibank (Hong Kong) and, pending such transfer and vesting, Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall hold any such property and liabilities in trust absolutely for Citibank (Hong Kong).<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637535_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Trust property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411107302_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any property vested or deemed to be vested in Citibank (Hong Kong) by virtue of this Ordinance which immediately prior to the appointed day was held by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, whether alone or jointly with any other person, as trustee or custodian trustee of any trust deed, settlement, covenant, agreement or other instrument (whether originally so appointed or not, and whether appointed under hand or seal, or by order of any court or otherwise), or as executor of the will, or administrator of the estate, of a deceased person or as judicial trustee appointed by order of any court, or in any other fiduciary capacity, shall, on and from the appointed day, be held by Citibank (Hong Kong) alone or, as the case may be, jointly with such other person, in the same capacity upon the trusts, and with and subject to the powers, provisions and liabilities, applicable thereto respectively.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107333_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any existing instrument or order of any court under or by virtue of which any property forming part of the undertakings became vested in Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, in any such fiduciary capacity as is referred to in subsection (1), and any provision in such instrument or order, or any existing contract or arrangement, for the payment to, or retention by, Citibank, Hong Kong Branch of remuneration for its services in any such fiduciary capacity, shall, on and from the appointed day, be construed and have effect, so far as the context permits, as if for any reference therein to Citibank, Hong Kong Branch not being a reference (however worded and whether express or implied) to terms and conditions of, or to a scale of fees of, Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, there were substituted a reference to Citibank (Hong Kong) provided always that this subsection shall not prevent Citibank (Hong Kong) from varying the remuneration or scale of fees payable in accordance with the terms of the relevant instrument or order.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637535_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Supplementary provisions</heading><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of any other provision of this Ordinance but subject to any provision of this Ordinance to the contrary effect, the following provisions of this section shall have effect other than in relation to the excluded property and liabilities—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411107411_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>All existing contracts, agreements, insurance policies, options, novations, certificates, awards, land grants, conveyances, deeds, leases, licences, notices, permits, guarantees, documents granting or comprising any security interest, bonds, indemnities, mandates, instructions and other instruments and undertakings entered into by, made with, given to or by or addressed to Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or (in so far as they are) entered into by, made with, given to or by or addressed to Citibank and insurance policies in which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch has an interest (and in any such case where the rights, liabilities, interest or any chose in action under or established by such instruments forms part of the undertakings) (whether alone or with any other person and whether as principal or agent and whether in writing or not), shall be construed and have effect on and from the appointed day as if—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107427_006" name="i" temporalId="s6_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>Citibank (Hong Kong) had been a party thereto instead of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the case may be, Citibank;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107427_014" name="ii" temporalId="s6_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>for any reference (however worded and whether express or implied) to Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the case may be, Citibank there were substituted, as respects anything falling to be done on or after the appointed day, a reference to Citibank (Hong Kong); and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107427_022" name="iii" temporalId="s6_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>any reference (however worded and whether express or implied) to the directors or to any director, officer or employee of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the case may be, Citibank were, as respects anything falling to be done on or after the appointed day, a reference to the directors of Citibank (Hong Kong) or, as the case may require, to such director, officer or employee of Citibank (Hong Kong) as Citibank (Hong Kong) may appoint for that purpose or, in default of appointment, to the director, officer or employee of Citibank (Hong Kong) who corresponds as nearly as may be to the first-mentioned director, officer or employee.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107442_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Paragraph <ref>(a)(ii)</ref> shall, subject to the provisions of <ref>section
                    14</ref>, apply to any statutory provision, to any provision of any existing
                contract to which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the case may be, Citibank was
                not a party and to any provision of any other existing document (not being a
                contract or a will) as they apply to a contract to which that paragraph
                applies.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107458_006" name="c" temporalId="s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content><leadIn>Any account between Citibank, Hong Kong Branch and a customer shall, on the appointed day, be transferred to Citibank (Hong Kong) and become an account between Citibank (Hong Kong) and such customer subject to the same conditions and incidents including, without limitation, any account number as theretofore; and each such account shall be deemed for all purposes to be a single continuing account; and any existing contracts, agreements, insurance policies, options, novations, certificates, awards, land grants, conveyances, deeds, leases, licences, notices, permits, guarantees, documents granting or comprising any security interest, bonds, indemnities, mandates, instructions and other instruments and undertakings entered into by, made with, given to or by or addressed to Citibank, Hong Kong Branch (whether alone or with any other person and whether as principal or agent and whether in writing or not), shall be construed and have effect on and from the appointed day as if any reference (however worded and whether express or implied) to such account between Citibank, Hong Kong Branch and a customer there were substituted, as respects anything falling to be done on or after the appointed day, and so far as the context permits, a reference to the continuing account between Citibank (Hong Kong) and such customer: </leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_c_proviso">Provided that nothing in this Ordinance shall
                    affect any right of Citibank (Hong Kong) or of any customer to vary the
                    conditions or incidents subject to which any account is
                    kept.<marker role="section-break"></marker></proviso></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107489_012" name="d" temporalId="s6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>Any existing instruction, order, direction, mandate, power of attorney, authority, undertaking or consent (whether in writing or not and whether or not in relation to an account) given to or by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or (in so far as they are) given to or by Citibank on behalf of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, either alone or jointly with another person, shall apply and have effect, on and from the appointed day, as if given to or by Citibank (Hong Kong) or, as the case may be, to or by Citibank (Hong Kong) jointly with such other person.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107505_006" name="e" temporalId="s6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>Any negotiable instrument or order for payment of money drawn on, or given to, or accepted or endorsed by, Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank on behalf of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, or payable at any place of business of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, whether so drawn, given, accepted or endorsed prior to, on or after the appointed day, shall have the same effect on and from the appointed day, as if it had been drawn on, or given to, or accepted or endorsed by Citibank (Hong Kong), or were payable at the same place of business of Citibank (Hong Kong).</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107520_006" name="f" temporalId="s6_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>The custody of any document or record, goods or other thing held by Citibank,
                Hong Kong Branch as bailee shall pass to Citibank (Hong Kong) on the appointed day,
                and the rights and obligations of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch under any contract of
                bailment relating to any such document or record, goods or thing shall on that day
                become rights and obligations of Citibank (Hong
                Kong).<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107520_014" name="g" temporalId="s6_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107520_017" name="i" temporalId="s6_g_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>Any security interest held immediately prior to the appointed day by
                    Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, or by a nominee or agent of or trustee for Citibank,
                    Hong Kong Branch, as security for the payment or discharge of any liability
                    shall, on and from the appointed day, be held by, or, as the case may require,
                    by that nominee, agent or trustee for, Citibank (Hong Kong), and be available to
                    Citibank (Hong Kong) (whether for its own benefit or, as the case may be, for
                    the benefit of any other person) as security for the payment or discharge of
                    that liability.</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107536_007" name="ii" temporalId="s6_g_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>In relation to any security interest vested or deemed to be vested in
                    Citibank (Hong Kong) in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance and any
                    liability thereby secured, Citibank (Hong Kong) shall be entitled to the rights
                    and priorities and be subject to the obligations and incidents to which
                    Citibank, Hong Kong Branch would have been entitled and subject if it had
                    continued to hold the security interest.</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107551_007" name="iii" temporalId="s6_g_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>Without prejudice to the generality of subparagraph (ii), in any case where
                    any existing liability subsists between Citibank, Hong Kong Branch and Citibank
                    (Hong Kong), in respect of which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank (Hong
                    Kong), or a nominee or agent of or trustee for Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or
                    Citibank (Hong Kong) holds a security interest, any liability referred to in
                    subparagraph (ii) shall, for the purpose of enforcing or realizing that security
                    interest, be deemed to continue in effect notwithstanding the vesting of the
                    undertakings in Citibank (Hong Kong).</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107567_007" name="iv" temporalId="s6_g_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>Any security interest referred to in subparagraph (i), (ii) or (iii) and
                    which extends to future advances or liabilities shall, on and from the appointed
                    day, be available to Citibank (Hong Kong) (whether for its own benefit or, as
                    the case may be, for the benefit of any other person) as security for the
                    payment of future advances and discharge of future liabilities to the same
                    extent and in the same manner in all respects as future advances by, or
                    liabilities to, Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank (Hong Kong) were secured
                    thereby immediately prior to that day.</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107583_007" name="v" temporalId="s6_g_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding subparagraph (i), where immediately prior to the appointed
                    day, any security interest would not be available to Citibank (Hong Kong) as
                    security for the payment or discharge of any liability owing to it or to
                    Citibank, Hong Kong Branch as security for the payment or discharge of any
                    liability owing to it, such security interest shall not become available to
                    Citibank (Hong Kong) as security for such liability on and from the appointed
                    day by virtue of this Ordinance, unless—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107583_014" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s6_g_v_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>the terms of such security interest expressly provide
                        otherwise;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107583_022" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s6_g_v_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>Citibank (Hong Kong) obtains the written consent of the person or
                        persons who granted such security interest; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107583_030" name="C" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s6_g_v_C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content>such security interest arises at general law.</content></subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107583_038" name="vi" temporalId="s6_g_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding subparagraph (ii), where immediately prior to the appointed
                    day, Citibank (Hong Kong) would not, in respect of any liability owing to it, be
                    entitled to the rights and priorities in relation to any security interest then
                    in existence, or Citibank, Hong Kong Branch would not, in respect of any
                    liability owing to it, be entitled to the rights and priorities in relation to
                    any security interest then in existence, Citibank (Hong Kong) shall not, in
                    respect of such liability, be entitled to such rights and priorities on and from
                    the appointed day by virtue of this Ordinance, unless—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107598_006" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s6_g_vi_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>the terms of such security interest expressly provide
                        otherwise;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107598_014" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s6_g_vi_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>Citibank (Hong Kong) obtains the written consent of the person or
                        persons who granted such security interest; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107598_022" name="C" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s6_g_vi_C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content>such security interest arises at general law.</content></subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107598_029" name="h" temporalId="s6_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107614_001" name="i" temporalId="s6_h_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>Where by virtue of this Ordinance any right or liability of Citibank, Hong
                    Kong Branch or Citibank where it holds any right or liability on behalf of
                    Citibank, Hong Kong Branch becomes or is deemed to become a right or liability
                    of Citibank (Hong Kong), Citibank (Hong Kong) and all other persons shall, on
                    and from the appointed day, have the same rights, powers and remedies (and in
                    particular the same rights and powers as to taking or resisting legal
                    proceedings or making or resisting applications to any authority) for
                    ascertaining, perfecting or enforcing that right or liability as if it had at
                    all times been a right or liability of Citibank (Hong Kong); and any legal
                    proceedings or application to any authority existing or pending immediately
                    prior to the appointed day by or against Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the
                    case may be, Citibank may be continued by or against Citibank (Hong
                    Kong).</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411107629_007" name="ii" temporalId="s6_h_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>Where any right or liability of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank
                    where it holds any right or liability on behalf of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch
                    was prior to the appointed day the subject of arbitral or legal proceedings to
                    which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank on behalf of Citibank, Hong Kong
                    Branch was a party, Citibank (Hong Kong) shall on and from the appointed day
                    automatically be substituted for Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the case may
                    be, Citibank as a party to those proceedings, without the need for consent from
                    any other party or from the arbitrator.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107645_006" name="i" temporalId="s6_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>Any judgment or award obtained by or against Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank where it has obtained a judgment or award or had a judgment or award held against it on behalf of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch and not fully satisfied prior to the appointed day shall on that day, to the extent to which it is enforceable by or against Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank on behalf of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, become enforceable by or against Citibank (Hong Kong).</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107661_006" name="j" temporalId="s6_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>Any court order which applies to Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or to Citibank on behalf of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall on and from the appointed day apply to Citibank (Hong Kong) instead of to Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the case may be, Citibank.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107661_014" name="k" temporalId="s6_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall terminate or prejudicially affect the appointment, authority, rights or powers of any receiver or of any receiver and manager appointed by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, whether alone or with others, prior to the appointed day.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411107676_006" name="l" temporalId="s6_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>The Privacy Commissioner may, on and from the appointed day, exercise in respect of Citibank (Hong Kong) any power under the Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap486">Cap. 486</ref>) which he could have immediately prior to the appointed day exercised in respect of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in respect of a breach or alleged breach by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch of that Ordinance or the data protection principles; but the transfer to, and vesting in, Citibank (Hong Kong) by this Ordinance of the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch and any disclosure to Citibank (Hong Kong) of any information in contemplation or as a result thereof shall not amount to a breach of any duty of confidentiality to which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch is subject immediately prior to the appointed day or to a contravention by Citibank (Hong Kong) or Citibank, Hong Kong Branch of the Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap486">Cap. 486</ref>) or the data protection principles.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402637551_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Accounting treatment of Citibank (Hong Kong) and Citibank, Hong Kong Branch</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411107817_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>On and from the appointed day, by virtue of this Ordinance and notwithstanding
                the provisions of any other Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411107817_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall be transferred to
                    Citibank (Hong Kong) at their carrying value in the accounts of Citibank, Hong
                    Kong Branch as stated in them immediately prior to the appointed day;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1591585332368_001" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the amount, description and character of every reserve of Citibank (Hong
                    Kong) which forms part of or otherwise relates to the undertakings shall be the
                    same in all respects as those of the corresponding existing reserve of Citibank,
                    Hong Kong Branch immediately prior to the appointed day, and all enactments and
                    rules of law shall apply to or in respect of every such reserve of Citibank
                    (Hong Kong) in the same manner in all respects as they applied to or in respect
                    of the corresponding existing reserve of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch immediately
                    prior to the appointed day.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107817_026" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every reference in subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> to an existing reserve of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall include a reference to any reserve or similar provision, irrespective of its name or designation (and whether the amount thereof be positive or negative in nature) and, without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing, every such reference shall include a reference to any sums standing to the credit (or debit) of any profit and loss account.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637566_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Taxation and revenue matters</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411107863_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>For the purposes of the Inland Revenue Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap112">Cap. 112</ref>), on and from the appointed day Citibank (Hong Kong) shall be treated as if it were the continuation of and the same person in law with regard to the undertakings as Citibank, Hong Kong Branch.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107863_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Accordingly (and without affecting the generality of subsection (1)) a vesting or deemed vesting in Citibank (Hong Kong) of any property or liability by virtue of this Ordinance does not constitute a sale or other divestiture of or a change in the nature of that property or the liability for any purpose under the Inland Revenue Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap112">Cap. 112</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107879_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The profits or losses of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch arising in the year of assessment in which the appointed day occurs, and for the period ended immediately prior to the appointed day, shall be taken into account for the purpose of computing the profits of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch which are chargeable to tax under <ref>Part 4</ref> of the Inland Revenue Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap112">Cap. 112</ref>) for the year of assessment in which the appointed day occurs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107879_013" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The profits or losses arising from the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch transferred to Citibank (Hong Kong) for any period commencing on or after the appointed day shall be taken into account for the purpose of computing the profits of Citibank (Hong Kong) which are chargeable to tax under <ref>Part 4</ref> of the Inland Revenue Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap112">Cap. 112</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/er1">E.R. 1 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402637582_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Waiver of prohibition of merger</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411107926_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any provision contained in any contract or other document to which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank (Hong Kong) or any of their respective subsidiaries is a party or to which Citibank is a party but the rights, liabilities or any chose in action under or established by such contract or other document forms part of the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch which prohibits or has the effect of prohibiting the transfer and vesting or deemed transfer and vesting of the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in Citibank (Hong Kong) shall be deemed by this Ordinance to have been waived.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411107957_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any provision contained in any contract or other document or other agreement to the effect that a breach of contract or a default shall occur or be deemed to occur as a result of the transfer and vesting or deemed transfer and vesting of the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in Citibank (Hong Kong), and to which Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or Citibank (Hong Kong) or any of their respective subsidiaries is a party or to which Citibank is a party but the rights, liabilities or any chose in action under or established by such contract or other document or other agreement forms part of the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, shall be deemed by this Ordinance to have been waived.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637582_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Evidence: books and documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411107988_012" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All books and other documents which would, prior to the appointed day, have been evidence in respect of any matter for or against Citibank, Hong Kong Branch shall be admissible in evidence in respect of the same matter for or against Citibank (Hong Kong) so far as they relate to the undertakings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108004_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Documents">In this section,
                    <term>documents</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">文件</term>) has the same meaning as in <ref>section
                    46</ref> of the Evidence Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap. 8</ref>).</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637613_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Part III of Evidence Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap. 8</ref>)</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411108004_027" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On and from the appointed day, Part III of the Evidence Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap. 8</ref>) shall apply to the banker’s records of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch vested or deemed to be vested in Citibank (Hong Kong) by virtue of this Ordinance, and to entries made in those records prior to the appointed day, as if such records were the records of Citibank (Hong Kong).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108019_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of <ref>section 20</ref> of the Evidence Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap. 8</ref>), banker’s records which are deemed to have become the banker’s records of Citibank (Hong Kong) by virtue of this Ordinance shall be deemed to have been the ordinary banker’s records of Citibank (Hong Kong) at the time of the making of an entry therein which purports to have been made prior to the appointed day, and any such entry shall be deemed to have been made in the usual and ordinary course of business.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108035_005" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of <ref>sections 40</ref> and <ref>41</ref> of the Evidence Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap. 8</ref>), documents previously in the custody or control of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch that relate to the undertakings shall by virtue of this Ordinance be deemed to be documents previously in the custody or control of Citibank (Hong Kong).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108035_013" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="BankersRecords">In this section,
                    <term>banker’s
                    records</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">銀行紀錄</term>) shall be construed in accordance with
                    <ref>section 2</ref> of the Evidence Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap8">Cap.
                    8</ref>).</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637613_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Evidence of transfer and vesting</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411108066_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The production of a Government Printer’s copy of this Ordinance shall, for all purposes, be conclusive evidence of the transfer and vesting or deemed transfer and vesting of the undertakings or any part of them of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in Citibank (Hong Kong) in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108066_012" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411108066_020" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a Government Printer’s copy of this Ordinance, together with evidence of publication of notice of the appointed day, shall, in relation to any registered securities transferred to, and vested or deemed to be vested in, Citibank (Hong Kong) by virtue of this Ordinance, operate for all purposes as a duly executed instrument of transfer in respect of the transfer of such registered securities from Citibank, Hong Kong Branch to Citibank (Hong Kong);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108082_006" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any deed or other document made or executed on or after the appointed day, whereby Citibank (Hong Kong) or Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, whether alone or jointly with any other person, conveys or transfers, or purports to convey or transfer, to any person (whether for consideration or not) or applies to be registered as the holder or proprietor of, any property held by Citibank, Hong Kong Branch immediately prior to the appointed day and forming part of the undertakings, whether alone or jointly with any other person, shall be sufficient evidence that, the interest of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch in that property is vested or deemed to be vested in Citibank (Hong Kong) under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108097_006" name="c" temporalId="s12_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where there is any other transaction or purported transaction by Citibank (Hong Kong) or Citibank, Hong Kong Branch on or after the appointed day in connection with, or in relation to, any property or liabilities which are property or liabilities of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch immediately prior to that day and forming part of the undertakings, it shall be deemed in favour of any other party to the transaction, or any person claiming through or under him, that Citibank (Hong Kong) has full power and authority for that transaction as if the property or liabilities were vested or deemed to be vested in it under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108113_006" name="d" temporalId="s12_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a certificate given by or on behalf of Citibank (Hong Kong) at any time that any property or liabilities specified in the certificate (which property or liabilities immediately prior to the appointed day are the property or liabilities of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch) are or, as the case may be, are not, deemed to be vested in Citibank (Hong Kong) under this Ordinance, shall be conclusive evidence for all purposes of the fact so certified.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108129_005" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in subsection <ref>(2)(c)</ref> or (d) shall affect the liability of Citibank (Hong Kong) and Citibank, Hong Kong Branch to one another in respect of anything done, or purporting to have been done, by any of them in connection with, or in relation to, any property or liabilities.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108129_013" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In subsection (2)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411108129_021" name="a" temporalId="s12_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="Convey"><term>convey</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">轉易</term>) includes mortgage, charge, lease,
                    assent, vest by way of vesting declaration or vesting instrument, disclaim,
                    release or otherwise assure; and</def></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108144_005" name="b" temporalId="s12_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="RegisteredSecurities"><term>registered
                        securities</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">註冊證券</term>) means shares, stocks, debentures,
                    loans, bonds, units of a unit trust scheme or other shares of the investments
                    subject to the trusts of such a scheme, and other securities of any description
                    which are transferable and the holders of which are entered in a register
                    (whether maintained in Hong Kong or elsewhere).</def></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108144_011" name="5" temporalId="s12_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Nothing in this section applies to any property and liabilities falling within <ref>section 4(2)</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637629_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Interests in land</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411108175_018" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The vesting or deemed vesting in Citibank (Hong Kong) of an interest in land by virtue of this Ordinance shall not where applicable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411108175_026" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>constitute an acquisition, disposal, assignment, transfer or parting with possession of that interest for the purposes of <ref>section 53(4)(a)</ref> or (7)(a) of the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap. 7</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108191_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>constitute an assignment or underlease of, or an agreement to assign or underlet, that interest for the purposes of <ref>section 6(1)(b)</ref> of the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap. 7</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108191_014" name="c" temporalId="s13_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>operate so as to merge any leasehold interest in the reversion expectant on it;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108191_022" name="d" temporalId="s13_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>constitute an assignment, transfer, devolution, parting with possession, dealing with or other disposition of that interest for the purposes of any provision contained in any instrument concerning or affecting that interest;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108191_030" name="e" temporalId="s13_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>operate as a breach of covenant or condition against alienation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108191_038" name="f" temporalId="s13_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>give rise to any forfeiture, damages or other right of action;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108191_046" name="g" temporalId="s13_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>invalidate or discharge any contract or security interest;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411108191_054" name="h" temporalId="s13_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>extinguish, affect, vary, diminish or postpone any priority of that interest, whether under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>), at law or in equity.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108191_061" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All existing registrations of any instruments relating to land or interests in land which form part of or otherwise relate to the undertakings that are in the name of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, or Citibank (whether alone or with any other person) immediately prior to the appointed day shall be construed and have effect on and from the appointed day as if the name “Citibank (Hong Kong) Limited (花旗銀行(香港)有限公司)” had been entered on the land register instead of the name of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or, as the case may be, Citibank.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108207_005" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>To enable Citibank (Hong Kong) to complete title, if thought fit, to any property transferred to it and vested or deemed to be vested in it by virtue of this Ordinance by notice of title, deed, instrument or otherwise, or to deduce title, this Ordinance shall be deemed to be an assignment, conveyance, transfer or, as the case may be, an instrument of a general disposition of such property in favour of Citibank (Hong Kong) and the production of a Government Printer’s copy of this Ordinance shall be conclusive evidence of this Ordinance for the purpose of proving or deducing title in favour of Citibank (Hong Kong).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108238_005" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purpose of enabling the public to be informed of this Ordinance through the public records at the Land Registry in relation to the properties or interests in land affected by this Ordinance, Citibank (Hong Kong) shall register or cause to be registered in the Land Registry a Government Printer’s copy of this Ordinance against a property transferred to it and vested or deemed to be vested in it by virtue of this Ordinance in respect of the vesting of all the properties of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch, or Citibank, in the case of some properties, held on behalf of or which form part of the undertakings of Citibank, Hong Kong Branch transferred to and vested or deemed to be vested in Citibank (Hong Kong) by virtue of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411108253_005" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>For the avoidance of doubt, nothing in this section shall exempt Citibank (Hong Kong) and Citibank, Hong Kong Branch from the provisions of the Stamp Duty Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap117">Cap. 117</ref>).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402637644_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Saving for other enactments</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall exempt Citibank (Hong Kong) or Citibank, Hong Kong Branch or any subsidiary of Citibank (Hong Kong) or Citibank, Hong Kong Branch from the provisions of any enactment regulating the carrying on of the business of any of them.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402637644_004" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Saving for companies</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall prejudice the powers of Citibank (Hong Kong) to
            alter its articles of association or to dispose of, or deal with, its property, security
            interests or liabilities or to carry on or discontinue any part of its business; and
            nothing in this Ordinance shall prejudice the powers of Citibank to alter its memorandum
            and articles of association or to dispose of, or deal with, its property, security
            interests or liabilities prior to the appointed day.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; 920)<marker role="section-break"></marker></sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402637660_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of any other person except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by, from or under them.</content></section></main></ordinance>