<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1023 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1023A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1023A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-08-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402532875_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2023-02-02">Hong
            Kong and Kowloon Wharf and Godown Company Limited By-laws</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap1023/s3">Cap. 1023, section
                3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[8 May 1964]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402532921_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2023-02-02" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These by-laws may be cited as the Hong Kong and Kowloon Wharf and Godown Company Limited By-laws.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402532937_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Prohibition of entry and being upon piers and premises of Company without permission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802430_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall enter or be upon any pier or premises of the Company except
                with the permission of an official of the Company.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln126">L.N. 126 of
                1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802430_012" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this by-law, the permission of an official of the Company to enter and be upon any pier of the Company shall, subject to any revocation under paragraph (3), be deemed to have been given to any person who, through the entrance or way provided and upon payment of such fee, if any, for entry as may be stipulated by the Company for the class of persons to which he belongs, enters upon the pier for the purpose of gaining access to any passenger terminal situate on, or to any vessel berthed alongside, that pier.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802446_005" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Company, in the manner specified in paragraph (4), (5) or (6), as the case may be, may in writing at any time, and without assigning any reason therefor, revoke the permission deemed to have been given under paragraph (2) in respect of any pier or premises either in relation to a particular person or class of persons or the employees or agents of any particular person or generally in relation to all persons.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802462_005" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the aforesaid revocation relates to all persons generally or to any class of persons, copies of the revocation shall be posted in a conspicuous place on the Company’s business premises and on the pier or piers concerned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802462_013" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the aforesaid revocation relates to the employees or agents of any person, a copy of the revocation shall be given or sent to that person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802462_021" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where the aforesaid revocation relates to a particular person a copy of the revocation shall be given or sent to that person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802462_029" name="7" temporalId="s2_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Any official of the Company may, for good reason communicated to the person concerned, order any person who is upon any pier or premises of the Company, whether such person entered or is upon the pier or premises with the permission of an official of the Company or not, to leave such pier or premises immediately.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802477_005" name="8" temporalId="s2_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410802477_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enters or is upon any pier or premises of the Company in contravention of the provisions of paragraph (1); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802477_021" name="b" temporalId="s2_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fails to leave any pier or premises immediately upon being so ordered by any official of the Company pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (7),</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802477_034" name="9" temporalId="s2_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Nothing in this by-law shall apply to any person who is in the employment of the Company.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402532968_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Control of couriers and prohibition of soliciting patronage by others</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802540_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No courier from any hotel, tourist agency or any like organization shall, in the course of his employment as such, enter or be upon the passenger terminal situate on, or on any other part of, any pier of the Company three hours before the expected arrival of any vessel carrying passengers that is to dock alongside such pier or at any other time while any such vessel is alongside the pier unless such courier is wearing a uniform clearly indicating the name of the hotel, tourist agency or other like organization that he represents.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802555_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No hotel, tourist agency or any like organization shall send more than one uniformed courier, or more than such other number of uniformed couriers as the Company may in writing permit in any particular case, to meet any vessel at, or to board any vessel from, any of the Company’s piers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802571_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No courier of any hotel, tourist agency or any like organization shall, in the course of his employment as such, remain upon the passenger terminal situate on, or other part of, any pier of the Company if there is then present at that passenger terminal or on any other part of the same pier any other uniformed courier of the same hotel, tourist agency or organization, whether such other courier entered upon the passenger terminal or other part of the pier before or after him, except where the presence on the passenger terminal or other part of the pier of more than one uniformed courier from the hotel, tourist agency or organization concerned on the occasion in question, is permitted under paragraph (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802586_005" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the presence on any passenger terminal situate on, or on any other part of, any pier of the Company of more than one courier from any hotel, tourist agency or other like organization is on any occasion permitted under paragraph (2), no courier of such hotel, tourist agency or organization shall, in the course of his employment as such, remain upon the passenger terminal or other part of the pier concerned if he together with all other couriers in uniform from the same hotel, tourist agency or organization then present at the passenger terminal or on any other part of the pier, exceed the number permitted as aforesaid.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802618_005" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Every courier of an hotel, tourist agency or like organisation shall, on entering the Company’s pier in the course of his employment as such, have in his possession a list of all passengers whom he is directed to meet and shall, on demand, produce such list for examination—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410802618_013" name="a" temporalId="s3_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to any official of the Company; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802618_021" name="b" temporalId="s3_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to any other person who is authorized in writing by the Company to examine such lists and who produces such authority.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802618_028" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>No courier shall solicit the patronage of any passenger other than a passenger shown on the list in his possession specified in paragraph (5), and no other person shall solicit any passenger to patronize any business whatsoever or in any manner assist the courier of any hotel, tourist agency or any like organization in soliciting, obtaining or attempting to obtain, the patronage of any passenger, whether such passenger’s name appears on the courier’s list or not, but nothing in this paragraph shall be taken to prohibit a courier from giving assistance to any passenger who, not having been solicited by the courier or any person on his behalf, approached the courier with a request for his assistance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802649_005" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Any person who contravenes any of the provisions of this by-law shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402532984_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Removal, etc. of merchandise, cargo and goods without permission prohibited</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802680_012" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall take onto or remove or attempt to take onto or remove from any of the Company’s piers or premises any merchandise, cargo or any other goods of any kind whatsoever except with the permission of an official of the Company.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802680_020" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes any of the provisions of this by-law shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402532999_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Prohibition of lorries entering or leaving premises without permission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802696_019" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No lorry, car, cart or other conveyance not in the service of the Company shall enter or leave or attempt to enter or leave any of the Company’s piers or premises except with the permission of an official of the Company.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802711_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes any of the provisions of this by-law shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533015_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Nuisances prohibited</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802727_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall commit any nuisance of any description on or about any of the Company’s piers or premises.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802727_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes the provisions of this by-law shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533015_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Prohibition of craft making fast, etc. to pier or premises without permission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802742_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No steamer, vessel, launch, boat, junk, sampan or other craft of any description
                whatsoever (other than craft in the service of the
                State
                (including the Offices set up by the Central People’s Government in the Hong Kong
                Special Administrative Region, and the Marine Police, the Fire Services Department,
                the Immigration Department, the Department of Health (Port Health) and the Customs
                and Excise Department of the
                Government))
                        shall—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1985/40">40 of 1985 s. 10</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln76">L.N. 76 of
                    1989</ref>; <ref href="hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 228</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410802742_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>make fast to, or hold on to, or lie alongside, or block the approaches to,
                    any of the Company’s piers or premises; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410802742_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>make fast broadside to the sea wall of the Company’s premises,</content></paragraph><continued>except with the permission of an official of the Company.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802742_033" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes any of the provisions of this
                by-law
                shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533031_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Smoking prohibited</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802758_027" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Save and except in the Company’s main offices no person shall smoke on any part of the Company’s piers or premises.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802758_035" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes the provisions of this by-law shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533093_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Prohibition of interference, etc. with equipment, etc. without permission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802774_019" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall interfere or meddle with or move in any way any of the Company’s mobile equipment or trucks, or make use of its tramlines except with the permission of an official of the Company.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802774_027" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes any of the provisions of this by-law shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802789_004" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this by-law shall apply to any person who is in the employment of the Company.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533093_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Prohibition of bringing cars, etc. onto pier or alongside manoeuvering vessel, without permission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410802805_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall without permission of the General Manager or Deputy General Manager enter upon or bring or attempt to bring any car, carriage, vehicle, launch, lighter or other craft onto or alongside any of the Company’s piers, or alongside any vessel while such vessel is manoeuvering in or out of berth.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802805_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes any of the provisions of this by-law shall be guilty of an offence against these by-laws.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410802805_020" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this by-law shall apply to any person who is in the employment of the Company.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533109_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2023-02-02" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Penalties</heading><content>Any person who is guilty of an offence against these by-laws shall
                                    be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                                    at
                                    level 1 for the first such offence and to a
                                    fine
                                    at
                                    level 1 for every subsequent such
                                    offence.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533124_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in these by-laws shall be taken to restrict, derogate from
                                    or otherwise interfere with any power or duty, or the exercise
                                    or performance of any power or duty, conferred or imposed by or
                                    under any law upon any person in the service of the
                                    State
                                    (including the Offices set up by the Central People’s Government
                                    in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, and the
                                    Government).</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 229</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>