<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1042</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1042</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1042!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402538771_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-09-29">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Sailors Home and
                Mission
                to Seafarers.
                </content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s.
            3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[8 August 1930]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402538803_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-05-25" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Sailors Home and
                Mission
                to Seafarers Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1526884178899_001" name="s1A" temporalId="s1A" startPeriod="2022-09-29" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1A">1A.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance—</leadIn><def name="FormerSection21"><term>former <ref>section 2(1)</ref></term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">原有<ref>第2(1)條</ref></term>) means <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of
            the Sailors Home and Missions to Seamen Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1042">Cap. 1042</ref>) that was in force immediately before the specified date;</def><def name="SpecifiedDate"><term>specified date</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明日期</term>) means the date on which the Sailors Home and Missions to Seamen
            Incorporation (Amendment) Ordinance 2018 (<ref href="/hk/2018/22">22 of 2018</ref>)
            comes into
            operation*.</def><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1644550382884_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Operation date: 25 May
                2018.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402538803_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-05-25" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410813475_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On
                and after the specified date, the body corporate of the committee established under
                the former <ref>section 2(1)</ref> and known as “The Sailors Home and Missions to
                Seamen” immediately before that date is to be known as “The Sailors Home and Mission
                to Seafarers”, and in that name shall have perpetual succession
                and shall and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may have
                and use a common seal.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1989/39">39 of 1989 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410813475_012" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The committee shall be composed of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1526885042406_001" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Archbishop of the Hong Kong Sheng Kung Hui; <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410813475_028" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the person for the time being performing the duties of Director of
                    Marine;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1526885042409_002" name="c" temporalId="s2_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a person nominated by Jardine Matheson Limited with power to such company
                    to fill up any vacancy occurring from time to time; <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410813491_006" name="d" temporalId="s2_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>2 persons who shall be nominated by The Hong Kong General Chamber of
                    Commerce with power to such Chamber to fill up any vacancy occurring in any of
                    such nominees from time to time;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410813491_014" name="e" temporalId="s2_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>2 persons nominated by The
                    Mission
                    to Seafarers with power to the same body to fill up any
                    vacancy occurring in any of such nominees from time to time;
                    </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1526885042412_003" name="f" temporalId="s2_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>a person nominated by Amalgamated Union of Seafarers, Hong Kong if the
                    person is an elected officer for the time being of such union and such union
                    continues to be a trade union duly registered under the Trade Unions Ordinance
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap332">Cap. 332</ref>), with power to such union to fill up
                    any vacancy occurring from time to time; <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1526885042416_004" name="fa" temporalId="s2_2_fa"><num value="fa">(fa)</num><content>a person nominated by Hong Kong Seamen’s Union if the person is an elected
                    officer for the time being of such union and such union continues to be a trade
                    union duly registered under the Trade Unions Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap332">Cap. 332</ref>), with power to such union to fill up any vacancy occurring
                    from time to time; <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1526885042420_005" name="fb" temporalId="s2_2_fb"><num value="fb">(fb)</num><content>a person nominated by Merchant Navy Officers’ Guild—Hong Kong if the person
                    is an elected officer for the time being of such guild and such guild continues
                    to be a trade union duly registered under the Trade Unions Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap332">Cap. 332</ref>), with power to such guild to fill up any
                    vacancy occurring from time to time; <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410813491_030" name="g" temporalId="s2_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>such other persons, one of whom must be
                    a
                    partner of PricewaterhouseCoopers Hong Kong nominated by it to act as the
                    honorary treasurer and secretary of the corporation, not exceeding at any one
                    time 5 in number as may from time to time be co-opted by the
                    other members of the committee with power to the committee to fill up any
                    vacancy occurring from time to time in the co-opted members.
                    </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410813491_037" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The committee shall have such powers and duties and shall hold such meetings as
                are specified in this Ordinance and in the regulations made thereunder.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1526885042424_006" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Despite the amendment of the former <ref>section 2(1)</ref>, the body corporate
                established under that section continues in existence on and after the specified
                date. Accordingly, the rights, obligations and liabilities of that body corporate
                are not affected in any way by the change of the corporate name effected by
                subsection (1). <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1939/33">33 of 1939</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1940/gn840">G.N. 840 of 1940</ref> Supp. <ref>Schedule</ref>; <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402538818_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-29" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Appointment of members of committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1526885326975_002" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>For the purposes of the nomination mentioned in <ref>section 2(2)(c)</ref>, a
                certificate from a director or the company secretary of Jardine Matheson Limited
                that a person has been nominated a member of the committee is sufficient.
                    <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s.
                7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1526885326979_003" name="1A" temporalId="s3_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>For the purposes of the nomination mentioned in <ref>section 2(2)(d)</ref> and
                    <ref>(e)</ref>, a certificate from the chairperson or the chief executive
                officer of The Hong Kong General Chamber of Commerce and a certificate from a member
                of the board of trustees or the secretary general of The Mission to Seafarers
                respectively that a person has been nominated a member of the committee is
                sufficient. <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s.
                    7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1526885326984_004" name="1B" temporalId="s3_1B"><num value="1B">(1B)</num><content>For the purposes of the nomination mentioned in <ref>section 2(2)(f)</ref>,
                    <ref>(fa)</ref> and <ref>(fb)</ref>, a certificate from the chairperson of
                Amalgamated Union of Seafarers, Hong Kong, Hong Kong Seamen’s Union or Merchant Navy
                Officers’ Guild—Hong Kong respectively that a person has been nominated a member of
                the committee is sufficient. <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s.
                        7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1526885326989_005" name="1C" temporalId="s3_1C"><num value="1C">(1C)</num><content>For the purposes of the nomination of the honorary treasurer and secretary
                mentioned in <ref>section 2(2)(g)</ref>, a certificate from the senior partner of
                PricewaterhouseCoopers Hong Kong that a person has been nominated a member of the
                committee is sufficient. <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s.
                        7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410813538_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The certificate of the
                Secretary
                for Transport and Logistics that any person was at the date of the
                certificate or had been at some previous specified date a member of the committee
                shall for all purposes be conclusive evidence of that fact.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1989/39">39 of 1989 s.
                    5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2004/ln125">L.N. 125 of 2004</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2007</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402538834_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-05-25" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Objects of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410813553_026" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall carry on the work and objects heretofore carried on both
                by the trustees of the Sailors Home and by The Missions to Seamen in
                Hong
                Kong before the establishment of the body corporate under the former section
                2(1),
                which, as regards the trustees of the Sailors Home, are the care of officers and men
                of the Mercantile Marine irrespective of their religion and also the provision of a
                suitable institute or home for the seafaring classes and officers and men aforesaid,
                and as regards The Missions to Seamen in Hong Kong are the provision of an institute
                for and the spiritual welfare of the seafaring classes and in pursuance of such work
                and objects the use of every means consistent with the principles and accepted
                practice of the
                Hong
                Kong Sheng Kung Hui; and the corporation shall continue to carry
                on such work and objects.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410813584_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation shall promote the spiritual moral and physical well-being of
                seafarers and their families at home and overseas and in pursuance of such
                objects
                the corporation may use any means consistent with the principles and accepted
                practice of the
                Hong
                Kong Sheng Kung Hui.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1989/39">39 of 1989 s.
            2</ref>. Amended <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402538849_002" name="s4A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4A"><num value="4A">4A.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410813616_004" name="1" temporalId="s4A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to acquire, accept and grant leases of, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what kind or nature soever and wheresoever situate, and also to invest moneys upon mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements or upon the mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation or company, and also to purchase, acquire and possess vessels and other goods and chattels of whatsoever kind or nature.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410813616_012" name="2" temporalId="s4A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation shall further have power by deed under its seal to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, pledge, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of whether for valuable consideration or by way of gift or donation or otherwise any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, funds, moneys, stocks, shares or securities, or other goods and chattels, which are for the time being vested in or belonging to the corporation, and may use and disburse the funds income principal and other moneys belonging to the corporation in pursuance of the objects of the corporation in such manner and upon such terms as the corporation may think fit.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1989/39">39 of 1989 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402538896_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><content>All deeds and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be sealed in the presence of 3 members of the committee and shall be signed by 3 members.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402538896_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-05-25" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Power to make regulations</heading><content>The corporation may, subject to the approval of the
            Chief
            Executive in Council, by a resolution passed by the majority of the
            committee, by regulation provide, from time to time as may in its discretion seem
            desirable, for the administration of the corporation and the management of the premises
            and property of whatever description thereof, with the exception that <ref>regulation
                11</ref> and that part of <ref>regulation 13</ref> which relates to the chaplain
            shall not in any way be altered except with the consent of The
            Mission
            to Seafarers.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402538912_002" name="s7" reason="repealed" startPeriod="2018-05-25" status="repealed" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402538927_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-05-25" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of
            the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other person except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and
            those claiming by, from or under them.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2018/22">22 of 2018 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>