<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1098</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1098</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1098!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-06-02</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402565713_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-06-02">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Permanent Secretary for Education, and
                for matters connected therewith.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 34</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
            2007</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[23 September 1960]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402565791_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><text>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Permanent Secretary for Education
                Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 35</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402565838_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-06-02" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Permanent Secretary for Education constituted a corporation
            sole</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote><text>The person for the time being performing the duties of the office of Permanent
            Secretary for Education shall be a corporation sole, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name of the “Permanent Secretary for
            Education Incorporated” and in that name shall have perpetual succession.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 36</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402565838_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Seal of corporation and authentication thereof, and instruments executed
            thereunder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410869277_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have and may use a common seal and the affixing of the
                seal shall be authenticated by the signature of the occupant of the corporation for
                the time being.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869277_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any instrument purporting to be an instrument duly executed under the seal of
                the corporation shall be received in evidence and shall, unless the contrary is
                proved, be deemed to be an instrument so executed.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402565853_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Power of corporation to act as trustee, etc.</heading><text>The corporation subject to the prior approval of the Chief Secretary for
            Administration may act as trustee of any trust created for purposes or objects connected
            with education or with the work of the Education Bureau and may acquire, take on lease,
            purchase, hold, hire and enjoy any movable or immovable property and may dispose of the
            same.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 37</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402565900_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Power to invest trust funds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410869308_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>The corporation may invest, in accordance with the provisions of the Trustee
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>), any trust funds in the hands of
                    the corporation whether at the time in a state of investment or not:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_1_proviso">Provided that where the occupant
                    of the corporation for the time being considers it impracticable for any reason
                    whatsoever for any such trust funds to be so invested, the corporation may
                    deposit such trust funds in any bank or savings bank approved by the Chief
                    Executive either generally or in any particular case.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/55">55 of 2000 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869308_025" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The powers conferred on the corporation by subsection (1) are in addition to
                the powers (if any) conferred by any trust but shall apply only if and so far as a
                contrary intention is not expressed in any term of any trust, and shall have effect
                subject to any such term.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402565916_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Property of corporation to pass to its successors</heading><text>Where any property or interest therein is vested in the corporation, the same shall,
            unless and until otherwise disposed of by the corporation, pass and devolve to and vest
            in the successors from time to time of the corporation.</text></section><section id="ID_1438402565962_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Certificate as to occupant of corporation</heading><text>If any question arises as to who is or was at any time the occupant of the corporation
            for the time being, a certificate under the hand of the Chief Secretary for
            Administration shall be conclusive evidence for all purposes as to the person who is or
            was such occupant.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/ln126">L.N. 126 of 1995</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402566009_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Accounts, audit and annual report</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410869370_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall keep accounts and records of all transactions in respect
                of any trust funds it administers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869370_019" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director of Accounting Services may give such directions in writing to the
                corporation as he thinks fit with respect to the keeping of accounts and records
                referred to in subsection (1) and the corporation shall comply with any such
                direction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869370_027" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The corporation shall prepare in relation to the trust funds it administers a
                statement of accounts of the funds for each period of 12 months ending on 31 August
                in any year, in such form as the Director of Accounting Services may require in
                writing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869370_035" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A statement of accounts required by subsection (3) shall be signed by the
                person for the time being performing the duties of the office of the Permanent
                Secretary for Education and shall, unless the accounts of the trust funds the
                corporation administers have been audited by an independent accountant under
                    <ref>section 24(4)</ref> of the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap.
                    29</ref>), be submitted by the corporation to the Director of Audit not later
                than 28 February following the end of the period to which it relates, or such later
                date as the Chief Executive may allow.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/55">55 of 2000 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 38</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869386_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the statement of accounts is submitted to the Director of Audit under
                subsection (4), such statement of accounts and the accounts of the funds referred to
                in subsection (1) shall be audited by the Director of Audit, who shall certify the
                statement of accounts together with such report, if any, as he may think fit and
                submit the audited statement of accounts and the report thereon, if any, to the
                corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869401_005" name="6" temporalId="s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A copy of the corporation’s audited statement of accounts, together with the
                Director of Audit’s report, if any, and a report, if any, by the corporation on the
                administration of the fund during the period covered by the audited statement of
                accounts shall be laid upon the table of the Legislative Council not later than 3
                months after the audited statement of account and the report thereon, if any, are
                received by the corporation from the Director of Audit.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1989/21">21 of 1989 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402566025_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-06-02" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving and transitional provisions relating to the Education Reorganization
            (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 2003</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410869448_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this section and <ref>section 10</ref>—</leadIn><def name="AmendedOrdinance"><term>Amended
                    Ordinance</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經修訂條例</term>) means this Ordinance as amended by
                the Education Reorganization (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 2003 (<ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003</ref>);</def><def name="DateOfCommencement"><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline><term>date
                    of
                commencement</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">生效日期</term>) means the date of
                commencement
                of the Education Reorganization (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 2003 (<ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003</ref>).</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869448_025" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A reference in <ref>section 10</ref> to property, rights and liabilities of the
                corporation sole known as the “Director of Education Incorporated” is a reference
                to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410869448_033" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>property and assets of every description (whether tangible or intangible)
                    and rights and liabilities of every description (whether present or future,
                    actual or contingent);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410869448_041" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>property wherever situated or rights and liabilities under the law of any
                    place.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869448_048" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary for Education and
                Manpower Incorporated” constituted by <ref>section 2</ref> of the Amended Ordinance
                is deemed to be a continuation of and the same legal entity as the corporation sole
                known as the “Director of Education Incorporated” constituted by <ref>section
                    2</ref> of this Ordinance before the date of commencement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869464_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The enactment of the Education Reorganization (Miscellaneous Amendments)
                Ordinance 2003 (<ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003</ref>) does not affect the legality
                and validity of anything done by the corporation sole known as the “Director of
                Education Incorporated” before the date of commencement.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 39</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1633678842013_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 28
                February 2003.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402566040_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2007-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Provisions incidental and supplemental to <ref>section 9</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438410869495_018" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The provisions in this section are for the avoidance of doubt and apply without
                limiting the generality of <ref>section 9</ref> and to the extent that they are
                appropriate in the circumstances and consistent with this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869495_026" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>As from the date of commencement, all property, rights and liabilities to which
                the corporation sole known as the “Director of Education Incorporated” was entitled
                or subject immediately before that date are deemed to be vested, without any actual
                transfer or conveyance, in the corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary
                for Education and Manpower Incorporated”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869511_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A reference to the corporation sole known as the “Director of Education
                Incorporated”—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410869511_013" name="a" temporalId="s10_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in any agreement, arrangement or contract or in any deed, bond or any other
                    instrument;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410869511_021" name="b" temporalId="s10_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in any process or other document issued, prepared or employed for the
                    purpose of any proceeding before a court, tribunal or similar body;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410869511_029" name="c" temporalId="s10_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in any other document whatsoever (other than an enactment) relating to or
                    affecting any property, right or liability of the corporation sole known as the
                    “Director of Education Incorporated” which vests in the corporation sole known
                    as the “Permanent Secretary for Education and Manpower Incorporated” by virtue
                    of subsection (2),</content></paragraph><continued>shall be taken as from the date of commencement as referring to the
                corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary for Education and Manpower
                Incorporated”.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869526_011" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The record of property of the corporation sole known as the “Director of
                Education Incorporated” immediately before the date of commencement that is in the
                form of any entry in the books of a bank, company or other corporation is to be
                transferred in those books to the corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary
                for Education and Manpower Incorporated” on the request of the corporation sole
                known as the “Permanent Secretary for Education and Manpower Incorporated” by the
                bank, company or other corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869542_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the corporation sole known as the “Director of Education Incorporated” is
                the trustee of any trust, the corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary for
                Education and Manpower Incorporated” shall effective on the date of commencement
                continue as trustee of that trust in substitution of the corporation sole known as
                the “Director of Education Incorporated”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869542_013" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary for Education and
                Manpower Incorporated” may sue on, recover or enforce any property or right vested
                in it under subsection (2) and may be sued for any liabilities to which it is
                subject under that subsection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869542_021" name="7" temporalId="s10_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary for Education and
                Manpower Incorporated” may sue on, recover or enforce a chose in action vested in it
                under subsection (2) without having to give a notice of transfer to the person bound
                by the chose in action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869557_005" name="8" temporalId="s10_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Any claim by or against the corporation sole known as the “Director of
                Education Incorporated” in any judicial or administrative proceedings that is
                subsisting immediately before the date of commencement does not abate by reason of
                the enactment of the Education Reorganization (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance
                2003 (<ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003</ref>) and may be continued or enforced by or
                against the corporation sole known as the “Permanent Secretary for Education and
                Manpower Incorporated”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869573_005" name="9" temporalId="s10_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>In any judicial or administrative proceedings that is subsisting immediately
                before the date of commencement in which the corporation sole known as the “Director
                of Education Incorporated” is a party, the corporation sole known as the “Permanent
                Secretary for Education and Manpower Incorporated” shall, on and from that date,
                substitute for the corporation sole known as the “Director of Education
                Incorporated” as that
                party.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869573_013" name="10" temporalId="s10_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><leadIn>This section and <ref>section 9</ref> shall not be construed as giving validity,
                continuing in force or giving effect to any or all of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410869573_021" name="a" temporalId="s10_10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>anything that could not have validly been done or given effect to under an
                    enactment amended or repealed by the Education Reorganization (Miscellaneous
                    Amendments) Ordinance 2003 (<ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003</ref>);
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410869589_006" name="b" temporalId="s10_10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>anything done otherwise than in the lawful exercise of a power or
                    performance of a duty.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410869589_013" name="11" temporalId="s10_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>This section and <ref>section 9</ref> are in addition to and not in derogation
                from <ref>section 23</ref> of the Interpretation and General Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 39</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>