<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1027</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1027</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1027!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402533655_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-04-28">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Hop Yat Church of The Church of Christ
                in China.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[22 September 1967]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402533686_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hop Yat Church of The Church of Christ in China Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533686_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of the Hop Yat Church
            approved from time to time by its members in accordance with the constitution for the
            time being in force;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>Corporation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means the body incorporated by <ref>section
                3</ref>;</def><def name="CouncilOfAUnitChurch"><term>Council
                of a Unit
            Church</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">單位堂堂會</term>) means the Council for the time being of a
            Unit Church of the Corporation;</def><def name="HopYatChurch"><term>Hop
                Yat
            Church</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合一堂</term>) means the Hop Yat Church of The Church of
            Christ in China taken as a whole which shall include all its churches schools and other
            establishments and their respective members for the time being;</def><def name="Ministers,Preachers"><term>ministers</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">牧師</term>) and
                <term>preachers</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">宣教師</term>) respectively mean the ministers and
            preachers for the time being employed by the Hop Yat Church;</def><def name="PropertiesManagementCommittee"><term>Properties
                Management
            Committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">管業委員會</term>) means the Properties Management Committee
            for the time being of the Corporation;</def><def name="RepealedOrdinance"><term>repealed
                Ordinance</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已廢除的條例</term>) means the Hop Yat Tong Church of Christ
            Hong Kong Incorporation Ordinance
            (Cap.
            1027,
            1964 Ed.);</def><def name="UnitChurch"><term>Unit
                Church</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">單位堂</term>) means a church establishment of the Hop Yat
            Church.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402533717_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The Council of Representatives for the time being of the Hop Yat Church of The Church
            of Christ in China shall be a body corporate, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    Corporation</i></b>,
            and shall have the name “The Council of Representatives of Hop Yat Church of the Church
            of Christ in China” and in that name shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be
            sued in all courts and tribunals in Hong Kong and shall have and may use a common seal,
            and may from time to time, break, change, alter and make anew the said seal as the
            Corporation may deem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1996/ln235">L.N. 235 of 1996</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533748_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2002-12-27" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Power of Corporation</heading><leadIn>The Corporation shall have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410803928_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to manage, administer and operate the Hong Kong Hop Yat Church, the Kowloon Hop Yat Church, the Kowloon Hop Yat Church School, the Hop Yat Church Kindergarten and the Hop Yat Church Kai Chi School;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803928_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to establish, manage, administer and operate any clinic or clinics, hospital or hospitals, church or churches, school or schools or educational or charitable institution or institutions as the Corporation shall think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803928_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take or otherwise hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/74">74 of 1974 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803944_006" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to acquire, by purchase or otherwise, goods and chattels of what nature or kind soever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803944_014" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong or in any government bonds or on mortgage of any land, buildings, messuages, or tenements in Hong Kong, or in or on debentures, debenture-stocks, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any corporation or company carrying on business in Hong Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803944_022" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, yield up, mortgage, demise, let, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of, any land, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture-stocks, stocks, funds, shares, securities, vessels, goods or chattels for the time being vested in the Corporation, upon such terms as the Corporation may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803944_030" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to act as custodian trustee or manager of any property or fund for any charitable purpose;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803959_006" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>to accept gifts, donations and endowments for all or any of the purposes of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803959_014" name="i" temporalId="s4_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to subscribe to and to grant donations for any charities or educational purposes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410803959_022" name="j" temporalId="s4_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>to develop either alone or jointly with other or others and turn to account any land acquired by the Corporation or in which it is interested, and in particular by laying out and preparing the same for building purposes, constructing, altering, pulling down, decorating, maintaining, fitting up, and improving buildings, and by planting, paving, draining, farming, cultivating and letting on building lease or building agreement, and by advancing money to and entering into contracts and arrangements of all kinds with builders, developers, contractors, land investment companies, land mortgage companies, building estate companies, banks, financiers, owners, lessees, tenants and others, in such manner or on such terms and conditions as the Corporation shall deem fit or expedient and to make applications and obtain orders under the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap. 7</ref>) and to agree and pay such compensation as the Tribunal within the meaning of that Ordinance may recommend or order;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2002/32">32 of 2002 s. 40</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804006_006" name="k" temporalId="s4_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the Corporation shall think fit, and to raise money by public or private subscription; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804006_014" name="l" temporalId="s4_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>generally to do such other things as may appear to be incidental or conducive to the aims and objects of the Corporation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1996/ln235">L.N. 235 of 1996</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402533779_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Vesting of property</heading><leadIn>On the
                commencement<sup>#</sup>
            of this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410804037_028" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all those pieces or parcels of ground specified in the second column of the
                    <ref>Schedule</ref>, together with all rights, easements and appurtenances
                thereto belonging, shall vest in the Corporation for the unexpired residue of the
                respective terms of years created by the Crown leases and Conditions of Grant
                specified opposite thereto in the third column of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, subject
                to payment of the rent and performance of the covenants and conditions reserved by
                and contained in the said Crown leases and Conditions of Grant; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804053_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Corporation shall succeed to all other property, rights, privileges,
                obligations and liabilities of the trustees for the time being of the Hop Yat Tong
                Church of Christ Hong Kong incorporated under the repealed Hop Yat Tong Church of
                Christ Hong Kong Incorporation Ordinance
                (Cap.
                1027,
                1964 Ed.).</content></paragraph><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1649229186616_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><sup>#</sup> Commencement date: 22 September 1967.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533795_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Members of the Corporation</heading><leadIn>The Corporation shall consist of the following members—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410804084_033" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all ministers and preachers for the time being of the Hop Yat Church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804084_041" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all deacons and deaconesses for the time being of the Hop Yat Church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804084_049" name="c" temporalId="s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the chairman, vice-chairman, and secretary for the time being of the Council of each Unit Church; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804084_057" name="d" temporalId="s6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>representatives for the time being from the Council of each Unit Church, which shall be entitled to have one elected member in respect of every 100 adult-members registered with such Unit Church to represent it in the Corporation: provided that the maximum number of the representatives of each Unit Church shall not exceed 5.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402533811_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Council of Unit Church</heading><content>Each Unit Church shall have a Council, and the organization, powers and duties of such Council shall be prescribed by the constitution for the time being of the Hop Yat Church.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402533842_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Existing constitution to be constitution of Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410804131_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The existing constitution of the Hop Yat Church shall be the constitution of the Corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410804131_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Amendments to the constitution shall be proposed in writing to the Council of Representatives by 2 deacons and 3 elected members of one or more Councils of the Unit Churches or by 10 voting members of the Church, and no amendments shall be made unless such amendment or amendments shall have been passed by three-fourths of the members of the Council of Representatives present at the meeting convened for the purpose.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410804131_020" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any such amendment shall not come into operation until it has been published in the Church bulletin 4 consecutive weeks for the information of the members and no objection thereto has been raised within 30 days from the first publication.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410804146_005" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The constitution shall not be amended without the consent in writing of the Registrar of Companies.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533842_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410804162_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Corporation shall forward to the Registrar of Companies for registration the
                following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410804162_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the registered office of the Corporation and any
                    change thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804162_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the constitution and any amendment thereto, certified as correct
                    by the Chairman or Vice-Chairman of the Corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804162_028" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a list of the names and addresses of the members for the time being of the
                    Corporation and any change therein, certified as correct by the Chairman or
                    Vice-Chairman of the Corporation; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410804162_036" name="d" temporalId="s9_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the name and address of any person appointed under <ref>section 10</ref> to
                    sign deeds, documents and other instruments, and any change therein certified as
                    correct by the Chairman or Vice-Chairman of the Corporation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410804162_043" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notification in accordance with subsection (1) shall be made within 28 days of
                the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance or within 28 days of any amendment, change or appointment as the
                case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410804178_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section upon
                payment of such fee as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section
                    26</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for
                the inspection of a document.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410804178_013" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Corporation shall pay such fees for registering any document with any
                public registry as may be payable under the regulations made under <ref>section
                    26</ref> of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>) for
                the registration of a document with the Registrar of Companies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1968/ln31">L.N. 31
                        of 1968</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1649229290838_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 22 September
                1967.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402533857_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Seal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410804209_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The seal of the Corporation shall not be affixed to any deed, document or instrument except by the authority of a resolution of the Corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410804209_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the Corporation shall be signed by any 3 of the 6 members of the Properties Management Committee of the Corporation and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402533904_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402533904_003" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap1027/s5">s.
                5</ref>]<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><content>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="446">
                
                <col width="10%"></col>
                
                <col width="48%"></col>
                
                <col width="5%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="37%"></col>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="valign_bottom">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Item</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="valign_bottom">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Description of
                            property</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Crown lease and
                            Conditions
                            of
                            Grant</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_5">
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">1.</center>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Section D of
                            Inland Lot No.
                            590</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_9 align_justified first_line_indent_0">Crown lease
                            dated<br></br>18
                            August
                            1859</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">2.</center>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">1/11th
                            undivided share in Section C of Sub<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 1</ref> of
                            Section B of Quarry Bay Marine Lot No.
                            4</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_9 align_justified first_line_indent_0">Crown lease
                            dated<br></br>31
                            December
                            1932</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">3.</center>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">1/7th undivided
                            share in Sub<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                5</ref> of Section B of Kowloon Inland Lot No.
                            615</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_9 align_justified first_line_indent_0">Crown lease
                            dated
                            <br></br>30
                            December
                            1902</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">4.</center>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Remaining
                            Portion of Kowloon Inland Lot No.
                            6591</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_9 align_justified first_line_indent_0">Conditions of
                            Grant No.
                            5259</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_5">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">5.</center>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Remaining
                            Portion of Kowloon Inland Lot No.
                            7266</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_9 align_justified first_line_indent_0">Conditions of
                            Grant No.
                            5973</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            
        </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of
        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>