<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1052</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1052</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1052!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-05-05</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402542235_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-05-05">
            <content>To make amended provision for the incorporation of the Trustees of the Union
                Church in Hong Kong.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 May 1962]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402542281_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Union Church Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402542297_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-05" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Adherent"><term>adherent</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">信徒</term>) means a person who has been listed as an
            adherent in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 8</ref>;</def><def name="Chairman,ViceChairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) and
                <term>Vice-Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">副主席</term>) mean respectively the
            chairman and
            vice-chairman of the committee of management appointed in accordance with the provisions
            of subsection (4) of <ref>section
            11</ref>;</def><def name="Church"><term>Church</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">教會</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">該教會</term>) means
            the Minister and members of Union Church, Kennedy Road, Hong Kong, and the buildings
            thereat;</def><def name="Committee"><term>committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">委員會</term>) means the committee of management elected
            in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 11</ref> including any person co-opted
            to be a member thereof;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>Corporation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means “The Trustees of the Union Church in
            Hong Kong” incorporated under <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="Deacon"><term>deacon</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">執事</term>) means a member of the Deacons’ Court;</def><def name="DeaconsCourt"><term>Deacons’
                Court</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">執事會</term>) means the Deacons’ Court established in
            accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 13</ref>;</def><def name="GeneralMeeting"><term>general
                meeting</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">大會</term>) means a general meeting of the members of
            the Church;</def><def name="Member"><term>member</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">成員</term>) means any person who has been enrolled as a
            full member or as an associate member in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section
                7</ref> and who is still so enrolled;</def><def name="Minister"><term>Minister</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">牧師</term>) means the minister of Union Church or, if at
            any time there shall be more than one minister, the senior minister in Hong Kong,
            appointed in accordance with the provisions of subsection (1) or (2) of <ref>section
                15</ref> or an acting minister appointed in accordance with the provisions of
            subsection (3) of
            that
            section;</def><def name="Prescribed"><term>prescribed</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訂明</term>) means prescribed by rules made under
                <ref>section 16</ref>;</def><def name="Secretary,Treasurer"><term>secretary</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">秘書</term>) and
                <term>treasurer</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">司庫</term>) mean respectively the honorary secretary and
            the honorary treasurer elected in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section
                12</ref>;</def><def name="VotingMember"><term>voting
                member</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有表決權的成員</term>) means a member who, in accordance with
            the provisions of subsection (2) of <ref>section 10</ref>, is entitled to vote at a
            general meeting of the Church.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402542313_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The Trustees for the time being of the Union Church in Hong Kong shall be a body
            corporate and shall have the corporate name “The Trustees of the Union Church in Hong
            Kong”, and in that name shall have perpetual succession and shall and may sue and be
            sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may have and use a common seal, and may
            from time to time, break, change, alter and make anew the said seal as to the
            Corporation may seem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402542328_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of Corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819388_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation shall have power to acquire, accept and grant leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate, and also to build, rebuild, alter, vary, renew, maintain and repair any building, messuage or tenements, and also to invest moneys upon mortgages of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements, or in debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation, or company, and also to purchase, acquire and possess goods and chattels of what nature and kind soever and to sue, carry on and defend all legal arbitration and other proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819403_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1974/74">74 of 1974 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819403_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Corporation shall further have power by deed under its seal to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, pledge, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities or goods and chattels whatsoever, which are for the time being vested in or belonging to the Corporation, upon such terms as to the Corporation may seem fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542344_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Execution of deeds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819434_034" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the
                Corporation shall be sealed in the presence of two or more of the trustees, and
                shall also be signed by the Chairman or, if he shall be absent from Hong Kong or
                otherwise for any good reason unable to act, by the Vice-Chairman, and by such
                trustees so present, and such signing shall be and be taken as sufficient evidence
                of the due sealing thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819450_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The seal shall be kept in the custody of the Chairman of Trustees elected in
                accordance with the provisions of subsection (6) of <ref>section 14</ref> or, if no
                Chairman of Trustees shall have been elected or if he shall be absent from Hong Kong
                or otherwise for any good reason be unable to act, in the custody of the person who
                has been trustee for the longest period.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402542344_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Trusts</heading><content>The Corporation shall hold the property vested in it and all property subsequently acquired by it and any other premises which may be substituted therefor and all the other property of the Church upon trust for the purpose of a church for the public worship of God and for preaching the Gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ according to the principles and usages of Protestant Christians, and for the sole object of spreading the knowledge of Christ, as shall seem most agreeable to the Word of God and not for the purpose of introducing or supporting presbyterianism, independency, episcopacy or any other form of church order and government about which there may be difference of opinion, but under such form of church government as the members shall direct, and also, subject to such direction, for the instruction of children and adults, and for religious and philanthropic purposes and for the providing of a residence for the Minister, provided that the Church shall always accept as its primary standards the Word of God as witnessed to by the scriptures of the Old and New Testaments, the Trinitarian Doctrine of the Christian Faith and the Sacraments of Baptism and the Lord’s Supper.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402542359_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-05" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Members</heading><leadIn>Every member of the Church shall have been baptized in or in accordance with the
            rites of a Christian Church and shall be either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410819512_019" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>a full member, that is to say, a person who has been received into the Church
                by—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410819512_027" name="i" temporalId="s7_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>profession of faith;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410819512_035" name="ii" temporalId="s7_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>letter of transfer from another Christian Church; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410819512_043" name="iii" temporalId="s7_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>re-affirmation of faith; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819512_050" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an associate member, that is to say, a person who is a regular member of a
                Christian Church other than the Church and who signifies his desire to worship with
                and to help and support the Church while he is in Hong Kong but still to retain his
                membership of his own church,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>who has been enrolled as such in such manner as may be prescribed:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_proviso">Provided that, subject and in such manner as
            may be prescribed, any person who was on the mailing list of the Church immediately
            before the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance may be so enrolled.</proviso><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1629879814006_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 May
                1962.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402542375_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Adherents</heading><text>Any person who, though not a member of a Christian Church, wishes to take part in the
            worship and other activities of the Church while he is resident in Hong Kong may,
            subject as may be prescribed, be listed as an adherent.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402542391_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>General meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819559_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The annual general meeting of the Church shall be held in the month of March in each year or as soon as is practicable thereafter.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819559_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A special general meeting may be called at any time by the Minister or by the
                committee and shall be called by the
                Minister if he shall receive a requisition, stating the purpose
                for which the meeting is required and signed by not less than forty voting
                members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819559_026" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notice of every general meeting shall be given at each service held in the Church on not less than two Sundays immediately preceding such meeting at the usual time in the usual manner for giving notices during divine service and the meeting shall be held not earlier than the Wednesday next following the second of such Sundays.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819559_034" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Save as may be otherwise prescribed, no motion shall be carried at a general meeting unless it shall receive the votes of not less than two-thirds of the voting members present and voting plus one.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542391_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Business at a general meeting</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819590_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>At every general meeting, the chair shall be taken by the Chairman or, in his absence by the Vice-Chairman or, if both the Chairman and the Vice-Chairman shall be absent, by such person as the meeting shall elect as chairman for the purpose of such meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819590_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>At every general meeting every member shall be entitled to attend and to speak at such meeting but only a member who is over the age of eighteen years and who has been enrolled as a member for not less than six months shall be entitled to vote at a general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819590_020" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>The quorum for a general meeting shall be such number as may be prescribed or, if no quorum is prescribed, forty voting members:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s10_3_proviso">Provided that if at a general meeting there is not a quorum, the Chairman shall adjourn the meeting for a period of not less than three weeks and notice of such adjourned meeting shall be given in accordance with the provisions of subsection (3) of <ref>section 9</ref> and at such adjourned meeting the quorum shall be the number of voting members there present.</proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542422_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Committee of management</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819622_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall be a committee of management which shall be responsible for the
                management of the Church property and the temporal affairs of the Church.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819622_019" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The committee shall consist of twelve voting members, or such other number as
                may be prescribed, elected at the annual general meeting together with the following
                ex-officio members—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410819622_027" name="a" temporalId="s11_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Minister;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819622_035" name="b" temporalId="s11_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the secretary; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819622_043" name="c" temporalId="s11_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the treasurer.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819622_050" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The committee shall hold office from the first day of the month next following
                the date of its election until the date on which a new committee elected by the
                Church at its annual general meeting shall assume office.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819622_058" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>At its first meeting, the committee shall elect from its elected members a
                chairman and vice-chairman and at any subsequent meeting may elect therefrom a
                temporary chairman or a temporary vice-chairman in substitution for any chairman or
                vice-chairman so elected if either such officer shall be absent from Hong Kong or
                otherwise for any good reason be unable to act.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819637_005" name="5" temporalId="s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The committee shall have power to co-opt to the committee any voting
                member.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542453_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819653_058" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall be an honorary secretary and an honorary treasurer who shall be
                voting members elected by the Church at its annual general meeting and who shall
                hold office from the first day of the month next following the date of such election
                until replaced by other officers similarly elected.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819668_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If an honorary secretary or an honorary treasurer shall be absent from Hong
                Kong or otherwise for any good reason be unable to act the committee may elect a
                member of the committee to hold such office during his absence or inability.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of
                        1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542453_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Deacons’ Court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819684_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall be a Deacons’ Court which shall be responsible with the Minister for all matters relating to the spiritual welfare of the Church and shall carry out such other duties as may be prescribed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819684_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Deacons’ Court shall consist of the Minister and such other persons as shall be nominated and approved as deacons or received as deacons in accordance with the provisions of subsection (3).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819684_020" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Every deacon shall be either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410819684_028" name="a" temporalId="s13_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>nominated by the Deacons’ Court, subject to approval by a general meeting of the Church in such manner as may be prescribed, and inducted as a deacon by the Minister; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819684_036" name="b" temporalId="s13_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if he had previously been elected and received into any other Christian church in an office equivalent to that of deacon, received as a deacon, by the Deacons’ Court.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819700_005" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>No person shall be nominated to be a deacon or be received as a deacon unless he is a voting member and a communicant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819700_013" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Every member who is inducted as a deacon or is received as a deacon shall continue to hold office as a deacon until he ceases to be a member or resigns.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819700_021" name="6" temporalId="s13_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Minister shall act as Moderator at every meeting of the Deacons’ Court at which he is present and, if he is absent, a deacon, who shall be selected by the deacons present at such meeting, shall act as Moderator.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819700_029" name="7" temporalId="s13_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>There shall be a clerk to the Deacons’ Court who shall be elected at the first meeting of the Deacons’ Court held after the annual general meeting of the Church and who shall be responsible for the summoning of meetings of the Deacons’ Court and the maintenance of the minutes of the Deacons’ Court and for carrying out such other duties as the Deacons’ Court may decide.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819715_005" name="8" temporalId="s13_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Deacons’ Court shall meet at intervals of not less than two months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542469_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Trustees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819809_059" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall be not more than ten and not less than three trustees.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819809_067" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Each trustee shall be a voting member and shall be elected by the members of
                the Church at a general meeting in such manner as shall be prescribed and shall hold
                office until he ceases to be a member, resigns or has been absent from Hong Kong for
                a continuous period of not less than two years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819824_005" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the number of trustees falls below four, at least one additional trustee
                shall be elected as soon as is practicable thereafter.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819824_013" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>When a person has been elected to be a trustee, the secretary shall, within
                three weeks after his election or within such further time as may be allowed by the
                Chief Executive, furnish to the Chief Executive such evidence as the Chief Executive
                may require of the election of such person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819824_021" name="5" temporalId="s14_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A notification in the Gazette under the hand of the Chief Secretary for
                Administration that such evidence has been furnished to the Chief Executive by the
                secretary shall be conclusive evidence of such election.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of
                        1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of
                        1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819840_005" name="6" temporalId="s14_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The trustees, in such manner as they may consider appropriate, may from time to
                time elect one of their number to be Chairman of Trustees for the purpose of
                summoning and presiding at meetings of trustees.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542500_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Minister</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819887_011" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Each Minister, on first appointment, shall be selected at a general meeting in
                such manner as may be prescribed, on the joint recommendation of the Deacons’ Court
                and the committee, meeting together and, on such selection, shall be appointed by
                the committee upon such terms as may be agreed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819887_019" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The appointment of a Minister may be renewed by the committee on the joint
                recommendation of the Deacons’ Court and of the committee, meeting together, subject
                to approval by a general meeting, in such manner as may be prescribed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819887_027" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Deacons’ Court and the committee meeting together may appoint any person to
                act as Minister during the absence from Hong Kong or inability to perform his
                duties, through illness or for any other cause, of any person appointed as Minister
                under this section.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542500_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410819918_003" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Deacons’ Court and the committee, meeting together, may make rules providing for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_011" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the selection and appointment of ministers of the Church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_019" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the election of trustees, members of the committee and office-bearers of the Church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_027" name="c" temporalId="s16_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the enrolment of full members, associate members and adherents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_035" name="d" temporalId="s16_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the preparation of a list of full members, associate members and adherents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_043" name="e" temporalId="s16_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the removal from the list of full members, associate members or adherents, of the name of any person thereon;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_051" name="f" temporalId="s16_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the keeping of registers of full members, associate members, adherents and communicants and of baptisms and marriages;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_059" name="g" temporalId="s16_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the holding of joint meetings of the Deacons’ Court and of the committee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_067" name="h" temporalId="s16_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the holding of meetings of the committee and the quorum and the conduct of business at such meetings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_075" name="i" temporalId="s16_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the holding of general meetings and the quorum and conduct of business at such meetings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_083" name="j" temporalId="s16_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>the appointment of any additional officers and servants of the Church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819918_091" name="k" temporalId="s16_1_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>fees to be charged by the committee to members, adherents and non-members;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819934_006" name="l" temporalId="s16_1_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>the keeping of accounts and of moneys received by or on behalf of the Church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410819934_014" name="m" temporalId="s16_1_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>generally, the carrying into effect of the provisions of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410819934_021" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>Any rule made in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be signed by the secretary and by the clerk to the Deacons’ Court and shall be displayed in a prominent place in the Church premises for not less than one month and shall not come into operation until the expiry of such period:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s16_2_proviso">Provided that any rule may be revoked at a general meeting.</proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402542515_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Property to be held in trust for London Missionary Society in certain events</heading><content>In the event of the Corporation failing to use, occupy and enjoy the present buildings of the Church, or any other premises which may be substituted therefor, for the purposes mentioned in <ref>section 6</ref>, for a period of more than two years at any one time, then the Corporation shall hold the said premises with the erections and buildings thereon, and all moneys, goods and chattels then belonging to the Corporation, in trust for the London Missionary Society Incorporated under the London Missionary Society Incorporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1033">Cap. 1033</ref>), absolutely.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402542531_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/32">32 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>