<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1061</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1061</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1061!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-12-22</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402546961_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-22">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Hong Kong Playground
                Association.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[21 September 1951]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402546977_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Playground Association Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/26">26 of 1974 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402546977_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Association"><term>Association</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">協會</term>) means the Hong Kong Playground
            Association;</def><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of the Hong Kong
            Playground Association approved from time to time by its members for the time
            being.</def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/26">26 of 1974 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402546993_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The Association shall be a body corporate and in that name shall have perpetual
            succession and shall and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and may have and
            use a common seal, and may from time to time break, change, alter and make anew the said
            seal as to the Association may deem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402547008_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Objects of the Association</heading><text>The objects of the Association shall be to provide recreational facilities for the
            children and youth of Hong Kong for whom no facilities or no adequate facilities exist
            and generally to promote their welfare.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/26">26 of 1974 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402547024_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Powers of the Association</heading><leadIn>The Association shall have full power to do all such acts and things as may be
            necessary or expedient for or conducive to the carrying out of the aims and objects of
            the Association under its constitution and without prejudice to the generality of such
            power the Association shall have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410831727_033" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire by purchase, lease, exchange or otherwise hold and enjoy land,
                buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever
                situate whether in Hong Kong or elsewhere;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410831743_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to acquire by purchase or otherwise goods and chattels of what nature or kind
                soever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410831743_014" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong or in any government bonds
                or on mortgage of any land, buildings, messuages or tenements in Hong Kong or
                elsewhere or in or on debentures, debenture-stocks, stock, funds, shares or
                securities of any corporation or company carrying on business in Hong Kong or
                elsewhere; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410831743_022" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, yield up, mortgage, demise, let,
                reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any land, buildings, messuages,
                tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture-stock, funds, securities, goods and
                chattels vested in the Association upon such terms as the Association may deem
                fit.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402547039_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Members</heading><content>The Association shall consist of such members as may be provided by its constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547055_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Existing constitution to become constitution of Association</heading><content>The existing constitution of the unincorporated Association shall be the constitution of the Association but the same may be changed or amended by the Association at any time and from time to time in accordance with the provisions of the constitution for the time being in force.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547071_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Filing of constitution and names of executive members</heading><content>A copy of the constitution of the Association and of any amendment thereto, and a list of the names and addresses of the members of the executive committee of the Association for the time being, certified in each case as correct by the chairman of the executive committee or by the secretary of the Association shall be forwarded to the Registrar of Companies for registration.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547086_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Registration fee</heading><content>The Association shall pay such fee for registering any document with any public registry as may be payable under any enactment relating thereto.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547086_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Inspection and search fee</heading><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered by the Association in pursuance of <ref>section 8</ref>, upon payment of such fee as may be payable under any enactment relating thereto.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547102_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Sealing of deeds</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the Association shall be signed by the chairman of the executive committee and the secretary of the Association or by such other person or persons as the executive committee from time to time appoint and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547117_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>