<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1063</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1063</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1063!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-05-12</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402547305_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-05-12">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Trustees of the Church of Christ in
                China, Wanchai
                Church.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[25 January 1952]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er2">E.R. 2 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402547320_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Church of Christ in China, Wanchai Church, Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547320_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-12" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Description and incorporation</heading><text>The trustees for the time being of the Church of Christ in China, Wanchai Church,
            shall be a body corporate, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name “The Trustees of the Church of
            Christ in China, Wanchai Church”, and in that name shall have perpetual succession and
            shall and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and shall and may have and use
            a common seal, and may from time to time break, change, alter and make anew the said
            seal as to the corporation may seem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402547336_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410832148_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate, and also to invest moneys upon mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements or upon the mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation, company or person, and also to purchase, acquire and possess vessels and other goods and chattels of what nature and kind soever.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410832164_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation shall further have power by deed under its seal to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities, or vessels or other goods and chattels, which are for the time being vested in or belonging to the corporation, upon such terms as to the corporation may seem fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402547351_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Number of trustees</heading><content>The number of trustees shall not be less than two or more than four.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547367_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Vacation of office by trustees</heading><content>The office of any trustee shall be automatically vacated if such trustee shall die or shall resign his office or if a resolution be passed at a general meeting of members of the said Wanchai Church requiring the resignation of such trustee or if his term of office shall come to an end.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547383_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>New trustees: their appointment and tenure of office</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410832226_011" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>New trustees shall be proposed for election by committee at a general meeting
                of the members of the said Wanchai Church and when elected shall, subject to the
                provisions of <ref>section 5</ref>, hold office for the term of five years from the
                date of such election. Trustees whose term of office has expired shall be eligible
                for re-election.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410832226_019" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Whenever any person or persons are appointed as trustees, such person or
                persons shall, within three weeks after their respective appointments or within such
                further time as may be allowed by the Chief Executive, furnish to the Chief
                Executive satisfactory evidence of their appointments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410832242_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A notification in the Gazette under the hand of the Chief Secretary for
                Administration that such evidence has been furnished to the Chief Executive by such
                persons shall be conclusive evidence of such appointments.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of
                        1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402547383_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Execution of deeds</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the said corporation shall be sealed in the presence of two trustees, and shall also be signed by the same two trustees so present, and such signing shall be and be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing thereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547398_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-05-12" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Committee of management</heading><content>A committee of management, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    committee</i></b>, shall be elected from among and at a meeting of the said
            Wanchai Church and those elected shall appoint a chairman, a vice-chairman, a secretary
            and a treasurer from those elected. One third of the committee shall retire annually but
            shall be eligible for re-election.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547414_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Appointment and removal of clergyman or pastor</heading><content>The committee may appoint a clergyman or pastor to perform and carry on divine worship and the services usual in the other churches of the Church of Christ in China and may also remove him and appoint a successor and all matters connected with the religious services of the said Wanchai Church shall be under the immediate direction of the clergyman or pastor subject to the control of the committee.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547429_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Committee to operate and maintain a vernacular school</heading><content>It shall be lawful for the committee to operate and maintain a vernacular school for the purpose of education under the name of “Wanchai Church School” and to collect tuition fees and to employ teachers subject to the provisions of the Education Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap279">Cap. 279</ref>) and any enactments made thereunder.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547429_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Committee to control temporal affairs</heading><leadIn>The temporal affairs of the said Wanchai Church shall be managed, directed and governed by the committee:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s11_proviso">Provided however that the members of the committee shall not be deemed personally liable for any payments of money in excess of that provided or available for the purposes of the said Wanchai Church.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402547445_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Power of committee to provide by regulation</heading><leadIn>The committee may by regulation provide for the following matters—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410832320_026" name="a" temporalId="s12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the number, qualification and disqualification of members of the committee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832320_034" name="b" temporalId="s12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the holding of meetings of the committee and the conduct of business thereat;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832320_042" name="c" temporalId="s12_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the temporary appointment of a clergyman or pastor during the absence from any cause of the substantive holder of that post;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832320_050" name="d" temporalId="s12_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the election and tenure of office of an auditor and the filling of casual vacancies among the committee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832320_058" name="e" temporalId="s12_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the appointment, tenure of office, salary and duties of any organist, verger or other officer or servant as the committee may think necessary or expedient;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832336_006" name="f" temporalId="s12_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the keeping of a register of members of the said Wanchai Church and of baptisms, marriages and burials;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832336_014" name="g" temporalId="s12_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the holding of meetings of members, the right of voting and the taking and recording of the votes at such meetings and the conduct of business thereat;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832336_022" name="h" temporalId="s12_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the appropriation, allotment, arrangement and use of the sittings in the said Wanchai Church;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832336_030" name="i" temporalId="s12_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the rents and subscriptions (if any) to be paid for sittings in the said Wanchai Church and the mode of collection thereat, the fees to be taken for baptisms, marriages and burials or other services and the collection and disposition of money, offerings, offertories and donations;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832336_038" name="j" temporalId="s12_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>the keeping of accounts of moneys received and expended by the committee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832336_046" name="k" temporalId="s12_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>the erection and maintenance of monuments, tablets, or other memorials in the said Wanchai Church or in the precincts thereof and the fees to be taken therefor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410832336_054" name="l" temporalId="s12_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>all other matters relating to the temporal affairs of the said Wanchai Church or of the committee otherwise than where specifically provided for by the Ordinance.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402547461_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Regulations not binding until approved</heading><content>No regulations made by the committee under <ref>section 12</ref> shall be binding on the members of the said Wanchai Church until such regulations have been passed by a majority of members present and voting at a general meeting of members.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547476_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Proof of membership</heading><content>A certificate under the hand of the chairman of the committee that any person therein named is a member of the said Wanchai Church shall be accepted for all purposes as sufficient proof of the fact that such person is a member of the said Wanchai Church.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402547523_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>