<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1057</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1057</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1057!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402543202_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-15">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Hong Kong Council of Social
                Service.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[9 March 1951]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402543217_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Council of Social Service Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543217_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Constitution"><term>constitution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the constitution of the Hong Kong
            Council of Social Service approved from time to time by its members for the time
            being.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402543249_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The Hong Kong Council of Social Service shall be a body corporate, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and in that name shall have perpetual succession and shall
            and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong Kong and may have and use a common seal,
            and may from time to time break, change, alter and make anew the said seal as to the
            corporation may deem fit. </text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402543249_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><leadIn>The corporation shall have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410823834_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire, by purchase, lease, exchange or otherwise, hold and enjoy land,
                buildings, messuages
                or
                tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate, whether in Hong
                Kong or elsewhere;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823834_027" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to acquire, by purchase or otherwise, goods and chattels of what nature or kind
                soever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823834_035" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong<inline class="width_3"> </inline>or in any government bonds, or on mortgage of any land, buildings,
                messuages or tenements in Hong Kong or elsewhere, or in or on debentures,
                debenture-stocks, stock, funds, shares or securities of any corporation or company
                carrying on business in Hong Kong or elsewhere; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410823849_006" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, yield up, mortgage, demise, let,
                reassign, transfer, or otherwise dispose of, any land, buildings, messuages,
                tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture-stock, funds, securities, goods and
                chattels vested in the corporation, upon such terms as the corporation may deem
                fit.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402543264_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Members</heading><content>The corporation shall consist of such members as provided by its constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543264_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Existing constitution to become constitution of corporation</heading><content>The existing constitution of the unincorporated Hong Kong Council of Social Service shall be the constitution of the corporation, but the same may be changed or amended by the corporation at any time and from time to time in accordance with the provisions of the constitution for the time being in force.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543280_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Filing of constitution and names of executive members</heading><content>A copy of the constitution of the corporation and of any amendment thereto, and a list of the names and addresses of the members of the executive committee of the corporation for the time being, certified in each case as correct by the chairman of the executive committee or by the secretary of the corporation, shall be forwarded to the Registrar of Companies for registration.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543295_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Registration fee</heading><content>The corporation shall pay such fee for registering any document with any public registry as may be payable under any enactment relating thereto.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543311_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Inspection and search fee</heading><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered by the corporation in pursuance of <ref>section 7</ref>, upon payment of such fee as may be payable under any enactment relating thereto.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543327_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Sealing of deeds</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be signed by the chairman of the executive committee and the secretary of the corporation or by such other person or persons as the executive committee shall from time to time appoint and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402543327_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/41">41 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>