<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1033</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1033</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1033!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-06-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402536197_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-06-08">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Senior Missionary in Hong Kong of the
                London Missionary Society.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[31 October 1891]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2023/er2">E.R. 2 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402536213_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>London Missionary Society Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536213_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-06-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Incorporation of the Senior Missionary in Hong Kong of the London Missionary
            Society</heading><leadIn>The holder of the appointment of Senior Missionary in Hong Kong of the London
            Missionary Society shall be a body corporate, hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    said corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name of “The Senior Missionary in
            Hong Kong of the London Missionary Society”, and by that name shall have perpetual
            succession, and shall and may sue and be sued in all courts, and shall and may have and
            use a common seal, and the said seal may break, change, alter, and make anew as to the
            said corporation may seem fit; and the said corporation shall have full power to
            acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold, and enjoy any lands, buildings,
            messuages, or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate in Hong
            Kong, and also to invest moneys on mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages, or
            tenements in Hong Kong or upon the mortgages or debentures, stocks, funds, shares, or
            securities of any corporation or company carrying on business or having an office in
            Hong Kong and also to purchase and acquire all manner of goods and chattels
            whatsoever;
            and the said corporation is hereby further empowered by deed under its seal, to grant,
            sell, convey, assign, surrender and yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer, or
            otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages and tenements, mortgages,
            debentures, stocks and securities, goods and chattels, vested in the said corporation,
            on such terms as to the said corporation may seem fit:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s2_proviso">Provided that due notice of appointment as
            such Senior Missionary in Hong Kong, and of the proof thereof having been placed in the
            hands of the Chief Executive, shall be given in the Gazette.</proviso><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/51">51 of
                1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1912/1">1 of 1912
            </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1912/12">12 of 1912 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of
                1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536229_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Use of seal</heading><content>All deeds, documents, and other instruments requiring the seal of the said
            corporation shall be sealed with the seal of the said corporation in the presence of the
            said Senior Missionary or his attorney duly authorized, and shall also be signed by him
            or his attorney, and such signing shall be and be taken as sufficient evidence of the
            due sealing of such deeds, documents, and other instruments.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/51">51 of
                1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1912/1">1 of 1912
            </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1912/2">2 of 1912 </ref>Schedule)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402536275_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-06-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1950/37">37 of 1950 </ref>Schedule. Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/33">33 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>