<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1108</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1108</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1108!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-01-27</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402572858_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-01-27">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the Hong Kong Conference of Youth
                Organizations.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[25 April 1963]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402572873_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hong Kong Conference of Youth Organizations Incorporation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402572889_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Chairman"><term>chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the chairman of the corporation
            appointed in accordance with the regulations of the Hong Kong Conference of Youth
            Organizations;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>corporation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means the Hong Kong Conference of Youth
            Organizations incorporated under <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="Regulations"><term>regulations</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">規例</term>) means the regulations of the Hong Kong
            Conference of Youth Organizations approved from time to time by its members for the time
            being in accordance with the regulations for the time being in operation.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402572889_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Incorporation</heading><text>The members of the Hong Kong Conference of Youth Organizations shall be a body
            corporate and shall have the name “Hong Kong Conference of Youth Organizations”, and in
            that name shall have perpetual succession and may sue and be sued in all courts in Hong
            Kong and shall have and may use a common seal and may from time to time, break, change,
            alter and make anew the said seal as the corporation may deem fit.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402572904_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Power of corporation</heading><leadIn>The corporation shall have full power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410886187_033" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take or otherwise hold and enjoy any
                lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and
                wheresoever situate;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/74">74 of 1974 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886203_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to acquire, by purchase or otherwise, goods and chattels of what nature or kind
                soever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886203_014" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to invest moneys on deposit in any bank in Hong Kong or in any Government bonds
                or on mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements in Hong Kong or in or
                on debentures, debenture-stocks, funds, shares or securities of any corporation or
                company carrying on business in Hong Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886203_022" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, yield up, mortgage, demise, let,
                reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of, any lands, or buildings, messuages,
                tenements, mortgages, debentures, debenture-stocks, funds, securities, vessels,
                goods and chattels for the time being vested in the corporation, upon such terms as
                the corporation may deem fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886203_030" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to erect any buildings, messuages or tenements and effect any improvement
                thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886203_038" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to borrow money upon such terms as the corporation shall think fit, and to
                raise money by public or private subscription; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886218_006" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>generally, to do such other things as may appear to be incidental or conducive
                to the aims and objects of the corporation as provided by its regulations or the
                purposes aforesaid or any of them.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402572920_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Members</heading><content>The corporation shall consist of such members as shall be provided by its regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402572920_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Registration with the Registrar of Companies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410886249_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The corporation shall forward to the Registrar of Companies for registration the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410886249_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice of the address of the principal office of the corporation and any change thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886249_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the regulations and any amendment thereto, certified as correct by the chairman;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886249_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a list of the names and addresses of the members of the corporation and any change therein, certified as correct by the chairman; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410886249_036" name="d" temporalId="s6_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the name and address of any person appointed under <ref>section 7</ref> to sign deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410886249_043" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notification in accordance with subsection (1) shall be made within twenty-eight days of any amendment or change, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410886249_051" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person may inspect any of the documents registered under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410886265_005" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A fee of five dollars shall be payable for registering any document under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410886265_013" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A fee of one dollar shall be payable for inspecting the documents filed with the Registrar of Companies under this Ordinance.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402572936_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Sealing of deeds, documents and other instruments</heading><content>All deeds, documents and other instruments requiring the seal of and sealed by the corporation shall be signed by the chairman and secretary of the corporation or by the chairman or secretary and such other member as the corporation may appoint or by two other members as the corporation may appoint, and such signing shall be taken as sufficient evidence of the due sealing of such deeds, documents and other instruments.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402572951_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Existing regulations to be regulations of corporation</heading><content>The regulations of the unincorporated Hong Kong Conference of Youth Organizations
            in operation at the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance shall be the regulations of the corporation, but the same may be
            changed or amended by the corporation at any time and from time to time in accordance
            with the provisions of the regulations for the time being in operation.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1659327441384_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 25 April
                1963.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402572967_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-27" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/4">4 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>