<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 1044</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>1044</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap1044!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402539349_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-15">
            <content>To provide for the incorporation of the
                Secretary
                for Home and Youth Affairs.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1969/ln22">L.N. 22 of 1969</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/ln67">L.N. 67 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln262">L.N. 262 of
                1989</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
            2022</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[10 April 1928]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1656903121621_001">Editorial Note:<content>Please see
                paragraph (3) of the Resolution of the Legislative Council (<ref href="hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of 2022</ref>) for the saving and transitional
                provisions relating to the amendment of “The Secretary for Home Affairs
                Incorporated” to “The Secretary for Home and Youth Affairs
            Incorporated”.</content></editorialNote><section id="ID_1438402539380_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the
                                <shortTitle>Secretary
                                for Home and Youth Affairs Incorporation
                                Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><sourceNote class="left_indent_36 align_justified">(Amended <ref href="/hk/1969/ln22">L.N.
                        22 of 1969</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/ln67">L.N. 67 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln262">L.N. 262 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/ln144">L.N.
                        144 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402539395_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Secretary
            for Home and Youth Affairs constituted a corporation
            sole</heading><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><content>The person for the time being performing the duties of the office
            of
            Secretary for Home and Youth Affairs shall be a corporation sole,
            hereinafter called
                    <b><i>the
                    corporation</i></b>, and shall have the name of
            “The
            Secretary for Home and Youth Affairs Incorporated” and shall and may
            have and use a common seal.</content></section><sourceNote class="left_indent_36 align_justified">(Amended <ref href="/hk/1957/18">18 of 1957
            </ref><ref>Third Schedule</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1969/ln22">L.N. 22 of 1969</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1970/ln15">L.N. 15 of 1970</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/ln67">L.N. 67 of
            1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/ln68">L.N. 68 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln262">L.N. 262 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln263">L.N. 263 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402539395_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Powers of corporation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410814583_025" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall have power to acquire, accept leases of, purchase, take, hold and enjoy any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements of what nature or kind soever and wheresoever situate, and also to invest moneys upon mortgage of any lands, buildings, messuages or tenements or upon the mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities of any government, municipality, corporation or company, and also to purchase, acquire and possess goods and chattels of what nature and kind soever.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410814598_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The corporation shall further have power to grant, sell, convey, assign, surrender, exchange, partition, yield up, mortgage, demise, reassign, transfer or otherwise dispose of any lands, buildings, messuages, tenements, mortgages, debentures, stocks, funds, shares or securities, or other goods and chattels whatsoever, which are for the time being vested in or belonging to the corporation, upon such terms as to the corporation may seem fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1955/4">4 of 1955 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402539427_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Property and rights transferred to corporation to vest or remain vested in corporation and not to pass to personal representatives of occupant</heading><content>Notwithstanding any change in the occupant of the corporation, whether on account of death, departure on leave, return from leave, temporary employment elsewhere, resumption of duties, new appointment or other cause whatsoever, and notwithstanding the nature of the property or rights, all property and rights whatsoever, transferred to the corporation or to any occupant of the corporation as such, in any manner whatsoever, shall vest or remain vested in the corporation so as to be capable of being dealt with by the occupant of the corporation for the time being and shall not vest in any occupant in his natural capacity.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402539458_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Evidence as to the identity of the occupant of the corporation</heading><content>If any question arises as to who is or was at any time the occupant of the corporation for the time being, a certificate under the hand of the Chief Secretary for Administration shall be conclusive evidence for all purposes whatsoever as to the person who is or was the occupant.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of 1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402539473_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Execution of documents</heading><content>All deeds and other instruments requiring the seal of the corporation shall be sealed in the presence of the occupant of the corporation for the time being, and such deeds and instruments, and all other documents, instruments and writings requiring the signature of the corporation, shall be signed by such occupant.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402539489_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Vesting of property</heading><leadIn>The corporation will continue to hold the pieces or parcels of ground which were
            vested in it on 10 April 1928, except such of the same as have been or may at any time
            be disposed of under <ref>section 3(2)</ref>, together with all rights, easements and
            appurtenances belonging or appertaining thereto, or therewith usually held, occupied and
            enjoyed—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410814692_019" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of premises held under Government lease, for the term granted
                thereby and subject to the payment of the rent and the performance of the covenants
                and conditions reserved thereby and contained therein; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410814692_027" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of there being no Government lease, for the term and subject to the
                payment of the rent and performance of the covenants and conditions to be implied in
                all the circumstances of the case,</content></paragraph><continued>and in every case whatsoever subject to the trusts on which the respective pieces
            or parcels of ground were held immediately before 10 April 1928.</continued><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1950/24">24 of 1950 </ref>Schedule. Amended <ref href="/hk/1966/13">13 of 1966 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1999/18">18 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402539505_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Power to accept other trusts, to invest and deposit trust funds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410814708_054" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>For the avoidance of doubt, it is hereby declared that it shall be lawful for
                the corporation to accept trusts other than those mentioned in <ref>section 7</ref>
                if the corporation first obtains the approval of the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1955/4">4 of 1955 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410814723_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>It is also hereby declared that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410814723_013" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the corporation may invest, in accordance with the provisions of the
                    Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>), such trust funds in the
                    hands of the corporation whether at the time in a state of investment or not;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410814723_021" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>notwithstanding such provisions, the corporation shall also have power and
                    shall be deemed always to have had power, in cases where the occupant of the
                    corporation for the time being considers it impracticable for any reason
                    whatsoever for such trust funds to be so invested, to deposit such trust funds
                    in the Hong Kong Savings Bank or such other savings bank as the Chief Executive
                    may approve generally or in any particular case.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1958/15">15 of 1958 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1958/15">15 of 1958 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/18">18 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402539520_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving</heading><text>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect or be deemed to affect the rights of the
            Central Authorities or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region
            under the Basic Law and other laws, or the rights of any body politic or corporate or of
            any other persons except such as are mentioned in this Ordinance and those claiming by,
            from or under them.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/18">18 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402539536_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-15" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Accounts, audit and annual report</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410814770_032" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The corporation shall keep accounts and records of all transactions in respect
                of any trust funds it administers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410814770_040" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director of Accounting Services may give such directions in writing to the
                corporation as he thinks fit with respect to the keeping of accounts and records
                referred to in subsection (1) and the corporation shall comply with any such
                direction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410814786_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The corporation shall prepare in relation to the trust funds it administers a
                statement of accounts of the funds for each period of 12 months ending on 31 March
                in any year, in such form as the Director of Accounting Services may require in
                writing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410814786_013" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A statement of accounts required by subsection (3) shall be signed by the
                person for the time being performing the duties of the office of the
                Secretary
                for Home and Youth Affairs and shall, unless the accounts of the
                trust funds the corporation administers have been audited by an independent
                accountant under <ref>section 24(4)</ref> of the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>), be submitted by the corporation to the Director
                of Audit not later than 30 September following the end of the period to which it
                relates, or such later date as the Chief Executive may allow.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1989/ln262">L.N. 262 of
                        1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/18">18 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410814801_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the statement of accounts is submitted to the Director of Audit under
                subsection (4), such statement of accounts and the accounts of the funds referred to
                in subsection (1) shall be audited by the Director of Audit, who shall certify the
                statement of accounts together with such report, if any, as he may think fit and
                submit the audited statement of accounts and the report thereon, if any, to the
                corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410814817_005" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A copy of the corporation’s audited statement of accounts, together with the
                Director of Audit’s report, if any, and a report, if any, by the corporation on the
                administration of the fund during the period covered by the audited statement of
                accounts shall be laid upon the table of the Legislative Council not later than 3
                months after the audited statement of accounts and the report thereon, if any, are
                received by the corporation from the Director of Audit.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1989/19">19 of 1989 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>