<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 278</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>278</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap278!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2018-12-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402919802_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2018-12-13">
            <content>To make provision for the use of parts of bodies of deceased persons for
                therapeutic purposes and for purposes of medical education and
                research.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[26 July 1968]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2018/er5">E.R. 5 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402919802_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Medical (Therapy, Education and Research) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402919818_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Removal of parts of body or specified parts in accordance with a request</heading><leadIn>If any person, either in writing at any time or orally in the presence of 2 or more witnesses during his last illness, has expressed a request that his body or any specified part of his body be used after his death for therapeutic purposes or for purposes of medical education or research—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411720118_005" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the person who has lawful possession of his body after his death may, unless he has reason to believe that the request was subsequently withdrawn, authorize in writing the removal from the body of any part or, as the case may be, of the specified part, for use in accordance with the request; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411720118_013" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an authorization validly given under paragraph (a) shall remain valid notwithstanding any objection by the next of kin of the person who has expressed the request to the body being dealt with in accordance with the request after the death.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 58</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402919818_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Removal of parts of body where no request and deceased dies in hospital</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411720133_033" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to <ref>section 2</ref>, the person who has lawful possession of the body of a deceased person who has died in a hospital, nursing home or other similar institution, may authorize in writing the removal of any part from the body for use for therapeutic purposes or for purposes of medical education or research, if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411720133_041" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he has obtained the written consent of the registered next of kin of the deceased; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411720149_006" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>having made such reasonable inquiries from the registered next of kin as may be practicable, he has no reason to believe—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411720149_014" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>that the deceased had expressed an objection to his body being so dealt with after his death, and had not withdrawn it; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411720149_022" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that the surviving spouse or any surviving parent or child of the deceased objects to the body being so dealt with.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411720149_028" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="RegisteredNextOfKin">For the purposes of this section,
                    <term>registered
                    next of
                kin</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經登記的最近親</term>), in relation to a person who dies
                in a hospital, nursing home or other similar institution, means the person who is
                recorded as the next of kin of the deceased in any form or document made out at the
                time of or after the admission of the deceased into such hospital, nursing home or
                other similar institution.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402919849_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Authorized removal to be lawful</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411720164_055" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsections (3) and (4), where an authorization has been given in respect of the body of a deceased person under <ref>section 2</ref> or <ref>3</ref>, the removal and use of any part of the body in accordance with such authorization shall be lawful.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411720180_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Such authorization shall not be questioned or challenged in any court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411720180_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No such removal shall be effected except by a registered medical practitioner, who shall have satisfied himself by personal examination of the body that life is extinct.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411720180_021" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where a person has reason to believe that under the Coroners Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap504">Cap. 504</ref>) a coroner may hold an inquest into the cause of the death of any person or order a post-mortem examination, he shall not, except with the consent of the coroner—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/27">27 of 1997 s. 77</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411720180_029" name="a" temporalId="s4_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>give an authorization in respect of the body of that person under <ref>section 2</ref> or <ref>3</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411720180_037" name="b" temporalId="s4_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>act on such an authorization given by any other person.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402919865_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Power to give authorization</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411720211_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person who has been entrusted with the body of a deceased person for the purposes of its burial or cremation shall give an authorization under <ref>section 2</ref> or <ref>3</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411720211_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In the case of the body of a deceased person lying in a hospital, nursing home
                or other similar institution, any authorization under <ref>section 2</ref> or
                    <ref>3</ref> may be given on behalf of the person having the control and
                management of the hospital, nursing home or institution by any officer or other
                person designated for that purpose by the person having such control and
                management.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402919865_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall be construed as rendering unlawful any dealing with, or with any part of, the body of a deceased person which would have been lawful if this Ordinance had not been enacted.</content></section></main></ordinance>