<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 190</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>190</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap190!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-12-12</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402813784_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-12-12">
            <content>To make provision as to privileges, immunities and facilities to be accorded in
                respect of certain international organizations and in respect of persons connected
                with such organizations and other persons; to apply to Hong Kong the international
                custom for the time being recognized by the People’s Republic of China relating to
                immunities and privileges as to the person, property or servants of sovereigns,
                diplomatic agents or the representatives of sovereign powers; and for matters
                connected therewith and incidental thereto. </content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1977/64">64 of 1977 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[29 October 1948]</commencementNote><sourceNote class="align_right">(Format changes——<ref href="/hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402813800_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>International Organizations and Diplomatic Privileges Ordinance</shortTitle>. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/64">64 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402813800_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Privileges, immunities and capacities of certain international organizations and
            their staffs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411509174_025" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive may, by notification in the Gazette, declare that this
                section shall apply to any organization specified in the notification of which the
                Government or Governments of one or more sovereign powers are members and of which
                the Government of Hong Kong or of the People’s Republic of China is a member or an
                associate member, and may in like manner—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/64">64 of 1977 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411509190_005" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>provide that any organization to which this section applies (hereinafter
                    referred to as
                            <b><i>the
                            organization</i></b>) shall, to such extent as may be specified in the
                    notification, have the immunities and privileges set out in Part I of the
                        <ref>First Schedule</ref>, and shall also have the legal capacities of a
                    body corporate;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411509190_013" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>confer upon—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411509190_021" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any persons who are representatives (whether of governments or not) on
                        any organ of the organization or are members of any committee of the
                        organization or of an organ thereof;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411509190_029" name="ii" temporalId="s2_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>such number of officers of the organization as may be specified in the
                        notification, being holders of such high offices in the organization as may
                        be so specified; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411509190_037" name="iii" temporalId="s2_1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>such persons employed on missions on behalf of the organization as may
                        be so specified,</content></subparagraph><continued>to such extent as may be specified in the notification, the immunities
                    and privileges set out in Part II of the <ref>First Schedule</ref>;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411509190_050" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>confer upon such other classes of officers and servants of the organization
                    as may be specified in the notification, to such extent as may be so specified,
                    the immunities and privileges set out in Part III of the <ref>First
                        Schedule</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>and Part IV of the <ref>First Schedule</ref> shall have effect for the
                purpose of extending to the staffs of such representatives and members as are
                mentioned in paragraph <ref>(b)(i)</ref> and to the families of officers of the
                organization any immunities and privileges conferred on the representatives, members
                or officers under that paragraph, except in so far as the operation of Part IV is
                excluded by the notification conferring the immunities and privileges:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s2_1_proviso">Provided that the notification shall
                be so framed as to secure that there are not conferred on any person any immunities
                or privileges greater in extent than those which, at the time of publication of the
                notification, are required to be conferred on that person in order to give effect to
                any international agreement in that behalf.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1951/3">3 of 1951 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1970/18">18 of 1970 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411509205_018" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any question arises whether or not any person is entitled to any
                privilege or immunity conferred on any person by a notification under subsection
                (1), a certificate issued by the Chief Secretary for Administration stating any fact
                relating to the question shall be conclusive evidence of the fact.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1967/56">56 of
                        1967 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                    1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402813816_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Diplomatic immunities of representatives attending international
            conferences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411509236_048" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a conference is held in Hong Kong and is attended by the representatives
                of the Central People’s Government and the government or governments of one or more
                foreign sovereign powers, and it appears to the Chief Executive that doubts may
                arise as to the extent to which the representatives of such foreign powers and
                members of their official staffs are entitled to diplomatic immunities, he
                may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411509252_005" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>compile a list of the persons aforesaid who are entitled to such
                    immunities, and cause that list to be published in the Gazette; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411509252_013" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>whenever it appears to the Chief Executive that any person ceases or begins
                    to be entitled to such immunities, amend the list and cause a notification of
                    amendment or, if he thinks fit, an amended list, to be published as
                    aforesaid,</content></paragraph><continued>and every representative of a foreign power who is for the time being
                included in the list shall, for the purposes of any enactment and rule of law or
                custom relating to the immunities of an envoy of a foreign power accredited to the
                Government of the People’s Republic of China, and of the retinue of such an envoy,
                be treated as if he were such an envoy, and such of the members of his official
                staff as are for the time being included in the list shall be treated for the
                purpose aforesaid as if they were his retinue.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411509252_026" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every list or notification published under subsection (1) in relation to any
                conference shall include a statement of the date from which the list or amendment
                takes or took effect; and the fact that any person is or was included or not
                included at any time among the persons entitled to diplomatic immunities as
                representatives attending the conference or as members of the official staff of any
                such representative may, if a list of those persons has been so published, be
                conclusively proved by producing the Gazette containing the list or, as the case may
                be, the last list taking effect before that time, together with the Gazette (if any)
                containing notices of the amendments taking effect before that time, and by showing
                that the name of that person is or was at that time included or not included in the
                said list.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402813831_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Immunities and privileges of judges of and suitors to, the International Court of
            Justice</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411509330_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive may, by notification in the Gazette, confer on judges and
                registrars of the International Court, and on suitors to that Court, and their
                agents, counsel and advocates, such immunities, privileges and facilities as may be
                required to give effect to any resolution of, or convention approved by, the General
                Assembly of the United Nations.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411509330_019" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="TheInternationalCourt">In this section, the expression
                    <term>the
                    International
                Court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">國際法院</term>) means the International Court of
                Justice set up under the Charter of the United Nations.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1951/3">3 of 1951 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402813831_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Reciprocal treatment</heading><text>Nothing in the foregoing provisions shall be construed as precluding the Chief
            Executive from declining to accord immunities or privileges to, or from withdrawing
            immunities or privileges from, nationals or representatives of any power on the ground
            that that power is failing to accord corresponding immunities or privileges to Chinese
            nationals or representatives.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402813847_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Certain international customs relating to immunities and privileges to have effect
            in Hong Kong</heading><text>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary contained in any Ordinance, the
            international custom relating to the immunities and privileges as to person, property or
            servants of sovereigns, diplomatic agents, or the representatives of foreign powers for
            the time being recognized by the People’s Republic of China shall, in so far as the same
            is applicable mutatis mutandis, have effect in Hong Kong.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402813862_001" name="s7" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="repealed" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402813878_001" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">First
            Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap190/s2">s.
                2</ref>]</note><part id="ID_1438411509408_017" name="PI" temporalId="sch1_PI"><num value="I"><inline>Part
                    I</inline></num><heading><inline>Immunities
                    and Privileges of the
                Organization</inline></heading><section id="ID_1438411509408_036" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_PI_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Immunity from suit and legal
                    process.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411509408_044" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_PI_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The like inviolability of official archives and premises occupied as
                    offices as is accorded in the People’s Republic of China in respect of the
                    official archives and premises of an envoy of a foreign sovereign power
                    accredited to the Government of the People’s Republic of
                    China.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411509408_052" name="s3" temporalId="sch1_PI_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The like exemption or relief from taxes and rates, other than taxes on the
                    importation of goods, as is accorded in the People’s Republic of China to a
                    foreign sovereign
                    power.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411509408_060" name="s4" temporalId="sch1_PI_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><content>Exemption from taxes on the importation of goods directly imported by the
                    organization for its official use in Hong Kong or for exportation, or on the
                    importation of any publications of the organization directly imported by it,
                    such exemption to be subject to compliance with such conditions as the
                    Commissioner of Customs and Excise<inline class="width_3"> </inline>may
                    prescribe for the protection of the revenue.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/40">40 of 1985 s.
                            10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438411509424_004" name="s5" temporalId="sch1_PI_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><content>Exemption from prohibitions and restrictions on importation or exportation
                    in the case of goods directly imported or exported by the organization for its
                    official use and in the case of any publications of the organization directly
                    imported or exported by
                    it.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411509424_012" name="s6" temporalId="sch1_PI_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><content>The right to avail itself, for telegraphic communications sent by it and
                    containing only matter intended for publication by the press or for broadcasting
                    (including communications addressed to or dispatched from places outside Hong
                    Kong) of any reduced rates applicable for the corresponding service in the case
                    of press telegrams.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438411509439_009" name="PII" temporalId="sch1_PII"><num value="II"><inline>Part
                    II</inline></num><heading><inline>Immunities
                    and Privileges of Representatives, Members<br></br>of Committees, High Officers and
                    Persons on
                Missions</inline></heading><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1951/3">3 of 1951 s.
                4</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438411509439_052" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_PII_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The like immunity from suit and legal process as is accorded in the
                    People’s Republic of China to an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited
                    to the Government of the People’s Republic of China.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438411509439_060" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_PII_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The like inviolability of residence as is accorded to such an
                    envoy.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411509439_068" name="s3" temporalId="sch1_PII_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The like exemption or relief from taxes as is accorded to such an
                    envoy.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438411509439_073" name="PIII" temporalId="sch1_PIII"><num value="III"><inline>Part
                    III</inline></num><heading><inline>Immunities
                    and Privileges of Other<br></br>Officers and
                Servants</inline></heading><section id="ID_1438411509455_004" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_PIII_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Immunity from suit and legal process in respect of things done or omitted
                    to be done in the course of the performance of official duties.
                    </content></section><section id="ID_1438411509455_012" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_PIII_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>Exemption from income tax in respect of emoluments received as an officer
                    or servant of the
                    organization.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438411509455_017" name="PIV" temporalId="sch1_PIV"><num value="IV"><inline>Part
                    IV</inline></num><heading><inline>Immunities
                    and Privileges of Official<br></br>Staffs and of High Officers’
                Families</inline></heading><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1951/3">3 of 1951 s.
                4</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438411509455_052" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_PIV_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Where any person is entitled to any such immunities and privileges as are
                    mentioned in Part II as a representative on any organ of the organization or a
                    member of any committee of the organization or of an organ thereof, his official
                    staff accompanying him as such a representative or member shall also be entitled
                    to those immunities and privileges to the same extent as the retinue of an envoy
                    of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s
                    Republic of China is entitled in the People’s Republic of China to the
                    immunities and privileges accorded to the envoy.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1951/3">3 of 1951 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438411509470_004" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_PIV_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>Where any person is entitled to any such immunities and privileges as are
                    mentioned in Part II as an officer of the organization, that person’s wife or
                    husband and children under the age of twenty-one shall also be entitled to those
                    immunities and privileges to the same extent as the wife or husband and children
                    of an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the
                    People’s Republic of China are entitled in the People’s Republic of China to the
                    immunities and privileges accorded to the envoy.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402813894_001" name="sch2" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="repealed" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Second
            Schedule</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
        3</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>