<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 56 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>56A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap56A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-12-10</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403460543_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-12-10">Boilers
                                    and Pressure Vessels Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap56/s65">Cap.
                                                56, section
                                    65</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 March 1963]</commencementNote><sourceNote class="align_right">(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403460714_001" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>General</heading><section id="ID_1438403461198_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the Boilers and Pressure Vessels
            Regulations.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 41</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403461447_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>General provisions as to construction, etc. of boilers, etc.</heading><content>Without prejudice to any other provisions of these regulations, every boiler and
            pressure vessel, every part of a boiler or pressure vessel and every part of the
            auxiliary equipment connected with a boiler or pressure vessel shall be of good
            construction, sound material, adequate strength and free from any patent
            defect.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 42</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403461510_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Boilers,
            Steam Receivers and Air Receivers</heading><section id="ID_1438403461525_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Requirements with respect to boilers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413390533_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every boiler, whether separate or one of a range—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413390533_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>shall have attached to it—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413390533_020" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a suitable spring-loaded safety valve, separate from any stop-valve and capable of being sealed, which shall be fixed directly to the boiler and so adjusted as to prevent the boiler being operated at a pressure greater than its maximum permissible working pressure;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413390548_007" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a suitable stop-valve connecting the boiler to the system;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 43</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413390548_015" name="iii" temporalId="s3_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a correct pressure gauge, connected to the boiler and easily visible by the boiler attendant, which shall have marked upon it by a red line the maximum permissible working pressure of the boiler and which shall indicate the pressure in the boiler in pascals or multiples of pascals;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 43</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413390548_023" name="iv" temporalId="s3_1_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>at least one water gauge of transparent material, or of such other type as the Authority may approve, to show the water level in the boiler, which shall, if it is of the glass tubular type, be provided with an efficient guard that does not obstruct the reading of the gauge; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 51</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413390564_007" name="v" temporalId="s3_1_a_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>where it is one of 2 or more boilers, a plate bearing a distinguishing number, which shall be easily visible;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390564_014" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall be provided with means for attaching a test pressure gauge; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390564_022" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>unless it is externally fired, shall be provided with a suitable fusible plug or an efficient low-water alarm device.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390564_029" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subregulation <ref>(1)(a)(ii)</ref> shall not apply with respect to economizers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390564_037" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subregulation <ref>(1)(a)(iii)</ref>, (iv) and (v), (b) and (c) shall not apply with respect to economizers or superheaters.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390564_045" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subregulation <ref>(1)(a)(iv)</ref> and (c) shall not apply to vessels in which oil is heated at a pressure greater than atmospheric pressure.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 43</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403461541_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Requirements with respect to steam receivers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413390626_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every steam receiver that is not so constructed and maintained as to withstand with safety the maximum permissible working pressure of the boiler to which it is connected or the maximum pressure that can be obtained in the pipe connecting the steam receiver with any other source of supply of steam shall be fitted with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413390626_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a suitable reducing valve or other suitable automatic appliance to prevent the maximum permissible working pressure of the steam receiver being exceeded;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390626_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a suitable spring-loaded safety valve that is capable of being sealed and is so adjusted as to permit the steam to escape as soon as the maximum permissible working pressure of the steam receiver is exceeded or a suitable appliance for cutting off automatically the supply of steam as soon as that pressure is exceeded;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390642_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a correct steam pressure gauge, which shall have marked on it by a red line the maximum permissible working pressure of the steam receiver and which shall indicate the pressure of steam in the steam receiver in pascals or multiples of pascals;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 44</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390642_014" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a suitable stop-valve; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390642_022" name="e" temporalId="s4_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>where it is one of 2 or more steam receivers, a plate bearing a distinguishing number, which shall be easily visible.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390642_029" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The safety valve and the steam pressure gauge of every steam receiver shall be fitted on the steam receiver or on the supply pipe between the steam receiver and the reducing valve or other appliance provided to prevent the maximum permissible working pressure of the steam receiver being exceeded.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390657_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Every steam receiver shall be provided with means for attaching a test pressure gauge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390657_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><leadIn>For the purposes of subregulation (1), other than the provisions of paragraph (e) thereof, any set of steam receivers supplied with steam through a single pipe and forming part of a single machine may be treated as one steam receiver, and, for the purposes of the said subregulation (1), other than the provisions of paragraphs (d) and (e) thereof, any other set of steam receivers supplied with steam through a single pipe may be treated as one steam receiver:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_4_proviso">Provided that this subregulation shall not apply to any such set of steam receivers unless the reducing valve or other appliance provided to prevent the maximum permissible working pressure of the steam receiver being exceeded is fitted on the said single pipe.</proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403461541_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Requirements with respect to air receivers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413390735_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every air receiver shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413390735_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the air receiver is connected with a compressor, be so constructed as to withstand with safety the maximum pressure that can be obtained in the compressor or be fitted with a suitable reducing valve or other suitable appliance to prevent the maximum permissible working pressure of the air receiver being exceeded;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390735_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be fitted with a suitable spring-loaded safety valve that is so adjusted as to permit the air to escape as soon as the maximum permissible working pressure of the air receiver is exceeded;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390735_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>be fitted with a correct pressure gauge, which shall indicate the pressure of air in the air receiver in pascals or multiples of pascals;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 45</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390751_006" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>be fitted with a suitable appliance for draining the air receiver;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390751_014" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>be provided with a suitable manhole, handhole or other means that will allow the interior thereof to be thoroughly cleaned; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390751_022" name="f" temporalId="s5_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>where more than one air receiver is being used by the same person in any industrial undertaking, bear a distinguishing mark, which shall be easily visible.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390751_029" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every air receiver, other than a pressurized fuel container, shall have marked upon it so as to be plainly visible the maximum permissible working pressure of the air receiver and the date on which it was last examined by an appointed examiner.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 45</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390751_037" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the safety valve fitted on an air receiver in accordance with subregulation <ref>(1)(b)</ref> is not fitted directly to the air receiver, a suitable fusible plug shall also be fitted to the air receiver.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390767_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><leadIn>For the purposes of those provisions of subregulations (1) and (3) that relate to safety valves and pressure gauges, any set of air receivers supplied with air through a single pipe may be treated as one air receiver:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_4_proviso">Provided that, where, by virtue of the said subregulation (1), the air receiver is required to be fitted with a reducing valve or other appliance to prevent the maximum permissible working pressure of the air receiver being exceeded, this subregulation shall not apply unless such valve or other appliance is fitted on the said single pipe.</proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403461572_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Special requirements with respect to pressurized fuel containers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413390813_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every pressurized fuel container shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413390813_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>be fitted with a pressure release valve;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390813_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be placed in a metal tray or housed in a suitable structure so that all valves and safety devices are readily accessible;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390813_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where it has a maximum permissible working pressure of not more than 500 kilopascals, be fitted with piping properly secured along its whole length, save that for a length of 600 millimetres immediately preceding the burner the piping shall be in the form of a loose coil so as to facilitate easy manipulation; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln107">L.N. 107 of 1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390813_036" name="d" temporalId="s6_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>be fitted with a remote control valve situated in a position as near to the burner as is possible consistently with its safe operation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390829_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The provisions of subregulation (1) shall apply to pressurized fuel containers in addition to any of the provisions of <ref>regulation 5</ref> that apply to such containers.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 46</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403461572_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Auxiliary
            Equipment</heading><section id="ID_1438403461588_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Pumps</heading><leadIn>Every pump used in connection with the fuel burning system in a fuel burning installation, whether the pump is used for the purpose of supplying the burners or of transferring fuel, shall be separated from any pump used for any other purpose and shall be provided with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413390876_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an efficient escape valve, which shall discharge into the suction side of the pump; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390876_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>means for stopping the pump, which shall be situated outside the boiler house in a readily access position.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403461588_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Heaters</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413390907_003" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No means, other than steam or such other means as may be approved by the Authority, shall be used for heating fuel in a fuel burning installation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 51</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390907_011" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every heater fitted in a fuel burning installation shall be of good design and adequate strength.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390907_019" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where, in any such heater, steam is used to heat the fuel and the condensate is
                returned to the boiler in connection with which the heater is provided, the heater
                shall be provided with an observation tank by means of which it can be readily
                ascertained whether or not the condensate is free from
                oil.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403461603_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Pumps, etc. to be fitted with equipment to catch any leakage of fuel</heading><content>Every pump, heater, strainer and furnace mouth in a fuel burning installation shall
            be fitted with save-alls or gutters for the purpose of catching any fuel that may leak
            therefrom or that may spill when any cover or door is open or of intercepting any fuel
            that may escape from the burners, as the case may be.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403461619_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Multiple burners</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413390954_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438413390954_008" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Where there is more than one burner in a fuel burning installation, a master valve shall be provided for the purpose of enabling the supply of fuel to every burner to be shut off in the event of an emergency.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413390954_014" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>Every such master valve shall—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413390954_022" name="i" temporalId="s10_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>be situated outside the boiler house in a readily accessible position; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413390954_030" name="ii" temporalId="s10_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>be of the quick-closing type.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390954_036" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The shut-off valves on the furnace front that control the supply of fuel to such burners shall be provided with safety catches so as to prevent any such burner from being removed until the supply of fuel is shut off.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403461619_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Flue dampers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413390985_027" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every flue damper fitted in a fuel burning installation shall be so constructed that it can be fixed securely in an open position.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413390985_035" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Save as provided in subregulation (3), the area of any such flue damper shall be such that it does not obstruct more than 90% of the free space of the flue.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413391001_005" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where any such flue damper does not comply with subregulation (2), the flue damper shall be interlocked with the fuel supply or otherwise so arranged that the fuel burning installation cannot be started up or operated when the flue is closed.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403461635_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Pipes</heading><section id="ID_1438403461635_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Steam pipes and water pipes to be protected against weather, etc.</heading><content>Every pipe that conveys oil, steam or water under pressure to or from a boiler,
            steam receiver or steam container shall be protected to the satisfaction of the
            Authority against the effect of weather and damp and against external damage.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 ss. 47</ref> &amp; 51)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403461650_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Steam pipes to be lagged</heading><content>Every pipe that conveys oil or steam under pressure shall be lagged to the satisfaction of the Authority with fire-proof material.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 ss. 48</ref> &amp; 51)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403461650_004" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Requirements with respect to pipes used for conveying fuel to burners</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413391094_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every pipe used for the purpose of conveying fuel from a pump or gravity tank to the burners in a fuel burning installation shall be constructed of suitable seamless material or, if it is of welded construction, shall be welded in accordance with a recognized engineering standard or code.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413391094_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No connection between any such pipe and any other fitting shall be made by
                means of soft
                solder.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413391094_020" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The flanges of any such pipe that conveys liquid fuel under pressure shall be machined so as, as far as practicable, to be metal to metal, and any jointing shall be of the thinnest material practicable and impervious to oil heated to a temperature of 120<sup>o</sup> Celsius.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln107">L.N. 107 of 1979</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403461666_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Offences,
            Supplementary and
            Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403461681_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Flash point of fuels, etc.</heading><content>Save for the purpose of ignition, no oil or liquid or gaseous fuel that has a flash
            point of less than 65<sup>o</sup> Celsius (close test) as determined by a standard type
            of flash point apparatus shall be used in any installation connected to a
            boiler.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln107">L.N. 107 of 1979</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1988/87">87
                of 1988 s. 50</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403461681_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Power of Authority to require taking of additional safety precautions</heading><content>Without prejudice to any of the provisions of these regulations, where, having
            regard to the situation of a fuel burning installation or, where the same is situated in
            an industrial undertaking, to the nature of the business carried on in the industrial
            undertaking, the Authority considers it necessary, he may require the owner of the fuel
            burning installation to take such safety precautions as he specifies.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s. 51</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403461697_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413391188_018" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the event of a contravention of any of the provisions of <ref>regulations 2
                    to 15</ref>, both inclusive, the owner of the boiler, steam receiver, air
                receiver or fuel burning installation, as the case may be, shall be guilty of an
                offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at level
                3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413391203_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who fails to comply with a requirement of the Authority made under
                    <ref>regulation 16</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
                summary conviction to a fine
                at level
                    4.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/87">87 of 1988 s.
                        51</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln339">L.N. 339 of
            1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403461713_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-12-10" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Fees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413391235_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who applies to be issued with a new certificate of competency or applies to have an existing certificate of competency endorsed by the Authority under <ref>section 6(1)(a)</ref> or (3A)(a) of the Ordinance, as the case may be, shall pay an application fee of $330.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413391235_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who applies to be issued with a new certificate of competency or applies to have an existing certificate of competency endorsed by the Authority under <ref>section 6(1)(b)</ref> or (3A)(b) of the Ordinance, as the case may be, shall pay an application fee of $610.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413391250_005" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subregulation (4), application fees paid under this regulation may not be refunded by the Authority.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413391250_013" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person who fails to attend an examination conducted under <ref>section 6(6)</ref> of the Ordinance shall, at his request, have his application fee refunded by the Authority if he has given not less than 2 days’ advance notice in writing to the Authority of his inability to attend the examination.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/15">15 of 2002 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></main></subLeg>