<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 91 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>91C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap91C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-04-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403571396_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-04-11">Legal
            Aid (Scale
            of
            Fees)
            Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap91/s28">Cap. 91, section
                28</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[23 June 1989]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403571412_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the Legal Aid (Scale of Fees) Regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571412_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="FixedCosts"><term>fixed
                costs</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">定額訟費</term>) means fixed costs prescribed by any
            Ordinance or rules of court as payable to a solicitor;</def><def name="RulesOfCourt"><term>rules
                of
            court</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院規則</term>) means the rules of court made under the
            Hong Kong Court of Final Appeal Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap484">Cap. 484</ref>), the
            High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>) or the District Court Ordinance
                (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/79">79 of 1995 s. 50</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TaxingMaster"><term>taxing
                master</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主理訟費評定事務聆案官</term>)
            means the officer acting under <ref>section 43</ref> of the Hong Kong Court of Final
            Appeal Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap484">Cap. 484</ref>) or the Registrar of the High
            Court acting as taxing master, or, in relation to proceedings that have been conducted
            in the District Court, the Registrar of the District Court acting as taxing
                master.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/79">79 of
                    1995 s. 50</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
            2</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section><section id="ID_1438403571428_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Fee payable for report or opinion under <ref>section 9</ref></heading><content>The fee payable by the Director to counsel or solicitor making a report or giving an opinion under <ref>section 9</ref> of the Ordinance shall be such sum as the Director may decide.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571428_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Fees payable to counsel generally</heading><content>The fees payable by the Director to counsel acting for an aided person shall be such as may be allowed on taxation or, in default of taxation, as may be fixed by the Director, not exceeding such amount as in the opinion of the Director would have been allowed if there had been taxation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571428_005" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Fees and costs payable to solicitor</heading><leadIn>The amount payable by the Director to a solicitor acting for an aided person shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414084744_026" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the full amount allowed on taxation on account of disbursements;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414084759_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the full amount allowed on taxation on account of profit costs; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414084759_014" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in cases where fixed costs are applicable and the solicitor has made an election to take fixed costs, the full amount of such fixed costs,</content></paragraph><continued>or, in default of taxation or where an election to take fixed costs has not been made, an amount as may be fixed by the Director, not exceeding such amount as in the opinion of the Director would have been allowed if there had been taxation or would have applied if there had been an election to take fixed costs.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403571443_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Advance of fees to counsel and solicitor</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414084791_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may before taxation make an advance to counsel or solicitor of an amount not exceeding 75% of the sum which the Director estimates will be payable under <ref>regulation 4</ref> or <ref>5</ref> and such advance shall be on account of moneys so payable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414084791_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the amount paid under subregulation (1) exceeds the amount payable under <ref>regulation 4</ref> or <ref>5</ref>, the counsel or solicitor, shall repay the excess to the Director.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403571443_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Fees and costs in referred cases</heading><content>If a case, in respect of which legal aid has been granted, is referred to any person by a court, there shall be payable to counsel and solicitor the same fees and costs as would have been payable if the reference had been a proceeding in the court by which it was referred, and all proceedings in connection with such reference shall be taxed by the court which referred them as if they were proceedings in the court.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571459_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Disallowance or reduction of costs on taxation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414084853_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Without prejudice to the rules of court, on the taxation of an aided person’s costs in any proceedings where the aided person’s solicitor has without good reason delayed in filing his bill of costs for taxation the whole of the profit costs may be disallowed or reduced.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414084853_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The aided person’s solicitor shall forthwith inform counsel of any disallowance or reduction of counsel’s fees on taxation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403571459_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Solicitor’s duty to safeguard interest of fund</heading><content>On any taxation pursuant to an order for costs made in favour of an aided person where that person may himself have no interest in the result of the taxation, it shall be the duty of an aided person’s solicitor to safeguard the interest of funds in the Director’s control, and for this purpose to take such steps as may appear to a solicitor to be necessary to obtain a review of taxation under <ref>regulation 10</ref> or <ref>11</ref>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571474_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Application to make objections to taxation</heading><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414084915_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an aided person is dissatisfied with any decision of a taxing master in regard to the amount which he is entitled to recover by virtue of an order or agreement for costs made in his favour or for which he is liable by virtue of an order for costs made against him; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414084915_020" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the aided person’s solicitor is dissatisfied with any decision of the taxing master on a taxation pursuant to an order for costs made in favour of the aided person,</content></paragraph><continued>the solicitor shall apply to the Director for authority to make objections to the taxation; and if the Director gives authority, the solicitor may thereupon make objections in accordance with the rules of court.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403571474_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Application to judge to review taxation</heading><content>Where the aided person or his solicitor, as the case may be, is dissatisfied with the decision of a taxing master on any matter to which objection is made under <ref>regulation 10</ref>, the solicitor shall apply to the Director for authority to have the taxation reviewed; and if the Director gives authority, the solicitor may thereupon apply to a judge either personally or by counsel to review the taxation in accordance with the rules of court.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571490_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Counsel dissatisfied with taxation</heading><content>Where counsel acting for an aided person is dissatisfied with any decision on a taxation, it shall be the duty of the aided person’s solicitor to report the matter to the Director and if the Director gives authority in that behalf, to make objection to the taxation or to apply to a judge, as the case may be, to review the taxation, and <ref>regulations 10</ref> and <ref>11</ref> shall apply as if the solicitor were the person dissatisfied.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571490_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Objection by other party</heading><content>If, in proceedings to which an aided person is a party, any other party makes objections to a taxation or applies to a judge to review the taxation the aided person’s solicitor may be heard on the objection or review notwithstanding that the aided person himself may have no interest in the taxation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571506_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Taxation proceedings deemed to be covered by legal aid certificate</heading><content>Any proceedings under <ref>regulations 10 to 13</ref> shall be deemed to be proceedings to which the aided person’s legal aid certificate relates, whether or not it has been discharged or revoked, and the costs of such proceedings shall be paid out of funds in the Director’s control.<inline class="width_3"> </inline></content></section><section id="ID_1438403571521_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Aided person having no interest or adverse interest</heading><leadIn>Where the aided person has no interest in the taxation or would, but for this regulation, have an interest adverse to that of his solicitor—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414085103_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it shall be the duty of the solicitor making objections under <ref>regulation 10</ref> or applying for a review under <ref>regulation 11</ref> to ensure that all matters which are properly to be taken into account in considering the objections or on the review are placed before the taxing master or judge as appropriate;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414085103_020" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the aided person shall not be required to make any contribution to the funds in the Director’s control on account of the costs of any proceedings arising under <ref>regulations 10 to 13</ref> or in consequence of any order made thereon; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414085118_006" name="c" temporalId="s15_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the charge created by <ref>section 18A</ref> of the Ordinance shall not apply as regards any resulting increase in the net liability of the Director.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403571521_004" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Time limits</heading><content>Where any party to a taxation is an aided person the certificate of costs shall not, save by consent, be signed within 14 days after the taxing master’s decision; and where an aided person’s solicitor applies under <ref>regulation 10</ref> or <ref>11</ref> for authority to make objections or to have a taxation reviewed, he shall do so before the expiration of the time allowed by the rules of court for making objections or for applying for review and shall thereupon give notice to the taxing master and to the opposite party of his application.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403571537_002" name="s17" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1992/ln196">L.N. 196 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>