<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 132 sub. leg. BG</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>132BG</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap132BG!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-02-17</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402679203_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2022-02-17">Private
                        Markets
                        Regulation</docTitle><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/1999/78">78 of
                                1999
                                s.7</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap132/s80">Cap. 132,
                                section
                        80</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 July 1963]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of
                        2021</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438402679265_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438402679281_001" name="s1" reason="repealed" startPeriod="2000-01-01" status="repealed" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679297_002" name="s2" reason="repealed" startPeriod="2000-01-01" status="repealed" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679312_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><def name="Commodity"><term>commodity</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">商品</term>) includes
                                    live stock;</def><def name="Director"><term>Director</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">署長</term>) means the
                                    Director of Food and Environmental Hygiene;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s.
                                                7</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="LicensedStallholder"><term>licensed
                                                stallholder</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">持牌檔主</term>) means a
                                    person licensed under <ref>section 22</ref> to carry on business
                                    from a stall in a private market;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/78">78
                                                  of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Owner"><term>owner</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>), in
                                    relation to a private market, means the person by whom the
                                    market place is operated;</def><def name="PrivateMarket"><term>private
                                                market</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">私營街市</term>) includes
                                    any building, shop, stall, shed, pen, or standing and any
                                    drainage or latrine accommodation appurtenant thereto, which
                                    comprise or form part of the market place;</def><def name="Stall"><marker role="section-break"></marker><term>stall</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">攤檔</term>) includes any
                                    pen or cage.</def><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402679328_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Registration
            of
            Private Markets
            and Regulation
            thereof
            Generally</heading><section id="ID_1438402679328_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Registration of private markets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411199825_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No private market shall be carried on unless it is registered by the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199825_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>No private market shall be registered by the Director unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411199825_020" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>plans of the market place, including plans of all buildings, stalls, sheds, pens, storerooms, latrine accommodation and drainage works appurtenant to the market place have been approved by the Director; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411199825_028" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at the time of registration such plans are accurate.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199825_035" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notwithstanding anything contained in subsection (2), the Director may refuse to register any private market if he considers the registration thereof not to be in the public interest.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199841_005" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purposes of first registration of any private market, the application therefor shall be submitted to the Director accompanied by 2 copies of the plans referred to in subsection (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199841_013" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Every plan, or any modification thereof, submitted to the Director for the purposes of an application for the registration of a private market shall, when it is approved by the Director, be endorsed to that effect, and one copy thereof shall be returned to the applicant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199841_021" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Every registration of a private market shall be renewable annually on 1 July.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199841_029" name="7" temporalId="s4_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content><leadIn>The registration or the renewal of the registration of a private market shall be subject to the payment in advance to the Director of a fee calculated at the rate of $10 per stall (whether or not any stall is occupied) up to a maximum fee of $1,000:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_7_proviso">Provided that, where a private market is first registered in the second half of any year of registration, the fee payable in respect of the grant of registration shall be one-half of the prescribed fee.</proviso></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679343_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Restriction on alteration of market building or stalls</heading><content>No alteration or addition shall be made to any private market or to any structure, or stall or any latrine or drainage works comprising any part of the market place otherwise than in accordance with plans approved by the Director. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679375_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Maintenance and repair of markets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411199888_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If in the opinion of the Director any part of a private market is in such a state by reason of dilapidation or lack of repair as to be unfit or unsuitable for the purpose of a private market, the Director, by notice served upon the owner of such market, may require him within such period, not being less than 30 days after the service of the notice, as shall be specified in the notice, to remedy such dilapidation or carry out such repairs to the satisfaction of the Director as shall be specified in the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199903_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the owner of a private market fails to comply with the requirements of any notice served upon him in accordance with the provisions of subsection (1), the Director may enter upon the premises in which the market is carried on and may carry out or cause to be carried out all such work as may be necessary for compliance with the notice and may recover the cost thereof from the owner of the market.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679390_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Stalls in private markets to be numbered and classified</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411199919_026" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Before first registration of any private market, the owner thereof shall allot a consecutive number to each stall, which shall be clearly indicated thereon in permanent form, and shall inform the Director of the nature of the commodities which will be sold therefrom.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2))</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199919_034" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director may by notice served upon the owner of any private market, either before first registration or at any time thereafter, prohibit the sale of any specified commodity from any stall at which any other specified commodity is sold, and a copy of such notice shall be kept posted by the owner of the market in a conspicuous place in the market during the currency of such notice.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2))</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199935_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any owner of a private market who fails to post a copy of any notice served upon him in accordance with subsection (2) and any person who after the posting of such copy fails to comply with the terms thereof shall be guilty of an offence.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679390_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Restrictions on sale of commodities in private markets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411199950_034" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No commodity other than fresh meat, fresh fish, poultry, fresh vegetables or fruit or such other commodity as the Director may from time to time permit, either generally or in any particular case, shall be sold in a private market.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2))</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199966_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No commodity shall be sold in a private market otherwise than from a stall in that part of the market place set aside by the Director as the part in which such commodity may be sold.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199966_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No commodity shall be sold in a private market otherwise than by retail.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679406_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Annual account</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411199981_019" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of every private market shall cause to be prepared for every period of 12 months ending on 31 March in each year an income and expenditure account, which shall be delivered, not later than 14 April next following the end of the period covered by the account, to the Director for inspection and return.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411199981_027" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every account referred to in subsection (1) shall be in such form as the Director may require, either generally or in any particular case, and, immediately after the return thereof by the Director the owner of the market to which such account relates shall cause the account, together with any report by the Director thereon, to be posted in a conspicuous place in the market place and there to remain posted for not less than 7 consecutive days.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679421_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Copies of Regulation to be posted</heading><content>The owner of any private market shall cause one copy of this Regulation in the English language and one copy thereof in the Chinese language to be kept posted at all times in a conspicuous position in every private market place.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679421_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Power of Director to prescribe hours during which private market to be closed to public</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411200044_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may prescribe the hours during which a private market shall be closed to the public.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200044_012" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Director has prescribed the hours during which a private market shall be closed to the public, he shall cause a notice specifying such hours to be posted in a conspicuous position in the market place.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200044_020" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Save with the permission in writing of the Director, no person shall be in a private market during the hours prescribed by the Director as the hours during which the market shall be closed to the public.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679468_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Cleanliness of private markets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411200059_034" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every private market shall at all times be maintained by the owner thereof in a clean and sanitary condition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200059_042" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If at any time the Director is of the opinion that a private market is not in a clean and sanitary condition it may, after serving upon the owner thereof 24 hours’ notice of intention, carry out, or cause to be carried out, such work as may be necessary to render the market clean and sanitary and, for that purpose, may, by notice in writing served on any licensed stallholder of such market, require him, at a time to be specified in the notice, to remove from his stall all articles of what kind so ever during such time as may be required to cleanse the stall and such part of the market as is adjacent thereto.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2))</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200091_005" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any expenses incurred by the carrying out under subsection (2) of any work may be recovered by the Director from the owner of the market.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2))</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679468_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Obstruction of private market by stalls</heading><content>No person shall erect any structure or place any article or vehicle in a private market so as to cause thereby obstruction in any passageway or open space therein intended for access by the public.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402679484_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Hawking, etc. in private market prohibited</heading><content>No person shall hawk or cry for sale in a private market any goods or wares whatsoever.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402679484_004" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Hawkers not to deposit or store goods, etc. in private market</heading><content>No hawker shall deposit or store in a private market any goods or wares or other articles whatsoever.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402679499_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Restriction on cleaving of carcasses and plucking, etc. of poultry</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411200153_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person in a private market shall cleave a carcass, or any part of a carcass, except upon a cleaving block, a chopping board or hooks provided for the purpose. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200153_012" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person in a private market shall kill, bleed, pluck, scald or clean any poultry or game otherwise than in a place approved for that purpose by the Director.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402679515_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Refuse</heading><content>No person shall throw or deposit any filth or refuse of any kind whatsoever in any passageway, surface channel or thoroughfare in a private market.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402679515_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Restriction on transport of goods through private market</heading><content>No person shall transport through a private market any goods or wares intended for sale elsewhere than in the market.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402679531_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Prohibition of begging</heading><content>No person in a private market shall beg or gather alms or, for the purpose of gathering alms, expose or exhibit any sores, wounds or bodily ailment or deformity.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402679531_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Dogs</heading><content>No person shall cause or suffer any dog that belongs to him or is in his charge to enter or remain in a private market.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402679562_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Disorderly conduct</heading><content>No person in a private market shall behave in a disorderly manner.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438402679562_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Licensing
            and Duties
            of
            Stallholders</heading><section id="ID_1438402679577_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Licensing of stallholders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411200278_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Save under and in accordance with a licence granted by the Director, no person shall carry on business from a stall of a private market.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200278_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every such licence shall be renewable annually on 1 July.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200278_020" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>The grant or renewal of such a licence shall be subject to the payment in advance to the Director of a fee of $5:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s22_3_proviso">Provided that, where the licence is issued in the second half of any year of licence, the fee payable in respect of the grant thereof shall be one-half of the fee prescribed.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200278_034" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the Director is satisfied that any such licence has been lost or destroyed, he may upon payment of a fee of $1 issue a duplicate thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200278_042" name="5" temporalId="s22_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If it appears to the Director that no or no appreciable business has been carried on from any stall for a period of 30 consecutive days, the Director may in his discretion, after serving upon the licensee of such stall 7 days’ notice in writing of his intention, cancel the licence therefor.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679577_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Stall cards</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411200309_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A licensed stallholder shall at all times keep posted in a conspicuous position on his stall a stall card to be issued by the Director to the stallholder upon application therefor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200309_012" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every application to the Director for a stall card shall be accompanied by 2 photographs of the licensed stallholder.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679593_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Register of employees of licensed stallholder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411200325_011" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A licensed stallholder shall at all times keep at his stall a register in a form to be prescribed by the Director containing the name and a photograph of each person for the time being employed by him at the stall.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200325_019" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every such register shall at all times be kept up to date and shall be produced for inspection upon demand by any police officer or health officer or officers of the Food and Environmental Hygiene Department.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679593_004" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Cleanliness of stalls</heading><content>Every licensed stallholder shall at all times keep his stall in a clean and sanitary condition and shall provide and use thereat a dustbin of a type approved by the Director.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32</ref>(2); <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679609_002" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Goods, etc. not to be deposited or stored outside stall</heading><content>No licensed stallholder shall deposit or store any of his goods or wares or any other article belonging to him in any part of the market outside his stall or permit or suffer any of his goods or wares or any such other article to be so placed or stored or to project outside his stall.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438402679624_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Offences
            and
            Penalties</heading><section id="ID_1438402679624_003" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411200403_004" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the event of a contravention of <ref>section 4(1)</ref> or <ref>5</ref>, the person by whom the private market is being carried on and any person taking any part in the management thereof shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine at level 3 and to imprisonment for 3 months and shall be liable in addition to a fine of $450 for each day during which it is proved to the satisfaction of the court that the offence has continued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200434_005" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes <ref>section 22(1)</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine at level 3 and to imprisonment for 3 months and shall be liable in addition to a fine of $450 for each day during which it is proved to the satisfaction of the court that the offence has continued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200434_013" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In the event of a contravention of <ref>section 7</ref>, <ref>9</ref>, <ref>10</ref>, <ref>12(1)</ref> or <ref>13</ref>, the owner of the private market and any person taking any part in the management thereof shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine at level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200730_005" name="4" temporalId="s27_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any licensed stallholder who contravenes <ref>section 8</ref>, <ref>23(1)</ref>, <ref>25</ref> or <ref>26</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine at level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411200746_005" name="5" temporalId="s27_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411200746_013" name="a" temporalId="s27_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>contravenes <ref>section 11(3)</ref>, <ref>14</ref>, <ref>15</ref>, <ref>16</ref>, <ref>17</ref>, <ref>18</ref>, <ref>19</ref>, <ref>20</ref>, <ref>21</ref> or <ref>24</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411200746_021" name="b" temporalId="s27_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fails to comply with a requirement made by the Director under <ref>section 12(2)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine at level 2.</continued></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32(2)</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/ln306">L.N. 306 of 1987</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1996/ln177">L.N. 177 of 1996</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402679640_002" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-17" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Name in which proceedings for offences may be brought</heading><content>Without prejudice to the provisions of any enactment relating to the prosecution of criminal offences and without prejudice to the powers of the Secretary for Justice in relation to the prosecution of such offences, prosecutions for an offence under this Regulation may be brought in the name of the Director.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/10">10 of 1986 s. 32(2)</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></main></subLeg>