<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 296 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>296A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap296A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-07-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402953935_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-03-19">Reserved
                                    Commodities (Control of Imports, Exports and Reserve Stocks)
                                    Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap296/s3">Cap.
                                                296, section
                                    3</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 November 1979]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402953935_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the Reserved Commodities (Control of Imports, Exports and Reserve Stocks) Regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402953951_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AirTranshipmentCargo"><term>air
                transhipment
            cargo</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">航空轉運貨物</term>) has the meaning assigned to it in
                <ref>section 2</ref> of the Import and Export Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap60">Cap.
                60</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/29">29
                    of 2000 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="CargoTranshipmentAreaOfHongKongInternationalAirport"><term>cargo
                transhipment area of Hong Kong International
            Airport</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機場貨物轉運區</term>) has the meaning assigned to it in
                <ref>section 2</ref> of the Import and Export Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap60">Cap.
                60</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/29">29
                    of 2000 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Licence"><term>licence</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">許可證</term>) means a licence issued under these
            regulations;</def><def name="Owner"><leadIn><term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>), in respect of a vessel, aircraft or
                vehicle, means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825168_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the registered owner and any person holding himself out to be the owner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825168_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any person acting as agent for the owner in connection with the handling of cargo carried in or on the vessel, aircraft or vehicle;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825168_042" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any person to whom the vessel, aircraft or vehicle has been chartered or hired; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825168_050" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any person having for the time being the control or management of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle;</content></paragraph></def><def name="ReservedCommodity"><term>reserved
                commodity</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">儲備商品</term>) means a commodity specified as a reserved
            commodity in the <ref>Schedule</ref>;</def><def name="ReservedCommodityStoragePlace"><term>reserved
                commodity storage
            place</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">儲備商品貯存地方</term>) means any godown, store or other place
            approved by the Director under <ref>regulation 10</ref>;</def><def name="Stockholder"><term>stockholder</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">貯存商</term>) means any person registered as a
            stockholder with the Director under <ref>regulation 13(1)(a)</ref>.</def><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/ln35">L.N. 35 of 2003</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402953966_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Prohibition of import of reserved commodities except under licence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825199_018" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), no person shall import into Hong Kong any reserved commodity except under an import licence issued by the Director.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln336">L.N. 336 of 1981</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825199_026" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If there is brought into Hong Kong in any ship an amount of any reserved commodity not exceeding that which is reasonably required for consumption or use in the working of such ship then such reserved commodity shall be deemed not to have been imported within the meaning of this regulation so long as it remains on such ship.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825215_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No import licence shall be required in respect of any reserved commodity imported into Hong Kong in the personal luggage of a person solely for his own consumption or as gifts, in an amount not exceeding 15 kg.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln336">L.N. 336 of 1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/ln143">L.N. 143 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402953982_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Prohibition of export of reserved commodities except under licence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825231_027" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (2), no person shall export from Hong Kong any reserved commodity except under an export licence issued by the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825231_035" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No export licence shall be required in respect of any reserved commodity exported from Hong Kong in the personal luggage of a person solely for his own consumption or as gifts, in an amount not exceeding 15 kg.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln336">L.N. 336 of 1981</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln336">L.N. 336 of 1981</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402953997_001" name="s4A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4A"><num value="4A">4A.</num><heading>Application of <ref>regulations 3</ref> and <ref>4</ref> to air transhipment cargo</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825262_004" name="1" temporalId="s4A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn><ref>Regulation 3(1)</ref> does not apply in relation to a reserved commodity that is air transhipment cargo; but if at any time between its being brought into and taken out of Hong Kong such reserved commodity is removed from the cargo transhipment area of Hong Kong International Airport then, for the purposes of <ref>regulation 3(1)</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825262_012" name="a" temporalId="s4A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the reserved commodity is deemed to be imported at the time of such removal; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825262_020" name="b" temporalId="s4A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the person who brought the reserved commodity, or caused it to be brought, into Hong Kong as air transhipment cargo is deemed to be the person who imports the reserved commodity at the time of its removal,</content></paragraph><continued>and, except to that extent, that regulation has effect as if this paragraph had not been enacted.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825262_033" name="2" temporalId="s4A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Regulation 4(1)</ref> does not apply in relation to a reserved commodity that is air transhipment cargo; but if at any time between its being brought into and taken out of Hong Kong such reserved commodity is removed from the cargo transhipment area of Hong Kong International Airport, <ref>regulation 4(1)</ref> has effect as if this paragraph had not been enacted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825277_005" name="3" temporalId="s4A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438411825277_009" name="a" temporalId="s4A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>For the purpose of the issue of a licence under <ref>regulation 11</ref> for the import of a reserved commodity, the import of a reserved commodity that is air transhipment cargo does not take place unless and until the reserved commodity is removed from the cargo transhipment area of Hong Kong International Airport other than for the purpose of its being taken out of Hong Kong by air.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825277_015" name="b" temporalId="s4A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Nothing in this regulation precludes the issue of a licence under <ref>regulation 11</ref> for the export of a reserved commodity that is air transhipment cargo only because the reserved commodity has been removed from the cargo transhipment area of Hong Kong International Airport.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825293_005" name="4" temporalId="s4A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In proceedings against a person for an offence under <ref>regulation 25(2)(a)</ref> for a contravention of <ref>regulation 3(1)</ref> or <ref>4(1)</ref>, being proceedings—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825293_013" name="a" temporalId="s4A_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to the import or export of a reserved commodity that is air transhipment cargo; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825293_021" name="b" temporalId="s4A_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in which it is necessary for the prosecution to prove that, at any time between its being brought into and taken out of Hong Kong, the reserved commodity was removed from the cargo transhipment area of Hong Kong International Airport,</content></paragraph><continued>it is a defence for the person to show that he took all reasonable steps and exercised reasonable diligence to avoid such removal occurring or that he reasonably believed that such removal had not occurred, as the case may be.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825293_034" name="5" temporalId="s4A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Where in any proceedings the defence provided by paragraph (4) involves an allegation that the commission of the offence was due to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825293_042" name="a" temporalId="s4A_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the act or default of another person; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825309_005" name="b" temporalId="s4A_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>reliance on information given by another person,</content></paragraph><continued>the defendant is not, without the leave of the court, entitled to rely on the defence unless, not less than 10 days before the hearing of the proceedings, he has served a notice in writing on the prosecutor giving all particulars of—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438411825309_019" name="i" temporalId="s4A_5_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the person who committed the act or default or gave the information; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825309_027" name="ii" temporalId="s4A_5_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the act, default or information,</content></paragraph><continued>of which he is aware at the time he serves the notice.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825309_040" name="6" temporalId="s4A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>A person is not entitled to rely on the defence provided by paragraph (4) by reason of his reliance on information supplied by another person, unless he shows that it was reasonable in all the circumstances for him to have relied on the information, having regard in particular to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825309_048" name="a" temporalId="s4A_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the steps which he took, and those which might reasonably have been taken, for the purpose of verifying the information; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825309_056" name="b" temporalId="s4A_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>whether he had any reason to disbelieve the information.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/29">29 of 2000 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402953997_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-07-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Delivery of import licence and manifest to
            Director
            etc.</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s. 83</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438411825355_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to <ref>regulation 6</ref>, a person to whom an import licence for a
                reserved commodity has been issued must, within 7 days after the day on which the
                reserved commodity was imported—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1752542492859_001" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>present the licence to the owner of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle in or
                    on which the reserved commodity was imported (<i><b>conveyance
                    owner</b></i>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752542492859_002" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>send, using the specified system, the licence to the conveyance owner;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752542492859_003" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>otherwise enable the conveyance owner to obtain, using the specified
                    system, the licence. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                        83</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825355_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>On obtaining the licence under paragraph (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1752542492890_004" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the conveyance owner may release the reserved commodity to the consignee if
                    the owner is satisfied that the owner is not prohibited from doing so under the
                    conditions of the licence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752542492890_005" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the conveyance owner must, within 7 days after the day on which the licence
                    was obtained—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1752542492890_006" name="1" temporalId="s5_2_b_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>deliver the licence to the Director, or (if applicable) inform the
                        Director, using the specified system, of the licence number of the licence;
                        and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1752542492890_007" name="2" temporalId="s5_2_b_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>deliver to the Director, using the specified system, a copy or extract
                        of the manifest of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle in or on which the
                        reserved commodity was imported. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of
                                2025 s. 83</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825371_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The conveyance owner is taken to have complied with the requirement under
                paragraph <ref>(2)(b)(ii)</ref> if, at the time of delivering the licence or
                informing the Director of the licence number (if applicable) under paragraph
                    <ref>(2)(b)(i)</ref>, the manifest has been lodged using the specified system
                with the Commissioner, or with an officer appointed by the Commissioner, under
                    <ref>regulation 11</ref> of the Import and Export (Registration) Regulations
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap60E">Cap. 60 sub. leg. E</ref>). <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s. 83</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954013_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-07-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Delivery of import licence and manifest in case of part shipment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825433_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If a reserved commodity which is imported forms part only of a consignment of the reserved commodity in respect of which the licence has been issued, the person to whom the licence was issued shall present—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825433_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the import licence endorsed by him to this effect; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825433_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a written declaration signed by him stating that the reserved commodity which has been imported forms part only of a consignment of that reserved commodity in respect of which the licence was issued,</content></paragraph><continued>to the owner of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle in or on which the reserved commodity was imported within 7 days after the reserved commodity is imported.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825433_033" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The owner of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle, on receiving from a licensee an endorsed import licence and written declaration pursuant to paragraph (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825433_041" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may release the reserved commodity to the consignee if he is satisfied that he is not prohibited from doing so under any condition of the import licence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825449_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>shall, within 7 days after receiving the import licence and written declaration—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825449_014" name="i" temporalId="s6_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>endorse the licence and return it to the person to whom it was issued;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/ln35">L.N. 35 of 2003</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825449_022" name="ii" temporalId="s6_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>deliver the declaration to the Director; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/ln35">L.N. 35 of 2003</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825449_030" name="iii" temporalId="s6_2_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>deliver to the Director, using
                        the
                        specified system, a copy or extract of the manifest of the
                        vessel, aircraft or vehicle in or on which the reserved commodity was
                            imported.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/ln35">L.N. 35 of
                            2003</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                            84</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825449_036" name="2A" temporalId="s6_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><content>The owner of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle is taken to have complied with the
                requirement under paragraph <ref>(2)(b)(iii)</ref> if, at the time of delivering the
                declaration under paragraph <ref>(2)(b)(ii)</ref>, the manifest has been lodged
                using the specified system with the Commissioner, or with an officer appointed by
                the Commissioner, under <ref>regulation 11</ref> of the Import and Export
                (Registration) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap60E">Cap. 60 sub. leg. E</ref>).
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                84</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825465_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The written declaration referred to in paragraph (1) or (2) shall be made in such form as the Director may specify.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954029_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-07-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Carrier not to accept reserved commodity for export unless licence produced</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825496_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Except in amounts and in the circumstances specified in <ref>regulation
                    4(2)</ref>, the owner of a vessel, aircraft or vehicle shall not accept a
                reserved commodity for export on the vessel, aircraft or vehicle
                until—
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln336">L.N. 336 of 1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/29">29 of
                        2000 s.
                    8</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                    85</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1752542685555_001" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an export licence for that reserved commodity is presented to the owner;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752542685555_002" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the owner has obtained, using the specified system, an export licence for
                    that reserved commodity. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                            85</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825496_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Paragraph (1) does not apply in relation to a reserved commodity that is air transhipment cargo.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/29">29 of 2000 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954029_003" name="s7A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-07-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7A"><num value="7A">7A.</num><heading>Retention of possession of reserved commodity after import</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825511_019" name="1" temporalId="s7A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Except in the amounts and in the circumstances specified in <ref>regulation
                    3(3)</ref>, the owner of a vessel, aircraft or vehicle in which any reserved
                commodity is imported shall retain possession of the reserved
                commodity
                        until— <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/29">29 of 2000 s.
                        8</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                    86</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825527_005" name="a" temporalId="s7A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an import licence for that reserved commodity is presented to the
                    owner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825527_013" name="b" temporalId="s7A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the owner has obtained, using the specified system, an import licence for
                    that reserved commodity; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752547056813_001" name="c" temporalId="s7A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Commissioner gives to the owner written directions in respect of the
                    removal or storage of that reserved commodity. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s. 86</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825527_020" name="2" temporalId="s7A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Paragraph (1) does not apply in relation to a reserved commodity that is air transhipment cargo.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/29">29 of 2000 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln336">L.N. 336 of 1981</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402954044_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-07-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Delivery of export licence and manifest to
            Director
            etc.</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s. 87</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438411825543_019" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An owner of a reserved commodity to whom a licence has been issued for the
                export of the reserved commodity must, before the reserved commodity is
                exported—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1752542902750_001" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>present the licence to the owner of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle in or
                    on which the reserved commodity is intended to be exported (<i><b>conveyance
                            owner</b></i>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752542902750_002" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>send, using the specified system, the licence to the conveyance owner;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752542902750_003" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>otherwise enable the conveyance owner to obtain, using the specified
                    system, the licence. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                        87</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825543_027" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>On obtaining the licence under paragraph (1), the conveyance owner must, within
                14 days after the day on which the reserved commodity was exported—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1752542902781_004" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>deliver the licence to the Director, or (if applicable) inform the
                    Director, using the specified system, of the licence number of the licence;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752542902781_005" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>deliver to the Director, using the specified system, a copy or extract of
                    the manifest of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle in or on which the reserved
                    commodity was exported. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s.
                            87</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825558_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The conveyance owner is taken to have complied with the requirement under
                paragraph <ref>(2)(b)</ref> if, at the time of delivering the licence or informing
                the Director of the licence number (if applicable) under paragraph
                <ref>(2)(a)</ref>, the manifest has been lodged using the specified system with the
                Commissioner, or with an officer appointed by the Commissioner, under
                    <ref>regulation 12</ref> of the Import and Export (Registration) Regulations
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap60E">Cap. 60 sub. leg. E</ref>). <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s. 87</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954060_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Storage of reserved commodities on importation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825589_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person to whom a licence to import a reserved commodity is issued shall upon its importation store the reserved commodity in a reserved commodity storage place if required to do so by the licence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825589_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>No person shall take or give delivery of any reserved commodity except in accordance with the written authority of the Commissioner:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_2_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825589_027" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the owner or agent of the owner of any vessel, aircraft or vehicle by which a reserved commodity has been imported may deliver such reserved commodity to a reserved commodity storage place and delivery of such reserved commodity at such reserved commodity storage place may be taken without any written authority from the Commissioner; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825605_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an export licence granted in accordance with <ref>regulation 4</ref> shall be deemed to be a sufficient authority for the purpose of this paragraph.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln294">L.N. 294 of 1982</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954060_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Approved reserved commodity storage places</heading><content>The Director may approve any godown, store or other place as a reserved commodity storage place either generally or limited to a specified period, a specified reserved commodity or a specified quantity of a reserved commodity and may attach to such approval such conditions as he thinks fit.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402954075_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Application for and conditions of licence to import or export</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825636_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may issue a licence to any person to import or export any reserved commodity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825636_019" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An application for a licence shall be made in writing to the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825636_027" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A licence issued by the Director may be subject to such conditions as the Director thinks fit as to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825636_035" name="a" temporalId="s11_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the amount of the reserved commodity comprised in such licence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825636_043" name="b" temporalId="s11_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the period of time within which and the means by which such reserved commodity may be imported or exported;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825636_051" name="c" temporalId="s11_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of an import licence, the period of time within which the said reserved commodity or any part thereof shall be sold or exported;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825652_006" name="d" temporalId="s11_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in the case of an import licence, whether the reserved commodity is to be stored in a reserved commodity storage place upon importation.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954075_003" name="s11A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s11A"><num value="11A">11A.</num><heading>Power to exempt from licensing requirements</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825667_004" name="1" temporalId="s11A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If the Director is satisfied that a person is engaged in the business of dealing in transhipment cargo he may exempt in writing, with respect to the transhipment of any reserved commodity specified in that exemption, that person from the licensing requirements under these regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825667_012" name="2" temporalId="s11A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director may impose such conditions as he thinks fit upon any exemption made under paragraph (1) and any person exempted under paragraph (1) shall comply with any condition imposed under this paragraph.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825667_020" name="3" temporalId="s11A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If a person contravenes or fails to comply with any condition imposed under paragraph (2)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825667_028" name="a" temporalId="s11A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a
                    fine
                    at
                    level 5 and to imprisonment for 1 year; and
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825683_006" name="b" temporalId="s11A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Director may by notice in writing revoke or suspend any exemption
                    granted to that person or
                    amend
                    any condition.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln257">L.N. 257 of 1984</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402954091_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Application to be registered as a stockholder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825699_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person may apply to the Director to be registered as a stockholder of a reserved commodity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825699_012" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An application for registration as a stockholder of a reserved commodity shall be in writing in a form approved by the Director and shall include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825699_020" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the reserved commodity in respect of which the applicant wishes to be registered as a stockholder; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825699_028" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the amount of such reserved commodity which the applicant is prepared to hold as a stockholder.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825699_035" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A separate application shall be made in respect of each reserved commodity.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954107_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Registration as a stockholder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825714_042" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Within 14 days of the receipt by him of an application under <ref>regulation 12</ref> for registration as a stockholder of a reserved commodity, the Director may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825714_050" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>register the applicant as a stockholder of the reserved commodity in respect of which the application was made; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825730_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>give notice in writing to the applicant of his refusal so to register the applicant.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825730_013" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The registration of a stockholder shall be subject to such conditions as the Director may impose.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954107_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Certificate of registration of stockholder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825745_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director shall issue to a stockholder a certificate of registration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825745_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to <ref>regulation 16</ref>, a certificate of registration as a stockholder shall be valid for the period stated in the certificate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825745_020" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The certificate of registration shall state—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825745_028" name="a" temporalId="s14_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the quantity of the reserved commodity which the stockholder is required to hold in stock; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825745_036" name="b" temporalId="s14_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the conditions imposed by the Director under <ref>regulation 13(2)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825745_043" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The quantity of a reserved commodity which a stockholder is required to hold in stock shall not exceed the amount stated by the stockholder in his application to be registered as a stockholder.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825745_051" name="5" temporalId="s14_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A certificate of registration shall be in such form as the Director may approve.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825745_059" name="6" temporalId="s14_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Director may at any time alter the conditions of registration of a stockholder and the quantity of the reserved commodity which the stockholder is required to hold in stock.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825761_005" name="7" temporalId="s14_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where the Director alters the conditions of registration of a stockholder or the quantity of the reserved commodity the stockholder is required to hold in stock the stockholder shall on being required by the Director surrender his certificate to the Director who shall issue a new certificate to the stockholder.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954122_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Register of stockholders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825777_052" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director shall cause to be maintained a register of stockholders for each reserved commodity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825777_060" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Such registers shall be available for inspection by any person at the offices of the Director during office hours on payment of a fee of $5.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954138_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Cancellation of registration of stockholder</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825808_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director may cancel the registration of a stockholder—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825808_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the request of the stockholder;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825808_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on the death, dissolution of partnership or bankruptcy of the stockholder or, in the case of a company, on the winding up of the stockholder;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825808_028" name="c" temporalId="s16_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if any condition of his registration in respect of the reserved commodity is contravened;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825808_036" name="d" temporalId="s16_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if the registered stockholder or any person employed by him commits an offence under the Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825808_044" name="e" temporalId="s16_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>by giving the stockholder 3
                    months’
                    notice in writing.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825808_051" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Director cancels the registration of a stockholder under paragraph (1), he shall notify the stockholder and shall state under which subparagraph of paragraph (1) the registration is cancelled.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825823_005" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the Director has notified a stockholder of the cancellation of his registration under paragraph (2), the stockholder shall forthwith surrender his certificate of registration to the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825823_013" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the Director serves a notice on a stockholder of the cancellation under paragraph <ref>(1)(e)</ref> of his registration, the stockholder shall surrender his certificate of registration to the Director within the period specified in the notice.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954153_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Disposal of stocks by stockholder on cancellation of registration</heading><content>Where the Director cancels the registration of a stockholder of a reserved commodity, the stockholder shall dispose of his stocks of that reserved commodity in accordance with the directions of the Director.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402954153_004" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Duty to maintain stock</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825855_011" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A stockholder shall at all times during the continuance of his certificate of registration maintain as stock not less than the amount of the reserved commodity specified in his certificate, or such lesser amount as the Director may from time to time authorize in writing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825855_019" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Such stock shall be maintained in such reserved commodity storage place as the Director may from time to time in writing direct.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825870_005" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Such stock shall be maintained in good condition to the satisfaction of the Director.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954169_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Records and returns of stocks</heading><leadIn>The Director may require a stockholder to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825870_043" name="a" temporalId="s19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>keep such records; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825886_006" name="b" temporalId="s19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>submit to the Director such returns of stock of and transactions in the reserved commodity in respect of which he is registered, balance sheets, profit and loss accounts and other financial records,</content></paragraph><continued>as the Director may specify.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438402954185_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Control of stocks</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825901_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director may by notice in writing to a stockholder order that the stock of a reserved commodity held by such stockholder or any part thereof shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825901_012" name="a" temporalId="s20_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>removed from any reserved commodity storage place in which it is stored;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825901_020" name="b" temporalId="s20_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>replaced by other stocks of such reserved commodity; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825901_028" name="c" temporalId="s20_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>otherwise dealt with as the Director may direct.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825901_035" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A stockholder who receives an order from the Director under this regulation shall forthwith carry out such order at the sole expense of such stockholder.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954185_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Inspection of stocks</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825917_028" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Commissioner or an authorized officer may at any time enter the premises of a stockholder for the purpose of examining the reserved commodities held by the stockholder and all documents relating thereto.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825917_036" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A stockholder shall permit the Commissioner or any authorized officer to enter any premises of the stockholder at any time for the purposes of paragraph (1) and to inspect any reserved commodities and any documents relating thereto on the premises.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln294">L.N. 294 of 1982</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402954200_002" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Restriction on sales by wholesale by stockholder and price control</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825933_033" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director may by notice in writing to a stockholder of a reserved commodity—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825948_005" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>restrict the sale by wholesale of that reserved commodity by the stockholder to—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825948_013" name="i" temporalId="s22_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>registered wholesalers; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825948_021" name="ii" temporalId="s22_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>specified registered wholesalers,</content></subparagraph><continued>in that reserved commodity; or</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825948_034" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>fix the maximum price at which the stockholder may sell that reserved commodity by wholesale—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825948_042" name="i" temporalId="s22_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>generally;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825948_050" name="ii" temporalId="s22_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to registered wholesalers in that reserved commodity; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411825948_058" name="iii" temporalId="s22_1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>to other classes of persons specified in the notice;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825948_065" name="c" temporalId="s22_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>require the stockholder to sell such quantity of the reserved commodity to
                    such registered wholesaler or other person, as the Director may specify at a
                    price not exceeding the maximum price fixed under
                    subparagraph (b).
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825948_072" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A notice under paragraph (1) may be addressed to all stockholders or to specified stockholders.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825948_080" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A notice under paragraph (1) shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825948_088" name="a" temporalId="s22_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>served on each stockholder to whom it applies; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825948_096" name="b" temporalId="s22_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>published in the Gazette.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825948_103" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A stockholder to whom a notice under paragraph (1) applies shall comply therewith as soon as the notice is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411825964_005" name="a" temporalId="s22_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>served on him; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411825964_013" name="b" temporalId="s22_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>published in the Gazette,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the sooner.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954216_001" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Prohibition of sales by wholesale to registered wholesaler convicted of offence against the Ordinance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411825995_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may by notice in writing to a stockholder of a reserved commodity prohibit the sale by wholesale of that reserved commodity by the stockholder to a registered wholesaler specified in the notice on the ground that such wholesaler has been convicted of an offence under the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825995_012" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of a prohibition under paragraph (1) shall be served on the stockholder who shall forthwith comply with the prohibition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411825995_020" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A copy of a notice served on a stockholder under paragraph (2) shall be served on the registered wholesaler specified in the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411826011_005" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A notice under paragraph (1) may specify more than 1 registered wholesaler and be addressed to more than 1 stockholder.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954216_003" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Offences in respect of applications, licences, certificates and records</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411826026_035" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411826026_043" name="a" temporalId="s24_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in an application for a licence under <ref>regulation 11</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411826026_051" name="b" temporalId="s24_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in an application for registration as a stockholder under <ref>regulation
                        12</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411826026_059" name="c" temporalId="s24_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in any record kept or return made under <ref>regulation 19</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>makes any statement or furnishes any information which he knows or ought to
                know to be false or misleading in a material particular shall be guilty of an
                offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                at
                level 5 and to imprisonment for 1 year.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411826042_011" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who, without the authority of the Director, alters in a material
                particular a licence issued under <ref>regulation 11</ref> or a certificate issued
                under <ref>regulation 14</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
                conviction to a fine
                at
                level 6 and to imprisonment for 2 years.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402954231_002" name="s25" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Other offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411826057_041" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any stockholder who fails to comply with <ref>regulation 18</ref> shall be
                guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                at
                level 6 and to imprisonment for 2 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411826057_049" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411826057_057" name="a" temporalId="s25_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>contravenes <ref>regulation 3</ref>, <ref>4</ref>, <ref>9</ref> or
                        <ref>21</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411826073_006" name="b" temporalId="s25_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fails to comply with <ref>regulation 19</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411826073_014" name="c" temporalId="s25_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>fails to comply with a notice under <ref>regulation 22(1)</ref> in
                    accordance with <ref>regulation 22(4)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411826073_022" name="d" temporalId="s25_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>fails to comply with a notice of prohibition under <ref>regulation
                        23(1)</ref> in accordance with <ref>regulation 23(2)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                at
                level 5 and to imprisonment for 1 year.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411826073_035" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person who contravenes <ref>regulation 7</ref> or <ref>7A</ref> shall,
                unless he proves that he did not know and could not with reasonable diligence have
                known that the commodity accepted for export, or imported, as the case may be, was a
                reserved commodity, be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a
                fine
                at
                level 5 and to imprisonment for 1 year.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln336">L.N. 336 of
                    1981</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411826073_043" name="4" temporalId="s25_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person who without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with any direction of
                the Director under <ref>regulation 17</ref> or with an order of the Director under
                    <ref>regulation 20</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
                conviction to a fine
                at
                level 5 and to imprisonment for 1 year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411826089_005" name="5" temporalId="s25_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person who fails to surrender his certificate of registration under
                    <ref>regulation 14(7)</ref> or <ref>regulation 16(3)</ref> or (4) shall be
                guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                at
                level 2 and to imprisonment for 3 months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411826089_013" name="6" temporalId="s25_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Any person who contravenes <ref>regulation 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref> or
                    <ref>8</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to
                a fine
                at
                level 2.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402954247_001" name="s26" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-07-11" status="repealed" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s. 88</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1752542979130_001" name="s27" temporalId="s27" startPeriod="2025-07-11" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Transitional provisions for Import and Export (Amendment) Ordinance 2025</heading><subsection id="ID_1752543045300_001" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>For the period specified in paragraph (2), a reference in <ref>regulation
                    5</ref>, <ref>6</ref> or <ref>8</ref> to using the specified system is, subject
                to any determination made under <ref>section 14(2)(a)</ref> of the Ordinance or
                notice published under <ref>section 15(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, to be construed as
                a reference to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1752543045316_002" name="a" temporalId="s27_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in so far as it relates to the transmission of a manifest of cargo carried
                    in or on an aircraft, train or vessel (or a copy or extract of the
                    manifest)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1752543045316_003" name="1" temporalId="s27_1_a_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>using a recognized electronic service (within the meaning of the
                        pre-amended Ordinance); or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1752543045316_004" name="2" temporalId="s27_1_a_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>using the specified system; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752543045316_005" name="b" temporalId="s27_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in so far as it relates to the transmission of a manifest of cargo carried
                    in or on a vehicle (other than a train) (or a copy or extract of the
                    manifest)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1752543045316_006" name="1" temporalId="s27_1_b_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>in paper form; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1752543045316_007" name="2" temporalId="s27_1_b_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>using the specified system.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1752543045316_008" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The period specified for the purposes of paragraph (1) is the period—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1752543045316_009" name="a" temporalId="s27_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>beginning on the gazettal date; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1752543045316_010" name="b" temporalId="s27_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>ending at midnight on the date to be appointed by the Commissioner of
                    Customs and Excise for the purposes of this paragraph by notice published in the
                    Gazette.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1752543045316_011" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A notice under paragraph <ref>(2)(b)</ref> may appoint different dates in
                relation to different classes of persons or information.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1752543045316_012" name="4" temporalId="s27_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A notice under paragraph <ref>(2)(b)</ref> is subsidiary legislation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1752543045316_013" name="5" temporalId="s27_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>In this regulation—</leadIn><def name="GazettalDate"><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline><term>gazettal date</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">刊憲日期</term>) means the date on which the Import and
                Export (Amendment) Ordinance 2025 (<ref href="hk/2025/30">30 of 2025</ref>) is
                published in the Gazette;</def><def name="PreamendedOrdinance"><term>pre-amended Ordinance</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">《原有條例》</term>) means the Ordinance as in force immediately
                before the gazettal date.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/30">30 of 2025 s. 89</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1753685387322_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Gazettal date: 11 July
                2025.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402954247_003" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap296A/s2">reg. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Reserved
            Commodities<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><section id="ID_1438411826198_020" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Rice, with or without husk, and milled or unmilled.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411826198_029" name="s2...3" temporalId="sch0_s2...3" class="no_header"><num value="2...3">2-3.</num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2000/ln143">L.N. 143 of
                        2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section></schedule></main></subLeg>