<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 6 sub. leg. E</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>6E</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap6E!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-12-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403559572_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-07-23">Proof
                                    of Debts Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap6/s36">Cap. 6,
                                                section
                                    36</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 January 1932]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="add-toc">Proof in Ordinary
        Cases</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403559587_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1"><b>1.</b></num><content>Every creditor shall prove his debt as soon as may be after the making of a
            bankruptcy order.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559603_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2023-12-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2"><b>2.</b></num><content>A debt may be proved by delivering or
            sending
            to the trustee a proof of debt in the prescribed form which shall be accompanied by the
            prescribed fee as the case may require.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln220">L.N. 220 of 1992</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of
            2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2023/22">22 of 2023 s. 15</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559634_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3"><b>3.</b></num><content>A proof of debt may be made by the creditor himself or by a person authorized by or
            on behalf of the creditor and having knowledge of the facts.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln220">L.N. 220 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559634_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4"><b>4.</b></num><subsection id="ID_1438414024840_018" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The creditor or the person authorized by or on behalf of the creditor shall
                declare in the proof of debt—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414024855_005" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the creditor’s name and address;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414024855_013" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the total amount of his claim as at the date of the bankruptcy
                        order;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414024855_021" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>whether or not that amount includes outstanding uncapitalised
                    interest;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414024855_029" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>particulars of how and when the debt was incurred by the bankrupt;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of
                            1998</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414024855_037" name="e" temporalId="s4_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>particulars of any security held, the date when it was given and the value
                    which the creditor puts upon it; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414024855_045" name="f" temporalId="s4_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the name and the authority of the person signing the proof (if other than
                    the creditor himself) and means of knowledge of the facts.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414024855_052" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>There shall be specified in the proof any documents by reference to which the
                debt can be substantiated and such documents or a copy of such documents shall be
                submitted together with the proof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414024871_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The trustee to whom the proof is sent may call for any document, which has not
                already been submitted, or other evidence to be produced to him, where he thinks it
                necessary for the purpose of substantiating the whole or any part of the claim made
                in the proof.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln220">L.N. 220 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559650_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5"><b>5.</b></num><subsection id="ID_1438414024949_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The trustee may, if he thinks it necessary, require a claim of debt to be
                verified by affidavit in the prescribed form notwithstanding that a proof of debt
                has already been lodged.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414024949_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The affidavit may be sworn before any person authorized to administer oaths or
                take statutory declarations.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln220">L.N. 220 of 1992</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559650_003" name="s5A" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s5A"><num value="5A"><b>5A.</b></num><content>If it is found at any time that the proof made by or on behalf of a secured
            creditor has omitted to state that he is a secured creditor, the secured creditor shall
            surrender his security to the trustee for the general benefit of the creditors unless
            the court on application is satisfied that the omission has arisen from inadvertence in
            which case the court may allow the proof to be amended upon such terms as to the
            repayment of any dividends or otherwise as the court may consider just.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln220">L.N. 220 of 1992</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559665_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6"><b>6.</b></num><content>A creditor shall bear the cost of proving his debt unless the court otherwise
            specially orders.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403559665_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7"><b>7.</b></num><content>Every creditor who has lodged a proof shall be entitled to see and examine the
            proofs of other creditors before the general meeting, and at all reasonable times on
            payment of the prescribed fee.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559681_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8"><b>8.</b></num><content>A creditor proving his debt shall deduct therefrom all trade discounts, but he
            shall not be compelled to deduct any discount, not exceeding 5 per cent on the net
            amount of his claim, which he may have agreed to allow for payment in cash.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Proof by
                Secured
                Creditors</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403559681_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9"><b>9.</b></num><content>If a secured creditor realizes his security, he may prove for the balance
                        due to him, after deducting the net amount realized.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403559696_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10"><b>10.</b></num><content>If a secured creditor surrenders his security to the trustee for the general
            benefit of the creditors, he may prove for his whole debt.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559712_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11"><b>11.</b></num><content>If a secured creditor does not either realize or surrender his security, he shall,
            before ranking for dividend, state in his proof the particulars of his security, the
            date when it was given and the value at which he assesses it, and shall be entitled to
            receive a dividend only in respect of the balance due to him after deducting the value
            so assessed.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403559868_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12"><b>12.</b></num><subsection id="ID_1438414025292_011" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a security is so valued the trustee may at any time redeem it on payment
                to the creditor of the assessed value.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414025292_019" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the trustee is dissatisfied with the value at which a security is assessed,
                he may require that the property comprised in any security so valued be offered for
                sale at such times and on such terms and conditions as may be agreed on between the
                creditor and the trustee or as, in default of such agreement, the court may direct.
                If the sale be by public auction, the creditor, or the trustee on behalf of the
                estate, may bid or purchase.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414025308_005" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Provided that the creditor may at any time by notice in writing require the
                trustee to elect whether he will or will not exercise his power of redeeming the
                security or requiring it to be realized, and if the trustee does not within 6 months
                after receiving the notice signify in writing to the creditor his election to
                exercise the power, he shall not be entitled to exercise it; and the equity of
                redemption, or any other interest in the property comprised in the security which is
                vested in the trustee, shall vest in the creditor and the amount of his debt shall
                be reduced by the amount at which the security has been valued.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403559899_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13"><b>13.</b></num><content>Where a creditor has so valued his security, he may at any time amend the valuation
            and proof on showing to the satisfaction of the trustee or the court that the valuation
            and proof were made bona fide on a mistaken estimate or that the security has diminished
            or increased in value since its previous valuation, but every such amendment shall be
            made at the cost of the creditor and upon such terms as the court shall order, unless
            the trustee allows the amendment without application to the court.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403559930_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14"><b>14.</b></num><content>Where a valuation has been amended in accordance with <ref>rule 13</ref>, the
            creditor shall forthwith repay any surplus dividend which he may have received in excess
            of that to which he would have been entitled on the amended valuation or, as the case
            may be, shall be entitled to be paid out of any money, for the time being available for
            dividend, any dividend or share of dividend which he may have failed to receive by
            reason of the inaccuracy of the original valuation, before that money is made applicable
            to the payment of any future dividend, but he shall not be entitled to disturb the
            distribution of any dividend declared before the date of the amendment.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403559962_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15"><b>15.</b></num><content>If a creditor after having valued his security subsequently realizes it, or if it
            is realized under the provisions of <ref>rule 12</ref>, the net amount realized shall be
            substituted for the amount of any valuation previously made by the creditor, and shall
            be treated in all respects as an amended valuation made by the creditor.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403559962_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16"><b>16.</b></num><content>If a secured creditor does not comply with the foregoing rules, he shall be
            excluded from all share in any dividend.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403559962_005" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17"><b>17.</b></num><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>rule 12</ref>, a creditor shall in no case
            receive more than the full amount of his debt, and interest as provided by the
            Ordinance.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Proof in respect of
        Distinct
        Contracts</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403559977_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18"><b>18.</b></num><content>If a bankrupt was at the date of the bankruptcy order liable in respect of distinct
            contracts as a member of 2 or more distinct firms, or as a sole contractor, and also as
            member of a firm, the circumstance that the firms are in whole or in part composed of
            the same individuals, or that the sole contractor is also one of the joint contractors,
            shall not prevent proof in respect of the contracts, against the properties respectively
            liable on the contracts.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Periodical
        Payments</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403559977_004" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19"><b>19.</b></num><content>When any rent or other payment falls due at stated periods and the bankruptcy order
            is made at any time other than one of those periods, the person entitled to the rent or
            payment may prove for a proportionate part thereof up to the date of the order as if the
            rent or payment became due from day to day.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403559993_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20"><b>20.</b></num><content>On any debt or sum certain, payable at a certain time or otherwise, whereon
            interest is not reserved or agreed and which is overdue at the date of the bankruptcy
            order and provable in bankruptcy, the creditor may prove for interest at the rate
            determined under <ref>section 49(1)(b)</ref> of the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>) that is in effect on the date of the bankruptcy order
            to the date of the order from the time when the debt or sum was payable, if the debt or
            sum is payable by virtue of a written instrument at a certain time, and if payable
            otherwise, then from the time when a demand in writing has been made giving the debtor
            notice that interest will be claimed from the date of the demand until the time of
            payment.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Interest<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Debt
        payable at a future time</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403560008_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21"><b>21.</b></num><content>A creditor may prove for a debt not payable on the date of the bankruptcy order as
            if it were payable presently, and may receive dividends equally with the other
            creditors, deducting only thereout a rebate of interest at the rate of 5 per cent per
            annum computed from the declaration of a dividend to the time when the debt would have
            become payable, according to the terms on which it was contracted.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Admission or
                Rejection of
                Proofs</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403560008_003" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22"><b>22.</b></num><content>The trustee shall examine every proof and the grounds of the debt, and in
                        writing admit or reject it in whole or in part or require further evidence
                        in support of it. If he rejects a proof, he shall state in writing to the
                        creditor the grounds of the rejection.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403560024_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23"><b>23.</b></num><content>If the trustee thinks that a proof has been improperly admitted, the court may, on
            the application of the trustee, after notice to the creditor who made the proof, expunge
            the proof or reduce its amount.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403560024_004" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24"><b>24.</b></num><content>If a creditor is dissatisfied with the decision of the trustee in respect of a
            proof, the court may, on the application of the creditor, reverse or vary the decision.
            The trustee shall not be personally liable for any costs in respect of the rejection by
            him in whole or in part of any proof unless it is proved to the satisfaction of the
            court that he has acted mala fide or with gross negligence.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403560040_002" name="s25" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25"><b>25.</b></num><content>The court may also expunge or reduce a proof upon the application of a creditor if
            the trustee declines to interfere in the matter.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln85">L.N. 85 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403560055_001" name="s26" reason="repealed" role="rule" startPeriod="2007-12-10" status="repealed" temporalId="s26"><num value="26"><b>26.</b></num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2007/ln129">L.N. 129 of
                2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438403560055_003" name="s27" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-07-23" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27"><b>27.</b></num><content>These rules may be cited as the Proof of Debts Rules.</content></section></main></subLeg>