<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 162 sub. leg. D</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>162D</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap162D!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-02-22</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402763240_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2024-02-22">Midwives
                                    Registration (Miscellaneous Provisions)
                                    Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap162/s23">Cap.
                                                162, section
                                    23(2)</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2024/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                                2024</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 January 2000]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1999/ln316">L.N. 316 of
                                                  1999</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2024/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402763240_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-02-22" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2024/er1">E.R. 1 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402763256_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2000-01-01" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Functions of secretary relating to practising certificates</heading><content>If a declaration referred to in <ref>section 22(3)(b)</ref> of the Ordinance shows that an applicant for a practising certificate has been convicted of a criminal offence that is punishable with imprisonment, in Hong Kong or elsewhere, the secretary shall submit the declaration to the chairman of the Preliminary Investigation Committee.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402763271_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2000-01-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Functions of secretary to give prior notice to legal adviser</heading><leadIn>The secretary shall notify the legal adviser to the Council in advance of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411437882_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any inquiry to be held;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411437882_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any other meeting held by the Council at which the legal adviser’s presence is likely to be specifically required.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402763271_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2002-07-12" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Functions of secretary relating to inquiry by Council</heading><leadIn>At an inquiry under <ref>section 8</ref> or <ref>10</ref> of the Ordinance, the secretary has, in particular, the following functions—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411437913_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>read the notice of inquiry at the opening of the inquiry;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411437913_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the absence of the respondent and the respondent’s representative at the opening of the inquiry, submit to the Council such evidence as the Council may require to prove that the notice of inquiry or, where applicable, the notice of adjournment has been served on the respondent in accordance with <ref>section 18(2)(b)</ref> or <ref>19(2)(a)</ref> of the Midwives (Registration and Disciplinary Procedure) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap162C">Cap. 162 sub. leg. C</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/9">9 of 2002 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411437913_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>present the case against the respondent, adduce evidence to support the case and close the case;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411437929_006" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>make a reply, if the respondent or the respondent’s representative has made any submission at the conclusion of the presentation of the case against the respondent by the secretary;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411437929_014" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>address the Council in reply at the conclusion of the respondent’s case, if the respondent is called upon to state the respondent’s case; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411437929_022" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>produce to the Council the records of any meeting of the Council at which an order has been made against the respondent under the Ordinance, if an order against the respondent is to be decided.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402763287_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2000-01-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Other functions of secretary</heading><content>The secretary has, other than those mentioned in <ref>sections 2</ref>, <ref>3</ref> and <ref>4</ref>, such other functions which are required to be performed by the secretary under the Midwives (Registration and Disciplinary Procedure) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap162C">Cap. 162 sub. leg. C</ref>).</content></section><section id="ID_1438402763287_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2000-01-01" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Attendance of legal adviser</heading><content>If notice has been given to the legal adviser to the Council under <ref>section 3</ref> in respect of an inquiry or a meeting of the Council, the legal adviser shall attend such inquiry or meeting.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402764051_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2000-01-01" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Advice given by legal adviser to inquiry</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411437976_018" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If, during an inquiry held under <ref>section 8</ref> or <ref>10</ref> of the Ordinance, the legal adviser to the Council advises the Council on any question of law as to evidence, procedure or any other matter, the legal adviser shall give the advice in the presence of every party to the proceedings or in the presence of the person representing each of the parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411437991_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If, after the Council has commenced to deliberate as to its findings, the legal adviser gives any advice on any question of law as to evidence, procedure or any other matter in respect of an inquiry under <ref>section 8</ref> or <ref>10</ref> of the Ordinance, the legal adviser shall inform all parties to the proceedings or their representatives of his advice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411438007_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the Council does not accept any of the advice given by the legal adviser under subsection (1) or (2), the legal adviser shall inform the parties to the proceedings or their representatives accordingly.</content></subsection></section></main></subLeg>