<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 294</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>294</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap294!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-09-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402946244_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-09-01">
            <content>To authorize the disposal of goods accepted in the course of a business for
                repair or other treatment but not redelivered; and for purposes connected
                therewith.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 January 1970]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402946244_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Disposal of Uncollected Goods Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402946260_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-01" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Right of bailees to sell goods accepted for repair or other treatment but not
            redelivered</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411798882_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance shall apply in relation to the bailment of any goods accepted
                (whether before or after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance) by the bailee, in the course of a business, for repair or other
                treatment on the terms (express or implied) that they will be redelivered to the
                bailor or in accordance with the bailor’s directions when the repair or other
                treatment has been carried out and on payment to the bailee of such charges as may
                be agreed between the parties or as may be reasonable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411798898_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where goods accepted as aforesaid are ready for redelivery but the bailor fails
                both—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411798898_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to pay or tender to the bailee his charges in relation to the goods;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411798898_021" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to take delivery of the goods or, if the terms of the bailment so provide,
                    to give directions as to their delivery,</content></paragraph><continued>the bailee shall, subject to the provisions of any agreement between him and
                the bailor and to the following provisions of this Ordinance, be entitled, while the
                failure continues, to sell the goods.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411798898_034" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The bailee shall not be entitled by virtue of subsection (2) to sell goods
                accepted by him for repair or other treatment unless the following provisions are
                complied with, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411798898_042" name="a" temporalId="s2_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at all premises used or appropriated by the bailee for accepting for repair
                    or other treatment goods of the class to which the goods accepted belong, there
                    is, at the time of the acceptance (whether or not the goods are accepted at any
                    such premises), conspicuously displayed in the part of the premises so used or
                    appropriated a notice written in English and Chinese indicating that the
                    acceptance by the bailee of goods of that class for repair or other treatment is
                    subject to the provisions of this Ordinance and that this Ordinance confers on
                    the bailee a right of sale exercisable in certain circumstances after an
                    interval of not less than 12 months from the date on which the goods are ready
                    for redelivery;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411798929_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>after the goods are ready for redelivery, or after the commencement of this
                    Ordinance, whichever is the later, the bailee gives to the bailor a notice that
                    the goods are ready for redelivery, being a notice complying with the
                    requirements of subsection (7);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411798929_014" name="c" temporalId="s2_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>after the expiration of the period of 12 months beginning with the date of
                    the giving of the notice that the goods are ready for redelivery and not less
                    than 14 days before the sale of the goods, the bailee gives to the bailor a
                    notice of his intention to sell the goods, being a notice complying with the
                    requirements of subsection (7),</content></paragraph><continued>and the bailee shall not be so entitled to sell the goods in a lot in which
                goods not accepted by him from the bailor are included or to sell them otherwise
                than by public auction:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s2_3_proviso">
                <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411798945_019" name="i" temporalId="s2_3_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>paragraph (a) shall not apply in relation to any goods accepted before
                        the commencement of this Ordinance for repair or other treatment;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411798945_027" name="ii" temporalId="s2_3_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>where the notice of the bailee’s intention to sell the goods states, in
                        addition to the matters required to be contained therein by subsection (7),
                        the lowest price which he is prepared to accept on a sale of the goods by
                        virtue of this section, he may sell the goods for not less than that price
                        otherwise than by public auction.</content></paragraph>
            </proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411798945_034" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where, at any time before the giving of the notice of the bailee’s intention to
                sell the goods, a dispute arises between the bailor and the bailee by reason of the
                bailor’s refusal to pay the sum which the bailee claims to be due to him by way of
                his charges in relation to the goods, or to take delivery thereof or give directions
                as to their delivery, on the ground that the charges are excessive or that the
                bailor is not satisfied that the repair or other treatment of the goods has been
                properly carried out, the bailee’s right to sell the goods shall be suspended until
                the dispute is determined.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411798976_005" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to any other mode of determining a dispute, it shall be
                treated for the purposes of this Ordinance as having been determined if the bailee,
                at any time after the dispute has arisen, gives to the bailor a notice (hereafter
                referred to as
                        <b><i>a
                        notice to treat the dispute as determined</i></b>)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411798976_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>stating that unless, within the period of one month beginning with the date
                    of the giving of the notice, the bailor objects thereto, the dispute will be
                    treated for the purposes of this Ordinance as having been determined;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411798976_021" name="b" temporalId="s2_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in other respects complying with the requirements of subsection
                    (7),</content></paragraph><continued>and within the said period of one month the bailor does not object to the
                notice; and where the dispute is so treated as having been determined, the date on
                which it shall be so treated as having been determined shall be the date of the
                giving of the notice.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411798976_034" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where a dispute in relation to any goods is determined (whether by virtue of
                subsection (5) or otherwise), subsection (3) shall have effect in relation to those
                goods as if paragraph (b) thereof were omitted and as if for the reference in
                paragraph (c) thereof to the date of the giving of the notice that the goods are
                ready for redelivery there were substituted a reference to the date on which the
                dispute is determined.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411798991_005" name="7" temporalId="s2_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>A notice required or authorized by this section to be given by the bailee to the
                bailor must contain a sufficient description of the goods to which the notice
                relates and a statement of the sum which the bailee claims to be due to him by way
                of his charges in relation to the goods, together with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411798991_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a notice that the goods are ready for redelivery or a notice
                    to treat the dispute as determined, a statement that if the bailor fails, within
                    the period of 12 months beginning with the date of the giving of the notice,
                    both to pay the said sum and to take delivery of the goods or give directions as
                    to their delivery they are liable to be sold in accordance with the provisions
                    of this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799007_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a notice of the bailee’s intention to sell the goods, a
                    statement of the date of the giving of the notice that the goods are ready for
                    redelivery or, where there has been a dispute between the bailor and bailee, the
                    date on which the dispute was determined, and a statement that if the bailor
                    fails, within the period of 14 days beginning with the date of the giving of the
                    notice of the bailee’s intention to sell the goods, both to pay the said sum and
                    to take delivery of the goods or give directions as to their delivery they are
                    liable to be sold in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 43 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1639471235411_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 January
                1970.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402946275_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Notices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411799085_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="Notice">In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires, the
                expression
                    <term>notice</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">通知</term>) means a notice in writing in English or
                Chinese.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799101_004" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A notice required or authorized by this Ordinance to be given by a bailee to a bailor shall, where the bailor is a corporation, be duly given if it is given to the secretary or clerk of the corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799101_012" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A notice required or authorized by this Ordinance to be given by a bailee to a bailor of the bailee’s intention to sell the goods shall be given by sending it by post in a registered letter.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799101_020" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A notice required or authorized by this Ordinance to be given by a bailee to a bailor, other than a notice of the bailee’s intention to sell the goods, may be given either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411799101_028" name="a" temporalId="s3_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by delivering it to the bailor;
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799101_036" name="b" temporalId="s3_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by leaving it at his proper address; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799101_044" name="c" temporalId="s3_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by post.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799101_051" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>For the purposes of this section, and of <ref>section 8</ref> of the Interpretation and General Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>), in its application to this section, the proper address of a person to whom a notice falling within the provisions of subsection (3) or (4) is required or authorized to be given shall, in the case of the secretary or clerk of a corporation, be that of the registered or principal office of the corporation, and, in any other case, be the last known address of the person to whom the notice is to be given.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 43 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402946275_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-01" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Procedure after sale</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411799147_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where goods are sold by virtue of the provisions of this Ordinance, any amount by which the gross proceeds of the sale exceed the charges of the bailee in relation to the goods shall be recoverable by the bailor from the bailee and any amount by which the said charges exceed the gross proceeds of the sale shall be recoverable by the bailee from the bailor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799147_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where goods are so sold, the bailee shall, before the expiration of the period of 7 days beginning with the date of the sale of the goods, prepare a record in relation to the goods containing the following particulars, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411799147_020" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a sufficient description of the goods;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799163_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the method, date and place of the sale;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799163_014" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the goods are sold by public auction, the name and principal place of business of the auctioneer, and where they are sold otherwise than by public auction and the gross proceeds of the sale thereof are not less than $20, the name and address of the buyer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799163_022" name="d" temporalId="s4_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the amount of the gross proceeds of the sale; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799163_030" name="e" temporalId="s4_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a statement of each item of the charges of the bailee in relation to the goods and the transaction to which each item relates,</content></paragraph><continued>and shall, during the period of 6 years beginning with the date on which the record is prepared, keep the record together with a copy of the notice of the bailee’s intention to sell the goods and the certificate of posting of the letter in which the notice was sent, and shall at any reasonable time during the said period of 6 years, if so requested by or on behalf of the bailor, produce the record, copy and certificate, or any of them, for inspection by the bailor or a person nominated in that behalf by him.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799163_043" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (2) shall be
                guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                at level
                1
                and to imprisonment for 3 months.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1970/21">21 of 1970 s.
                    35</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/er4">E.R. 4 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 43 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402946291_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Supplemental provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411799210_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>References in this Ordinance to goods accepted by a bailee in the course of a business for repair or other treatment shall, in relation to goods of any class, be construed as references to goods of that class accepted by him for repair or other treatment in the course of a business consisting of or comprising the acceptance by him of goods of that class for repair or other treatment (whether or not the repair or other treatment is effected by him) wholly or mainly from persons who deliver to him, otherwise than in the course of a business, goods of that class for repair or other treatment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799225_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>References in this Ordinance to the charges of the bailee in relation to any goods shall, subject to the provisions of any agreement between the bailor and the bailee, be construed as references to the amount agreed between them as the charge for the repair or other treatment of the goods or, if no amount has been so agreed, a reasonable charge therefor and, in a case where the goods have been sold, the following additional amounts that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411799241_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a reasonable charge for storing the goods during the period beginning with the date of the giving of the notice that the goods are ready for redelivery, or, where there has been a dispute between the bailor and bailee, the date on which the dispute was determined, and ending with the date of the sale;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799241_013" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any costs of or in
                    connexion
                    with the sale; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799241_021" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the cost, if any, of insuring the goods.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799241_028" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>References in this Ordinance to a bailor or bailee of goods shall, as respects a period during which his rights and obligations in relation to the goods are vested in any other person, be construed as references to that other person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799241_036" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The powers conferred on a bailee by this Ordinance shall be in addition to and not in derogation of any powers exercisable by him independently of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 43 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402946307_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-09-01" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Special provisions applicable to certain cases of goods accepted before the
            commencement of this Ordinance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411799272_019" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where the bailee of goods accepted before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance for repair or other treatment does not at the commencement of this
                Ordinance know any address of the bailor, the bailee shall not be disentitled to
                sell the goods by reason only that paragraphs (b) and (c) of <ref>section 2(3)</ref>
                are not complied with, if the following provisions are complied with, that is to
                say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411799272_027" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>within the period of 6 months beginning with the commencement of this
                    Ordinance, the bailee publishes in an English or Chinese newspaper a notice
                    complying with the requirements of subsection (4);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799288_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at all premises used or appropriated by the bailee after the commencement
                    of this Ordinance for accepting for repair or other treatment goods of the class
                    to which the goods so accepted belong, there is, throughout the period of 12
                    months immediately following the expiration of the said period of 6 months or
                    throughout that portion of the said period of 12 months during which the
                    premises are so used or appropriated, conspicuously displayed in the part of the
                    premises so used or appropriated a notice written in English and Chinese
                    indicating that, in the case of goods of that class accepted before the
                    commencement of this Ordinance for repair or other treatment, this Ordinance
                    confers on the bailee a right of sale exercisable in certain circumstances after
                    an interval of not less than 18 months from the commencement of this
                    Ordinance,</content></paragraph><continued>but the bailee shall not be entitled to sell the goods before the expiration
                of the period of 18 months beginning with the commencement of this
                Ordinance.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799319_011" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the provisions of subsection (1) are complied with in relation to any
                goods, the bailee shall, notwithstanding anything in <ref>section 2(3)</ref>, be
                entitled to sell them otherwise than by public auction, and paragraph (ii) of the
                proviso to the said <ref>section 2(3)</ref> shall not apply in relation to those
                goods.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799319_019" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where goods are sold by virtue of the fact that subsections (1) and (2) have
                been complied with, then <ref>sections 2 to 5</ref> shall have effect in relation to
                the goods subject to the following modifications, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411799319_027" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for any reference in <ref>section 4(2)</ref> to a copy of the notice of the
                    bailee’s intention to sell the goods and the certificate of posting of the
                    letter in which the notice was sent there shall be substituted a reference to a
                    statement of the name and issue of the newspaper in which the notice under
                    subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> was published;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799335_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for the reference in <ref>section 5(2)(a)</ref> to the giving of the notice
                    that the goods are ready for redelivery there shall be substituted a reference
                    to the publication of the notice under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799335_013" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A notice under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> in relation to any goods must
                contain—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411799335_021" name="a" temporalId="s6_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a sufficient description of the class to which the goods belong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799335_029" name="b" temporalId="s6_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the name under which the bailee carries on the business consisting of or
                    comprising the acceptance of goods of that class for repair or other treatment
                    and the address of the bailee’s principal place of business or, where the bailee
                    is a corporation, the registered or principal office of the corporation, and if
                    the name or the address have changed during the 12 months immediately preceding
                    the date of the publication of the notice, the last such name or, as the case
                    may be, the last such address preceding the change thereof; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411799350_006" name="c" temporalId="s6_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a statement that if the bailor of the goods fails within the period of 18
                    months beginning with the commencement of this Ordinance both to pay the sum
                    which the bailee claims to be due to him by way of his charges in relation to
                    the goods and to take delivery of the goods or give directions as to their
                    delivery they are liable to be sold in accordance with the provisions of this
                    Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411799366_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the bailee of goods accepted before the commencement of this Ordinance
                for repair or other treatment does not at the commencement of this Ordinance know
                any address of the bailor and at any time during the period of 18 months beginning
                with the commencement of this Ordinance a dispute arises between the bailor and the
                bailee by reason of either or both of the matters mentioned in <ref>section
                    2(4)</ref>, subsections (1) to (4) shall not apply in relation to the goods, but
                    <ref>sections 2 to 5</ref> shall apply in relation thereto as they apply in a
                case where a dispute arises between the bailor and the bailee before the giving of
                the notice of the bailee’s intention to sell the
                goods.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 43 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1639471734867_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 January
                1970.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></main></ordinance>