<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 284</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>284</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap284!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-08-18</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402934482_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2017-02-15">
            <content>To amend the law relating to innocent
                misrepresentations.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[29 August 1969]<marker role="blank-line"></marker></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402934497_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Misrepresentation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402934513_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Removal of certain bars to rescission for innocent misrepresentation</heading><leadIn>Where a person has entered into a contract after a misrepresentation has been made to him, and—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411770958_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the misrepresentation has become a term of the contract; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411770958_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the contract has been performed,</content></paragraph><continued>or both, then, if otherwise he would be entitled to rescind the contract without alleging fraud, he shall be so entitled, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, notwithstanding the matters mentioned in paragraphs (a) and (b).</continued><referenceNote>[cf. 1967 c. 7 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402934529_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Damages for misrepresentation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411770974_040" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a person has entered into a contract after a misrepresentation has been made to him by another party thereto and as a result thereof he has suffered loss, then, if the person making the misrepresentation would be liable to damages in respect thereof had the misrepresentation been made fraudulently, that person shall be so liable notwithstanding that the misrepresentation was not made fraudulently, unless he proves that he had reasonable grounds to believe and did believe up to the time the contract was made that the facts represented were true.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411770989_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a person has entered into a contract after a misrepresentation has been made to him otherwise than fraudulently, and he would be entitled, by reason of the misrepresentation, to rescind the contract, then, if it is claimed, in any proceedings arising out of the contract, that the contract ought to be or has been rescinded the court or arbitrator may declare the contract subsisting and award damages in lieu of rescission, if of opinion that it would be equitable to do so, having regard to the nature of the misrepresentation and the loss that would be caused by it if the contract were upheld, as well as to the loss that rescission would cause to the other party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411771005_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Damages may be awarded against a person under subsection (2) whether or not he is liable to damages under subsection (1), but where he is so liable any award under subsection (2) shall be taken into account in assessing his liability under subsection (1).</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1967 c. 7 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402934544_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Avoidance of provision excluding liability for misrepresentation</heading><leadIn>If a contract contains a term which would exclude or restrict—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411771052_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any liability to which a party to a contract may be subject by reason of any misrepresentation made by him before the contract was made; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411771052_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any remedy available to another party to the contract by reason of such a misrepresentation,</content></paragraph><continued>that term shall be of no effect except in so far as it satisfies the requirement of reasonableness as stated in <ref>section 3(1)</ref> of the Control of Exemption Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap71">Cap. 71</ref>); and it is for the person claiming that the term satisfies that requirement to show that it does.</continued><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1989/59">59 of 1989 s. 20</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402934544_003" name="s5" reason="hadItsEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="expiredSpent" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><sourceNote>(Has had its effect)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402934560_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Saving for past transactions</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall apply in relation to any misrepresentation or contract of sale which is made before the commencement of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1967 c. 7 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402934560_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Application to
            Government</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2024/21">21 of 2024 s. 78</ref>)</sourceNote><content>This Ordinance binds the
            Government.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2024/21">21 of 2024 s. 78</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>