<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 107 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>107A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap107A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-07-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402556977_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-07-08">Prevention
                                    of Nuisances
                                    and Regulation
                                    of
                                    Travelling
                                    Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap107/s39">Cap.
                                                107, section
                                    39</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 February 1916]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of
                                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center">Rules made by the company </crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402556992_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>These rules shall extend and apply to all cars used on the tramways and to all places in respect of which the company has for the time being power to make rules.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402556992_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410848014_018" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All tickets issued by the company are issued on the conditions that these rules are to be observed. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410848014_026" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Monthly tickets issued by the company may be issued upon such terms, consistent with the Ordinance and any rules made thereunder, as the company may from time to time impose. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410848014_034" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Every person to whom a monthly ticket is issued shall sign the monthly ticket in ink before using it. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410848014_042" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Every person using a monthly ticket shall, at the request of an uniformed inspector of the company, furnish such inspector with a specimen of his signature to enable the inspector to compare the same with the signature appearing on the monthly ticket produced by such person. </content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1956/gna93">G.N.A. 93 of 1956</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557008_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>No person shall travel or attempt to travel as a passenger on a car in any class if a notice has been put up in the said car stating that the accommodation in that class is fully taken up.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557024_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>No person shall travel or attempt to travel on the top of any car in excess of the number of passengers for which seating accommodation is provided on the top of such car.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557024_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>No passenger shall enter or depart from a car from that side which is on the right hand of the motorman.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557039_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>No person shall converse with the driver of any car while such driver is on duty.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557039_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><content>No passenger shall take any luggage on a car of a description calculated in the opinion of the conductor to annoy or inconvenience other passengers. All personal and other luggage shall be carried by the passenger unless the conductor requires it to be put in some particular place in which case the passenger shall comply with the requirements of the conductor.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557055_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><content>No passenger shall smoke so as to cause nuisance or inconvenience to other passengers.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557086_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><content>No person shall spit inside or upon any car.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557102_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><content>No passenger or other person shall while travelling in or upon any car play or perform on any musical instrument.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557102_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><content>No person in a state of intoxication or affected with any infectious or contagious disease shall enter or mount or attempt to enter or mount any car. Any such person found on any car shall leave on request, and in default of compliance, may be removed by or under the direction of the conductor.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557117_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><content>No person shall swear or use obscene or offensive language whilst in or upon any car or commit any nuisance in or upon or against any car or any premises or property of the company or interfere with the comfort of any passenger.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557117_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><content>No person whose dress or clothing might in the opinion of the conductor soil or injure the seats or fittings of a car or the dress or clothing of any passenger, and no person who in the opinion of the conductor might for any other reason be offensive to passengers, shall be entitled to enter or remain in or on any car and shall leave on request. Any such person may be prevented from entering any car and shall not enter any car if requested not to do so by the conductor; and if found in or on any car shall on the request of the conductor leave the car upon the fare, if previously paid, being returned.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557133_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><content>Every passenger shall upon demand pay to the conductor the fare legally demandable for the journey and accept a ticket corresponding thereto, but this rule shall not apply to a monthly ticket holder or to Government postmen and policemen on duty and in uniform.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557148_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><content>Every passenger shall when required show the ticket or monthly ticket given to him covering the journey he is travelling on, or any free pass held by him, to the conductor or to any duly authorized servant of the company and shall also, when required, either deliver up any such ticket or pass for inspection or pay the fare legally demandable for the distance travelled over by such passenger.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557164_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><subsection id="ID_1438410848248_011" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall use or attempt to use a monthly ticket which does not bear his signature in ink.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410848248_019" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person to whom a monthly ticket has been issued shall sell or transfer or attempt to sell or transfer the monthly ticket issued to him, to any other person. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410848248_027" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person to whom a monthly ticket has been issued shall knowingly permit any other person to use such monthly ticket. </content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1956/gna93">G.N.A. 93 of 1956</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557164_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><content>If a person to whom a monthly ticket has been issued is convicted of any offence against these rules, the monthly ticket issued to him shall be forfeited, and no compensation shall be payable to him or to any other person in respect of such forfeiture. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1956/gna93">G.N.A. 93 of 1956</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557180_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><content>The company, in its absolute discretion, may decline to issue a monthly ticket to any person or to renew a monthly ticket already issued to any person. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1956/gna93">G.N.A. 93 of 1956</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557195_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><content>Any reference in these rules to the holder of a monthly ticket shall be deemed to refer to and include any person to whom and in whose name the company issues a monthly ticket and whose name appears on the face thereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557195_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><content>Tickets shall only be available for the car on which they are issued. Every passenger who leaves a car for any reason and resumes his journey by another car shall pay a fresh fare from the point at which he enters the second car.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557211_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><content>No passenger or any other person not being an official or servant of the company
            shall travel on the front, back, steps or sides of a tramcar or elsewhere than in or
            upon that space, or a part thereof, within the tramcar provided for the accommodation of
            passengers. Any person travelling in contravention of this rule shall immediately cease
            so to do upon request by the conductor or motorman of the tramcar or any other official
            of the company or by any police officer in uniform. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1946/gn67">G.N. 67 of 1946</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557226_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><content>No person except a passenger or intending passenger shall enter or mount any car.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557226_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><content>No person shall enter, mount or leave or attempt to enter, mount or leave any car whilst in motion.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557242_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><content>No person shall take a dog or other animal into or on any car except by
                        permission of the conductor. Any dog or other animal taken into or on any
                        car which becomes a nuisance or annoyance to passengers or which interferes
                        with or gets in the way of the driver or the driving or controlling
                        apparatus of the car shall be removed by the person in
                        charge of such dog or other animal from the car
                        immediately upon request of the conductor, and in default of compliance with
                        such request, may be removed by or under the direction of the
                        conductor.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557242_004" name="s25" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><content>No person shall enter, get upon or travel in or on any car with loaded firearms or with any article, instrument or implement which may in the opinion of the conductor be dangerous or offensive to any passenger.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557258_002" name="s26" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><content>No person shall stand in such a position on the car as to hamper the motorman in any way or shall touch any part of the controlling gear of any car.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557273_001" name="s27" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><content>No passenger shall stand on the platform of a car after being requested to go inside by the conductor. No passenger shall stand or travel in any exit passage-way.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557273_003" name="s28" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><content>Any person who requires change to be given him before he is able to pay his right fare shall, if the conductor is unable to give him change, upon request immediately leave the car.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557289_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><content>No person shall wilfully obstruct or impede any officer or servant of the company
            in the execution of his duty upon or in
            connexion
            with any car or tramway of the company.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557304_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><content>The conductor of each car shall enforce or prevent a breach of these rules to the best of his ability.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557304_003" name="s31" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><content>If the conductor has reason to believe that any person has committed a breach of any rule made by the company, he shall be entitled to ask such person for his name and address in Hong Kong and any such person shall on demand forthwith furnish to the conductor his true name and his true address in Hong Kong.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557320_001" name="s32" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><content>Any person offending against or committing a breach of any of these rules shall be
            liable to a penalty of one hundred dollars.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1947/gna112">G.N.
                112 of 1947</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557336_001" name="s33" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><def name="Conductor">In these rules,
                <term>conductor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">售票員</term>) includes any officer or servant in the
            employment of the company and having charge either temporarily or otherwise of a car and
            also includes an inspector of the company.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402557336_003" name="s34" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><content>These rules may be cited as the Prevention of Nuisances and Regulation of Travelling Rules.</content></section></main></subLeg>