<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 159 sub. leg. R</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>159R</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap159R!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-02-04</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402756673_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2017-11-16">Foreign
                  Lawyers
                  Practice
                  Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap159/s73">Cap. 159, section
                        73</ref>)
                  </enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2017/er4">E.R. 4 of
                  2017</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[9 September 1994]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er4">E.R. 4 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402756688_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these Rules, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Business"><term>overseas firm</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">海外律師行</term>)
            means a firm carrying on the business of practising the law in a foreign jurisdiction,
            but does not include a Hong Kong firm which has a branch in a foreign
                jurisdiction;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/23">23 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Business"><term>principal</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主管</term>) means
            the sole practitioner or a partner of a foreign firm and shall also include any foreign
            lawyer who is held out or holds himself out as such a partner or sole
            practitioner;</def><def name="Business"><term>Secretary General</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">秘書長</term>)
            means the Secretary General of the Society. </def></section><section id="ID_1438402756704_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>General conduct</heading><leadIn>A foreign lawyer shall not, in the course of practising as a foreign lawyer, do or permit to be done on his behalf anything which compromises or impairs or is likely to compromise or impair—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419115_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>his independence or integrity; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419115_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the freedom of any person to instruct a foreign lawyer of his choice; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419115_028" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>his duty to act in the best interests of his client; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419115_036" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>his own reputation or the reputation of foreign lawyers in Hong Kong; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419115_044" name="e" temporalId="s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a proper standard of work. </content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402756704_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Prohibition against publicity etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419146_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), a foreign lawyer shall not publicise or otherwise promote his practice or permit his practice to be published or otherwise promoted. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419146_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection (1) does not apply to anything done in accordance with the Solicitors’ Practice Promotion Code as made under <ref>rule 2AA</ref> of the Solicitors’ Practice Rules (<ref href="/hk/cap159H">Cap. 159 sub. leg. H</ref>) from time to time by the Council with the prior approval of the Chief Justice, which Code shall be construed for the purposes of this subsection as if every reference in the Code to a solicitor were a reference to a foreign lawyer and every reference to a firm of solicitors were construed as a reference to a foreign firm or an Association. </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402756844_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Name of firm</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419193_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), the name of a foreign firm shall consist solely of the name or names of one or more foreign lawyers who are principals of the firm.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419193_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subsection (1) shall not preclude—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419193_020" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the use of the name of a predecessor or former partner in that practice;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419193_028" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the use of the name of an overseas firm of which the foreign firm is a branch; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419193_036" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>the use of a style or firm name—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419193_044" name="i" temporalId="s4_2_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in use at the date of the coming into operation of these Rules; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419193_052" name="ii" temporalId="s4_2_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>approved in writing by the Council.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1480996254988_001" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Despite subsections (1) and (2), for a foreign firm that is not a limited liability partnership within the meaning of <ref>section 7AB</ref> of the Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1480996254988_002" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>if the firm has an English name, the firm must not include, as part of that name—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1480996254988_003" name="1" temporalId="s4_3_a_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>the words “limited liability partnership”;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1480996254988_004" name="2" temporalId="s4_3_a_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>the abbreviation “L.L.P.” or “LLP”; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1480996254988_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3_a_3"><num value="3">(iii)</num><content>any words or abbreviations that convey the message that the firm is a limited liability partnership within the meaning of that section;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1480996254988_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>if the firm has a Chinese name, the firm must not include, as part of that name—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1480996254988_007" name="1" temporalId="s4_3_b_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>the words “有限法律責任合夥”; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1480996254988_008" name="2" temporalId="s4_3_b_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>any words or abbreviations that convey the message that the firm is a limited liability partnership within the meaning of that section; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1480996254988_009" name="c" temporalId="s4_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the firm has a name in a language other than English or Chinese, the firm must not include, as part of that name, any words or abbreviations that convey the message that the firm is a limited liability partnership within the meaning of that section. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2015/ln101">L.N. 101 of 2015</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402756860_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Business letters</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419271_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that there is stated on all business letters issued in connection with the firm’s practice—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419271_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the name and address of the firm; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419287_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the main jurisdiction in the law of which the firm practises, or the country of that jurisdiction; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419287_014" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the names of all principals of the firm who are ordinarily resident in Hong Kong; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419287_022" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if the name of any principal not ordinarily resident in Hong Kong is stated, a description of the person as non-resident; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419287_030" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>in respect of each individual whose name appears on the letter, his foreign jurisdiction of admission or the country of that jurisdiction, except that no such statement is required where the foreign jurisdiction of admission of the individual, or the country of that jurisdiction, is the same as that stated on the letter for the purpose of paragraph (b).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419302_005" name="1A" temporalId="s5_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>A principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that if the name or any other description of the firm is stated in more than one language on any business letter issued in connection with the firm’s practice, each version of the name or description corresponds to the other version or versions of the name or description.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/ln111">L.N. 111 of 2003</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419302_013" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A principal of a foreign firm forming part of an Association shall ensure that on all business letters issued in connection with the firm’s practice—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419302_021" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the firm’s name is more prominent than the name of any other firm; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419302_029" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any reference to another firm in the Association clearly distinguishes that firm from any other that is not in the Association; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419318_006" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the firm’s address in Hong Kong is more prominent than any other address. </content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402756907_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Supervision of office</heading><leadIn>A principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that every office where his firm practises is and can reasonably be seen to be properly supervised in accordance with the following minimum standards—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419365_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>every such office shall be managed by a foreign lawyer who shall normally be in attendance at that office during all the hours when it is open to the public; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419365_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>every such office shall be attended on each day when it is open to the public by a foreign lawyer who holds an unconditional certificate of registration being either a principal of, or a foreign lawyer employed by, the firm and who shall spend sufficient time at such office to ensure adequate control of the staff employed there and afford requisite facilities for consultation with clients. </content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402756922_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Sharing an office and staff</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419411_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that the firm’s practice is conducted in self-contained premises, and that the firm’s staff and facilities are under its exclusive control. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419411_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (3), a principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that in the conduct of its practice the firm does not—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419411_020" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>share premises, which term includes waiting rooms and reception areas; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419411_028" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>share staff, which term includes telephonists, receptionists and all other non-fee earning staff employed by the firm; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419411_036" name="c" temporalId="s7_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>share telephone, computer or electronic equipment used for the transmission or storage of clients’ confidential information. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419411_043" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Subject to the need to maintain clients’ confidentiality—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419427_005" name="a" temporalId="s7_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a foreign firm may share services reasonably regarded as those of an independent contractor with any other foreign firm or third party; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419427_013" name="b" temporalId="s7_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a foreign firm forming part of an Association may share premises, personnel and facilities with any other firm in the Association, </content></paragraph><continued>but subject to the foregoing a principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that the firm does not share any services, premises, personnel or facilities with any other person. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419427_026" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where a building is shared by a foreign firm with another business or where there are shared common areas a principal of the foreign firm shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419427_034" name="a" temporalId="s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>there are signs displayed in a conspicuous position at the main entrance of the premises of the firm so as to distinguish them from the premises occupied by others;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2008/ln6">L.N. 6 of 2008</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419427_042" name="b" temporalId="s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>common areas do not give the appearance of being part of another business. </content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402756938_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-02-04" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Control of employment of unqualified persons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419474_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that the firm does not employ persons who are not foreign lawyers (<term>unqualified persons</term>) in a number more than 6 plus 8 times the number of resident principals and foreign lawyers employed full-time in that firm. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419474_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419474_020" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>persons employed otherwise than by a foreign firm (such as by a service company set up by the principal or principals of the firm) but for the purposes of the firm shall be deemed to be persons employed in that firm; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419474_028" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in calculating the number of unqualified persons employed in a foreign firm, full-time law students working part-time or full-time during holidays and breaks or part-time during the academic year shall not be taken into account; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419474_036" name="c" temporalId="s8_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in calculating the number of resident principals and foreign lawyers employed full-time in a foreign firm, a foreign lawyer shall not be taken into account in respect of more than one firm. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419489_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A principal of a foreign firm shall ensure that every name card of an employee who is an unqualified person, being a card which bears the name of the foreign firm, includes a clear description of the capacity in which the employee is being employed.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln98">L.N. 98 of 1995</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1547620575569_001" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A principal of a foreign firm must not, except with the written approval of the Council, knowingly employ any unqualified person who is in the part-time or full-time employment of a Hong Kong firm or another foreign firm. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2018/ln39">L.N. 39 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402756953_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Reporting of particulars</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419521_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A principal of a foreign firm shall, within 14 days after the establishment of a place of business by the firm, advise the Society in writing in a form approved by the Society of the following particulars in respect of any member of staff of the firm whether part-time or full-time, remunerated or otherwise, other than a member of staff who is a foreign lawyer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419521_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the member’s name; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419521_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>his identity card or passport number; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419521_028" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>his Chinese commercial code, if applicable; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419521_036" name="d" temporalId="s9_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>his date of birth; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419521_044" name="e" temporalId="s9_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>his position in the firm; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419521_052" name="f" temporalId="s9_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the date on which his employment began. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419521_059" name="1A" temporalId="s9_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><leadIn>The principal of the firm shall also, within 14 days after the establishment of a place of business by the firm, advise the Society in writing in a form approved by the Society of the following particulars in relation to any service company engaged by the firm—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419536_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_1A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the name of the service company, its registered office, its Business Registration Number, the names of its directors and whether or not they are foreign lawyers; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419536_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_1A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the following particulars in respect of any employee of the service company, whether or not the employee has been provided as staff of the foreign firm, whether part-time or full-time, remunerated or otherwise, and whether or not the employee is a foreign lawyer—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419536_021" name="i" temporalId="s9_1A_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the employee’s name; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419536_029" name="ii" temporalId="s9_1A_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>his identity card or passport number; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419536_037" name="iii" temporalId="s9_1A_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>his Chinese commercial code, if applicable; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419536_045" name="iv" temporalId="s9_1A_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>his date of birth; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419536_053" name="v" temporalId="s9_1A_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>his position in the firm or the service company;
                        and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="v" temporalId="s9_1A_b_v" id="ID_1485507373798_001"><num value="v">(vi)</num><content>the date on which his employment began; and </content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419536_060" name="c" temporalId="s9_1A_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the address or addresses of the service company together with telephone, fax, telex and DX numbers, where appropriate.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln472">L.N. 472 of 1995</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1480996839396_001" name="1B" temporalId="s9_1B"><num value="1B">(1B)</num><content>Subject to <ref>rule 5(1)</ref> of the Limited Liability Partnerships (Top-up Insurance) Rules (<ref href="hk/cap159AL">Cap. 159 sub. leg. AL</ref>), a principal of a foreign firm that is a limited liability partnership within the meaning of <ref>Part IIAAA</ref> of the Ordinance must, within 14 days after the establishment of a place of business by the firm, provide the Society with evidence of the firm’s compliance with the insurance requirement in <ref>section 7AD</ref> of the Ordinance. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2012/22">22 of 2012 s. 10</ref>; <ref href="hk/2015/ln101">L.N. 101 of 2015</ref>; <ref href="hk/2016/er1">E.R. 1 of 2016</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419536_067" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A principal of a foreign firm shall, within 14 days of such occurrence, advise the Society in writing in a form approved by the Society of any change in any of the particulars required to be given in—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419552_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an application for registration as a foreign firm;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419552_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a return under subsection (1) or (1A).
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln472">L.N. 472 of 1995</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1480996839396_002" name="2A" temporalId="s9_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><content>If at any time a foreign firm that is a limited liability partnership within the meaning of <ref>Part IIAAA</ref> of the Ordinance does not have in existence a policy of insurance as is required under <ref>section 7AD</ref> of the Ordinance, a principal of the firm must notify the Society in writing within 14 days of the occurrence of that fact. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2012/22">22 of 2012 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419552_020" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A principal of a foreign firm who is in practice at any time during a calendar year shall, not later than 31 January in the next calendar year, furnish to the Secretary General a declaration in a form approved by the Society as to the following particulars in respect of the relevant calendar year—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419552_028" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the names of all the principals, employed foreign lawyers and consultants in the firm;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419552_036" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in respect of any principal, employed foreign lawyer or consultant in the firm who is also a principal or employee of another foreign firm or firm of solicitors in Hong Kong, or a salaried employee of a service company in Hong Kong, the name of the person and of the other firm or company and the person’s position in the other firm or company;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419552_044" name="c" temporalId="s9_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>in respect of any member of staff of the firm, whether part-time or full-time, remunerated or otherwise (except an employee who is a foreign lawyer)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419567_006" name="i" temporalId="s9_3_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the member’s name; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419567_014" name="ii" temporalId="s9_3_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>his identity card or passport number; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419567_022" name="iii" temporalId="s9_3_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>his Chinese commercial code, if applicable; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419567_030" name="iv" temporalId="s9_3_c_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>his date of birth; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419567_038" name="v" temporalId="s9_3_c_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>his position in the firm; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419567_046" name="vi" temporalId="s9_3_c_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>if applicable, the date during the calendar year on which employment began or ceased; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419567_053" name="d" temporalId="s9_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if the firm engages a service company to provide staff for the firm, the name of any such company and the names of the directors of any such company.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419567_060" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purposes of subsections (1) and (3), persons engaged as a member of staff otherwise than by a foreign firm (such as by a service company set up by the principal or principals of the firm) but for the purposes of the firm shall be deemed to be persons engaged as a member of staff of that firm.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419567_068" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Except upon formal resolution of the Council, any particulars given to the Secretary General under subsection <ref>(3)(b)</ref> or (d) shall not be disclosed by the Secretary General to any person other than—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419583_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Council members; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419583_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>members of Committees established by the Council; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419583_021" name="c" temporalId="s9_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a Solicitors Disciplinary Tribunal; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419583_029" name="d" temporalId="s9_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the Tribunal Convenor of the Solicitors Disciplinary Tribunal Panel; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419583_037" name="e" temporalId="s9_5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>counsel, accountants, solicitors and agents appointed by the Society; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419583_045" name="f" temporalId="s9_5_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>employees of the Society, </content></paragraph><continued>whose proper business it is to have access to such particulars for the purposes of ascertaining whether the provisions of these Rules or any other laws or regulations concerning foreign lawyers, employees of foreign lawyers or solicitors have been complied with or of dealing with the disciplinary consequences of any alleged breach thereof. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419583_058" name="6" temporalId="s9_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The particulars, evidence and notification required to be given under subsections (1), (1B), (2), (2A) and (3) may be given by one principal on behalf of the other principals. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2012/22">22 of 2012 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402756969_001" name="s9A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9A"><num value="9A">9A.</num><heading>Particulars relating to sole practitioner foreign lawyer</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419645_004" name="1" temporalId="s9A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A foreign lawyer who commences practice as a foreign lawyer in his own name or
                under the name of a foreign firm, where he is the sole proprietor of the foreign
                firm, (in this section referred to as a
                    <term>sole
                    practitioner foreign
                lawyer</term>)
                shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419645_012" name="a" temporalId="s9A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>ensure that, at the commencement of his practice, there is in effect a
                    testamentary provision which provides—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419645_020" name="1" temporalId="s9A_1_a_1"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>for the management of his practice as a sole practitioner foreign
                        lawyer after his death, pending the disposal or cessation of that practice;
                        and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419661_007" name="2" temporalId="s9A_1_a_2"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>for such management to be carried out by a person who is a foreign
                        lawyer holding an unconditional certificate of registration and who has
                        consented in writing to so
                        manage
                        that practice;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419661_014" name="b" temporalId="s9A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>within 14 days of commencement of practice as a sole practitioner foreign
                    lawyer advise the Society in writing in a form approved by the Society of the
                    following particulars—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419661_022" name="1" temporalId="s9A_1_b_1"><num value="i">(i)</num><leadIn>the name, address, telephone number, fax number, telex number and DX
                        number, where appropriate, of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419661_029" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s9A_1_b_1_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>the executor of the will which contains the testamentary provision
                            as required under paragraph (a); and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419661_037" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s9A_1_b_1_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>the foreign lawyer mentioned in paragraph
                            <ref>(a)(ii)</ref>;</content></subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411419661_045" name="2" temporalId="s9A_1_b_2"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if that will has been lodged with another person by the sole
                        practitioner foreign lawyer, the name and address of that person.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419661_051" name="2" temporalId="s9A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A foreign lawyer who practises as a sole practitioner foreign lawyer
                shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419661_059" name="a" temporalId="s9A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>ensure that a testamentary provision as required under subsection
                        <ref>(1)(a)</ref> remains in effect at all times during his practice as a
                    sole practitioner foreign lawyer, except for a period of 14 days after any
                    change in the foreign lawyer mentioned in subsection
                    <ref>(1)(a)(ii)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419677_006" name="b" temporalId="s9A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>advise the Society in writing in a form approved by the Society within 14
                    days of such occurrence of any change in any of the particulars referred to in
                    subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419677_013" name="3" temporalId="s9A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>This section does not apply to a sole practitioner foreign lawyer where the
                foreign firm mentioned in subsection (1) is a branch of an overseas firm and is
                registered as a foreign firm under <ref>section 39B</ref> of the
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419677_021" name="4" temporalId="s9A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Except upon formal resolution of the Council, the particulars furnished under
                subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> or <ref>(2)(b)</ref> shall not be disclosed by the
                Secretary General to any person other than—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419677_029" name="a" temporalId="s9A_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Council members;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419677_037" name="b" temporalId="s9A_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>members of committees established by the Council;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419677_045" name="c" temporalId="s9A_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a Solicitors Disciplinary Tribunal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419677_053" name="d" temporalId="s9A_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the Tribunal Convenor of the Solicitors Disciplinary Tribunal
                    Panel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419677_061" name="e" temporalId="s9A_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>counsel, accountants, solicitors and agents appointed by the Society;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419692_007" name="f" temporalId="s9A_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>employees of the Society,</content></paragraph><continued>whose proper business it is to have access to such particulars for the
                purposes of—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438411419692_021" name="1" temporalId="s9A_4_1"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>ascertaining whether the provisions of these Rules or any other laws or
                    regulations concerning the sole practitioner foreign lawyer have been complied
                    with; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419692_029" name="2" temporalId="s9A_4_2"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>dealing with the disciplinary consequences of any alleged breach of those
                    provisions.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln264">L.N. 264 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1460952179330_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><ref>Section 9A</ref> was added by <ref>section 1</ref> of the Foreign Lawyers
                Practice (Amendment) <ref>Rules 2000</ref> (<ref href="/hk/2000/ln264">L.N. 264 of
                    2000</ref>).
                    <ref>Please
                    see
                    section
                    2</ref> of those
                Rules
                for the transitional
                provisions.</content>
            <content>
                </content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402756985_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Powers of Council to verify compliance with Rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411419755_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In order to ascertain whether the provisions of these Rules have been complied with, the Council, acting either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411419755_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on its own motion; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411419755_020" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on a written complaint lodged with it by a third party, </content></paragraph><continued>may require any foreign lawyer
                to produce
                at such time and place as may be fixed by the Council, his books of account, bank
                pass books, loose-leaf bank statements, statements of account, vouchers and any
                other necessary documents for the inspection of any person appointed by the Council,
                and such person shall be directed to prepare for the information of the Council a
                report on the result of such inspection and any such report may be used as a basis
                for proceedings under the Ordinance. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419755_033" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Upon being required so to do a foreign lawyer shall produce such books of account, bank pass books, loose-leaf bank statements, statements of account, vouchers and documents at the time and place fixed. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419770_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Before instituting an inspection on a written complaint lodged with it by a third party, the Council shall require prima facie evidence that a ground of complaint exists, and may require the payment by such party to the Council of a reasonable sum to be fixed by it to cover the costs of the inspection, and the costs of the foreign lawyer against whom the complaint is made and the Council may deal with any sum so paid in such manner as it thinks fit. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411419770_013" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Council may make such order for the payment of the costs of any inspection required by the Council under this section as it thinks fit. </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402756985_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Power of waiver</heading><content>The Council shall have power to waive in writing any of the provisions of these Rules in any particular case or cases, either unconditionally or subject to such conditions as the Council may think fit to impose. </content></section><section id="ID_1438402757000_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Application of other Rules</heading><content>The Rules specified in column 2 of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, with the necessary changes and specifically with the changes, if any, to those Rules specified opposite such Rules in column 3 of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, shall apply to foreign lawyers and foreign firms as if every reference in those Rules to a solicitor were a reference to a foreign lawyer and every reference to a firm of solicitors were a reference to a foreign firm. </content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402757016_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-11-16" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap159R/s12">s. 12</ref>]</note><heading>Rules to be Applied to Foreign Lawyers
            and
            Foreign
            Firms</heading><text>
            
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="460">
                
                <col width="6%"></col>
                
                <col width="42%"></col>
                
                <col width="5%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="44%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_left">Item</p>
                    </td>
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_15">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Rules</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_25">
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Changes</center>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td></td>
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_15">
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td></td>
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_25"></td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_left">1.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_15">
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Accountant’s Report Rules
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap159A">Cap. 159 sub. leg. A</ref>)
                            <sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/2017/er4">E.R. 4 of
                            2017</ref>)</sourceNote></p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_25">
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Every reference to a
                            practising certificate shall be read as a reference to a certificate of
                            registration as a foreign lawyer issued by the Society under the Foreign
                            Lawyers Registration Rules (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap159S">Cap. 159 sub. leg. S</ref>)
                            <sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/2017/er4">E.R. 4 of
                            2017</ref>)</sourceNote></p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td></td>
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_15">
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td></td>
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_25"></td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_left">2.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpaddings_left_15" colspan="3"><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(Repealed <ref href="hk/2012/ln155">L.N. 155 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote></td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>