<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 112 sub. leg. AX</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>112AX</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap112AX!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-04-23</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402590439_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-04-23">Specification
            of
            Arrangements (Government
            of
            the Kingdom
            of
            Thailand) (Avoidance
            of
            Double Taxation
            on Income
            and Prevention
            of
            Fiscal
            Evasion)
            Order</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap112/s49">Cap. 112, section
            49</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of
            2020</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[28 October
                    2005]<sourceNote><inline class="width_6"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2005/ln179">L.N. 179 of
                2005</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402590454_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Declaration under <ref>section 49</ref></heading><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 49</ref> of the Ordinance, it is declared—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410941973_038" name="a" temporalId="s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the arrangements specified in <ref>section 2</ref> have been made with the Government of the Kingdom of Thailand with a view to affording relief from double taxation in relation to income tax and any tax of a similar character imposed by the laws of the Kingdom; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410941988_006" name="b" temporalId="s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that it is expedient that those arrangements should have effect.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402590470_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Arrangements specified</heading><leadIn>The arrangements specified for the purposes of <ref>section 1(a)</ref> are the arrangements in—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410942004_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Articles 1 to 28 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the Kingdom of Thailand for the Avoidance of Double Taxation and the Prevention of Fiscal Evasion with respect to Taxes on Income done in duplicate at Bangkok on 7 September 2005 in the English language, the text of which Articles is reproduced in <ref>Part 1</ref> of the <ref>Schedule</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410942004_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><ref>Paragraphs 1 to 3</ref> of the Protocol to that Agreement, the text of which Paragraphs is reproduced in <ref>Part 2</ref> of the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></paragraph></section><schedule id="ID_1438402590501_001" name="sch0" temporalId="sch0" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap112AX/s2">s.
            2</ref>]</note><part id="ID_1438410943299_009" name="P1" temporalId="sch0_P1" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1">Part
                1</num><heading>Articles
                1 to 28 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special
                Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the
                Kingdom of Thailand for the Avoidance of Double Taxation and the Prevention of
                Fiscal Evasion with respect to Taxes on
                Income</heading><text>
                <crossHeading> </crossHeading>
            </text><text class="align_center"><b>Article
                    1</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>PERSONS
                    COVERED</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>This Agreement shall apply to persons who are residents of one or both of the
                Contracting
                Parties.</text><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    2</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>TAXES
                    COVERED</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943299_076" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>This Agreement shall apply to taxes on income imposed on behalf of a
                    Contracting Party or of its local authorities, irrespective of the manner in
                    which they are
                    levied.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943299_084" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>There shall be regarded as taxes on income all taxes imposed on total
                    income, or on elements of income, including taxes on gains from the alienation
                    of movable or immovable property, taxes on the total amounts of wages or
                    salaries paid by enterprises, as well as taxes on capital
                    appreciation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943299_092" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><leadIn>The existing taxes to which this Agreement shall apply are:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514950_001" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region,</leadIn><continued>— profits tax,<br></br>— salaries tax, and<br></br>— property
                        tax;</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514951_002" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of Thailand,</content><content>— income tax, and<br></br>— petroleum income
                        tax.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943314_020" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>This Agreement shall apply also to any identical or substantially similar
                    taxes that are imposed after the date of signature of this Agreement in addition
                    to, or in place of, the existing taxes as well as any other taxes falling within
                        <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> of this Article which a Contracting
                    Party may impose in future. The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties
                    shall notify each other of significant changes that have been made in their
                    respective taxation
                    laws.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943314_028" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><content>The existing taxes, together with the taxes imposed after the signature of
                    this Agreement, are hereinafter referred to as “Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region tax” and “Thai
                    tax”.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    3</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>GENERAL
                DEFINITIONS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943314_052" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><leadIn>For the purposes of this Agreement, unless the context otherwise
                    requires:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514953_003" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the term “Hong Kong Special Administrative Region” means the Hong Kong
                        Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China; used in a
                        geographical sense, it means the land and sea comprised within the boundary
                        of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, including Hong Kong Island,
                        Kowloon, the New Territories and the waters of Hong Kong;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514953_004" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the term “Thailand” means the territory of the Kingdom of Thailand,
                        including its internal waters, its territorial seas, and any maritime areas
                        over which the Kingdom of Thailand has sovereign rights or jurisdiction
                        under international law;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514954_005" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the term “company” means any body corporate or any entity which is
                        treated as a body corporate for tax purposes;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514954_006" name="d" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>the term “competent authority” means:</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1495441514955_007" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, the
                            Commissioner of Inland Revenue, or his authorised representative or any
                            person or body authorised to perform any functions at present
                            exercisable by the Commissioner or similar functions;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514956_008" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of Thailand, the Minister of Finance or his authorised
                            representative;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514956_009" name="e" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the terms “a Contracting Party” and “the other Contracting Party” mean
                        the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region or Thailand, as the context
                        requires;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514957_010" name="f" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the terms “enterprise of a Contracting Party” and “enterprise of the
                        other Contracting Party” mean respectively an enterprise carried on by a
                        resident of a Contracting Party and an enterprise carried on by a resident
                        of the other Contracting Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514957_011" name="g" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the term “international traffic” means any transport by a ship or
                        aircraft operated by an enterprise of a Contracting Party, except when the
                        ship or aircraft is operated solely between places in the other Contracting
                        Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514958_012" name="h" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the term “person” includes an individual, a company, a trust, a
                        partnership, any other body of persons as well as any entity treated as a
                        taxable unit under the taxation laws in force in either Contracting
                        Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514958_013" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the term “tax” means Hong Kong Special Administrative Region tax or
                        Thai tax, as the context requires;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514959_014" name="j" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><leadIn>the term “national” means, in the case of Thailand,</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410943330_017" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_j_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any individual possessing Thai nationality;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410943330_026" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_j_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any legal person, partnership, association and any other entity
                            deriving its status as such from the laws in force in
                            Thailand.</content></subparagraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943330_031" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>As regards the application of this Agreement at any time by a Contracting
                    Party, any term not defined therein shall, unless the context otherwise
                    requires, have the meaning which it has at that time under the laws of that
                    Contracting Party for the purposes of the taxes to which this Agreement applies,
                    any meaning under the applicable tax laws of that Contracting Party prevailing
                    over a meaning given to the term under other laws of that Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    4</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>RESIDENT</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943330_055" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><leadIn>For the purposes of this Agreement, the term “resident of a Contracting
                    Party” means:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514959_015" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region,</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1495441514960_016" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any individual who ordinarily resides in the Hong Kong Special
                            Administrative Region;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514960_017" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any individual who stays in the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                            Region for more than 180 days during a year of assessment or for more
                            than 300 days in two consecutive years of assessment one of which is the
                            relevant year of assessment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514961_018" name="iii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a company incorporated in the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                            Region or, if incorporated outside the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                            Region, being normally managed or controlled in the Hong Kong Special
                            Administrative Region;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514961_019" name="iv" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>any other person constituted under the laws of the Hong Kong
                            Special Administrative Region, or if constituted outside the Hong Kong
                            Special Administrative Region, being normally managed or controlled in
                            the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514962_020" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of Thailand, any person who, under the laws of Thailand, is
                        liable to tax therein by reason of his domicile, residence, place of
                        incorporation, place of management or any other criterion of a similar
                        nature. This term, however, does not include any person who is liable to tax
                        in Thailand in respect only of income from sources in Thailand;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514962_021" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of either Contracting Party, the Government of that
                        Contracting Party and any local authority
                        thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943330_125" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>Where by reason of the provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, an individual
                    is a resident of both Contracting Parties, then his status shall be determined
                    as follows:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514963_022" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he shall be deemed to be a resident only of the Contracting Party in
                        which he has a permanent home available to him; if he has a permanent home
                        available to him in both Contracting Parties, he shall be deemed to be a
                        resident only of the Contracting Party with which his personal and economic
                        relations are closer (“centre of vital interests”);</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514964_023" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the Contracting Party in which he has his centre of vital interests
                        cannot be determined, or if he has not a permanent home available to him in
                        either Contracting Party, he shall be deemed to be a resident only of the
                        Contracting Party in which he has an habitual abode;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514965_024" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if he has an habitual abode in both Contracting Parties or in neither
                        of them, he shall be deemed to be a resident only of the Contracting Party
                        in which he has the right of abode (in the case of the Hong Kong Special
                        Administrative Region) or Contracting Party of which he is a national (in
                        the case of Thailand);</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514965_025" name="d" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if he has the right of abode in the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                        Region and is also a national of Thailand or if he does not have the right
                        of abode in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region nor is he a national
                        of Thailand, the competent authorities of the Contracting Parties shall
                        settle the question by mutual
                        agreement.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943345_031" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>Where by reason of the provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> a person other
                    than an individual is a resident of both Contracting Parties, then the competent
                    authorities of the Contracting Parties shall determine that the person is a
                    resident of a Contracting Party for the purposes of this Agreement by mutual
                    agreement.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    5</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>PERMANENT
                    ESTABLISHMENT</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943345_055" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>For the purposes of this Agreement, the term “permanent establishment”
                    means a fixed place of business through which the business of an enterprise is
                    wholly or partly carried
                    on.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943345_063" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>The term “permanent establishment” includes especially:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514966_026" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a place of management;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514967_027" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a branch;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514968_028" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an office;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514968_029" name="d" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a factory;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514969_030" name="e" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a workshop;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514969_031" name="f" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>a mine, an oil or gas well, a quarry or any other place of extraction
                        of natural resources; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514970_032" name="g" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>a warehouse, in relation to a person providing storage facilities for
                        others.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943345_133" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><leadIn>The term “permanent establishment” also encompasses:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514971_033" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>A building site, a construction, assembly or installation project or
                        supervisory activities in connection therewith, but only if such site,
                        project or activities last more than six months;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514971_034" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>The furnishing of services, including consultancy services, by an
                        enterprise through employees or other personnel engaged by the enterprise
                        for such purpose, but only if activities of that nature continue (for the
                        same or a connected project) within a Contracting Party for a period or
                        periods aggregating more than six months within any twelve-month
                        period.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943361_004" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this Article, the term
                    “permanent establishment” shall be deemed not to include:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514972_035" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the use of facilities solely for the purpose of storage or display of
                        goods or merchandise belonging to the enterprise;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514972_036" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the maintenance of a stock of goods or merchandise belonging to the
                        enterprise solely for the purpose of storage or display;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514973_037" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the maintenance of a stock of goods or merchandise belonging to the
                        enterprise solely for the purpose of processing by another
                        enterprise;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514973_038" name="d" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the maintenance of a fixed place of business solely for the purpose of
                        purchasing goods or merchandise, or of collecting information, for the
                        enterprise;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514974_039" name="e" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the maintenance of a fixed place of business solely for the purpose of
                        carrying on, for the enterprise, any other activity of a preparatory or
                        auxiliary character;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514974_040" name="f" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the maintenance of a fixed place of business solely for any combination
                        of the activities mentioned in sub-paragraphs (a) to (e) of this paragraph,
                        provided that the overall activity of the fixed place of business resulting
                        from this combination is of a preparatory or auxiliary
                        character.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943361_065" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref>,
                    where a person — other than an agent of an independent status to whom
                        <ref>paragraph 6</ref> applies — is acting in a Contracting Party, on behalf
                    of an enterprise of the other Contracting Party, that enterprise shall be deemed
                    to have a permanent establishment in the first-mentioned Contracting Party in
                    respect of any activities which that person undertakes for the enterprise, if
                    such a person:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514977_041" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has and habitually exercises in a Contracting Party an authority to
                        conclude contracts in the name of the enterprise, unless the activities of
                        such person are limited to those mentioned in <ref>paragraph 4</ref> which,
                        if exercised through a fixed place of business, would not make this fixed
                        place of business a permanent establishment under the provisions of that
                        paragraph;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514978_042" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has no such authority, but habitually maintains in the first-mentioned
                        Contracting Party a stock of goods or merchandise belonging to the
                        enterprise from which he regularly delivers on behalf of the enterprise;
                        or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514978_043" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>has no such authority, but habitually secures orders in the
                        first-mentioned Contracting Party wholly or almost wholly for the enterprise
                        or for the enterprise and other enterprises which are controlled by it or
                        have a controlling interest in
                        it.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943361_099" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_P1_s6" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="6"><inline class="not_bold">6.</inline></num><content>An enterprise of a Contracting Party shall not be deemed to have a
                    permanent establishment in the other Contracting Party merely because it carries
                    on business in that other Contracting Party through a broker, general commission
                    agent or any other agent of an independent status, provided that such persons
                    are acting in the ordinary course of their business. However, when the
                    activities of such an agent are devoted wholly or almost wholly on behalf of
                    that enterprise, and conditions are made or imposed between that enterprise and
                    the agent in their commercial and financial relations which differ from those
                    which would have been made between independent enterprises, he will not be
                    considered an agent of an independent status within the meaning of this
                    paragraph.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943361_107" name="s7" temporalId="sch0_P1_s7" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="7"><inline class="not_bold">7.</inline></num><content>The fact that a company which is a resident of a Contracting Party controls
                    or is controlled by a company which is a resident of the other Contracting
                    Party, or which carries on business in that other Contracting Party (whether
                    through a permanent establishment or otherwise), shall not of itself constitute
                    either company a permanent establishment of the
                    other.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    6</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>INCOME
                    FROM IMMOVABLE
                PROPERTY</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943377_020" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Income derived by a resident of a Contracting Party from immovable property
                    (including income from agriculture or forestry) situated in the other
                    Contracting Party may be taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943377_028" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>The term “immovable property” shall have the meaning which it has under the
                    laws of the Contracting Party in which the property in question is situated. The
                    term shall in any case include property accessory to immovable property,
                    livestock and equipment used in agriculture, forestry and fishery, rights to
                    which the provisions of general law respecting landed property apply, usufruct
                    of immovable property and rights to variable or fixed payments as consideration
                    for the working of, or the right to explore for or work, mineral deposits,
                    quarries, sources and other natural resources; ships, boats and aircraft shall
                    not be regarded as immovable
                    property.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943377_036" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> shall apply to income derived from
                    the direct use, letting, or use in any other form of immovable
                    property.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943377_044" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>3</ref> shall also apply
                    to the income from immovable property of an enterprise and to income from
                    immovable property used for the performance of independent personal
                    services.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    7</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>BUSINESS
                    PROFITS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943377_068" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>The profits of an enterprise of a Contracting Party shall be taxable only
                    in that Contracting Party unless the enterprise carries on business in the other
                    Contracting Party through a permanent establishment situated therein. If the
                    enterprise carries on business as aforesaid, the profits of the enterprise may
                    be taxed in the other Contracting Party, but only so much of them as is
                    attributable to that permanent
                    establishment.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943377_076" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>paragraph 3</ref>, where an enterprise of
                    a Contracting Party carries on business in the other Contracting Party through a
                    permanent establishment situated therein, there shall in each Contracting Party
                    be attributed to that permanent establishment the profits which it might be
                    expected to make if it were a distinct and separate enterprise engaged in the
                    same or similar activities under the same or similar conditions and dealing
                    wholly independently with the enterprise of which it is a permanent
                    establishment.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943377_084" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>In determining the profits of a permanent establishment, there shall be
                    allowed as deductions expenses which are incurred for the purposes of the
                    permanent establishment, including executive and general administrative expenses
                    so incurred, whether in the Contracting Party in which the permanent
                    establishment is situated or
                    elsewhere.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943377_092" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>Insofar as it has been customary in a Contracting Party to determine the
                    profits to be attributed to a permanent establishment on the basis of an
                    apportionment of the total profits of the enterprise to its various parts,
                    nothing in <ref>paragraph 2</ref> shall preclude that Contracting Party from
                    determining the profits to be taxed by such an apportionment as may be
                    customary; the method of apportionment adopted shall, however, be such that the
                    result shall be in accordance with the principles contained in this
                    Article.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943377_100" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><content>No profits shall be attributed to a permanent establishment by reason of
                    the mere purchase by that permanent establishment of goods or merchandise for
                    the
                    enterprise.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943392_004" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_P1_s6" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="6"><inline class="not_bold">6.</inline></num><content>If the information available to the taxation authority of a Contracting
                    Party is inadequate to determine the profits to be attributed to the permanent
                    establishment of an enterprise, nothing in this Article shall affect the
                    application of any law of that Contracting Party relating to the determination
                    of the tax liability of a person provided that that law shall be applied in
                    accordance with the principles of this Article, so far as the information
                    available to the taxation authority
                    permits.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943392_012" name="s7" temporalId="sch0_P1_s7" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="7"><inline class="not_bold">7.</inline></num><content>For the purposes of the preceding paragraphs, the profits to be attributed
                    to the permanent establishment shall be determined by the same method year by
                    year unless there is good and sufficient reason to the
                    contrary.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943392_020" name="s8" temporalId="sch0_P1_s8" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="8"><inline class="not_bold">8.</inline></num><content>Where profits include items of income which are dealt with separately in
                    other Articles of this Agreement, then the provisions of those Articles shall
                    not be affected by the provisions of this
                    Article.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    8</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>SHIPPING
                    AND AIR
                TRANSPORT</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943392_044" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Income or profits derived by an enterprise of a Contracting Party from the
                    operation of aircraft in international traffic shall be taxable only in that
                    Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943392_052" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Income or profits of an enterprise of a Contracting Party derived in the
                    other Contracting Party from the operation of ships in international traffic may
                    be taxed in the other Contracting Party but the tax so charged shall be reduced
                    by an amount equal to 50 per cent
                    thereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943392_060" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> shall also apply
                    to income or profits from the participation in a pool, a joint business or an
                    international operating
                    agency.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    9</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>ASSOCIATED
                    ENTERPRISES</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943392_084" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><leadIn>Where:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514983_044" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an enterprise of a Contracting Party participates directly or
                        indirectly in the management, control or capital of an enterprise of the
                        other Contracting Party; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514984_045" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the same persons participate directly or indirectly in the management,
                        control or capital of an enterprise of a Contracting Party and an enterprise
                        of the other Contracting Party,</content></subsection><continued>and in either case conditions are made or imposed between the two
                    enterprises in their commercial or financial relations which differ from those
                    which would be made between independent enterprises, then any income or profits
                    which would, but for those conditions, have accrued to one of the enterprises,
                    but, by reason of those conditions, have not so accrued, may be included in the
                    income or profits of that enterprise and taxed
                    accordingly.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438410943392_117" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Where a Contracting Party includes in the profits of an enterprise of that
                    Contracting Party — and taxes accordingly — profits on which an enterprise of
                    the other Contracting Party has been charged to tax in that other Contracting
                    Party and the profits so included are profits which would have accrued to the
                    enterprise of the first-mentioned Contracting Party if the conditions made
                    between the two enterprises had been those which would have been made between
                    independent enterprises, then that other Contracting Party shall make an
                    appropriate adjustment to the amount of the tax charged therein on those
                    profits. In determining such adjustment, due regard shall be had to the other
                    provisions of this Agreement and the competent authorities of the Contracting
                    Parties shall if necessary consult each
                    other.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    10</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>DIVIDENDS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943408_020" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Dividends paid by a company which is a resident of a Contracting Party to a
                    resident of the other Contracting Party, may be taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943408_028" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>However, such dividends may also be taxed in the Contracting Party of which
                    the company paying the dividends is a resident, and according to the laws of
                    that Contracting Party, but if the beneficial owner of the dividends is a
                    resident of the other Contracting Party, the tax so charged shall not exceed 10
                    per cent of the gross amount of the
                    dividends.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content><content>This paragraph shall not affect the taxation of the company in respect of
                    the profits out of which the dividends are
                    paid.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943408_044" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>The term “dividends” as used in this Article means income from shares,
                    founders’ shares or other rights, not being debt-claims, participating in
                    profits, as well as income from other corporate rights which is subjected to the
                    same taxation treatment as income from shares by the laws of the Contracting
                    Party of which the company making the distribution is a
                    resident.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943408_052" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> shall not apply
                    if the beneficial owner of the dividends, being a resident of a Contracting
                    Party, carries on business in the other Contracting Party of which the company
                    paying the dividends is a resident, through a permanent establishment situated
                    therein, or performs in that other Contracting Party independent personal
                    services from a fixed base situated therein, and the holding in respect of which
                    the dividends are paid is effectively connected with such permanent
                    establishment or fixed base. In such case the provisions of Article 7 or Article
                    14, as the case may be, shall
                    apply.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943408_060" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><content>Where a company which is a resident of a Contracting Party derives income
                    or profits from the other Contracting Party, that other Contracting Party may
                    not impose any tax on the dividends paid by the company, except insofar as such
                    dividends are paid to a resident of that other Contracting Party or insofar as
                    the holding in respect of which the dividends are paid is effectively connected
                    with a permanent establishment or a fixed base situated in that other
                    Contracting Party, nor subject the company’s undistributed profits to a tax on
                    the company’s undistributed profits, even if the dividends paid or the
                    undistributed profits consist wholly or partly of income or profits arising in
                    such other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    11</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>INTEREST</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943408_084" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Interest arising in a Contracting Party and paid to a resident of the other
                    Contracting Party may be taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943408_092" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>However, such interest may also be taxed in the Contracting Party in which
                    it arises, and according to the laws of that Contracting Party, but if the
                    beneficial owner of the interest is a resident of the other Contracting Party,
                    the tax so charged shall not exceed:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514986_046" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>10 per cent of the gross amount of the interest if the interest is
                        beneficially owned by any financial institution or insurance
                        company;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514986_047" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>10 per cent of the gross amount of the interest if the interest is
                        beneficially owned by a resident of the other Contracting Party and is paid
                        with respect to indebtedness arising as a consequence of a sale on credit by
                        a resident of that other Contracting Party of any equipment, merchandise or
                        services, except where the sale was between persons not dealing with each
                        other at arm’s length; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514987_048" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>15 per cent of the gross amount of the interest in all other
                        cases.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943423_013" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of this Article,
                    interest arising in a Contracting Party is exempt from tax in that Contracting
                    Party, if it is paid:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514988_049" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region,</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1495441514989_050" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                            Region;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514989_051" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to the Hong Kong Monetary Authority;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514990_052" name="iii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>to a financial institution appointed by the Government of the Hong
                            Kong Special Administrative Region and mutually agreed upon by the
                            competent authorities of the two Contracting Parties;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514990_053" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the case of Thailand,</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1495441514991_054" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to the Government of the Kingdom of Thailand;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514991_055" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to any local authority;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514992_056" name="iii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>to the Bank of Thailand;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514992_057" name="iv" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>to the Export-Import Bank of Thailand;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441514993_058" name="v" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>to a financial institution appointed by the Government of the
                            Kingdom of Thailand and mutually agreed upon by the competent
                            authorities of the two Contracting
                            Parties.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943423_110" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>The term “interest” as used in this Article means income from debt-claims
                    of every kind, whether or not secured by mortgage, and whether or not carrying a
                    right to participate in the debtor’s profits, and in particular, income from
                    government securities and income from bonds or debentures, including premiums
                    and prizes attaching to such securities, bonds or debentures, as well as income
                    treated as income from money lent by the taxation laws of the Contracting Party
                    in which the income arises. Penalty charges for late payment shall not be
                    regarded as interest for the purpose of this
                    Article.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943423_118" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> shall not apply
                    if the beneficial owner of the interest, being a resident of a Contracting
                    Party, carries on business in the other Contracting Party in which the interest
                    arises through a permanent establishment situated therein, or performs in that
                    other Contracting Party independent personal services from a fixed base situated
                    therein, and the debt-claim in respect of which the interest is paid is
                    effectively connected with such permanent establishment or fixed base. In such
                    case the provisions of Article 7 or Article 14, as the case may be, shall
                    apply.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943423_126" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_P1_s6" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="6"><inline class="not_bold">6.</inline></num><content>Interest shall be deemed to arise in a Contracting Party when the payer is
                    a resident of that Contracting Party. Where, however, the person paying the
                    interest, whether he is a resident of a Contracting Party or not, has in a
                    Contracting Party a permanent establishment or a fixed base in connection with
                    which the indebtedness on which the interest is paid was incurred, and such
                    interest is borne by such permanent establishment or fixed base, then such
                    interest shall be deemed to arise in the Contracting Party in which the
                    permanent establishment or fixed base is
                    situated.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943439_004" name="s7" temporalId="sch0_P1_s7" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="7"><inline class="not_bold">7.</inline></num><content>Where, by reason of a special relationship between the payer and the
                    beneficial owner or between both of them and some other person, the amount of
                    the interest, having regard to the debt-claim for which it is paid, exceeds the
                    amount which would have been agreed upon by the payer and the beneficial owner
                    in the absence of such relationship, the provisions of this Article shall apply
                    only to the last-mentioned amount. In such case, the excess part of the payments
                    shall remain taxable according to the laws of each Contracting Party, due regard
                    being had to the other provisions of this
                    Agreement.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    12</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>ROYALTIES</b></text><section id="ID_1438410943439_028" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Royalties arising in a Contracting Party and paid to a resident of the
                    other Contracting Party may be taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943439_036" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>However, such royalties may also be taxed in the Contracting Party in which
                    they arise and according to the laws of that Contracting Party, but if the
                    beneficial owner of the royalties is a resident of the other Contracting Party,
                    the tax so charged shall not exceed:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441514995_059" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>5 per cent of the gross amount of the royalties if they are made as a
                        consideration for the use of, or the right to use, any copyright of
                        literary, artistic or scientific work;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514995_060" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>10 per cent of the gross amount of the royalties if they are made as a
                        consideration for the use of, or the right to use, any patent, trademark,
                        design or model, plan, secret formula or process; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441514996_061" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>15 per cent of the gross amount of the royalties in all other
                        cases.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943439_070" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>The term “royalties” as used in this Article means payments of any kind
                    received as a consideration for the use of, or the right to use, any copyright
                    of literary, artistic or scientific work including cinematograph films, or films
                    or tapes used for radio or television broadcasting, any patent, trademark,
                    design or model, plan, secret formula or process, or for the use of, or the
                    right to use, industrial, commercial, or scientific equipment or for information
                    concerning industrial, commercial or scientific
                    experience.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943439_078" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> shall not apply
                    if the beneficial owner of the royalties, being a resident of a Contracting
                    Party, carries on business in the other Contracting Party in which the royalties
                    arise through a permanent establishment situated therein, or performs in that
                    other Contracting Party independent personal services from a fixed base situated
                    therein, and the right or property in respect of which the royalties are paid is
                    effectively connected with such permanent establishment or fixed base. In such
                    case the provisions of Article 7 or Article 14, as the case may be, shall
                    apply.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943439_086" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><content>Royalties shall be deemed to arise in a Contracting Party when the payer is
                    a resident of that Contracting Party. Where, however, the person paying the
                    royalties, whether he is a resident of a Contracting Party or not, has in a
                    Contracting Party a permanent establishment or a fixed base in connection with
                    which the liability to pay the royalties was incurred, and such royalties are
                    borne by such permanent establishment or fixed base, then such royalties shall
                    be deemed to arise in the Contracting Party in which the permanent establishment
                    or fixed base is
                    situated.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943455_004" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_P1_s6" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="6"><inline class="not_bold">6.</inline></num><content>Where, by reason of a special relationship between the payer and the
                    beneficial owner or between both of them and some other person, the amount of
                    the royalties, having regard to the use, right and information for which they
                    are paid, exceeds the amount which would have been agreed upon by the payer and
                    the beneficial owner in the absence of such relationship, the provisions of this
                    Article shall apply only to the last-mentioned amount. In such case, the excess
                    part of the payments shall remain taxable according to the laws of each
                    Contracting Party, due regard being had to the other provisions of this
                    Agreement.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    13</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>CAPITAL
                    GAINS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943455_028" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Gains derived by a resident of a Contracting Party from the alienation of
                    immovable property referred to in Article 6 and situated in the other
                    Contracting Party may be taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943455_036" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Gains from the alienation of movable property forming part of the business
                    property of a permanent establishment which an enterprise of a Contracting Party
                    has in the other Contracting Party or of movable property pertaining to a fixed
                    base available to a resident of a Contracting Party in the other Contracting
                    Party for the purpose of performing independent personal services, including
                    such gains from the alienation of such a permanent establishment (alone or with
                    the whole enterprise) or of such a fixed base, may be taxed in that other
                    Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943455_044" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>Gains derived by an enterprise of a Contracting Party from the alienation
                    of ships or aircraft operated in international traffic or movable property
                    pertaining to the operation of such ships or aircraft, shall be taxable only in
                    that Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943455_052" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>Gains derived by a resident of a Contracting Party from the alienation of
                    shares of a company deriving more than 50 per cent of its asset value directly
                    or indirectly from immovable property situated in the other Contracting Party
                    may be taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943455_060" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><content>Gains from the alienation of any property, other than that referred to in
                        <ref>paragraphs 1</ref>, <ref>2</ref>, <ref>3</ref> and <ref>4</ref>, shall
                    be taxable only in the Contracting Party of which the alienator is a
                    resident.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    14</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>INDEPENDENT
                    PERSONAL
                SERVICES</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943455_084" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><leadIn>Income derived by a resident of a Contracting Party in respect of
                    professional services or other independent activities of a similar character
                    shall be taxable only in that Contracting Party except in the following
                    circumstances, when such income may also be taxed in the other Contracting
                    Party:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441515000_062" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if he has a fixed base regularly available to him in the other
                        Contracting Party for the purpose of performing his activities; in that
                        case, only so much of the income as is attributable to that fixed base may
                        be taxed in that other Contracting Party; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515000_063" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if his stay in the other Contracting Party is for a period or periods
                        amounting to or exceeding in the aggregate 183 days in any twelve-month
                        period commencing or ending in the taxable period concerned; in that case,
                        only so much of the income as is derived from his activities performed in
                        that other Contracting Party may be taxed in that other Contracting
                        Party.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943470_013" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>The term “professional services” includes especially independent
                    scientific, literary, artistic, educational or teaching activities as well as
                    the independent activities of physicians, dentists, lawyers, engineers,
                    architects and
                    accountants.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    15</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>DEPENDENT
                    PERSONAL
                SERVICES</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943470_037" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Subject to the provisions of Articles 16, 18 and 19, salaries, wages and
                    other similar remuneration derived by a resident of a Contracting Party in
                    respect of an employment shall be taxable only in that Contracting Party unless
                    the employment is exercised in the other Contracting Party. If the employment is
                    so exercised, such remuneration as is derived therefrom may be taxed in that
                    other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943470_045" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, remuneration
                    derived by a resident of a Contracting Party in respect of an employment
                    exercised in the other Contracting Party shall be taxable only in the
                    first-mentioned Contracting Party if:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441515002_064" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the recipient is present in the other Contracting Party for a period or
                        periods not exceeding in the aggregate 183 days in any twelve-month period
                        commencing or ending in the taxable period concerned, and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515002_065" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the remuneration is paid by, or on behalf of, an employer who is not a
                        resident of the other Contracting Party, and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515003_066" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the remuneration is not borne by a permanent establishment or a fixed
                        base which the employer has in the other Contracting
                        Party.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1495441515003_067" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this Article, remuneration
                    derived in respect of an employment exercised aboard a ship or aircraft operated
                    in international traffic by an enterprise of a Contracting Party shall be
                    taxable only in that Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    16</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>DIRECTORS’
                    FEES</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>Directors’ fees and other similar payments derived by a resident of a Contracting
                Party in his capacity as a member of the board of directors of a company which is a
                resident of the other Contracting Party may be taxed in that other Contracting
                Party.</text><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    17</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>ARTISTES
                    AND
                SPORTSPERSONS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943470_127" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of Articles 14 and 15, income derived by a
                    resident of a Contracting Party as an entertainer, such as a theatre, motion
                    picture, radio or television artiste, or a musician, or as a sportsperson, from
                    his personal activities as such exercised in the other Contracting Party, may be
                    taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943470_135" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Where income in respect of personal activities exercised by an entertainer
                    or a sportsperson in his capacity as such accrues not to the entertainer or
                    sportsperson himself but to another person, that income may, notwithstanding the
                    provisions of Articles 7, 14 and 15, be taxed in the Contracting Party in which
                    the activities of the entertainer or sportsperson are
                    exercised.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943486_004" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> of this Article
                    shall not apply to remuneration derived from activities performed in a
                    Contracting Party by an entertainer or a sportsperson and paid by the other
                    Contracting Party if the visit to that Contracting Party is substantially
                    supported by public funds of the other Contracting Party including its local
                    authority or statutory body. In such a case the remuneration shall be taxable
                    only in the Contracting Party of which the entertainer or sportsperson is a
                    resident.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    18</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>PENSIONS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943486_028" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of Article 19, pensions
                    (including a lump sum payment) and other similar remuneration paid to a resident
                    of a Contracting Party in consideration of past employment shall be taxable only
                    in that Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943486_036" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, pensions
                    (including a lump sum payment) and other payments made under a pension or
                    retirement scheme which is:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441515006_068" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a public scheme which is part of the social security system of a
                        Contracting Party or local authorities thereof; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515007_069" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an arrangement in which individuals may participate to secure
                        retirement benefits and which is recognised for tax purposes in a
                        Contracting Party,</content></subsection><continued>shall be taxable only in that Contracting
                    Party.</continued></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    19</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>GOVERNMENT
                    SERVICE</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943486_085" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><subsection id="ID_1438410943486_090" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Salaries, wages and other similar remuneration, other than a pension,
                        paid by the Government of a Contracting Party or a local authority thereof
                        to an individual in respect of services rendered to that Contracting Party
                        or authority shall be taxable only in that Contracting Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410943486_096" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>However, such salaries, wages and other remuneration shall be taxable
                        only in the other Contracting Party if the services are rendered in that
                        Contracting Party and the individual is a resident of that Contracting Party
                        who:</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410943486_105" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, has the
                            right of abode therein and in the case of Thailand is a national
                            thereof; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410943486_114" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>did not become a resident of that Contracting Party solely for the
                            purpose of rendering the
                            services.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410943486_128" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Any pension (including a lump sum payment) paid by, or out of funds
                    created, or contributed to, by the Government of a Contracting Party or a local
                    authority thereof to an individual in respect of services rendered to that
                    Contracting Party or authority shall be taxable only in that Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943486_136" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>The provisions of Articles 15, 16 and 18, instead of this Article, shall
                    apply to salaries, wages and other similar remuneration, and to pensions
                    (including a lump sum payment), in respect of services rendered in connection
                    with a business carried on by the Government of a Contracting Party or a local
                    authority
                    thereof.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    20</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>STUDENTS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>Payments which a student or business apprentice who is or was immediately before
                visiting a Contracting Party a resident of the other Contracting Party and who is
                present in the first-mentioned Contracting Party solely for the purpose of his
                education or training receives for the purpose of his maintenance, education or
                training shall not be taxed in that Contracting Party, provided that such payments
                arise from sources outside that Contracting
                Party.</text><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    21</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>OTHER
                    INCOME</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943501_044" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Items of income of a resident of a Contracting Party, wherever arising, not
                    dealt with in the foregoing Articles of this Agreement shall be taxable only in
                    that Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943501_052" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>The provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> shall not apply to income, other
                    than income from immovable property as defined in <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of
                    Article 6, if the recipient of such income, being a resident of a Contracting
                    Party, carries on business in the other Contracting Party through a permanent
                    establishment situated therein, or performs in that other Contracting Party
                    independent personal services from a fixed base situated therein, and a right or
                    property in respect of which the income is paid is effectively connected with
                    such permanent establishment or fixed base. In such case, the provisions of
                    Article 7 or Article 14, as the case may be, shall
                    apply.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943501_060" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref>,
                    items of income of a resident of a Contracting Party not dealt with in the
                    foregoing Articles of this Agreement and arising in the other Contracting Party
                    may also be taxed in that other Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    22</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>METHODS
                    FOR ELIMINATION OF DOUBLE
                TAXATION</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943501_084" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Subject to the provisions of the laws of the Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region relating to the allowance of a credit against Hong Kong
                    Special Administrative Region tax of tax paid in a jurisdiction outside the Hong
                    Kong Special Administrative Region (which shall not affect the general principle
                    of this Article), Thai tax paid under the laws of Thailand and in accordance
                    with this Agreement, whether directly or by deduction, in respect of income
                    derived by a person who is a resident of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region from sources in Thailand, shall be allowed as a credit against Hong Kong
                    Special Administrative Region tax payable in respect of that income, provided
                    that the credit so allowed does not exceed the amount of Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region tax computed in respect of that income in accordance with
                    the tax laws of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943501_092" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Subject to the laws of Thailand regarding the allowance as a credit against
                    Thai tax of tax paid in any country other than Thailand, Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region tax paid in respect of income derived from Hong Kong
                    Special Administrative Region shall be allowed as a credit against Thai tax paid
                    in respect of that income. The amount of credit shall not, however, exceed that
                    portion of Thai tax which is appropriate to that
                    income.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943501_100" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>For the purpose of allowance as a credit in a Contracting Party the tax
                    paid in the other Contracting Party shall be deemed to include the tax which is
                    otherwise payable in that other Contracting Party but has been reduced or waived
                    in accordance with special incentive laws designed to promote economic
                    development in that other Contracting Party. The provisions of this paragraph
                    shall only apply for a period of 7 years from the day on which this Agreement
                    comes into effect according to <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of Article 27. The periods
                    may be extended by mutual agreement between the competent
                    authorities.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    23</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>NON-DISCRIMINATION</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943517_020" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Persons who, in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region,
                    have the right of abode or are incorporated or otherwise constituted therein,
                    and in the case of Thailand, are nationals of Thailand shall not be subjected in
                    the other Contracting Party to any taxation or any requirement connected
                    therewith, which is other or more burdensome than the taxation and connected
                    requirements to which persons who have the right of abode or are incorporated or
                    otherwise constituted in that other Contracting Party (where that other
                    Contracting Party is the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region) or nationals
                    of that other Contracting Party (where that other Contracting Party is Thailand)
                    in the same circumstances, in particular with respect to residence, are or may
                    be
                    subjected.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943517_028" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>The taxation on a permanent establishment which an enterprise of a
                    Contracting Party has in the other Contracting Party shall not be less
                    favourably levied in that other Contracting Party than the taxation levied on
                    enterprises of that other Contracting Party carrying on the same
                    activities.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943517_036" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>Except where the provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 9,
                        <ref>paragraph 7</ref> of Article 11, or <ref>paragraph 6</ref> of Article
                    12 apply, interest, royalties and other disbursements paid by an enterprise of a
                    Contracting Party to a resident of the other Contracting Party shall, for the
                    purpose of determining the taxable profits of such enterprise, be deductible
                    under the same conditions as if they had been paid to a resident of the
                    first-mentioned Contracting
                    Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943517_044" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>Enterprises of a Contracting Party, the capital of which is wholly or
                    partly owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by one or more residents of
                    the other Contracting Party, shall not be subjected in the first-mentioned
                    Contracting Party to any taxation or any requirement connected therewith which
                    is other or more burdensome than the taxation and connected requirements to
                    which other similar enterprises of the first-mentioned Contracting Party are or
                    may be
                    subjected.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943517_052" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_P1_s5" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="5"><inline class="not_bold">5.</inline></num><content>The provisions of this Article shall not be construed as obliging a
                    Contracting Party to grant to residents of the other Contracting Party any
                    personal allowances, reliefs and reductions for taxation purposes on account of
                    civil status or family responsibilities which it grants to its own
                    residents.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943517_060" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_P1_s6" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="6"><inline class="not_bold">6.</inline></num><content>The provisions of this Article shall only apply to the taxes which are the
                    subject of this
                    Agreement.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    24</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>MUTUAL
                    AGREEMENT
                PROCEDURE</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943517_084" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Where a person considers that the actions of one or both of the Contracting
                    Parties result or will result for him in taxation not in accordance with the
                    provisions of this Agreement, he may, irrespective of the remedies provided by
                    the domestic laws of those Contracting Parties, present his case to the
                    competent authority of the Contracting Party of which he is a resident or if his
                    case comes under <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 23, to that of the
                    Contracting Party in which he has the right of abode or is incorporated or
                    otherwise constituted (in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region) or of which he is a national (in the case of Thailand). The case must be
                    presented within three years from the first notification of the action resulting
                    in taxation not in accordance with the provision of this
                    Agreement.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943533_004" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>The competent authority shall endeavour, if the objection appears to it to
                    be justified and if it is not itself able to arrive at a satisfactory solution,
                    to resolve the case by mutual agreement with the competent authority of the
                    other Contracting Party, with a view to the avoidance of taxation which is not
                    in accordance with this Agreement. Any agreement reached shall be implemented
                    notwithstanding any time limits in the domestic laws of the Contracting
                    Parties.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943533_012" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P1_s3" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content>The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties shall endeavour to
                    resolve by mutual agreement any difficulties or doubts arising as to the
                    interpretation or application of this Agreement. They may also consult together
                    for the elimination of double taxation in cases not provided for in this
                    Agreement.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943533_020" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_P1_s4" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="4"><inline class="not_bold">4.</inline></num><content>The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties may communicate with
                    each other directly for the purposes of giving effect to the provisions of this
                    Agreement.</content></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    25</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>EXCHANGE
                    OF
                INFORMATION</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943533_044" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties shall exchange such
                    information as is necessary for carrying out the provisions of this Agreement or
                    of the domestic laws of the Contracting Parties concerning taxes covered by this
                    Agreement insofar as the taxation thereunder is not contrary to this Agreement.
                    Any information received by a Contracting Party shall be treated as secret in
                    the same manner as information obtained under the domestic laws of that
                    Contracting Party and shall be disclosed only to persons or authorities
                    (including courts and administrative bodies) concerned with the assessment or
                    collection of, the enforcement or prosecution in respect of, or the
                    determination of appeals in relation to, the taxes covered by this Agreement.
                    Such persons or authorities shall use the information only for such purposes.
                    They may disclose the information in public court proceedings or in judicial
                    decisions, including, in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region, the decisions of the Board of Review. Information may not be disclosed
                    to any third jurisdiction for any purpose without the consent of the Contracting
                    Party originally furnishing the
                    information.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943533_052" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>In no case shall the provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> be construed so as
                    to impose on a Contracting Party the obligation:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441515014_070" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to carry out administrative measures at variance with the laws and the
                        administrative practice of that or of the other Contracting Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515014_071" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to supply information which is not obtainable under the laws or in the
                        normal course of the administration of that or of the other Contracting
                        Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515015_072" name="c" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to supply information which would disclose any trade, business,
                        industrial, commercial or professional secret or trade process, or
                        information, the disclosure of which would be contrary to public policy
                        (ordre
                        public).</content></subsection></section><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                    26</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>MISCELLANEOUS
                    PROVISIONS</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438410943533_102" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Nothing in this Agreement shall prejudice the right of each Contracting
                    Party to apply its domestic laws and measures concerning tax avoidance, whether
                    or not described as
                    such.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943548_004" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content>Nothing in this Agreement shall affect the fiscal privileges of persons
                    entitled to such fiscal privileges under the general rules of international law
                    or under the provisions of special
                    agreements.</content></section><text>
                <content class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                        27</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>ENTRY
                        INTO
                    FORCE</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
            </text><section id="ID_1438410943548_028" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P1_s1" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content>Each of the Contracting Parties shall notify the other in writing of the
                    completion of the procedures required by its law for the entering into force of
                    this Agreement. This Agreement shall enter into force on the date of receipt of
                    the later of these
                    notifications.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410943548_036" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><leadIn>The provisions of this Agreement shall have effect:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1495441515016_073" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, in respect of Hong Kong
                        Special Administrative Region tax, for any year of assessment beginning on
                        or after 1 April in the calendar year next following that in which this
                        Agreement enters into force;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515016_074" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in Thailand,</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1495441515017_075" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in respect of taxes withheld at source, on amounts of income paid
                            on or after 1 January in the calendar year next following that in which
                            the Agreement enters into force; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441515017_076" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in respect of other taxes on income, on such taxes chargeable for
                            any tax year or accounting period, beginning on or after 1 January in
                            the calendar year next following that in which this Agreement enters
                            into
                            force.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><text>
                <content class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><b>Article
                        28</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>TERMINATION</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
            </text><text>
                <content>This Agreement shall remain in force indefinitely, but either of the
                    Contracting Parties may give the other Contracting Party written notice of
                    termination on or before 30 June in any calendar year beginning after the
                    expiration of a period of five years from the date of its entry into
                    force.</content>
            </text><text>
                <content>In such event this Agreement shall cease to have effect:</content>
            </text><section id="ID_1495441515018_077" name="s0" temporalId="sch0_P1_s0" class="no_header" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><subsection id="ID_1495441515019_078" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P1_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, in respect of Hong Kong
                        Special Administrative Region tax, for any year of assessment beginning on
                        or after 1 April in the calendar year next following that in which the
                        notice is given;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1495441515019_079" name="b" temporalId="sch0_P1_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in Thailand,</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1495441515020_080" name="i" temporalId="sch0_P1_s0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in respect of taxes withheld at source, on amounts of income paid
                            on or after 1 January in the calendar year next following that in which
                            the notice is given; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1495441515020_081" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_P1_s0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in respect of other taxes on income, on such taxes chargeable for
                            any tax year or accounting period beginning on or after 1 January in the
                            calendar year next following that in which the notice is
                            given.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></subsection></section></part><part name="P2" temporalId="sch0_P2" id="ID_1495441515021_082" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2">Part
                2</num><heading>
                Paragraphs
                1 to 3 of the Protocol to the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong
                Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government
                of the Kingdom of Thailand for the Avoidance of Double Taxation and the Prevention
                of Fiscal Evasion with respect to Taxes on
                Income</heading><section class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified no_header" id="ID_1576812794032_001" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_P2_s1"><num class="align_left" value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0">The Agreement applies to the
                    existing taxes set out in sub-paragraph (a) of <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of Article
                    2, whether or not charged under personal assessment.</content></section><section class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified no_header" id="ID_1576812794032_002" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_P2_s2"><num class="align_left" value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0">In the Agreement, the terms
                    “Hong Kong Special Administrative Region tax” and “Thai tax” do not include any
                    penalty or interest imposed under the laws of either Contracting Party relating
                    to the taxes to which this Agreement applies by virtue of Article 2. In the case
                    of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, “penalty or interest” includes,
                    without limitation, any sum added to Hong Kong Special Administrative Region tax
                    by reason of default and recovered therewith, and “additional tax” assessed for
                    infringement of or failure to comply with its tax laws.</content></section><section class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified no_header" id="ID_1576812794032_003" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_P2_s3"><num class="align_left" value="3"><inline class="not_bold">3.</inline></num><content class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0">For the purposes of Article 8,
                    income and profits from the operation of ships or aircraft in international
                    traffic shall include in particular:</content></section><subsection class="left_indent_12" id="ID_1576812794032_004" name="0" temporalId="sch0_P2_0"><subsection name="a" temporalId="sch0_P2_0_a" id="ID_1576812794032_005"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revenues and gross receipts from the operation of ships or aircraft for
                        the transport of persons, livestock, goods, mail or merchandise in
                        international traffic including,</content></subsection></subsection><paragraph class="left_indent_45" id="ID_1576812794032_006" name="0-1" temporalId="sch0_P2_0-1"><paragraph name="1" temporalId="sch0_P2_0-1_1" id="ID_1576812794032_007"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>income derived from the lease of ships or aircraft on a bareboat
                        charter basis where such lease is incidental to the operation of ships or
                        aircraft in international traffic;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="2" temporalId="sch0_P2_0-1_2" id="ID_1576812794032_008"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>income derived from the sale of tickets and the provision of services
                        connected with such transport whether for the enterprise itself or for any
                        other enterprise, provided that in the case of provision of services, such
                        provision is incidental to the operation of ships and aircraft in
                        international traffic;</content></paragraph></paragraph><subsection class="left_indent_12" id="ID_1576812794032_009" name="0-2" temporalId="sch0_P2_0-2"><subsection name="b" temporalId="sch0_P2_0-2_b" id="ID_1576812794032_010"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>interest on funds directly connected with the operation of ships or
                        aircraft in international traffic and deposited in savings
                        accounts;</content></subsection><subsection name="c" temporalId="sch0_P2_0-2_c" id="ID_1576812794032_011"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>profits from the lease of containers by the enterprise, when such lease
                        is incidental to the operation of ships or aircraft in international
                        traffic.</content></subsection></subsection></part></schedule></main></subLeg>