<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 190 sub. leg. F</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>190F</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap190F!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2015-01-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402814596_004" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2015-01-29">The Organization for the Network of
            Aquaculture Centres in Asia and the Pacific Notification</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap190/s2">Cap. 190, section
                2</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2015/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2015</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[4 May 1990]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2015/er1">E.R. 1 of 2015</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402814611_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>This notification may be cited as the Organization for the Network of Aquaculture Centres in Asia and the Pacific Notification.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402814627_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><content>In this notification, the official activities of the Organization for the Network of Aquaculture Centres in Asia and the Pacific (hereinafter referred to as the Organization) means its activities carried out in pursuance of its objectives as defined in the Agreement on the Network of Aquaculture Centres in Asia and the Pacific, opened for signature at Bangkok on 8 January 1988 and thereafter at the Headquarters of the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations in Rome until 7 January 1989, and includes its administrative activities. </content></section><section id="ID_1438402814642_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>The Organization is an organization to which the International Organizations and Diplomatic Privileges Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap190">Cap. 190</ref>) applies.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402814658_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Legal capacity</heading><subsection id="ID_1517972942016_001" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Organization shall have the legal capacities of a body corporate and,
                except in so far as in any particular case it has expressly waived its immunity,
                immunity from suit and legal process.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1517972942016_002" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No waiver of immunity shall be deemed to extend to any measure of
                execution.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402814674_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Inviolability of archives and offices</heading><content>The Organization shall have the like inviolability of official archives and premises occupied as offices as is accorded in the People’s Republic of China in respect of the official archives and premises of an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402814674_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Exemption from taxes and rates</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411511576_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Organization shall have the like exemption or relief from taxes and rates, other than taxes on the importation of goods, as is accorded in the People’s Republic of China to a foreign sovereign power.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411511576_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Organization shall have exemption from taxes on the importation of goods directly imported by the Organization for its official use in Hong Kong or for exportation, or on the importation of any publications of the Organization directly imported by it, such exemption to be subject to compliance with such conditions as the Commissioner of Customs and Excise may prescribe for the protection of the revenue.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402814689_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Exemption from prohibition or restriction on importation or exportation of goods</heading><content>The Organization shall have exemption from prohibitions and restrictions on importation or exportation in the case of goods directly imported or exported by the Organization for its official use and in the case of any publications of the Organization directly imported or exported by it.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402814705_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Right to telegraphic communications</heading><content>The Organization shall have the right to avail itself, for telegraphic communications sent by it and containing only matter intended for publication by the press or for broadcasting (including communications addressed to or dispatched from places outside Hong Kong), of any reduced rates applicable for the corresponding service in the case of press telegrams.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402814798_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Immunity of representatives</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411511639_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by the Government whom he represents a representative of a member to the Governing Council, the Technical Advisory Committee or to any conference, meeting or other organ of the Organization shall enjoy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411511639_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>while exercising his function as such and during his journeys to and from the place of meeting, immunity from personal arrest or detention and from seizure of his personal baggage and inviolability for all papers and documents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411511639_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or written and things done or omitted to be done by him in his capacity as a representative.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411511654_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the incidence of any form of taxation depends upon residence, a representative shall not be deemed to be resident in Hong Kong during any period when he is present in Hong Kong for the discharge of his duties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411511654_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="Representative"><leadIn>In this paragraph, <term>representative</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">代表</term>) shall include, in addition to a representative to whom subparagraph (1) applies, the following members of his official staff—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411511654_021" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>alternate
                        representatives;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411511654_029" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>advisers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411511654_037" name="c" temporalId="s9_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>technical
                        experts;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411511654_045" name="d" temporalId="s9_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>secretaries of Delegations,</content></paragraph><continued>and Part IV of the <ref>First Schedule</ref> to the Ordinance shall not operate so as to confer privileges or immunities on the staffs of a representative other than on those persons falling within the above-mentioned descriptions.</continued></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411511654_058" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>This paragraph shall not confer any immunity or privilege on any person as the representative of the Central People’s Government in Hong Kong or as a member of the staff of such representative or any person who is a Chinese national.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402814830_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Co-ordinator of the Organization</heading><content>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by the Organization, the Co-ordinator shall be accorded in respect of himself, his spouse and his children under the age of 21 the like immunity from suit and legal process, the like inviolability of residence and the like exemption or relief from taxes, other than income tax, as is accorded in the People’s Republic of China to an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s Republic of China, his spouse and children, and exemption from income tax in respect of emoluments received by him as an officer of the Organization.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402814830_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Other officials of the Organization</heading><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by the Organization, officials of the Organization of any category specified by it by notice to the Chief Executive shall enjoy—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411511717_012" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>immunity from suit and legal process in respect of words spoken or written and things done or omitted to be done by them in the course of the performance of their official duties;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411511717_020" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>exemption from income tax in respect of emoluments received by them as officers or servants of the Organization.</content></paragraph></section></main></subLeg>