<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 258</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>258</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap258!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-09-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402904873_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-09-19">
            <content>For the removal of doubts as to the validity of certain marriages celebrated in
                Hong Kong after the outbreak of hostilities with
                Japan.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[18 June 1948]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402904873_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Marriage (War Period) (Validity)
                Ordinance</shortTitle>, and shall be construed as one with the Marriage Ordinance
                (<ref href="/hk/cap181">Cap. 181</ref>), hereinafter referred to as the
                    <b><i>principal
                    Ordinance</i></b>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402904889_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Registrar"><term>Registrar</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">登記官</term>) means
            the Registrar of Marriages under the principal Ordinance and includes a deputy
            registrar;</def><def name="WarPeriod"><term>war
                period</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">戰爭時期</term>) means the period from
            8
            December 1941 to
            15
            October 1945.
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of
            2019</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section><section id="ID_1438402904889_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>Save as hereinafter appears this Ordinance shall apply to all marriages duly
            celebrated in Hong Kong during the war period except non-Christian customary marriages
            celebrated according to the personal law and religion of the parties.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904904_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Validation of marriages celebrated during the war period</heading><content>A marriage celebrated in Hong Kong during the war period shall not be deemed
            invalid by reason of its having been celebrated in a place which had not been duly
            licensed under <ref>section 4</ref> of the principal Ordinance, or without compliance
            with the requirements of such Ordinance concerning notice of marriage, certificate of
            notice, licence or competency of the officiating minister, and, subject as is herein
            provided, all such marriages are hereby declared to be and always to have been
            valid.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904920_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Prevailing grounds of invalidity</heading><leadIn>Nothing in this Ordinance shall validate any marriage which was invalid on the
            ground of kindred or affinity, or because one of the parties was under the age of
            16
            years, or any marriage which would have been invalid notwithstanding compliance with all
            the requirements of the said Ordinance, or any marriage which before the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance has been declared invalid by a court of competent jurisdiction:
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of
            2019</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_proviso">Provided further that where any marriage to
            which this Ordinance applies would, but for this Ordinance, have been invalid and either
            party has subsequently during the life of the other party, but before the commencement
            of this Ordinance, lawfully married any other person, this Ordinance shall not render
            the first marriage valid or affect the validity of the subsequent marriage.</proviso><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1562214357554_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 18 June
                1948.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904920_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Relief against penalties applicable to ministers</heading><content>No minister who has complied with <ref>section 7</ref> shall be liable to any penalties under the principal Ordinance in respect of any matter referred to in <ref>section 4</ref> hereof and no proceedings shall be taken without the consent of the Secretary for Justice against a minister who has not so complied in respect of a marriage to which this Ordinance applies.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904935_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Certificate by officiating minister</heading><leadIn>Every minister who has officiated at a marriage to which this Ordinance applies and who has not already given the parties a certificate in the prescribed form under the principal Ordinance shall, at the request of either party, give such a certificate:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_proviso">Provided that if such minister satisfies the Registrar that he is unable to give such a certificate because he is unable to secure the signatures of the two witnesses to the marriage and has no certificate with their signatures in his possession, or because he is unable to obtain information necessary to enable him to complete the certificate, it shall suffice if the officiating minister, with the consent of the Registrar, gives a certificate which, in lieu of being signed by two witnesses of the marriage, states the names of two such witnesses and gives such information as he and the parties or either of them are able to supply.</proviso><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1948/20">20 of 1948 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904951_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Effect of certificate of marriage issued by the officiating minister</heading><content>A certificate in the prescribed form under the principal Ordinance whether given
            before or after the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance, or a certificate in the alternative form authorized by <ref>section
                7</ref> if countersigned by the Registrar, shall, if given in respect of a marriage
            to which this Ordinance applies, be admissible as evidence of the marriage to which the
            same relates in any court or before any person having by law or by consent of parties
            authority to receive evidence.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1948/20">20 of 1948 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1559637337517_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 18 June
                1948.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904951_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Duties of the Registrar</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411695002_018" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar shall collect and preserve in a register in a convenient form
                such information in relation to marriages to which this Ordinance applies as has
                already been, or may subsequently be, furnished to him, and shall for a fee of
                $5
                supply any person requiring it with the information in his possession regarding a
                particular marriage.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411695017_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Registrar shall enter in a convenient place in such register the fact of his consent in any particular case to the form of certificate secondly referred to in <ref>section 7</ref>, and shall note on such certificate that his consent was obtained and sign the same.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904967_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations
                prescribing—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411695033_019" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>rules, forms and fees for any application by an officiating minister for the
                Registrar’s consent under <ref>section 7</ref> and for information under
                    <ref>section 9</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411695033_027" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for further cases in which an officiating minister should be relieved from
                penalties notwithstanding that he has been unable to give any certificate under
                    <ref>section 7</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411695033_035" name="c" temporalId="s10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>generally for carrying this Ordinance into effect.</content></paragraph></section></main></ordinance>