<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 123 sub. leg. L</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>123L</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap123L!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-05-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402651700_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-05-13">Building
                                    (Appeal) Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap123/s38">Cap.
                                                123, section
                                    38(1B)</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[16 November 1994]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402651700_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402651716_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Appellant"><term>appellant</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">上訴人</term>) means a person who has given notice of
            appeal;</def><def name="Chairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the chairman of the Tribunal appointed
            under <ref>section 48(1)</ref> of the Ordinance;</def><def name="ExtendedPeriod"><term>extended
                period</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經延展的期限</term>) means, in relation to a particular case,
            a period allowed under <ref>section 13</ref>;</def><def name="Hearing"><term>hearing</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">聆訊</term>) means the hearing of an appeal and includes
            a preliminary hearing;</def><def name="NoticeOfAppeal"><term>notice
                of
            appeal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">上訴通知</term>) means a notice of appeal referred to in
                <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="PreliminaryHearing"><term>preliminary
                hearing</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">初步聆訊</term>) means a hearing held under <ref>section
                49</ref> of the Ordinance;</def><def name="Secretary"><term>Secretary</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">秘書</term>) means the Secretary to the Appeal Tribunal
            appointed under <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance;</def><def name="Tribunal"><term>Tribunal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">審裁小組</term>) means, in relation to a particular appeal,
            the tribunal appointed under <ref>section 48(1)</ref> of the Ordinance to hear and
            determine that appeal.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402651731_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Notice of appeal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411142277_067" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A notice of appeal for the purposes of <ref>section 47</ref> of the Ordinance shall be in writing and served on the Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142293_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A notice of appeal may be served on the Secretary by sending it to him by registered or ordinary mail addressed to him at his office or facsimile transmission or serving it personally on him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142293_013" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The appellant shall serve a copy of the notice of appeal on the Building Authority within the period specified in <ref>section 47</ref> of the Ordinance for giving notice of appeal.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402651747_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Statement of particulars</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411142308_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The appellant shall, within 28 days beginning on the date notice of appeal is given or, where appropriate, within the extended period, furnish to the Secretary a statement containing—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411142308_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the particulars of the decision to which the appeal relates;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142308_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the grounds of appeal if they have not been specified in the notice of appeal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142308_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a detailed description of the matter to which the appeal relates;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142308_036" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a description of each document the appellant intends to produce at the hearing;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142308_044" name="e" temporalId="s4_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>where relevant, the address and description of any property or land to which the appeal relates and a statement of the interest of the appellant in that property or land; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142308_052" name="f" temporalId="s4_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the particulars of the witnesses the appellant intends to call on his behalf at the hearing.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142324_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The appellant shall serve a copy of the statement referred to in subsection (1) on the Building Authority within the period or extended period, as may be appropriate, referred to in that subsection.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402651762_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Representations and documents as regards need for a preliminary hearing</heading><leadIn>The Building Authority shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411142339_020" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>within 28 days beginning on the date of receiving a copy of a statement under <ref>section 4(2)</ref> or, where appropriate, within the extended period, furnish to the Secretary representations in writing and documents (if any) in his possession or custody, which he considers would assist the Tribunal to determine or otherwise dispose of the appeal; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142339_028" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>within the period referred to in paragraph (a) or the extended period, as may be appropriate, serve a copy of the representations and a copy each of any document furnished under that paragraph, on the appellant.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402651762_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Request for further particulars</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411142371_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A party to an appeal may, by serving a notice—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411142371_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>request the other party to furnish further particulars on any matter relevant to the appeal; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142371_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>request the other party to make available to him for inspection any document which he considers relevant to the appeal and which is in the custody, control or possession of that party or to furnish a copy of any such document.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142371_027" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A request under subsection (1) may only be made—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411142371_035" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by the Building Authority, within 14 days beginning on the date a copy of the statement is served on him under <ref>section 4(2)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142371_043" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by the appellant, within 14 days beginning on the date a copy of the representations is served on him under <ref>section 5(b)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>or, where appropriate, within the extended period.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142371_056" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A party of whom a request is made under this section shall, within 14 days beginning on the date the relevant notice is served or within the extended period, as may be appropriate, comply with such request unless the Tribunal is satisfied that the request was unreasonable or that reasonable grounds exist for not complying with it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142386_005" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A party who furnishes any particulars or a copy of a document under subsection (3) shall, within the period referred to in that subsection or within the extended period, as may be appropriate, furnish a copy of the particulars or a copy of such document or, where appropriate, both, to the Secretary.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402651778_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Notification of hearing</heading><content>Not less than 21 days before the date fixed for a hearing the Secretary shall notify each party, in writing, of the date and time fixed for the hearing and the place at which it will take place.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402651778_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Issue of witness summons</heading><content>The Tribunal may, on application made in that regard by a party to an appeal, issue a summons signed by the Chairman, requiring a person to appear before the Tribunal at a hearing and give evidence or produce any document in his custody, control or possession.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402651794_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Hearing to be in public</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411142433_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsections (2) and (3), the hearing of an appeal shall be in public.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142433_019" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Tribunal may, by order, direct that a hearing or part of a hearing is to be held in private, if after consulting the parties to the appeal it is satisfied that it is desirable to do so, and give directions as to the persons who may be present.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142433_027" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the Tribunal makes an order under subsection (2), it may give directions prohibiting the publication or disclosure to some or all of the parties to the appeal, or to some or all of the persons referred to in subsection (2), of evidence given before the Tribunal or any matter contained in a document lodged with or received in evidence by the Tribunal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142449_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In exercising its powers under subsections (2) and (3), the Tribunal shall, in addition to any other matter it may take into account, take into account any views or the private interests of and any claim as to privilege by any party to the appeal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142449_013" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any claim as to privilege arising at a hearing shall be treated as a question of law.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402651809_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Withdrawal of appeal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411142480_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The appellant may withdraw his appeal or abandon any part of it by giving notice in writing to the Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142480_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An appellant who gives a notice under subsection (1) shall serve a copy thereof on the Building Authority as soon as practicable after giving it.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402651809_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Consequences of failure by appellant to furnish statements, particulars, etc.</heading><leadIn>Where the Tribunal is satisfied that the appellant has failed to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411142495_012" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>serve a copy of the notice of appeal on the Building Authority under <ref>section 3(3)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142495_020" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>furnish a statement under <ref>section 4(1)</ref> or serve a copy of it under <ref>section 4(2)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142495_028" name="c" temporalId="s11_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>comply with a request made under <ref>section 6(2)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>it may dismiss the appeal.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438402651825_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Record of hearing and publication of decision</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411142527_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>At any hearing the Chairman shall record or cause to be recorded the grounds of appeal, the name of the appellant, the names of all the witnesses who have been summoned or have appeared at the hearing, the evidence given and the decision of the Tribunal and the reasons for it and any order for costs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142542_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The decision of the Tribunal at the conclusion of a hearing, reasons for the decision and any order for costs shall be signed by the Chairman and the other members of the Tribunal and a copy of each of those shall be served on both the appellant and the Building Authority. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142542_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Tribunal may publish, in a manner it thinks fit, any decision referred to in subsection (2), including a decision made at the conclusion of a hearing the whole or any part of which was held in private under <ref>section 9(2)</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402651825_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Extension of time limits</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411142558_027" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Tribunal may upon application by a party extend, as regards the case to which the application relates, any time limit specified in <ref>section 4(1)</ref>, <ref>5(a)</ref> or <ref>6(2)</ref> or (3), if it considers it appropriate to do so.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411142573_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The power of the Tribunal under subsection (1) may be exercised by the Chairman.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402651856_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Service of notices, etc.</heading><leadIn>Subject to <ref>section 3(2)</ref>, for the purposes of this Regulation, the service of any notice, statement, order, summons, particulars in writing or other document shall be effected, in the case of service—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411142589_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on the Tribunal or the Secretary, by serving it or them personally on the Secretary or by sending by registered post addressed to him at his office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142589_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on the Building Authority, by serving it or them personally or by sending by registered post addressed to the Building Authority at his office; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411142589_028" name="c" temporalId="s14_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>on an appellant or any other person—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411142589_036" name="i" temporalId="s14_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>who is an individual, by serving it or them personally or by sending by registered post addressed to him at his last known place of residence; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411142589_044" name="ii" temporalId="s14_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>who is not an individual, by sending it or them by registered post to its registered address or last known place of business.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section></main></subLeg>