<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 178</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>178</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap178!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-06-20</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402801679_004" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-06-20">
            <content>To make provision with regard to customary marriages, concubinage, modern
                marriages and the dissolution of marriages, and for connected purposes.
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[10 July 1970]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438402801694_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438402801710_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Marriage Reform Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402801710_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AppointedDay"><term>appointed
                day</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指定日期</term>) means 7 October 1971;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1999/34">34 of 1999
                    s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ChineseLawAndCustom"><term>Chinese
                law and
            custom</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">中國法律與習俗</term>) means such of the laws and customs of
            China as would immediately prior to 5 April 1843 have been applicable to Chinese
            inhabitants of Hong Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/34">34 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="CustomaryMarriage"><term>customary
                marriage</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">舊式婚姻</term>) means a marriage celebrated in Hong Kong
            in accordance with <ref>section 7</ref>; </def><def name="DesignatedPublicOfficer"><term>designated
                public
            officer</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明公職人員</term>) means a public officer designated for
            the purposes of Part V by the Chief Executive under <ref>section 22</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/34">34 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ModernMarriage"><term>modern
                marriage</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">新式婚姻</term>) means a marriage celebrated in Hong Kong
            before the appointed day by open ceremony as a
            modern marriage and in the presence of 2 or more witnesses; </def><def name="PartiesToACustomaryMarriage,PartyToACustomaryMarriage"><term>parties
                to a customary
            marriage</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">舊式婚姻的雙方</term>) means the husband and the principal
            wife (tsai) whether such wife is a kit fat or a tin fong wife; and, for the avoidance of
            doubt,
                <term>party
                to a customary
            marriage</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">舊式婚姻的一方</term>) does not include a concubine (tsip); </def><def name="Registrar"><term>Registrar</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">登記官</term>) means the Registrar of Marriages, and any
            deputy registrar of marriages, appointed under <ref>section 3</ref> of the Marriage
            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap181">Cap. 181</ref>); </def><def name="ValidatedMarriage"><term>validated
                marriage</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">認可婚姻</term>) means a modern marriage made valid by
                <ref>section 8</ref>.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402801726_002" name="s3" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="repealed" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/34">34 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402801726_004" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Marriages
            on and after Appointed Day</heading><section id="ID_1438402801741_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Marriages on and after appointed day to be monogamous</heading><content>Marriages entered into in Hong Kong on or after the appointed day shall imply the voluntary union for life of one man with one woman to the exclusion of all others and may be contracted only in accordance with the Marriage Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap181">Cap. 181</ref>). </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1979/62">62 of 1979 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402801741_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Status of concubinage not to be acquired on and after appointed day</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477319_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On or after the appointed day, no man may take a concubine and no woman may acquire the status of a concubine. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477319_026" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subsection (1) shall not affect in any way—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477319_034" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the status or rights of a concubine lawfully taken before the appointed day; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477319_042" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the status or rights of a child, whether born before, on or after the appointed day, of a concubine lawfully taken before the appointed day.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402801772_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Kim tiu (兼祧) marriages not to be entered into</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477334_034" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On or after the appointed day no person shall contract a kim tiu (兼祧) marriage. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477334_042" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subsection (1) shall not affect in any way—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477334_050" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the status or rights of a party to a kim tiu (兼祧)<inline class="width_3"> </inline>marriage lawfully contracted before the appointed day; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477334_058" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the status or rights of a child, whether born before, on or after the appointed day, of parties to a kim tiu (兼祧) marriage contracted before the appointed day.</content></paragraph></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438402801772_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Customary
            and Modern Marriages</heading><section id="ID_1438402801788_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Customary marriage</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477366_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, a marriage shall constitute a customary marriage if it was or is celebrated in Hong Kong before the appointed day in accordance with Chinese law and custom. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477366_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A marriage shall be deemed to accord with Chinese law and custom if it was celebrated or is celebrated before the appointed day in Hong Kong in accordance with the traditional Chinese customs accepted at the time of the marriage as appropriate for the celebration of marriage either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477366_020" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the part of Hong Kong where the marriage took place; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477366_028" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the place recognized by the family of either party to the marriage as their family place of origin. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477381_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A customary marriage of persons who are subject to Chinese law and custom is hereby declared to be a valid marriage.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402801804_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Validation of modern marriage</heading><leadIn>Subject to <ref>section 14</ref>, every marriage celebrated in Hong Kong before the
            appointed day as a modern marriage by a man and a woman each of whom, at the time of the
            marriage, was not less than 16 years of age and was not married to any other person
            shall be a valid marriage, and shall be deemed to have been valid since the time of
            celebration,
            notwithstanding—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477397_012" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the proper personal law and religion of the parties, or one of them, was Chinese law and custom, and the marriage was prohibited by or failed to comply with the requirements of Chinese law and custom; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477397_020" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the marriage was not under and in accordance with the Marriage Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap181">Cap. 181</ref>).</content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438402801804_003" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Post-Registration
            of Customary Marriages and Validated Marriages</heading><section id="ID_1438402801819_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Registration of customary marriages and validated marriages</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477428_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar shall maintain separate registers for the registration of customary marriages and validated marriages. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477428_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The parties to a customary marriage or a validated marriage celebrated in Hong Kong before the appointed day may apply to the Registrar in the prescribed manner at any time for the registration of their marriage. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477428_020" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The District Court shall have jurisdiction to hear and determine an application by a person claiming to be a party to a customary marriage or a validated marriage for a declaration that a customary marriage or validated marriage, as the case may be, subsists between that person and the other party to such marriage where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477428_028" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the other party disputes the existence of the marriage; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477428_036" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the other party is unwilling to join in the application for the registration of the marriage under this section; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477428_044" name="c" temporalId="s9_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the whereabouts of the other party cannot after careful and reasonable inquiry be ascertained or it is for any other reason impracticable for such other party to be apprised of the application for the registration of the marriage under this section.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1979/62">62 of 1979 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote> </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477444_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>One party to a customary marriage or a validated marriage celebrated in Hong Kong before the appointed day may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477444_013" name="a" temporalId="s9_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with the consent in writing of the other party to the marriage; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477444_021" name="b" temporalId="s9_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the District Court has under subsection (3) declared the marriage to subsist, </content></paragraph><continued>apply to the Registrar in the prescribed manner at any time for the registration of the marriage. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477444_034" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Where the Registrar is satisfied that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477444_042" name="a" temporalId="s9_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the particulars contained in any application under this section are true; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477444_050" name="b" temporalId="s9_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a form of marriage did take place between the parties named at the time and place and before the witnesses specified in the application; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477444_058" name="c" temporalId="s9_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the marriage constitutes either a valid customary marriage or a validated marriage, </content></paragraph><continued>he shall prepare a certificate of marriage in the prescribed form and the Registrar, and the applicants, or applicant as the case may be, and 2 witnesses to the marriage, shall thereupon sign duplicate certificates; but a certificate shall not be invalidated by the absence of signature by one or both witnesses if the Registrar is satisfied that one or both is or are not available, and cannot reasonably be made available, to sign and he records that he is so satisfied on the certificate. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477459_004" name="6" temporalId="s9_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>When a certificate is signed in accordance with subsection (5), the Registrar shall deliver one certificate to the applicants or applicant and the other certificate shall form part of the register which the Registrar is required to maintain under subsection (1). </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477459_012" name="7" temporalId="s9_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where, on an application to the Registrar under this section, the Registrar is not satisfied with respect to the matters specified in subsection <ref>(5)(a)</ref>, (b) and (c), a party to the marriage may apply to the District Court for a declaration that a customary marriage or a validated marriage, as the case may be, subsists between the parties, and the District Court shall have jurisdiction to hear and determine any such application.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402801819_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Power of Registrar</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477522_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Upon receipt of an application under <ref>section 9</ref> for the registration of a customary marriage or a validated marriage, the Registrar may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477522_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>summon before him any applicant, any alleged party to the marriage and any person alleged to have been present at the marriage, and may require any person so summoned to answer such questions as the Registrar may ask for the purpose of determining the application before him; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477537_006" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>require any applicant to furnish such further information either by statutory declaration or otherwise as he may reasonably require. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477537_013" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who, without lawful excuse, fails to comply with a summons or requirement issued or made under subsection (1) shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable to a fine at level 1 and to imprisonment for 6 months.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1996/ln25">L.N. 25 of 1996</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402801835_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Effect of certificate of marriage registered under this Part</heading><content>A certificate of marriage registered under this Part, or a copy of such a certificate, shall if it purports to be signed and certified as a true copy by the Registrar and to be sealed or stamped with his official seal be admissible as evidence of the marriage to which it relates in any court and before any person having by law or by consent of parties authority to hear, receive, and examine evidence.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402801850_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Correction of error in certificate of marriage</heading><content>The Registrar may correct any clerical error in any certificate of marriage registered under this Part on production to him of the certificate delivered to the parties, and shall authenticate every such correction by his signature, or by marking the same with his initials, and the date of making the correction.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402801850_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Searches may be made and certified copies granted</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477584_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar may allow searches to be made amongst all certificates, registers
                and indices in his possession for the purposes of this Part and may give a certified
                copy of any entry therein, and issue a certificate that there is no record of any
                marriage of the person named having been registered under this Part.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/5">5 of 1999
                        s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477584_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A certificate issued or purporting to be issued under this section before the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of the Marriage
                (Certificate of Absence of Marriage Record) Ordinance 1999 (<ref href="/hk/1999/5">5
                    of 1999</ref>) shall be deemed to have been issued as if that Ordinance had been
                in force at the time of its issue.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1999/5">5 of 1999 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1556179738906_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 5 February
                1999.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402801866_001" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Dissolution
            of Validated Marriages and Customary Marriages</heading><section id="ID_1438402801866_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Dissolution of validated marriages</heading><content>The dissolution, at any time before the appointed day, of a validated marriage by the mutual consent of the parties to the marriage signified by the signature of each of the parties in the presence of 2 other persons who have also signed as attesting witnesses, to an agreement or memorandum in writing which sets forth unequivocally the final and complete dissolution of the marriage shall be valid for all purposes and shall be deemed to have been so valid since the execution of the agreement or memorandum.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402801882_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Dissolution of certain marriages on and after the appointed day</heading><leadIn>A customary marriage or a validated marriage subsisting on the appointed day and registered
            in accordance with Part IV may where at least one party to the marriage has a
            substantial
            connexion
            with Hong Kong be dissolved on or after the day upon which such marriage has been so
            registered—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477631_019" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in accordance with the Matrimonial Causes Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap179">Cap. 179</ref>); or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477631_027" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in accordance with this Part. </content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1979/62">62 of 1979 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402801882_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Notice of intention to dissolve marriage</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477646_033" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The parties to a marriage, of a kind which may be dissolved under this Part, may give notice of their intention to dissolve the marriage in the prescribed form to a designated public officer, signed by both parties to the marriage and published or otherwise given in such manner as may be prescribed. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477646_041" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who has given notice in accordance with subsection (1) may, by publication or otherwise as may be prescribed, cancel such notice.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402801897_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Parties may appear before designated public officer</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477709_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Not less than one month after the giving of notice under <ref>section
                    16(1)</ref>, the parties to the marriage may, if neither of them has cancelled
                the notice under <ref>section 16(2)</ref>, appear personally before the designated
                public officer to whom notice was given for the purpose of satisfying him that each
                of them wishes voluntarily and freely to dissolve his or her marriage to the other.
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477724_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If a designated public officer is satisfied that the parties appearing before him—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477724_013" name="a" temporalId="s17_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>have given notice of intention to dissolve their marriage under subsection (1) of <ref>section 16</ref> and notice of changed intention under subsection (2) of that section has not been given; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477740_006" name="b" temporalId="s17_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>understand that the effect of dissolution is to put an end to the marriage so as to permit the parties to marry again should either of them so wish; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477740_014" name="c" temporalId="s17_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>freely and voluntarily desire to dissolve the marriage, </content></paragraph><continued>he shall sign the prescribed form in duplicate and deliver one copy to each of the parties.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402801897_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Functions of designated public officer</heading><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 17</ref>, a designated public officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477771_012" name="a" temporalId="s18_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall interview each of the parties to a marriage appearing before him in the presence of each other and also in the absence of each other, and no other person, except an interpreter (should one be necessary), shall be present at any such interview; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477771_020" name="b" temporalId="s18_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may require the parties or either of them to appear before him again on some specified occasion or occasions; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477771_028" name="c" temporalId="s18_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>may require the parties or either of them to furnish such further information as he may reasonably require.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402801913_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Memorandum of dissolution of marriage</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477787_034" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The parties to a marriage may, within one month of the delivery to them under
                    <ref>section 17</ref> of the prescribed forms by a designated public officer,
                sign, in Hong Kong in the presence of each other and in the presence of 2 other
                adult persons who shall also sign as attesting witnesses, an agreement or memorandum
                in writing for the dissolution of the marriage unequivocally with effect from
                registration under <ref>section
                20</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477802_005" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An agreement or memorandum for the dissolution of a marriage, signed and witnessed in the manner required by subsection (1), shall have the effect, as from registration under <ref>section 20</ref> of dissolving the marriage.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402801944_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Registration of memorandum for dissolution of marriage</heading><content>The parties to an agreement or memorandum for the dissolution of a marriage signed under and in accordance with <ref>section 19</ref> shall, within 14 days from the date of signature or such longer period as the designated public officer before whom the parties appeared under <ref>section 17</ref> may for special reasons in any particular case permit, register, either personally or through their duly authorized agent, particulars of the agreement or memorandum for dissolution of marriage with the designated public officer before whom the parties appeared under <ref>section 17</ref>; and that officer shall endorse on the agreement or memorandum a record of registration under this section.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402801960_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Register of dissolutions of marriage</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477834_011" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director of Home Affairs shall maintain a register for the registration of dissolutions of marriage effected under <ref>section 19</ref>. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477834_019" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A designated public officer with whom a dissolution of marriage is registered under <ref>section 20</ref> shall send to the Director of Home Affairs once in each month, or more often if so directed by the Director of Home Affairs, particulars of all such dissolutions registered by him and the Director of Home Affairs shall cause such particulars to be entered in the register and preserved for record at his office. </content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/ln67">L.N. 67 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln262">L.N. 262 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln621">L.N. 621 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402801960_003" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Chief Executive may designate public officers</heading><text>The Chief Executive by notice in the Gazette may designate public officers for the
            purposes of this Part.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/34">34 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402801975_002" name="P5A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="P5A"><num value="5A">Part
            VA</num><heading>Validation
            of Dissolution in Hong Kong of Certain Marriages Celebrated in
            China</heading><section id="ID_1438402801975_004" name="s22A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s22A"><num value="22A">22A.</num><heading>Validation of dissolution of certain Chinese marriages</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411477880_011" name="1" temporalId="s22A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to a marriage celebrated in China after 4 May 1931 but before 1 May 1950 under and in accordance with the law of China in force when the marriage was celebrated. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477896_005" name="2" temporalId="s22A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The purported dissolution in Hong Kong, at any time before 7 October 1971, of a marriage to which this section applies by the mutual consent of the parties to the marriage signified by the signature of each of the parties, in the presence of 2 other persons who have also signed as attesting witnesses, to an agreement or memorandum in writing which sets forth unequivocally the final and complete dissolution of the marriage shall be valid for all purposes and shall be deemed to have been so valid since the execution of the agreement or memorandum, if at the date of the agreement or memorandum—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477896_013" name="a" temporalId="s22A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>both parties were domiciled in Hong Kong; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477896_021" name="b" temporalId="s22A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>either of the parties had a substantial
                    connexion
                    with Hong Kong. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411477896_028" name="3" temporalId="s22A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A child of both parties to a marriage to which this section applies shall, whether born before or after the date of the agreement or memorandum referred to in subsection (2), be deemed to have been born legitimate for all purposes. </content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/70">70 of 1971 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402801991_002" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            VI</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438402802006_001" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Penalty for removing, etc. records</heading><content>Any person who wilfully removes, defaces, alters or destroys any notice, certificate, index, or other document kept or filed by the Director of Home Affairs or the Registrar pursuant to or for the purposes of this Ordinance shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable to a fine at level 1 and to imprisonment for 6 months. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/ln67">L.N. 67 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln262">L.N. 262 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln621">L.N. 621 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1996/ln25">L.N. 25 of 1996</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402802006_003" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Power to make regulations</heading><leadIn>The Chief Executive may make regulations for the better carrying out of the purposes
            and provisions of this Ordinance and in particular may make
                regulations—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/34">34 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411477943_033" name="a" temporalId="s24_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>as to all matters of procedure under this Ordinance; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411477943_041" name="b" temporalId="s24_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>prescribing the forms to be used under this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></section></part></main></ordinance>