<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 104 sub. leg. E</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>104E</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap104E!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-06-30</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402541314_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-06-30">“Star”
                                    Ferry
                                    Company,
                                    Limited,
                                    By-laws</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap104/s45">Cap.
                                                104, section 45(1)</ref>)
                                    <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[13 July 1984]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of
                                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402541314_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These by-laws may be cited as the “Star” Ferry Company, Limited, By-laws.
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541345_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these by-laws, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Company"><term>Company</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公司</term>) means the “Star” Ferry Company, Limited; </def><def name="RushHours"><term>rush
                hours</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">繁忙時間</term>) means
            8 a.m. to
            9 a.m.
            from Monday to Saturday; and
            5 p.m. to
            6.30 p.m. from Monday to Friday.
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section><section id="ID_1438402541361_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Conduct of public</heading><subsection id="ID_1547000464942_001" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject
                to paragraph (2), no person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410817625_033" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>trespass on any part of the Company’s piers, premises or vessels;
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817625_041" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>alight from or enter any of the Company’s vessels in motion except by the
                    proper entrances or exits, and no person shall sit or climb on ship rails or
                    bulwarks or climb over or under any barrier or gate erected on any of the
                    Company’s piers; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817640_006" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>embark on or disembark from any of the Company’s vessels from or to any
                    sampan, boat or other craft; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817640_014" name="d" temporalId="s3_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>embark on or travel by any of the Company’s vessels without having first
                    paid the appropriate fare; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817640_022" name="e" temporalId="s3_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>embark on or travel in any of the Company’s vessels in use after being
                    informed by any servant of the Company that such vessel already contains the
                    full complement of passengers; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817640_030" name="f" temporalId="s3_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>travel on any of the Company’s vessels in a class higher than that for
                    which he has paid the fare; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817640_038" name="g" temporalId="s3_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>remain on board any of the Company’s vessels upon completion of any
                    journey. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1547000464942_002" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subparagraphs
                (b), (c), (d), (e), (f) and (g) of paragraph (1) shall not apply to a servant of the
                Company while acting in the course of his duty.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541377_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Conduct of persons</heading><subsection id="ID_1547005614284_001" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>
                Subject to paragraph (2), no person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410817672_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>smoke or carry a lighted pipe, cigar or cigarette in or upon any part of
                    the Company’s vessels or premises which is clearly designated as a “no smoking”
                    area or is otherwise sign-posted as prohibited for smoking; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817672_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>except in case of emergency pass from one deck to another or open any grill
                    or door on any of the Company’s vessels for the purpose of so passing;
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817672_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>enter any part of the Company’s vessels or premises which is marked with an
                    indication that admission is prohibited or restricted; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817672_036" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>play or perform upon any musical instrument, or use in the hearing of
                    another person any radios and cassette players or television set or
                    tape-recorder or swear or use obscene or offensive language or sing any indecent
                    or obscene songs, while in or upon any of the Company’s vessels or any of the
                    Company’s premises, or commit any nuisance in or on any of the Company’s vessels
                    or premises; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817687_006" name="e" temporalId="s4_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>obstruct the approaches to the gangways of any of the Company’s vessels or
                    impede or hamper in any way the movements of such gangways; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817687_014" name="f" temporalId="s4_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>wilfully interfere with or obstruct or distract any servant of the Company
                    from carrying out his duties; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817687_022" name="g" temporalId="s4_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>wilfully give any sound or signal which may reasonably be interpreted by
                    any servant of the Company as an official order or instruction; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817687_030" name="h" temporalId="s4_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>throw or deposit without lawful authority or excuse any litter into the
                    waters of Hong Kong or in any place from which it is likely that the litter will
                    be swept by the tide into the waters of Hong Kong from any of the Company’s
                    vessels or any of the Company’s premises; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817703_006" name="i" temporalId="s4_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>spit in, on or from any of the Company’s piers, premises or vessels;
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817703_014" name="j" temporalId="s4_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>stand or place his feet on any seat on any of the Company’s vessels or
                    piers; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817703_022" name="k" temporalId="s4_1_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>drop any lighted cigarettes or rubbish on to any of the Company’s vessels
                    or piers otherwise than in a receptacle provided for that purpose; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817703_030" name="l" temporalId="s4_1_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>throw any lifebuoy or any equipment of the Company on or from any of the
                    Company’s vessels or piers except in case of emergency. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1547005614284_002" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subparagraphs
                (b) and (c) of paragraph (1) shall not apply to a servant of the Company while
                acting in the course of his duty.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541392_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Luggage</heading><leadIn>No person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410817750_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>take on to any of the Company’s vessels as personal luggage anything other than small handbaskets, bags or parcels all of which shall not exceed either 12 kilograms in weight or 0.028 cubic metre in measurement, except that passengers may take with them on to the Company’s vessels a reasonable quantity of hand baggage at any time except during rush hours. All such personal luggage and hand baggage shall be carried by hand and the Company shall not be responsible for its safe custody or for any damage sustained by it. Such personal luggage and hand baggage shall not occupy any part of the seats nor be of a form or description to annoy, or inconvenience, or be a danger to, other persons; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817781_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>take on to any of the Company’s premises or any of the Company’s vessels any livestock, salt fish, vegetables or poultry (whether dead or alive) in open parcels; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817781_014" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>take on to any of the Company’s premises or any of the Company’s vessels any
                type of cargo whatsoever other than personal luggage and hand baggage as described
                in
                subparagraph
                (a);
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817781_022" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>take on to any of the Company’s premises or any of the Company’s vessels any
                dangerous goods other than provided for in <ref>by-law
                13</ref>.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402541392_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Monthly and season tickets and in case where no ticket is issued</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410817796_042" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every monthly or season ticket shall bear in legible form the name of the holder thereof. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817812_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall use any monthly or season ticket which is not issued in his own name or upon the face of which his own name does not appear and no monthly or season ticket holder shall sell or transfer a monthly or season ticket of which he is the holder to any other person. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817812_013" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The holder of a monthly or season ticket shall produce it for inspection by any servant of the Company whenever the holder is entering upon any of the Company’s piers or travelling on any of the Company’s vessels or being on any of the Company’s piers. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817812_021" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where no ticket is issued in exchange for
                                                  payment of a fare for embarking on to any of the
                                                  Company’s vessels, each passenger shall pass
                                                  through any of the Company’s appropriate
                                                  turnstiles or other authorized entry points on the
                                                  Company’s piers before embarking on to any of the
                                                  Company’s vessels.
                                                  </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541423_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Forfeiture and cancellation of monthly or season tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410817843_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the event of any monthly or season ticket holder committing a breach of
                these by-laws in
                connexion
                with such monthly or season ticket any servant of the Company shall be entitled, if
                he is satisfied that an offence has been committed, to retain such ticket.
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817843_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the Company is satisfied that an offence has been committed against these
                by-laws, the Company shall be entitled to forfeit such monthly or season ticket and
                shall not be under any liability to make any refund in respect
                thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541423_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Defaced, altered or mutilated
            tickets,
            and replacement of damaged tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410817859_019" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the event of any monthly or season ticket being defaced, altered or
                mutilated it shall be deemed as invalid and in the case of any person using such
                ticket the Company shall be entitled to charge the appropriate fare, or difference,
                or refuse admission on to the Company’s premises and the Company’s vessels.
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817874_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Company may at its discretion, if it is satisfied that a monthly or season
                ticket has been damaged otherwise than by reason of the fault or negligence of the
                holder, replace the damaged ticket without additional
                charge.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541439_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Dress</heading><content>No person whose dress or clothing may in the opinion of any servant of the Company soil or
            damage the seats or fittings of any of the Company’s vessels or of the Company’s piers
            or the dress or clothing of any other passenger, and no person who in the opinion of any
            servant of the Company may for any other appropriate reason be offensive to passengers
            shall enter upon any of the Company’s piers or travel in any of the Company’s vessels,
            and it shall be lawful for any servant of the Company to prevent any such person from so
            doing by giving any of the aforesaid reasons
            therefor.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541455_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Animals or birds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410817906_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall take an animal or bird in any of the Company’s vessels or on to any of the Company’s premises except after first having obtained the permission of any servant of the Company on duty. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817906_019" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any animal or bird taken in any vessel of the Company or on to any of the
                Company’s premises shall be suitably restrained or caged and shall be removed by the
                person in charge of such animal or bird from the Company’s vessel or the Company’s
                premises immediately on request by a servant of the Company, and in default of
                compliance with such request, may be removed by or under the direction of a servant
                of the
                Company.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541470_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Intoxication</heading><content>No person who in the opinion of any servant of the Company is in such a state of
            intoxication, or under the influence of drugs or both, as to render him unfit to travel
            on the Company’s vessels shall enter upon any pier or vessel belonging to the Company
            and it shall be lawful for any servant of the Company to refuse to allow any such person
            access to any of the Company’s piers or vessels by giving any of the aforesaid reasons
            therefor.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541470_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Damage</heading><content>No person shall wilfully damage or deface any of the Company’s
            property.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541486_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Firearms</heading><content>No person other than a member of the Chinese People’s Liberation Army or a police or revenue officer on duty shall enter any of the Company’s piers or travel on any of the Company’s vessels with firearms. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541517_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Collections or gratuities</heading><content>No person shall take any part in unauthorized soliciting of contributions or collection of
            money, or distribute any handbills or advertising matter, upon any of the Company’s
            premises or vessels, or except as authorized by the
            Company.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541517_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Betting and gambling</heading><content>No person shall bet or gamble at any time upon any of
                                    the
                                    Company’s premises or
                                    vessels.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541533_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Obedience to lawful instructions</heading><content>All passengers shall at all times obey all reasonable and lawful instructions of a servant
            of the Company acting in the course of his
            duties.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541548_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Interference with mechanism or equipment</heading><content>No person shall interfere with any mechanism or equipment on the Company’s premises or
            vessels in any way, or do anything liable to cause damage to such mechanism, equipment,
            premises or vessels, or to delay the Company’s operations, or to cause injury or
            discomfort to any
            person.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541564_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Name and address</heading><content>If any servant of the Company has reason to believe that any person has committed or is
            committing a breach of these by-laws, he shall be entitled to ask such person for his
            name and address, and any such person shall then forthwith furnish to the servant of the
            Company his true name and his true
            address.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541579_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Lost property</heading><content>Property found on any of the Company’s vessels or premises and not immediately claimed by the true owner thereof shall be handed over to the servant of the Company, who shall pass the same to the Company’s officers for safe custody until it is claimed by the true owner thereof.<inline class="width_3"> </inline></content></section><section id="ID_1438402541579_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading><ref>Sections 38</ref>, <ref>39</ref> and <ref>40</ref> of Ferry Services Ordinance</heading><content>Notwithstanding any provisions herein contained to the contrary, the Director of Civil Engineering and Development, the Director of Marine and the Commissioner for Transport and any person so authorized by any one of them may at all reasonable times have access to and may enter upon any of the Company’s piers, premises or vessels in accordance with <ref>sections 38</ref>, <ref>39</ref> and <ref>40</ref> of the Ferry Services Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap104">Cap. 104</ref>). </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1986</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1991/ln364">L.N. 364
                of 1991</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2004/ln104">L.N. 104 of
            2004</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541611_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Penalties</heading><content>Any person who contravenes any of these by-laws commits an offence and is liable on
            conviction to a fine
            at level
            1. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>