<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 59 sub. leg. AC</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>59AC</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap59AC!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-04-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403502600_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-06-20">Factories
            and
            Industrial
            Undertakings
            (Suspended
            Working
            Platforms)
            Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap59/s7">Cap. 59, section
            7</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of
            2019</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 July 1995]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403502600_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of
            2019</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403502616_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>This Regulation applies to an industrial undertaking in which any suspended working platform for carrying persons is used.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403502616_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647227_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Climber"><term>climber</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">爬升器</term>) means a lifting appliance through which
                a suspension rope passes which is controlled either by friction grips or by turns of
                the rope round drums within the appliance and the lower end of which rope is not
                anchored to the climber;</def><def name="CompetentExaminer"><leadIn><term>competent
                    examiner</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合資格檢驗員</term>), in relation to the carrying out
                    of any thorough examination or load test and thorough examination required by
                    this Regulation, means a person who is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647227_026" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>appointed by the owner required by this Regulation to ensure that such thorough examination or load test and thorough examination is carried out;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647243_006" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a registered professional engineer registered under the Engineers Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap409">Cap. 409</ref>) within a relevant discipline specified by the Commissioner; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647243_014" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by virtue of his previous experience, competent to carry out such thorough examination or load test and thorough examination;</content></paragraph></def><def name="CompetentPerson"><leadIn><term>competent
                    person</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合資格的人</term>), in relation to any duty to be
                    performed by such a person under this Regulation, means a person who
                    is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647243_028" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>appointed by the owner to ensure that the duty is carried out; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647243_036" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by reason of substantial training and practical experience, competent to perform the duty;</content></paragraph></def><def name="ConstructionSite"><term>construction
                site</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築地盤</term>) means a place where construction work
                is undertaken and also any area in the immediate vicinity of any such place which is
                used for the storage of materials or plant used or intended to be used for the
                purpose of the construction work;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 102</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="LiftingAppliance"><term>lifting
                appliance</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">起重機械</term>) includes a winch, climber, chain
                block, hoisting block, pulley block or gin wheel used for raising or lowering, or as
                a means of suspension of, a suspended working platform;</def><def name="LiftingGear">
                <term>lifting
                gear</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">起重裝置</term>) includes a chain sling, wire rope
                sling or similar gear and a ring, link, hook, shackle, swivel or eyebolt;</def><def name="Maintain"><term>maintain</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">維修</term>) means maintain in safe working order and
                in good repair;</def><def name="Owner"><term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>), in relation to any suspended working
                platform, includes the lessee or hirer thereof, and any overseer, foreman, agent or
                person in charge or having the control or management of the suspended working
                platform, and the contractor who has control over the way any construction work
                which involves the use of the suspended working platform is carried out and, in the
                case of a construction site, includes the contractor responsible for the
                construction site;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/ln261">L.N. 261 of 2003</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Repair"><term>repair</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">修理</term>) includes renewal, alteration or
                addition;</def><def name="SafeWorkingLoad"><term>safe working
                load</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">安全操作負荷</term>), in relation to a suspended working
                platform, means the safe working load for operating it as specified in the current
                certificate of thorough examination or load test and thorough examination given by a
                competent examiner;</def><def name="SlungScaffold"><term>slung
                scaffold</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">吊索式棚架</term>) means a scaffold suspended by means
                of lifting gear, ropes or chains or rigid members and not provided with means of
                raising or lowering by a lifting appliance or similar device;</def><def name="SuspendedWorkingPlatform"><term>suspended working
                platform</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">吊船</term>) means a scaffold (not being a slung
                scaffold) or a working platform suspended from a building or structure by means of
                lifting gear and capable of being raised or lowered by lifting appliances (but does
                not include a boatswain’s chair or similar device), and includes all lifting
                appliances, lifting gear, counterweights, ballast, outriggers, other supports and
                the whole of the mechanical and electrical apparatus required in connection with the
                operation and safety of such a scaffold or working platform.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647289_004" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purpose of this Regulation, a contractor is responsible for a construction site if he is undertaking construction work there or, where there is more than one contractor undertaking construction work at the site, if he is the principal contractor undertaking construction work there.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502632_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Construction and maintenance</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless it is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647352_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of good design and construction;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647352_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>of adequate strength for the purpose for which it is used;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647352_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>made of sound material and free from patent defect;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647352_036" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>properly installed or assembled; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647352_044" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>properly maintained.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502632_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Anchorage and support</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647383_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647383_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the arrangement for fixing and anchoring it are adequate to secure its safety;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647383_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it is adequately and securely supported;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647383_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>every structure supporting it is of good construction and adequate strength, of sound materials and free from patent defect.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647383_035" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where outriggers are used, the owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless the outriggers are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647383_043" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of adequate length and strength and properly installed and supported;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647383_051" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>firmly anchored at the inner ends; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647383_059" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>securely fastened to any ballast or counterweights.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502632_005" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Suspension</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647414_043" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the points of suspension are at adequate horizontal distances from the face of the building or other structure so as to prevent the suspended working platform from coming into contact with such face;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647430_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>wire ropes or chains are used for the raising, lowering and suspension of the platform;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647430_014" name="c" temporalId="s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the wire ropes or chains are securely attached to the outriggers or other supports;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647430_022" name="d" temporalId="s6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the wire ropes or chains are of such length that the platform is capable of being lowered to the ground or a safe landing place; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647430_030" name="e" temporalId="s6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>adequate arrangements are made to prevent undue tipping, tilting or swinging of the platform and to secure it to prevent undue horizontal movement while it is being used.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502647_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Counterbalance and counterweights</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform which is counterbalanced by counterweights shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647461_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>water or other liquids, earth, clay, sand, chippings or aggregates are not used as counterweights;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647461_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>every portable counterweight has its weight permanently and distinctly stamped, engraved or embossed thereon;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647461_028" name="c" temporalId="s7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all counterweights are securely attached at the inner end of the outriggers to prevent tampering by any person; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647477_006" name="d" temporalId="s7_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the counterweights on any outriggers are not less than 3 times the weight necessary to balance the load on the projecting part of the outriggers when the platform is fully loaded.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502647_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Platforms</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless the platform is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647492_036" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at least 440 millimetres wide and of sufficient length to allow the number of persons using it to do so safely;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647508_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>except to the extent necessary for drainage, either closely boarded, planked or plated;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647508_014" name="c" temporalId="s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>provided on all sides with toe boards placed at a height not less than 200 millimetres above its floor level; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647508_022" name="d" temporalId="s8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>provided on all sides with guard-rails of adequate strength, which guard-rails
                shall be so positioned that the top guard-rail is at a height between 900
                millimetres and
                1 150
                millimetres above the floor level and the lowest guard-rail is not more than 700
                millimetres above the top of the toe board.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502663_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Safe means of access</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless sufficient safe means of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647555_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>access and egress is provided to the platform of the suspended working platform; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647555_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>access is provided to those parts of the installation of the suspended working platform requiring periodic inspection or maintenance.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502663_004" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Drums and pulleys</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform that has a drum or pulley on which a rope is carried shall ensure that the suspended working platform is not used for carrying persons—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647586_005" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>unless the drum or pulley is designed and of sufficient diameter for the rope used; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647586_013" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>unless, where the rope terminates at the winding drum of the suspended working platform—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413647586_021" name="i" temporalId="s10_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the rope is properly secured to the drum; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413647586_029" name="ii" temporalId="s10_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the rope is long enough so that, at all times, at least 2 turns of the rope will remain on the drum.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502678_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Brakes</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless the winches, climbers or other lifting appliances or similar devices of the suspended working platform are, in the case of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647617_012" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>manually operated appliances or devices, provided with an efficient brake which comes into operation when the operating handle or lever is released; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647617_020" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>power operated appliances or devices, provided with 2 independent, efficient braking systems, each of which is capable of preventing the suspended working platform from falling out of control or in a dangerous manner.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502678_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Control levers, switches, etc.</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647648_012" name="a" temporalId="s12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>every lever, handle, switch or other device used for controlling its operation (being a lever, handle, switch or other device the accidental movement or displacement of which is liable to cause danger) is, unless it is so placed as to prevent accidental movement or displacement, provided with a suitable spring or other locking arrangement to prevent accidental movement or displacement; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647648_020" name="b" temporalId="s12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>every lever, handle, switch or other device for controlling its operation has either on or adjacent to it clear markings to indicate its purpose and mode of operation.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502678_005" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Protection of climbers against the effect of weather, etc.</heading><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless the winches, climbers or other lifting appliances or similar devices of the platform are adequately protected against the effect of weather, dust or material likely to cause damage to them that could result in a malfunction.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403502694_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Safety ropes and safety devices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647695_011" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), the owner of a suspended working platform that is raised or lowered by winches or climbers shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless it is provided, at each suspension point, with a safety rope having an automatic safety device mounted on it, such that, should the primary suspension rope, the winch, the climber or any part of the mechanism for raising or lowering the platform fail, the safety rope with the automatic safety device will support the platform.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1996/ln391">L.N. 391 of 1996</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647711_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subsection (1) does not apply if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647711_013" name="a" temporalId="s14_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the platform is supported on 2 independent suspension wire ropes at or near each end such that, in the event of the failure of one rope, the other rope is capable of sustaining the weight of the working platform and its load and preventing it from tilting; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647726_006" name="b" temporalId="s14_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a system is incorporated which operates automatically to support the platform and its load in the event of the failure of the primary suspension rope.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647726_013" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform provided with the safety rope and automatic safety device referred to in subsection (1) shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless the safety rope and automatic safety device are properly maintained and kept in good working order.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502694_004" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Safety belts, lifelines, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647757_020" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform used for carrying persons shall provide each person using it with a safety belt and an independent lifeline or an anchorage with fittings; and each such safety belt, lifeline, anchorage and fitting shall be properly maintained and shall be of such a design and so constructed as to prevent serious injury in the event of a fall to any person using it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647773_005" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless every person carried on it is wearing a safety belt that is attached to the safety equipment specified in subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647773_013" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for
                carrying persons unless a notice in English and Chinese in the following form is
                displayed prominently on the suspended working
                platform—</leadIn><text class="align_center ">“Every person riding on a suspended working platform
                shall<br></br>wear a safety belt properly attached to an independent<br></br>lifeline or an
                appropriate anchorage<br></br>吊船上的人員須佩戴安全帶；安全帶須繫於<br></br>獨立救生繩上或穩固的繫穩物上”.</text></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502710_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Erection, dismantling and alteration</heading><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not erected, dismantled or the structure as originally designed altered, except under the supervision of a competent person.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403502710_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Trained and competent workers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647835_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that every person working thereon shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647835_012" name="a" temporalId="s17_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>be at least 18 years old; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647835_020" name="b" temporalId="s17_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>have undergone training that is either recognized by the Commissioner or provided by the manufacturer of the suspended working platform or its local agent, on—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413647835_028" name="i" temporalId="s17_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>general construction of the suspended working platform; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413647835_036" name="ii" temporalId="s17_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>how to operate it safely,</content></subparagraph><continued>and have obtained a certificate in respect of such training from the person who provided the training.</continued></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647835_048" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection (1) does not apply where a person is undergoing training in working on a suspended working platform providing that he is doing so under the supervision of a person who meets the requirements specified in subsection (1).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502710_005" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Use in bad weather conditions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647882_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used under weather conditions likely to endanger its stability or cause danger to the persons carried thereon.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647882_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>After exposure to weather conditions likely to have affected the stability of the suspended working platform, the owner shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647882_020" name="a" temporalId="s18_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>cause the suspended working platform to be load tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner as soon as practicable thereafter and before the suspended working platform is again used; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647882_028" name="b" temporalId="s18_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the event of the anchorage, ballast, counterbalance or supports being found on examination to be unsafe, take such steps as will again ensure the stability of the suspended working platform.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502725_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Inspections by competent persons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647913_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647913_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it has been inspected in the immediately preceding 7 days before its use by a competent person; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647913_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he has obtained a certificate in the approved form in which the competent person has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647929_005" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In addition to the requirements in subsection (1), the owner shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647929_013" name="a" temporalId="s19_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all the suspension ropes and safety ropes have been inspected and found in safe working condition by a competent person prior to commencement of daily work; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647929_021" name="b" temporalId="s19_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>a notice in English and Chinese in the following form is prominently
                    displayed on the
                    platform—</leadIn><text class="align_center">“All wire ropes shall be inspected prior
                    to<br></br>commencement of daily work<br></br>每日開工前須檢查所有繩索”.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502725_004" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Test and examination prior to use</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413647960_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless it has been thoroughly examined by a competent examiner in the immediately preceding 6 months before its use and he has obtained a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647976_005" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless it has been load tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner during the immediately preceding 12 months before its use and he has obtained a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413647976_013" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the fact that an owner has complied with subsections (1) and (2), where a suspended working platform has subsequently undergone—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413647976_021" name="a" temporalId="s20_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>substantial repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647991_006" name="b" temporalId="s20_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>re-erection, including erection following its removal to a different location;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647991_014" name="c" temporalId="s20_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>adjustment to any member of the suspended working platform, being an adjustment which involves changes in the arrangements for anchoring or supporting the suspended working platform; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413647991_022" name="d" temporalId="s20_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>failure or collapse,</content></paragraph><continued>the owner of the suspended working platform shall ensure that it is not used for carrying persons unless it has been further load tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner and the owner has obtained from him another certificate in the approved form in which he has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502741_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Duties of competent examiner</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648023_019" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A competent examiner shall deliver the certificate or relevant report to the owner of a suspended working platform within 28 days after thoroughly examining it or load testing and thoroughly examining it, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648038_005" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Should the competent examiner discover that the suspended working platform cannot be used safely unless certain repairs are carried out, he shall immediately inform the owner and deliver a report to him, with a copy of that report to the Commissioner, within 14 days.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648038_013" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the competent examiner concludes that the suspended working platform is safe but will require repairs before the next certificate will be required, he shall note that fact on the certificate and shall send a copy of it to the Commissioner.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502741_004" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Marking of safe working load and number of persons allowed</heading><leadIn>The owner of a suspended working platform shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648069_012" name="a" temporalId="s22_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>clearly and legibly mark on the platform—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648069_020" name="i" temporalId="s22_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the safe working load applicable to the suspended working platform;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648069_028" name="ii" temporalId="s22_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the maximum number of persons that may be carried at any one time; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648069_036" name="iii" temporalId="s22_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>an appropriate mark to distinguish it from other similar suspended working platforms owned by him; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648085_006" name="b" temporalId="s22_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>ensure that it is not used to carry—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648085_014" name="i" temporalId="s22_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any load greater than the safe working load except that, for the purpose of carrying out a load test under <ref>section 20</ref>, the safe working load may be exceeded by such amount as a competent examiner carrying out the load test may authorize; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648085_022" name="ii" temporalId="s22_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a greater number of persons than the maximum number marked on the platform.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502756_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Construction of wire rope</heading><leadIn>Without prejudice to any other provision of this Regulation, the owner of a suspended working platform shall ensure that a wire rope is not used for raising or lowering, or as a means of suspension of, the suspended working platform or as its safety rope if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648116_012" name="a" temporalId="s23_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in any length of 10 diameters, the total number of visible broken wires exceeds 5% of the total number of wires in the rope;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648116_020" name="b" temporalId="s23_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>there is any kink or distortion in the rope; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648116_028" name="c" temporalId="s23_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>there is on the rope marked signs of wear or corrosion.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502756_004" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Keeping of records of maintenance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648147_004" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall keep in a safe place records of maintenance carried out under this Regulation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648147_012" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any suspended working platform is taken out of use, the owner shall keep the records of maintenance in a safe place for a period of at least 6 years after the date on which it was taken out of use.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648147_020" name="3" temporalId="s24_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The owner shall ensure that the records of maintenance required to be kept under this section are available for inspection by an occupational safety officer at all reasonable times.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502772_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Keeping and displaying of reports</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648179_012" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall keep the certificates or reports received by him in respect of any thorough examination or load test and thorough examination carried out under this Regulation for a period of 3 years after the date he received each of them.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648194_005" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner shall display prominently a copy of the most recent certificate or report on the suspended working platform.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648194_013" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If a suspended working platform is taken out of use, the owner shall keep the most recent certificates or reports in a safe place for a period of at least 2 years after the date on which it was taken out of use.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648194_021" name="4" temporalId="s25_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The owner shall ensure that the certificates and reports required to be kept under this section are available for inspection by an occupational safety officer at all reasonable times.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502772_003" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Reports or records to be furnished to occupational safety officer</heading><content>The owner of a suspended working platform shall, on request in writing by an occupational safety officer, within such period (being not less than 7 days) as may be specified in the request, deliver to the occupational safety officer a copy of or an extract from any record or report required to be kept under this Regulation.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403502772_005" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Forms</heading><content>Every form required under this Regulation shall be in such form as the Commissioner may from time to time approve by notice published in the Gazette.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403502788_002" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Prohibitions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648272_004" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall, without reasonable excuse, tamper or interfere with or render inoperative any safety rope and automatic safety device required to be provided under this Regulation on a suspended working platform.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648272_012" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall use a suspended working platform unless he wears a safety belt and keeps it attached to the lifeline or other anchorage required under this Regulation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502788_004" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Offences by owners</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648303_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An owner who contravenes any of the provisions of this Regulation other than
                    <ref>section 15(3)</ref>, <ref>17</ref>,
                    <ref>19</ref>,
                    <ref>22</ref>, <ref>24</ref>, <ref>25</ref> or <ref>26</ref>
                commits an offence and is liable
                on
                conviction to a fine of $400,000 and to imprisonment for 12 months.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s. 56</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1681963631043_001" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An owner who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1681963631044_002" name="a" temporalId="s29_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>contravenes <ref>section 15(3)</ref>, <ref>17</ref> or <ref>22(a)</ref>
                    commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 6;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681963631049_003" name="b" temporalId="s29_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>contravenes <ref>section 19(1)</ref> commits an offence and is liable on
                    conviction to a fine of $200,000 and to imprisonment for 12 months;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681963631051_004" name="c" temporalId="s29_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>contravenes <ref>section 19(2)</ref> commits an offence and is liable on
                    conviction to a fine at level 6 and to imprisonment for 12 months;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681963631053_005" name="d" temporalId="s29_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>contravenes <ref>section 22(b)</ref> commits an offence and is liable on
                    conviction to a fine of $400,000; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681963631055_006" name="e" temporalId="s29_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>contravenes <ref>section 24</ref>, <ref>25</ref> or <ref>26</ref> commits
                    an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 4. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s. 56</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502803_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Offences by employees and other persons</heading><leadIn>An employee or other person who contravenes <ref>section 28</ref> commits an offence
            and, in respect of a contravention of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648335_012" name="a" temporalId="s30_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content><ref>section 28(1)</ref>, is liable
                on
                conviction to a fine of $150,000 and to imprisonment for 6 months;
                and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648335_020" name="b" temporalId="s30_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><ref>section 28(2)</ref>, is liable
                on
                conviction to a fine of $150,000.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of
            2019</ref>; <ref href="hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s. 57</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403502803_003" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Offences by competent examiners</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648350_026" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A competent examiner who, having carried out any thorough examination or load
                test and thorough examination, contravenes any of the provisions of <ref>section
                    21</ref> commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 5.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648366_005" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A competent examiner who, having carried out any thorough examination or load test and thorough examination required by this Regulation, delivers to an owner any report which is to his knowledge false as to a material particular commits an offence and is liable to a fine of $200,000 and to imprisonment for 12 months.</content></subsection></section></main></subLeg>