<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 298</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>298</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap298!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-04-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402954668_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-04-11">
            <content>To provide for the probation of
                offenders.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[7 December 1956]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402954668_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Probation of Offenders Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402954684_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411827539_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ApprovedInstitution"><term>approved
                    institution</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">核准院舍</term>) means an institution approved under
                    <ref>section 11</ref>;</def><def name="ConditionalDischarge"><term>conditional
                    discharge</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有條件釋放</term>) means a conditional discharge made
                under the provisions of <ref>section 36</ref> of the Magistrates Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap227">Cap. 227</ref>) or <ref>section 107</ref> of the Criminal
                Procedure Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap221">Cap. 221</ref>);</def><def name="PrincipalProbationOfficer"><term>principal
                    probation
                officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">首席感化主任</term>) means the person appointed to be the
                principal probation officer under <ref>section 9</ref>;</def><def name="ProbationOfficer"><term>probation
                    officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">感化主任</term>) means a person appointed to be a
                probation officer under <ref>section 9</ref>;</def><def name="ProbationOrder"><term>probation
                    order</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">感化令</term>) has the meaning assigned to it by
                    <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="ProbationPeriod"><term>probation
                    period</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">感化期</term>) means the period for which a
                probationer is placed under supervision by a probation order;</def><def name="Probationer"><term>probationer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受感化者</term>) means a person for the time being
                under supervision by virtue of a probation order.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/26">26 of 1976 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438411827555_039" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, except <ref>section 3(7)</ref>, where a probation order or an order for conditional discharge has been made on appeal, the order shall be deemed to have been made by the court from which the appeal was brought.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1987/7">7 of 1987 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954699_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Probation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411827586_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a court by or before which a person is tried for an offence (not being an offence the sentence for which is fixed by law) is of opinion that having regard to the circumstances, including the nature of the offence and the character of the offender, it is expedient to do so, the court may, after conviction, make a probation order, that is to say, an order requiring him to be under the supervision of a probation officer for a period to be specified in the order of not less than 1 year nor more than 3 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961 s. 2</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline>Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/20">20 of 1971 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/55">55 of 1986 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827586_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>A probation order may in addition require the offender to comply during the whole or any part of the probation period with such requirements as the court, having regard to the circumstances of the case, considers necessary for securing the good conduct of the offender or for preventing a repetition by him of the same offence or the commission of other offences:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s3_2_proviso">Provided that (without prejudice to the power of the court to make an order under <ref>section 7(2)</ref>) the payment of compensation under that section shall not be included among the requirements of a probation order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1972/48">48 of 1972 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1948 c. 58 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827602_011" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (2), a probation order may include requirements relating to the residence of the offender:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s3_3_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411827602_026" name="a" temporalId="s3_3_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>before making an order containing any such requirements, the court shall consider the home surroundings of the offender; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411827602_034" name="b" temporalId="s3_3_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the order requires the offender to reside in an approved institution, the name of the institution and the period for which he is so required to reside shall be specified in the order, and that period shall not extend beyond 12 months from the date of the order.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827602_041" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Before making a probation order, the court shall explain, or cause to be explained, to the offender in a language understood by him the effect of the order (including any additional requirements proposed to be inserted therein under subsection (2) or (3)) and that if he fails to comply therewith or commits another offence he will be liable to be sentenced for the original offence; and if the offender is not less than 14 years of age the court shall not make the order unless he expresses his willingness to comply with the requirements thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827617_005" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A probationer shall be subject to the supervision of the probation officer appointed or assigned to the area in which such probationer may from time to time reside, or to such other probation officer as the principal probation officer may nominate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827633_005" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 53</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827633_013" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The court by which a probation order is made, or any court by which an order is made under <ref>section 4(2)</ref> amending any such probation order, shall forthwith give copies of such order, or such amending order as the case may be, to the probation officer responsible for the supervision of the probationer and he shall give a copy thereof to the probationer and to the person in charge of any institution in which the probationer is or was by such order or such amending order required to reside.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954793_001" name="s3A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3A"><num value="3A">3A.</num><heading>Restriction on punishment of probationer</heading><content>An offender in whose case a probation order is made shall not be sentenced further.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402954918_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Discharge, amendment and review of probation orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411827695_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Any court may upon application made by the probation officer responsible for
                    the supervision of an offender or by a probationer discharge a probation
                    order:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_1_proviso">Provided that if the probation
                    order was made by the Court of First Instance or by the District Court such
                    order shall not be discharged except by the court which made the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54
                            of 1961 s. 3</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline>Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827695_025" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Any court may, upon application made by the probation officer responsible
                    for the supervision of an offender or by a probationer, by order amend a
                    probation order by cancelling any of the requirements thereof or by inserting
                    therein (either in addition to or in substitution for any such requirement) any
                    requirement which could be included in the order if it were then being made by
                    that court in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 3(2)</ref>:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of
                            1961 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_2_proviso">
                    <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438411827695_040" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a court shall not amend a probation order by reducing the probation
                            period, or by extending that period beyond the end of 3 years from the
                            date of the original probation order;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/ln587">L.N. 587
                                    of 1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438411827695_048" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a court shall not so amend a probation order that the probationer
                            is thereby required to reside in an approved institution for any period
                            exceeding 12 months in all; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961
                                    s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438411827695_056" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the probation order was made by the Court of First Instance
                            or the District Court, the order shall not be amended except by the
                            court which made the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961 s.
                                    3</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline>Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1948 c. 58
                                    <ref>Schedule 1</ref> U.K.]</referenceNote></content></paragraph>
                </proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827711_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Where a court proposes to amend a probation order under this section,
                    otherwise than on the application of the probationer, it shall summon him to
                    appear before the court; and if the probationer is not less than 14 years of
                    age, the court shall not amend a probation order unless the probationer
                    expresses his willingness to comply with the requirements of such probation
                    order as amended:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_3_proviso">Provided that this subsection
                    shall not apply to an order cancelling a requirement of a probation order or
                    reducing the period of any requirement thereof.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827711_019" name="4...5" temporalId="s4_4...5"><num value="4...5">(4)-(5)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1979/76">76 of 1979 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827711_027" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where, under any of the provisions of this Ordinance, a probation order is
                discharged or amended or the probationer is sentenced for the offence for which he
                was placed on probation, the court shall send for the record in which the original
                order of probation appears and shall endorse thereon any order it may make or any
                sentence it may pass, as the case may be, and where the probationer is sentenced for
                the offence for which he was placed on probation, the probation order shall cease to
                have effect.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402954980_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Breach of requirements of probation order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411827758_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If at any time during the probation period it appears on information to
                    a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>magistrate that the probationer has failed to
                comply with any of the requirements of the order, the magistrate may issue a summons
                requiring the probationer to appear at the place and time specified therein, or may,
                if the information is in writing and on oath, issue a warrant for his arrest.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of
                        1961 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827758_019" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If it is proved to the satisfaction of the magistrate’s court before which a
                probationer appears or is brought under this section that the probationer has failed
                to comply with any of the requirements of the probation order, the court may,
                without prejudice to the continuance of the probation order, caution him or impose
                on him a fine not exceeding $500, or may—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1979/76">76 of 1979
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411827773_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the probation order was made by a magistrate’s court, deal with the
                    probationer for the offence in respect of which the probation order was made, in
                    any manner in which the court could deal with him if he had just been tried for
                    or convicted of that offence by or before that court or refer the case to the
                    court by which the probation order was made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411827773_013" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the probation order was made by the Court of First Instance or District
                    Court, commit him to custody or release him on bail (with or without sureties)
                    until he can be brought or appear before the Court of First Instance or the
                    District Court, as the case may be.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                            2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827773_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where the magistrate’s court deals with the case as provided in subsection
                    <ref>(2)(b)</ref>, then—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411827773_028" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the court shall send to the Court of First Instance or the District Court a
                    certificate signed by the magistrate, certifying that the probationer has failed
                    to comply with such of the requirements of the probation order as may be
                    specified in the certificate, together with such other particulars of the case
                    as may be desirable; and a certificate purporting to be so signed shall be
                    admissible as evidence of the failure before the Court of First Instance or
                    District Court; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411827789_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the probationer is brought or appears before the Court of First
                    Instance or District Court, and it is proved to the satisfaction of such court
                    that he has failed to comply with any of the requirements of the probation
                    order, the court may deal with him, for the offence in respect of which the
                    probation order was made, in any manner in which the court could deal with him
                    if he had just been tried for or convicted of that offence by or before that
                        court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827805_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A fine imposed under this section in respect of a failure to comply with the
                requirements of a probation order shall be deemed for the purposes of any enactment
                to be a sum adjudged to be paid by a conviction (which expression includes any costs
                or compensation adjudged to be paid by the conviction of which the amount is
                ascertained by the conviction).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1972/48">48 of 1972 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1948 c. 58 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402955027_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Commission of further offence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411827836_034" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>If it appears to a judge or magistrate on whom jurisdiction is hereinafter
                    conferred that a person in whose case a probation order or an order for
                    conditional discharge has been made has been convicted by any court in Hong Kong
                    of an offence committed during the probation period or during the period of
                    conditional discharge, and has been dealt with in respect of that offence, the
                    judge or magistrate may issue a summons requiring that person to appear at the
                    place and time specified therein, or may issue a warrant for his arrest:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/17">17 of
                            1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_1_proviso">Provided that a magistrate shall
                    not issue such a warrant except on information in writing and on oath.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827851_004" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The following persons shall have jurisdiction for the purposes of subsection
                (1), that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411827851_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the probation order or the order for conditional discharge was made by
                    the Court of First Instance, a judge of the Court of First Instance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411827851_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the order was made by the District Court, a district judge;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411827851_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the order was made by a magistrate’s court, or juvenile court, a
                    magistrate. <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s.
                        10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827851_035" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                <leadIn>A summons or warrant issued under this section shall direct the person so
                    convicted to appear or be brought before the court by which the summons or
                    warrant was issued or before the court by which the probation order or the order
                    for conditional discharge was made: <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_3_proviso">Provided that if that court is the
                    Court of First Instance or the District Court and he cannot forthwith be brought
                    before that court a summons or warrant shall have effect as if it directed him
                    to be brought before a magistrate’s court or juvenile court and such
                    magistrate’s court or juvenile court shall commit him to custody or release him
                    on bail with or without sureties until he can be brought or appear before the
                    Court of First Instance or District Court, as the case may be.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827867_004" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If a person in whose case a probation order or an order for conditional
                discharge has been made by the Court of First Instance or the District Court is
                convicted by a magistrate’s court in respect of an offence committed during the
                probation period or during the period of conditional discharge, the magistrate’s
                court may order that he be brought or appear before the court by which the order was
                made if the magistrate considers it expedient to do so, and for this purpose may
                commit him to custody or release him on bail (with or without sureties); and if the
                magistrate’s court makes such an order, it shall send to the Court of First Instance
                or the District Court, as the case may be, a copy of the minute or memorandum of the
                conviction entered in the register, signed by the magistrate.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1979/76">76 of 1979 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827883_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where it is proved to the satisfaction of the court before which a probationer
                or a person subject to an order for conditional discharge appears or is brought
                pursuant to this section that the person in whose case such order was made has been
                convicted and, except in the case of an order under subsection (4), dealt with in
                respect of an offence committed during the probation period, or during the period of
                conditional discharge, as the case may be, the court may deal with him, for the
                offence for which the order was made, in any manner in which the court could deal
                with him if he had just been tried for or convicted of that offence by or before
                that court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of 1961 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1979/76">76 of 1979
                        s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827914_005" name="5A" temporalId="s6_5A"><num value="5A">(5A)</num><content>Where a person has been ordered to be brought or appear before the Court of
                First Instance or District Court under subsection (4), that court, after dealing
                with him under subsection (5) in respect of the original offence, may deal with such
                person in respect of the offence referred to in subsection (4) in any manner in
                which he could be dealt with by a magistrate’s court for that offence, or order that
                he be brought or appear before the magistrate’s court to be dealt with in respect of
                that offence and for such purpose may commit him to custody or release him on bail
                (with or without sureties); and if the Court of First Instance or District Court
                makes such an order it shall send to the magistrate’s court a copy of every order or
                sentence made or imposed, signed by the judge.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1979/76">76 of 1979 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411827945_005" name="6" temporalId="s6_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If a person in whose case a probation order or an order for conditional
                discharge has been made by a magistrate’s court is convicted before the Court of
                First Instance or District Court or another magistrate’s court of an offence
                committed during the probation period or during the period of conditional discharge,
                the Court of First Instance or the District Court or such other magistrate’s court
                may deal with him, for the offence for which the order was made, in any manner in
                which the magistrate’s court by which the order was made could deal with him if he
                had just been tried for or convicted of that offence by or before that court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1961/54">54 of
                        1961 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402955043_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Supplementary
            provisions
            as to probation and discharge</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411827992_033" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Without prejudice to the provisions of <ref>section 15(j)</ref> of the Juvenile
                Offenders Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap226">Cap. 226</ref>) (which enables a court
                to order the parent or guardian of a child or young person charged with an offence
                to give security for his good behaviour), any court may, on making a probation order
                or an order for conditional discharge, if it thinks it expedient for the purpose of
                the reformation of the offender, allow any person who consents to do so to give
                security for the good behaviour of the offender; and <ref>section 64</ref> of the
                Magistrates Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap227">Cap. 227</ref>) shall apply to any
                such security as if it were a security given under the provisions of that Ordinance
                by a surety.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411828023_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A court, on making a probation order or an order for conditional discharge, may,
                without prejudice to its power to award costs against him, order the offender to pay
                to any aggrieved person such compensation for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411828023_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>personal injury;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828023_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>loss of or damage to property; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828023_029" name="c" temporalId="s7_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>both such injury and loss or damage,</content></paragraph><continued>as it thinks reasonable; but in the case of an order made by a magistrate’s
                court, the compensation shall not exceed $5,000.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1972/48">48 of 1972 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411828023_042" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An order for the payment of compensation as aforesaid may be enforced in like
                manner as an order for the payment of costs by the offender; and where a court, in
                addition to making such an order for the payment of compensation to any person,
                orders the offender to pay to that person any costs, the orders for the payment of
                compensation and for the payment of costs may be enforced as if they constituted a
                single order for the payment of costs.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1972/48">48 of 1972 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411828039_005" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In proceedings before the Court of First Instance under the foregoing
                provisions of this Ordinance, any question whether a probationer has failed to
                comply with the requirements of the probation order or has been convicted of an
                offence committed during the probation period, and any question whether any person
                in whose case an order for conditional discharge has been made has been convicted of
                an offence committed during the period of conditional discharge, shall be determined
                by the court and not by the verdict of a jury.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411828054_005" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>When a court makes any order under the provisions of this section, then if the
                offender—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411828054_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is under 14 years of age, such order shall be enforced against the parent
                    or guardian of the offender;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828054_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is under 16 years of age, such order may be enforced either against the
                    parent or guardian of the offender or against the offender as to the court seems
                    just in any particular case.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. No. <ref href="/hk/1951/27">27 of 1951 s.
                            10</ref>(5) Singapore]</referenceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1948 c. 58 s. 11 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402955058_002" name="s8" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1986/55">55 of 1986 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402955074_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Appointment of probation officers</heading><text>The Chief Executive may by notification in the Gazette appoint a principal probation
            officer, and probation officers of either sex.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/17">17 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402955074_003" name="s10" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1976/26">26 of 1976 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402955089_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Approved institutions</heading><text>The Chief Executive may by order approve premises for the reception of persons who may
            be required to reside therein by a probation order, and such premises shall be known as
            approved institutions.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/17">17 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. No. <ref href="/hk/1951/27">27 of 1951 s. 12</ref>
            Singapore]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402955105_001" name="s11A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s11A"><num value="11A">11A.</num><heading>Charges for food and accommodation</heading><content>If, with the permission of the superintendent of an approved institution, a probationer who resides in the institution is employed outside the institution under a contract of service or apprenticeship, and is paid wages, the superintendent may require the probationer to pay such charge in respect of his food and accommodation at the institution as the principal probation officer, with the approval of the Financial Secretary, may determine.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1967/23">23 of 1967 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402955105_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Power to make rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411828163_025" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Secretary for Labour and Welfare may make rules providing
                    for—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 18</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411828163_033" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the duties of the principal probation officer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828163_041" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the duties of probation officers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828163_049" name="c" temporalId="s12_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1976/26">26 of 1976 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828163_057" name="d" temporalId="s12_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the regulation, management and inspection of approved
                    institutions;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828163_065" name="e" temporalId="s12_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1987/7">7 of 1987 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828163_073" name="f" temporalId="s12_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 18</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411828163_081" name="g" temporalId="s12_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>generally, the carrying into effect of the provisions of this
                    Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411828179_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may make rules providing for fees and charges to
                be made for any act, matter or thing to be done or observed under this
                    Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 18</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/17">17 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402955121_002" name="s12A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s12A"><num value="12A">12A.</num><heading>Forms</heading><content>The Director of Social Welfare may specify the form of records to be kept under this Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1987/7">7 of 1987 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402955136_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>The provisions of this Ordinance shall be in addition to and not in derogation of the provisions of the Juvenile Offenders Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap226">Cap. 226</ref>).</content></section></main></ordinance>