<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 200 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>200A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap200A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2012-08-02</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402824439_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2012-08-02">Suppression of Piracy Regulations</docTitle><text class="align_center">(<ref href="/hk/cap200/s23">Cap.
                200, section
                23</ref>)<ref value="ID_1479111354911_001">#</ref><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><commencementNote>[16
            March 1928]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2012/er2">E.R. 2 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1479111354911_001">
            <content>Editorial Note: </content>
            
            
            <content class="align_justified">#
                These regulations were made under the repealed Suppression of Piracy Ordinance
                (Cap.
                218,
                1964 Ed.) and, by virtue of <ref>section 36(1)</ref> of the Interpretation and
                General Clauses
                Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>), continue to have the like
                effect as if they had been made under the Crimes Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap200">Cap.
                200</ref>).</content>
        </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438402824455_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1"><b>1.</b></num><content>These regulations may be cited as the Suppression of Piracy Regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824455_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2"><b>2.</b></num><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Passenger"><term>passenger</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">乘客</term>) means
            any person carried in a vessel, other than the owner, charterer and licensee, their
            families, agents, servants and workmen, and the master, pilot, officers, staff and
            crew;</def><def name="Ship"><term>ship</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船舶</term>) includes any
            description of vessel used in navigation in the propulsion of which use is made of any
            mechanical means other than oars and sails, also any description of junk or craft,
            howsoever propelled or moved, used or intended to be used for carrying any passenger;
            and</def><def name="Vessel"><term>vessel</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船隻</term>) includes any
            ship or boat, and any other description of craft used in navigation.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402824470_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3"><b>3.</b></num><content>The Commissioner of Police shall have power to search any vessel, and after search
            to make further searches, and to detain any vessel for such purpose, and he may delegate
            his powers under this regulation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824486_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4"><b>4.</b></num><content>Every vessel in the waters of Hong Kong shall stop when hailed by the
            police.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/13">13 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402824502_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5"><b>5.</b></num><content>The owners, agents, charterers and licensees shall notify the Commissioner of
            Police confidentially beforehand on any occasion when it is expected that treasure will
            be carried on a ship from or through the waters of Hong Kong.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/13">13 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402824502_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6"><b>6.</b></num><content>While any ship is lying alongside a wharf in the harbour of Victoria, no person,
            except persons concerned in the loading or unloading of the cargo of the ship, shall be
            permitted to come on board the ship on the side of the ship away from the wharf, and no
            person whatsoever shall be permitted to bring or put on board anything, except cargo, on
            the side of the ship away from the wharf.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824517_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7"><b>7.</b></num><content>When the master of any ship propelled by any mechanical means other than oars and
            sails in the waters of Hong Kong has any cause whatever to believe that any vessel may
            be in need of assistance in respect of a piratical attack, it shall be his duty, as far
            as reasonably may be, to approach such vessel as closely as possible, to stand by it, to
            prevent the access of pirates thereto, to assist in rescue work, to call other ships to
            the aid of the vessel attacked, and do all such other acts as may be necessary or
            advisable to assist the said vessel in repelling the attack, and after the attack, and
            he shall act accordingly.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/13">13 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402824517_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8"><b>8.</b></num><content>The owner, charterer, agent or licensee of any vessel not required by or under
            these regulations to undergo search may apply to the Commissioner of Police for police
            search of the vessel; the Commissioner of Police may refuse to comply with any such
            application, or may impose conditions on which any such application will be granted;
            every search undertaken pursuant to this regulation shall be deemed to be an authorized
            search under these regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824533_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9"><b>9.</b></num><content>No ship required under these regulations to undergo police search shall commence or
            attempt to commence a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>voyage or trip except from a
            place and at an hour previously notified to and approved by the Commissioner of Police.
            Such approval may be conveyed to masters and others in charge of ships by special or
            general instructions issued from time to time by the Commissioner of Police.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824548_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10"><b>10.</b></num><leadIn>Subject to exemption granted under these regulations, no ship shall carry or attempt
            to carry any passenger from Hong Kong or through the waters of Hong Kong on a voyage to
            or including any port or place—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/13">13 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411534789_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on the Canton River; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411534789_020" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on the West River or any river or estuary in the Guangdong Province or Guangxi
                Zhuang Autonomous Region; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/ln80">L.N. 80 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411534789_028" name="c" temporalId="s10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in either the Guangdong Province or Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/ln80">L.N. 80 of
                        2012</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411534789_036" name="d" temporalId="s10_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in Taiwan; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411534789_044" name="e" temporalId="s10_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>on the east coast of Asia south of Shanghai and north of Singapore,</content></paragraph><continued>unless and until a search thereof, conducted in such manner as the Commissioner
            of Police may direct and approve, shall have been carried out, nor until the master or
            other person in charge thereof shall have received a certificate in writing signed by
            the Commissioner of Police, or by some police officer authorized by the Commissioner of
            Police in that behalf, from which it shall appear that such search has been completed.
            Such certificate shall contain a concise statement of the result of the
            search.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438402824548_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11"><b>11.</b></num><leadIn>Subject to exemption granted under these regulations and to the provisos herein
            contained, no ship shall carry any passenger or attempt to carry any passenger from the
            harbour of Victoria on any voyage in the waters surrounding the Island of Hong Kong
            within the following boundaries—</leadIn><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                
                <col width="35%"></col>
                
                <col width="65%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_25">(a)
                            on the east:</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">a north and south line drawn
                            through the Fat Tong Mun Pass;</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_25">(b)
                            on the west:</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">a north and south line drawn
                            through the Kap Shui Mun Pass; and</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_25">(c)
                            on the south:</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">an east and west line drawn
                            through the centre of Lo Chau or Beaufort Island, and continued until it
                            meets the east and west boundaries,</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </text><continued><text class="left_indent_108 first_line_indent_-48 ">(hereinafter referred to as
                the local trade limits)</text>or leave or attempt to leave any place of mooring or
            place of call in the waters of Hong Kong and outside the said harbour, while carrying or
            for the purpose of carrying any passenger to any place within the local trade limits,
            unless and until a search of the nature mentioned in <ref>regulation 10</ref> has been
            carried out, nor until the master or other person in charge thereof shall have obtained
            a certificate in writing of the kind mentioned in <ref>regulation 10</ref>:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/13">13 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s11_proviso">
            
            <continued>Provided that this regulation shall not apply—</continued>
            
            
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411534836_033" name="a" temporalId="s11_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of any launch or motor boat on occasions when it is used solely
                    for purposes of pleasure; and</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411534836_041" name="b" temporalId="s11_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to any ship anchoring solely for purposes of navigation.</content></paragraph>
        </proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402824564_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12"><b>12.</b></num><content>No ship to which <ref>regulation 11</ref> applies shall call at any place en route
            unless such place of call and the intended hour of departure therefrom have been
            notified to and approved by the Commissioner of Police. Approved hours of departure
            shall be adhered to.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824580_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13"><b>13.</b></num><content>Except with the permission of the Commissioner of Police, or in saving life or
            rescue work at sea, no person shall be allowed to embark on and nothing shall be brought
            on board any ship after delivery of the certificate required by <ref>regulations
                10</ref> and <ref>11</ref> and before leaving the waters of Hong Kong, or arrival at
            the first place of call therein (notified and approved as aforesaid), as the case may
            be.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/13">13 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402824595_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14"><b>14.</b></num><subsection id="ID_1438411534898_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every police officer in carrying out or taking part in any search required or
                authorized by these regulations shall have power to search any vessel and its stores
                and equipment, and the master, officers, staff and crew, and their belongings, the
                passengers and their goods and baggage, and the cargo, and every person and thing on
                board, and every person who may apparently be about to go on board and everything
                which apparently is about to be put on board, and may do all such acts and things as
                may be reasonably necessary in order to carry out such search effectually.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411534914_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The police officer in charge of any search party, and any police officer
                superior to him, shall have power to detain any vessel until in his opinion the
                searching shall have been completed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411534914_013" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>It shall be lawful for the police officer in charge of any searching party, and
                any officer superior to him, to order that no passenger or thing shall embark or be
                brought on board without his express consent while the search is proceeding; no
                person shall act contrary to such order; any such order shall be in force as soon as
                the same shall have been communicated to the master or other person in charge of the
                vessel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411534914_021" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>No person shall obstruct any such search or detention.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402824611_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15"><b>15.</b></num><content>The master or other person in charge of a ship shall take effective measures to
            cause, and he shall cause, the movements of his ship to be in accordance with these
            regulations, and he shall take effective measures to prevent, and he shall prevent, the
            coming on board or embarkation of any person and the bringing on board of anything
            contrary to or not in accordance with these regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824611_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16"><b>16.</b></num><content>The Commissioner of Police shall have power, in his discretion, to exempt any
            vessel from any provision or requirement of these regulations, either generally, or
            during any period, or on any occasion, and to impose conditions of exemption. Every
            condition imposed under this regulation shall be duly performed and observed by the
            grantee.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824626_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17"><b>17.</b></num><content>These regulations shall not apply to any vessel being or having the status of a
            ship of war.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402824642_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18"><b>18.</b></num><content>Any person who contravenes any of the <ref>regulations 4</ref>, <ref>5</ref>,
                <ref>6</ref>, <ref>7</ref>, <ref>9</ref>, <ref>10</ref>, <ref>11</ref>,
                <ref>12</ref>, <ref>13</ref>, <ref>14(4)</ref> and <ref>15</ref> shall be liable to
            a fine at level 1 or to imprisonment for six months.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1951/gna93">G.N.A. 93 of 1951</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2012/er2">E.R. 2 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>