<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 59 sub. leg. AD</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>59AD</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap59AD!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-04-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403502819_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2014-04-10">Factories and Industrial Undertakings (Asbestos)
            Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap59/s7">Cap. 59, section
            7</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of
            2014</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 September 1997]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1997/ln429">L.N. 429 of 1997</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403502834_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part 1</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403502834_004" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403502850_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648459_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ActionLevel"><leadIn><term>action level</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">措施水平</term>) means one of the following cumulative exposures to asbestos over a continuous 12-week period, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648475_005" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the exposure is solely to chrysotile, 96 fibre-hours per millilitre of air; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648475_013" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the exposure is to any other form of asbestos either alone or in mixtures including mixtures of chrysotile with any other form of asbestos, 48 fibre-hours per millilitre of air; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648475_021" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where both types of exposure occur separately during the 12-week period, a proportionate number of fibre-hours per millilitre of air;</content></paragraph></def><def name="AmphiboleAsbestos"><term>amphibole asbestos</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">閃石類石棉</term>) means any of the minerals crocidolite, amosite, fibrous actinolite, fibrous anthophyllite, fibrous tremolite and any mixture containing any of those minerals;</def><def name="ApprovedRespiratoryProtectiveEquipment"><term>approved respiratory protective equipment</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">認可呼吸防護設備</term>) means any respiratory protective equipment approved by the Commissioner under <ref>section 4</ref>;</def><def name="Asbestos"><term>asbestos</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">石棉</term>) means chrysotile and amphibole asbestos and any mixture containing any of those minerals;</def><def name="AsbestosCement"><term>asbestos cement</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">石棉水泥</term>) means a material which is predominantly a mixture of cement and asbestos and which when in a dry state has a density greater than 1 tonne per cubic metre;</def><def name="AsbestosCoating"><term>asbestos coating</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">石棉塗層</term>) means a surface coating which contains asbestos;</def><def name="AsbestosInsulatingBoard"><term>asbestos insulating board</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">石棉絕緣板</term>) means any sheet, tile or building board consisting of a mixture of asbestos and other material which mixture when in a dry state has a density greater than 500 kilograms per cubic metre;</def><def name="AsbestosInsulation"><leadIn><term>asbestos insulation</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">石棉絕緣物</term>) means any material containing asbestos and used for thermal, acoustic or other insulation purposes (including fire protection) except—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648491_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a-1"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>asbestos cement or asbestos insulating board; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648491_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b-1"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any article of bitumen, plastic, resin or rubber which contains asbestos and the thermal and acoustic properties of which are incidental to its main purpose;</content></paragraph></def><def name="AsbestosSpraying"><term>asbestos spraying</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">石棉噴塗</term>) means the application by spraying of any material containing asbestos to form a continuous surface coating;</def><def name="ControlLimit"><leadIn><term>control limit</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">控制限度</term>) means one of the following concentrations of asbestos in the atmosphere of the industrial undertaking, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648491_055" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a-2"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>for chrysotile—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648506_006" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>0.5 fibres per millilitre of air averaged over any continuous period of 4 hours;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648506_014" name="ii" temporalId="s2_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>1.5 fibres per millilitre of air averaged over any continuous period of 10 minutes;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648506_021" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b-2"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>for any other form of asbestos either alone or in mixtures including mixtures of chrysotile with any other form of asbestos—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648506_029" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>0.2 fibres per millilitre of air averaged over any continuous period of 4 hours;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648506_037" name="ii" temporalId="s2_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>0.6 fibres per millilitre of air averaged over any continuous period of 10 minutes;</content></subparagraph></paragraph></def><def name="Proprietor"><term>proprietor</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">東主</term>) means a proprietor of any industrial undertaking;</def><def name="ProtectiveClothing"><term>protective clothing</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">防護衣物</term>) means clothing which is impervious to asbestos dust and which when worn can protect the body and personal clothing of the wearer from contamination by asbestos;</def><def name="WorkWithAsbestosCoatingOrAsbestosInsulation"><term>work with asbestos coating or asbestos insulation</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">石棉塗層或石棉絕緣物工作</term>) includes any work in which asbestos coating or asbestos insulation is removed, repaired or disturbed.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648506_063" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purpose of this Regulation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648506_071" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any reference to a workman being exposed to asbestos in an industrial undertaking shall be construed as a reference to the exposure of that workman to asbestos dust arising out of or in connection with any work with asbestos which is carried out in the industrial undertaking;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648522_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in determining whether a workman is exposed to asbestos or whether the extent of exposure exceeds the action level or any control limit, no account shall be taken of any respiratory protective equipment that is being worn by the workman; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648522_014" name="c" temporalId="s2_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the method for measuring exposure of workman to asbestos in the atmosphere of the industrial undertaking shall be a method approved by the Commissioner.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502850_004" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>This Regulation applies to all industrial undertakings in which any work with asbestos is carried out.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403502866_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Approval of respiratory protective equipment, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648615_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>For the purposes of this Regulation, the Commissioner may approve any respiratory protective equipment and shall publish in the Gazette the name or description of the respiratory protective equipment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648615_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Commissioner may, by notice in the Gazette, revoke any approval given by him under subsection (1) in respect of any respiratory protective equipment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648615_020" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Commissioner may also by notice in the Gazette set out the approved form for notification under <ref>section 6(4)</ref> and the approved method for measuring exposure to asbestos under <ref>section 15(1)(a)</ref>, as well as the approved form of health register under <ref>section 17(3)</ref>.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403502866_004" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part 2</num><heading>Identification, Assessment and Notification</heading><section id="ID_1438403502881_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Assessment of work</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648662_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A proprietor shall before carrying out any work which exposes or is liable to expose any workman to asbestos ensure that an adequate assessment of exposure or the likely exposure has been made by a person who by reason of his training and experience is competent to make that assessment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648678_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The assessment shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648678_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648678_016" name="i" temporalId="s5_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>identify the type of asbestos to which any workman is or is liable to be exposed by analysis or otherwise; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413648678_023" name="ii" temporalId="s5_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>without performing the identification, assume that the asbestos involved is not chrysotile alone;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648678_030" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>determine the nature and degree of exposure or the likely exposure; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648678_038" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>set out the steps that may be taken to prevent the exposure or to reduce it to the lowest level reasonably practicable.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648678_045" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The proprietor shall keep a written record of the assessment and shall, on being requested by an occupational safety officer, produce the record for inspection.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648678_053" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A proprietor shall ensure that a further assessment is made under subsection (1) when—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648693_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>there is reason to suspect that the existing assessment is no longer valid; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648693_013" name="b" temporalId="s5_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>there is a significant change in the work to which the existing assessment relates.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502881_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Notification</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648725_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), before a proprietor begins to carry out work with asbestos coating or asbestos insulation or other asbestos work, he shall give the Commissioner not less than 28 days’ notice, or such shorter notice as the Commissioner may agree to accept, of the work.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648740_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notification is not required in respect of work with asbestos other than work with asbestos coating and asbestos insulation if the extent of exposure of that asbestos work neither exceeds nor is liable to exceed the action level.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648740_013" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where there is a material change in the asbestos work which might affect the particulars notified under subsection (1), the proprietor shall, within 7 days after he becomes aware of the change, notify the Commissioner of that change.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648740_021" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Notification under subsections (1) and (3) shall be in the approved form.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403502897_001" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part 3</num><heading>Hygiene and Safety Requirements</heading><section id="ID_1438403502897_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Prevention or reduction of exposure</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648787_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A proprietor shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648787_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>prevent the exposure of any workman to asbestos; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648787_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where it is not reasonably practicable to prevent exposure, reduce the exposure of any workman to asbestos to the lowest level reasonably practicable by measures other than the use of respiratory protective equipment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648787_027" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A proprietor shall in all circumstances—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648787_035" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>provide every workman who is or is liable to be exposed to asbestos with approved respiratory protective equipment that is suitable for the circumstances; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648803_006" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>ensure the full and proper use by each workman of the respiratory protective equipment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648803_013" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Without prejudice to the generality of the requirement in subsection (2), where after taking the measures required in subsection (1) exposure of any workman to asbestos still exceeds or is liable to exceed the control limit, a proprietor shall ensure that the respiratory protective equipment provided under subsection (2) is capable of effectively reducing the concentration of asbestos in the air inhaled by the workman to below the control limit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648818_005" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A proprietor shall not provide respiratory protective equipment which has been used by another person for use by any workman unless the equipment has first been thoroughly cleaned and disinfected.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502912_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Prevention of spread of asbestos</heading><content>A proprietor shall take such measures as may be necessary to prevent or, where this is not reasonably practicable, reduce to the lowest level reasonably practicable, the spread of the asbestos from any place where work with asbestos is carried out, including providing in cases where there is risk of spread of asbestos dust in the use of changing and washing facilities, separate facilities for washing and changing of personal protective clothing, of personal clothing and of respiratory protective equipment.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403502912_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Cleanliness of premises and plant</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648881_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A proprietor who carries out work with asbestos shall ensure that the premises or those parts of the premises where the work is carried out and the plant used in connection with the work are kept in a clean state and as far as possible free from asbestos and, in particular, where work with asbestos has been completed the premises or those parts of the premises and the plant used in connection with the work are thoroughly cleaned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648881_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The cleaning required by subsection (1) shall be carried out—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648881_020" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by means of vacuum cleaning equipment; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648896_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by such other method,</content></paragraph><continued>so designed, constructed and used that asbestos dust neither escapes nor is discharged into the air.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502912_005" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Provision and cleaning of protective clothing</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413648912_033" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A proprietor shall provide adequate and suitable protective clothing for use by any workman who is exposed to asbestos unless no asbestos is liable to be deposited on the body or personal clothing of the workman.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648927_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A proprietor shall ensure that the protective clothing is either disposed of as asbestos waste within the meaning of the Waste Disposal Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap354">Cap. 354</ref>) and the Waste Disposal (Chemical Waste) (General) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap354C">Cap. 354 sub. leg. C</ref>), or adequately cleaned at suitable intervals.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648927_013" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The cleaning of protective clothing shall be carried out in a suitably equipped facility located on the premises where work with asbestos is being done or in a suitably equipped laundry elsewhere, and if protective clothing is to be removed from the person for cleaning or disposal, it shall be packed in a suitable container labelled in accordance with <ref>section 19(1)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413648943_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where, as a result of failure or improper use of the protective clothing, asbestos is deposited on the personal clothing of a workman, then that personal clothing shall be treated in the manner prescribed in subsection (2) as if it were protective clothing and shall forthwith be handed over by the workman concerned to the proprietor who shall be responsible for such treatment.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403502928_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Use and maintenance of control measures</heading><leadIn>A proprietor who provides any control measure, personal protective equipment or other thing or facility pursuant to this Regulation shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413648990_005" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>ensure so far as is reasonably practicable that it is properly used or applied, as the case may be; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413648990_013" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>ensure that it is maintained in an efficient state, in efficient working order and in good repair.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502928_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Protective equipment zone</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649005_012" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438413649005_016" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), a proprietor shall designate any area where work with asbestos is being carried out as protective equipment zone.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649005_022" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>In respect of the protective equipment zone, a proprietor shall—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413649005_030" name="i" temporalId="s12_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>ensure that the area is clearly demarcated and identified by notices indicating that it is a protective equipment zone, that entry into it is limited to persons authorized by the proprietor and that any person who enters the area must wear suitable approved respiratory protective equipment and suitable protective clothing;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413649021_007" name="ii" temporalId="s12_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>provide suitable approved respiratory protective equipment and suitable protective clothing for the use of every workman in the protective equipment zone; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413649021_015" name="iii" temporalId="s12_1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>ensure that no person enters or remains in a protective equipment zone unless he is wearing suitable approved respiratory protective equipment and suitable protective clothing.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649021_021" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subsection (1) shall not apply where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649021_029" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2014/1">1 of 2014 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649037_006" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the concentration of asbestos in the air from work with asbestos in the area does not exceed or is not liable to exceed any control limit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649037_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person shall enter or remain in a protective equipment zone unless he is wearing suitable approved respiratory protective equipment and suitable protective clothing.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502944_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Prohibition of eating, drinking and smoking</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649068_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A proprietor shall take all reasonable steps to ensure that no workman eats, drinks or smokes in an area where work with asbestos is being carried out.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649068_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A proprietor shall put up sufficient number of notices in prominent positions prohibiting eating, drinking and smoking in the area where work with asbestos is being carried out.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649068_020" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person shall eat, drink or smoke in the area where work with asbestos is being carried out.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502944_004" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Washing and changing facilities</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649099_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where any workman in an industrial undertaking is exposed to asbestos, the proprietor shall provide for the use of the workman—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649099_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>adequate and suitable washing and changing facilities;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649099_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>where he is required to provide protective clothing, adequate and suitable facilities for the storage of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413649099_028" name="i" temporalId="s14_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the protective clothing; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413649099_036" name="ii" temporalId="s14_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>personal clothing not worn during working hours; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649115_006" name="c" temporalId="s14_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where he is required to provide approved respiratory protective equipment, adequate and suitable facilities for storage of the equipment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649115_013" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The facilities provided for the storage of personal protective clothing, of personal clothing and of respiratory protective equipment shall be separated from each other and indicated in both English and Chinese.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649115_021" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The proprietor shall ensure that the facilities provided for washing, changing and storage are fully and properly used.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502959_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Air monitoring</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649146_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A proprietor shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649146_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the exposure of any workman in an industrial undertaking to asbestos in the air is monitored by means of an approved method where such monitoring is appropriate for the protection of the health of the workman and whenever there is a substantial change in the working conditions rendering the findings of the previous air monitoring no longer valid; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649161_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the air monitoring required in paragraph (a) is carried out by a laboratory that is accredited for the relevant asbestos test by the Hong Kong Laboratory Accreditation Scheme (HOKLAS) managed by the Commissioner for Innovation and Technology on behalf of the Government or by a scheme with which HOKLAS has a mutual recognition agreement.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln221">L.N. 221 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649161_013" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A record of any monitoring carried out in pursuance of subsection (1) shall be kept by the proprietor who shall, on being requested by an occupational safety officer, produce the record for inspection.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403502975_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Safety information, instruction and training</heading><leadIn>A proprietor shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649193_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>give every workman who is or is liable to be exposed to asbestos adequate information about risks of asbestos and the precautions that should be observed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649193_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>ensure that every workman who works with asbestos is trained and instructed in—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413649193_028" name="i" temporalId="s16_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>safety precautions for working with asbestos; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413649208_007" name="ii" temporalId="s16_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the purpose, proper use and limitations of any control measure, personal protective equipment or other thing or facility provided in pursuance of this Regulation.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403502975_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Medical surveillance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649224_019" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A proprietor shall not employ any person in working with asbestos unless that person has within the 4 months immediately preceding the commencement of such employment undergone a radiographic examination of his chest and is certified by a registered medical practitioner to be fit to do such work.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649239_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A proprietor shall ensure that at intervals of not more than 12 months every person employed in working with asbestos—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649239_013" name="a" temporalId="s17_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>undergoes a radiographic examination of his chest; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649239_021" name="b" temporalId="s17_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is certified by a registered medical practitioner to be fit to continue to do such work.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649239_028" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A proprietor who employs a person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649239_036" name="a" temporalId="s17_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>maintain a health register in the approved form for every person employed in working with asbestos;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649239_044" name="b" temporalId="s17_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>keep the register for at least 5 years from the date of last entry by the proprietor and it shall be made available for inspection by the Commissioner when requested by him; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649239_052" name="c" temporalId="s17_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>give a copy of the health register to the person covered by it upon termination of his employment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649255_005" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Every person employed or to be employed in working with asbestos shall within a reasonable time after being requested by the proprietor present himself to a registered medical practitioner for medical examination.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649255_013" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The cost of any radiographic and medical examination undergone by any person under this Regulation shall be borne by the proprietor.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403502990_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part 4</num><heading>Storage, Distribution and Labelling</heading><section id="ID_1438403502990_004" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Storage, distribution of loose asbestos and waste</heading><leadIn>A proprietor who undertakes work with asbestos shall ensure that no loose asbestos or waste which contains asbestos is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649302_012" name="a" temporalId="s18_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>stored;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649302_020" name="b" temporalId="s18_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>received into or despatched from any place of work; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649302_028" name="c" temporalId="s18_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>distributed, except in a totally enclosed distribution system, within any place of work,</content></paragraph><continued>unless it is in a suitable and sealed container clearly marked in accordance with <ref>section 19</ref>.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403503006_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Labelling of container and articles containing asbestos</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649333_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any asbestos is required to be put in a container that container shall have affixed to it a clear and visible label on which is written—<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><quotedText class="align_center">“DANGER—CONTAINS ASBESTOS<br></br>DO NOT INHALE
                    DUST<marker role="blank-line"></marker>危險——載有石棉<br></br>切勿吸入塵埃<marker role="blank-line"></marker>(Follow Safety Instructions)<br></br>(遵從安全指示)”.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></quotedText></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649333_053" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any article which contains asbestos, being an article for use at work, shall be labelled as required in subsection (1). The labelling shall be effected by means of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649349_005" name="a" temporalId="s19_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an adhesive label firmly affixed to the article or its packaging;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649349_013" name="b" temporalId="s19_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a tie-on label firmly attached to the article or its packaging; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649349_021" name="c" temporalId="s19_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>direct printing onto the article or its packaging, as the case may be.</content></paragraph></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403503006_004" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part 5</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403503022_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Employment of young persons</heading><leadIn>No proprietor shall employ any young person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649395_012" name="a" temporalId="s20_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in working with asbestos;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649395_020" name="b" temporalId="s20_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in carrying out any cleaning in connection with work with asbestos.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403503022_003" name="s21" reason="repealed" startPeriod="2014-04-04" status="repealed" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2014/1">1 of 2014 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403503022_005" name="s21A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s21A"><num value="21A">21A.</num><heading>Ban on asbestos spraying</heading><content>The proprietor of an industrial undertaking must not undertake asbestos spraying in the industrial undertaking.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/1">1 of 2014 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403503037_001" name="s21B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s21B"><num value="21B">21B.</num><heading>Ban on using asbestos insulation</heading><content>The proprietor of an industrial undertaking must not use in the industrial undertaking asbestos insulation for thermal, acoustic or other insulation (including fire protection).</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/1">1 of 2014 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403503037_003" name="s21C" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s21C"><num value="21C">21C.</num><heading>Ban on working with amphibole asbestos</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649473_004" name="1" temporalId="s21C_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The proprietor of an industrial undertaking must not carry out work with amphibole asbestos in the industrial undertaking.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649473_012" name="2" temporalId="s21C_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection (1) does not prohibit the proprietor from removing or disposing of amphibole asbestos that was in use before 1 September 1997.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/1">1 of 2014 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403503037_005" name="s21D" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s21D"><num value="21D">21D.</num><heading>Ban on working with chrysotile</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649489_026" name="1" temporalId="s21D_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The proprietor of an industrial undertaking must not carry out work with chrysotile in the industrial undertaking.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649505_005" name="2" temporalId="s21D_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection (1) does not prohibit the proprietor from removing or disposing of chrysotile that was in use before <ref>Part 3</ref> of the Air Pollution Control (Amendment) Ordinance 2014 (<ref href="/hk/2014/1">1 of 2014</ref>) comes into operation*.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/1">1 of 2014 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1522808029861_001"><content>Editorial Note:</content><content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>
                Operation Date : 4 April 2014.</content></editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403503053_002" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part 6</num><heading>Duties of Workmen and Other Persons</heading><section id="ID_1438403503053_004" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Responsibilities of any person</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413649551_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any workman in an industrial undertaking where work with asbestos is carried out shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413649551_012" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>observe the safety precautions and the procedures set by the proprietor in respect of the asbestos work which have been made known to him in the industrial undertaking;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649551_020" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>make full and proper use of any control measure, personal protective equipment or other thing or facility provided in pursuance of this Regulation which have been made known to him in the industrial undertaking; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413649551_028" name="c" temporalId="s22_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>report forthwith to the proprietor any fault or defect in any such control measure, personal protective equipment or other thing or facility as provided in pursuance of this Regulation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649551_035" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The obligations set out in subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> and (b) shall apply also to any other person in the industrial undertaking.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403503084_001" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part 7</num><heading>Offences and Penalties</heading><section id="ID_1438403503084_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Offences by proprietors</heading><subsection temporalId="s23_1" id="ID_1683104389661_001" name="1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A proprietor who—</leadIn><paragraph temporalId="s23_1_a" id="ID_1683104389662_002" name="a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>fails to comply with section 5(1), (3) or (4), 6(1) or (3), 7, 8, 9, 10,
                    11, 12(1), 13(1), 14, 15, 16, 17(1), (2) or (5), 18, 19 or 20 commits an offence
                    and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 6; or</content></paragraph><paragraph temporalId="s23_1_b" id="ID_1683104389663_003" name="b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fails to comply with section 6(4), 13(2) or 17(3) commits an offence and is
                    liable on conviction to a fine at level 4.<inline class="width_3"></inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s.
                        58</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413649614_004" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A proprietor who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with <ref>section
                    21A</ref>, <ref>21B</ref>, <ref>21C</ref> or <ref>21D</ref> commits an offence
                and is liable
                on
                conviction to a fine of $400,000 and to imprisonment for 6
                    months.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/1">1
                        of 2014 s.
                    12</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s.
                58</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403503100_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Offence by workman</heading><content>Any workman who fails to comply with <ref>section 10(4)</ref> or <ref>22(1)</ref>
            commits an offence and is liable
            on
            conviction to a fine at level 5.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s. 59</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403503100_004" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Offence by any person</heading><content>Any person who fails to comply with <ref>section 12(3)</ref>, <ref>13(3)</ref> or
                <ref>22(2)</ref> commits an offence and is liable
            on
            conviction to a fine at level 5.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s. 60</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403503115_001" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><content>For assessment of work under <ref>section 5(1)</ref> where work with asbestos has been commenced before the coming into operation of this Regulation or within 28 days after that date, it shall be sufficient compliance with that section if the proprietor makes the assessment within 28 days after the date of coming into operation of this Regulation.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403503115_003" name="P8" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="omitted" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part VIII</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403503131_001" name="s27" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2014-04-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></main></subLeg>