<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 112 sub. leg. AP</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>112AP</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap112AP!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-08-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402590049_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-08-13">Specification
            of
            Arrangements (Government
            of
            the
            Democratic
            Socialist Republic
            of
            Sri
            Lanka) (Avoidance
            of
            Double Taxation
            on Income
            from Shipping
            and
            Air
            Transport)
            Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap112/s49">Cap. 112, section
                49</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of
            2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[19 November
            2004]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402590064_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-13" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Declaration under <ref>section 49</ref></heading><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 49</ref> of the Ordinance, it is declared—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410940444_012" name="a" temporalId="s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the arrangements specified in <ref>section 2</ref> have been made with the Government of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka with a view to affording relief from double taxation in relation to income tax and other taxes of a similar character imposed by the laws of the Republic; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940444_020" name="b" temporalId="s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that it is expedient that those arrangements should have effect.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402590080_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Arrangements specified</heading><content>The arrangements specified for the purposes of <ref>section 1(a)</ref> are the arrangements in Articles 1 to 6 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka for the Avoidance of Double Taxation with respect to Taxes on Income derived from Shipping and Air Transport done in duplicate at Sri Lanka on 26 March 2004 in the English and Sinhala languages, the English text of which Articles is reproduced in the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402590096_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-13" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap112AP/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Articles
            1
            to
            6 of
            the Agreement
            between
            the Government
            of
            the
            Hong
            Kong
            Special
            Administrative Region
            of
            the People’s
            Republic
            of China
            and
            the Government
            of
            the
            Democratic
            Socialist Republic
            of
            Sri Lanka
            for
            the Avoidance
            of
            Double Taxation
            with
            respect
            to
            Taxes
            on Income
            derived
            from
            Shipping
            and
            Air
            Transport<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE 1</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Taxes
            Covered<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1588561537346_001" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(1)</num><leadIn>The existing taxes to which this Agreement shall apply are:</leadIn></paragraph><section id="ID_1438410940506_046" name="s0" temporalId="sch0_s0" class="no_header align_justified"><subsection name="a" id="ID_1585108217659_001" temporalId="sch0_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region,</content><content>profits tax and salaries tax (hereinafter referred to as “Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region tax”);</content></subsection><subsection name="b" id="ID_1585108217675_002" temporalId="sch0_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka,</content><content>the income tax (hereinafter referred to as “Sri Lanka tax”).</content></subsection></section><paragraph id="ID_1438410940506_086" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">(2)</num><content>This Agreement shall apply also to any identical or substantially similar taxes
                that are imposed after the date of signature of this Agreement in addition to, or in
                place of, the existing taxes. The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties
                shall notify each other of any substantial changes which have been made in their
                taxation laws and which may affect the application of this Agreement.</content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE 2</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>General
            Definitions<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1588561537346_002" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(1)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this Agreement, unless the context otherwise
                requires:</leadIn></paragraph><section id="ID_1438410940522_022" name="s0" temporalId="sch0_s0" class="no_header"><subsection id="ID_1438410940522_031" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="AContractingParty,TheOtherContractingParty">the terms “<term class="old_format">a Contracting Party</term>” and “<term class="old_format">the other Contracting Party</term>” mean the Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China or the Democratic
                    Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka, as the context requires;</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940522_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="Company">the term “<term class="old_format">company</term>” means any
                    body corporate or any entity that is treated as a body corporate for tax
                    purposes;</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940522_047" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><def name="CompetentAuthority">
                    <content>the term “<term class="old_format">competent authority</term>”
                        means:</content>
                </def><paragraph id="ID_1438410940522_055" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s0_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, the
                        Commissioner of Inland Revenue or his authorized representative or any
                        person or body authorized to perform any functions at present exercisable by
                        the Commissioner or similar functions;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940522_064" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_s0_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of Sri Lanka, the Commissioner General of Inland
                        Revenue;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940522_073" name="d" temporalId="sch0_s0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><def name="EnterpriseOfAContractingParty">
                    <content>the term “<term class="old_format">enterprise of a Contracting
                            Party</term>” means:</content>
                </def><paragraph id="ID_1438410940522_081" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s0_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><leadIn>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, a business
                        carried on by a person as an operator of ships or aircraft, and</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410940537_008" name="A" temporalId="sch0_s0_d_i_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>where the person is an operator of aircraft, that person is a
                            company incorporated and has its principal place of business in the Hong
                            Kong Special Administrative Region; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410940537_017" name="B" temporalId="sch0_s0_d_i_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>where the person is an operator of ships, the business is
                            controlled or managed in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region or
                            the person is a company incorporated in the Hong Kong Special
                            Administrative Region;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940537_026" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_s0_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><leadIn>in the case of Sri Lanka,</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410940537_035" name="A" temporalId="sch0_s0_d_ii_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>Sri Lankan Airlines, or other designated airline(s) of Sri Lanka,
                            operating air services in accordance with the Agreement between the
                            Government of Hong Kong and the Government of the Democratic Socialist
                            Republic of Sri Lanka concerning Air Services signed on 24 February
                            1993; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410940537_044" name="B" temporalId="sch0_s0_d_ii_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>a business for the operation of ships carried on by a company or
                            body of persons, where the company or body of persons has its registered
                            or principal office in Sri Lanka, or where the control and management of
                            the business are exercised in Sri Lanka;</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940553_008" name="e" temporalId="sch0_s0_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><def name="InternationalTraffic">the term “<term class="old_format">international
                        traffic</term>” means any transport by ship or aircraft operated by an
                    enterprise of a Contracting Party, except when the ship or aircraft is operated
                    solely between places in the area of the other Contracting Party;</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940553_016" name="f" temporalId="sch0_s0_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><def name="Operator">the term “<term class="old_format">operator</term>” includes an
                    owner or a charterer;</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940553_024" name="g" temporalId="sch0_s0_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><def name="Person">the term “<term class="old_format">person</term>” includes an
                    individual, a company, a trust, or any body of persons, whether incorporated or
                    unincorporated, and, in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region,
                    also a partnership;</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940553_032" name="h" temporalId="sch0_s0_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><def name="Profits">
                    <content>the term “<term class="old_format">profits</term>” includes revenues,
                        gross receipts or income from the operation of ships or aircraft for the
                        transport of persons, livestock, goods, mail or merchandise
                        including:</content>
                </def><paragraph id="ID_1438410940553_040" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s0_h_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>profits from the lease of ships or aircraft provided that such lease is
                        incidental to the operation of ships or aircraft in international
                        traffic;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940569_008" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_s0_h_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>profits from the sale of tickets or similar documents and the provision
                        of services connected with such transport either for the enterprise itself
                        or on behalf of any other enterprise provided that the provision of services
                        is incidental to the operation of ships or aircraft in international
                        traffic;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940569_017" name="iii" temporalId="sch0_s0_h_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>interest on funds directly connected with the operation of ships or
                        aircraft in international traffic;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410940569_026" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s0_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><def name="Tax">the term “<term class="old_format">tax</term>” means Hong Kong
                    Special Administrative Region tax or Sri Lanka tax, as the context
                    requires.</def></subsection></section><paragraph id="ID_1438410940569_033" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">(2)</num><content>As regards the application of this Agreement at any time by a Contracting
                Party, any term not defined herein shall, unless the context otherwise requires,
                have the meaning that it has at that time under the law in force in the area of that
                Contracting Party for the purposes of the taxes to which this Agreement applies, any
                meaning under the applicable tax laws of that Contracting Party prevailing over a
                meaning given to the term under other laws of that Contracting Party.</content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE 3</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Avoidance of Double
            Taxation<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph id="ID_1438410940584_022" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">(1)</num><content>Profits of an enterprise of a Contracting Party derived from the operation of
                aircraft in international traffic shall be taxable only in the area of that
                Contracting Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940584_030" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">(2)</num><content>Profits of an enterprise of a Contracting Party derived in the area of the
                other Contracting Party from the operation of ships in international traffic may be
                taxed in the area of the other Contracting Party but the tax so charged shall be
                reduced by an amount equal to fifty per centum thereof.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940584_038" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">(3)</num><content>The provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this Article shall also apply to
                profits from the participation in a pool, a joint business or an international
                operating agency.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940600_006" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="4" class="align_left">(4)</num><content>Remuneration derived in respect of an employment exercised aboard a ship or
                aircraft operated in international traffic by an enterprise of a Contracting Party
                shall be taxable only in the area of that Contracting Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940600_014" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="5" class="align_left">(5)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of the law of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                Region regarding the allowance as a credit against Hong Kong Special Administrative
                Region tax of tax paid in a jurisdiction outside the Hong Kong Special
                Administrative Region (which shall not affect the general principle hereof), tax
                paid under the law of Sri Lanka and in accordance with this Agreement, whether
                directly or by deduction, on profits of an enterprise of the Hong Kong Special
                Administrative Region derived in Sri Lanka from the operation of ships in
                international traffic shall be allowed as a credit against any Hong Kong Special
                Administrative Region tax payable in respect of the same profits, provided that the
                amount of credit shall not exceed the amount of Hong Kong Special Administrative
                Region tax attributable to such profits.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940631_006" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="6" class="align_left">(6)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of the law of Sri Lanka regarding the allowance as a
                credit against Sri Lanka tax of tax paid in a jurisdiction outside Sri Lanka (which
                shall not affect the general principle hereof), tax paid under the law of the Hong
                Kong Special Administrative Region and in accordance with this Agreement, whether
                directly or by deduction, on profits of an enterprise of Sri Lanka derived in the
                Hong Kong Special Administrative Region from the operation of ships in international
                traffic shall be allowed as a credit against any Sri Lanka tax payable in respect of
                the same profits, provided that the amount of credit shall not exceed the amount of
                Sri Lanka tax attributable to such profits.</content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE 4</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Mutual Agreement
            Procedure<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_justified">The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties shall
            endeavour to resolve by consultation any difficulties or doubts arising as to the
            interpretation or application of this Agreement. They may also consult together for the
            avoidance of double taxation in cases not provided for in this Agreement.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE 5</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Entry into
            Force<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_justified">Each Contracting Party shall notify the other Contracting
            Party of the completion of the procedures required by its law for the bringing into
            force of this Agreement. This Agreement shall enter into force on the date of the later
            of these notifications and shall thereupon have effect for any year of assessment
            beginning on or after 1 April in the calendar year next following that in which this
            Agreement enters into force.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE 6</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Termination<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_justified">This Agreement shall remain in force indefinitely but either
            Contracting Party may terminate this Agreement by giving written notice of termination
            to the other Contracting Party at least six months before the end of any calendar year
            after the fifth year following that in which it enters into force. In such event, this
            Agreement shall cease to have effect for any year of assessment beginning on or after 1
            April in the calendar year next following that in which notice is given.</text></schedule></main></subLeg>