<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 112 sub. leg. L</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>112L</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap112L!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-11-26</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402598520_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-11-26">Specification
                                    of Arrangements (Government of the Republic of Korea concerning
                                    Air Services) (Double Taxation)
                                    Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap112/s49">Cap.
                                                112, section
                                    49</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2020/er6">E.R. 6 of
                                                2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[7 June 1996]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er6">E.R. 6 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402598535_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-11-26" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Declaration under <ref>section 49</ref></heading><content>For the purposes of <ref>section 49</ref> of the Ordinance it is declared that the arrangements referred to in <ref>section 2</ref> have been made with the Government of a territory outside Hong Kong with a view to affording relief from double taxation in relation to income tax and any tax of a similar character imposed by the laws of that territory, and that it is expedient that those arrangements should have effect.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402598535_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-11-26" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Arrangements specified</heading><content>The arrangements mentioned in <ref>section 1</ref> are in Article 9 of the Agreement between the Government of Hong Kong and the Government of the Republic of Korea concerning Air Services done, in duplicate at Seoul, in the Republic of Korea on 29 March 1996 in the English and Korean languages as specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> and having effect according to the tenor of that Agreement.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402598551_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-11-26" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap112L/s2">s.
            2</ref>]</note><heading>Article 9 of the Agreement between the Government of Hong Kong and the Government
            of the Republic of Korea concerning Air
            Services<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><content class="first_line_indent_0">Done, in duplicate, at Seoul on the 29th day of March
            1996 in the English and Korean languages.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><quotedStructure>
                <content class="align_center">“<b>ARTICLE
                        9</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>Avoidance of
                        Double Taxation with respect to International<br></br>Air
                    Traffic</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
                <text class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_24">(1)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purposes of this Article,</text>
                <paragraph class="left_indent_58"><subparagraph name="a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="RevenuesGrossReceiptsIncomeOrProfitsDerivedFromTheOperationOfAircraftInInternationalTraffic">the term “<term class="old_format">revenues, gross receipts, income or
                                profits derived from the operation of aircraft in international
                                traffic</term>” shall include revenues, gross receipts, income or
                            profits from the operation of aircraft for the carriage of persons,
                            livestock, goods, mail or merchandise including the sale of tickets for
                            and the provision of services connected with such carriage, either for
                            the airline itself or for any other airline;</def></subparagraph><subparagraph name="b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="InternationalTraffic">the term “<term class="old_format">international traffic</term>” means any transport by an aircraft
                            operated by an airline of a Contracting Party, except when the aircraft
                            is operated solely between places in the area of the other Contracting
                            Party;<marker role="section-break"></marker></def></subparagraph><subparagraph name="c"><num value="c">(c)</num><def name="AirlineOfOneContractingParty">the term “<term class="old_format">airline of one Contracting Party</term>” means, in the case of Hong
                            Kong, an airline incorporated and having its principal place of business
                            in Hong Kong, in the case of the Republic of Korea, an airline
                            substantially owned and effectively controlled by the Government of the
                            Republic of Korea or its nationals.</def></subparagraph></paragraph>
                <text class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_24">(2)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Revenues, gross receipts, income or profits
                    derived from the operation of aircraft in international traffic by an airline of
                    one Contracting Party, including participation in a pool service, a joint air
                    transport operation or an international operating agency, which are subject to
                    tax in the area of that Contracting Party shall be exempt from income tax,
                    profits tax and all other taxes on revenues, receipts, income or profits imposed
                    in the area of the other Contracting Party on a reciprocal basis in accordance
                    with the laws and regulations of the latter Contracting Party.</text>
                <text class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_24">(3)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Capital and assets of an airline of one
                    Contracting Party relating to the operation of aircraft in international traffic
                    shall not be subject to any taxes imposed by the other Contracting Party on a
                    reciprocal basis in accordance with the laws and regulations of the latter
                    Contracting Party.</text>
                <text class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_24">(4)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The operation of aircraft in international traffic
                    carried on by an airline of one Contracting Party shall be exempt from value
                    added tax and any similar tax imposed by the other Contracting Party on a
                    reciprocal basis in accordance with the laws and regulations of the latter
                    Contracting Party.</text>
                <text class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_24">(5)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Article shall have effect in respect of
                    taxes, other than withholding taxes, for the taxable year or year of assessment
                    beginning on or after the first day of January in the year in which this
                    Agreement enters into force.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text>
                <text class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_24">(6)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The Article shall cease to have effect in respect
                    of taxes, other than withholding taxes, for the taxable year or year of
                    assessment beginning on or after the first day of January in the year in which
                    this Agreement is terminated.</text>
                <text class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_24">(7)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Article shall be replaced by an Agreement for
                    the avoidance of double taxation with respect to taxes on income and on capital
                    providing for similar exemptions if and when such Agreement is concluded between
                    the Contracting Parties.”.</text>
            </quotedStructure></content></schedule></main></subLeg>