<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 188</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>188</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap188!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-01-16</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402811054_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2020-01-16">
            <content>To make new provision, in place of the Maintenance Orders (Facilities for
                Enforcement)
                Ordinance,
                for facilitating the recovery of maintenance by or from persons in Hong Kong from or
                by other persons in reciprocating
                countries.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[31 January 1979]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1979/ln27">L.N. 27 of 1979</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402811070_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Maintenance Orders (Reciprocal Enforcement) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402811320_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411502653_018" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AffiliationOrder"><term>affiliation
                order</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">親父鑑定令</term>) means an order (however described)
                adjudging, finding or declaring a person to be the father of a child, whether or not
                it also provides for the maintenance of the child;</def><def name="CertificateOfArrears"><term>certificate of
                arrears</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欠款證明書</term>), in relation to a maintenance order,
                means a certificate certifying that the sum specified in the certificate is, to the
                best of the information or belief of the officer giving the certificate, the amount
                of the arrears due under the order at the date of certificate or, as the case may
                be, that, to the best of his information or belief, there are no arrears due
                thereunder at that date;</def><def name="CertifiedCopy"><term>certified
                copy</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">核證副本</term>), in relation to an order of a court,
                means a copy of the order certified to be a true copy by the proper officer of the
                court which made the order;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Court"><term>court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院</term>) includes any tribunal or person having
                power to make, confirm, enforce, vary or revoke a maintenance order;</def><def name="MaintenanceOrder"><leadIn><term>maintenance
                    order</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">贍養令</term>) means any of the following orders
                    (however described)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411502669_033" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an order (including an affiliation order or order consequent upon an
                        affiliation order) which provides for the periodical payment of sums of
                        money towards the maintenance of any person, being a
                        person
                        whom the person liable to make payments under the order is, according to the
                        law applied in the place where the order was made, liable to maintain;
                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502684_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an affiliation order or order consequent upon an affiliation order, being an order which provides for the payment by a person adjudged, found or declared to be a child’s father of expenses incidental to the child’s birth or, where the child has died, of his funeral expenses; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/37">37 of 1985 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502684_014" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of a maintenance order which has been varied, that order as varied, but does not include a maintenance order being, or made pursuant to, a judgement which by virtue of the Foreign Judgments (Restriction on Recognition and Enforcement) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap46">Cap. 46</ref>) cannot be recognized or enforced in Hong Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1985/37">37 of 1985 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def><def name="Payee"><term>payee</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受款人</term>), in relation to a
                maintenance
                order, means the person entitled to the payments for which the order provides;</def><def name="Payer"><term>payer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">付款人</term>), in relation to a maintenance order,
                means the person liable to make payments under the order;</def><def name="ProvisionalOrder"><leadIn><term>provisional
                    order</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">臨時命令</term>) means (according to the
                    context)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411502700_019" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an order made by a court in Hong Kong which is provisional only and has no effect unless and until confirmed, with or without alteration, by a competent court in a reciprocating country; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502700_027" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an order made by a court in a reciprocating country which is provisional only and has no effect unless and until confirmed, with or without alteration, by a court in Hong Kong having power under this Ordinance to confirm it;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def><def name="ReciprocatingCountry"><term>reciprocating
                country</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">交互執行國</term>) has the meaning assigned to it by
                    <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="RegisteredOrder"><term>registered
                order</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">登記命令</term>) means a maintenance order which is for
                the time being registered in the District Court under this Ordinance;</def><def name="Registrar"><leadIn><term>Registrar</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">司法常務官</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411502700_055" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to proceedings in the Court of First Instance, the
                        Registrar, a Senior Deputy Registrar, a Deputy Registrar and an Assistant
                        Registrar of the High Court;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998
                                s.
                                2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2005/10">10 of 2005 s. 177</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502716_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to proceedings in the District Court, the Registrar, a Deputy Registrar and an Assistant Registrar of the District Court;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def><def name="RepealedOrdinance"><term>repealed
                Ordinance</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已廢除條例</term>) means the Maintenance Orders
                (Facilities for Enforcement) Ordinance
                (Cap.
                15,
                1964 Ed.) repealed by <ref>section 21</ref>;</def><def name="ResponsibleAuthority"><term>responsible
                authority</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">負責當局</term>), in relation to a reciprocating
                country, means any person who in that country has functions similar to those of the
                Chief Executive under this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502716_026" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this
                Ordinance,
                an order shall be taken to be a maintenance order so far (but only so far) as it
                relates to the periodical payment of sums of money as mentioned in paragraph (a) of
                the definition of
                    <term>maintenance
                    order</term>
                in subsection (1) or to the payment by a person adjudged, found or declared to be a
                child’s father of any such expenses as are mentioned in paragraph (b) of that definition.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502731_005" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any reference in this Ordinance to the payment of money for the maintenance of a child shall be construed as including a reference to the payment of money for the child’s education.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 21 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811335_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Orders by the Chief Executive designating reciprocating countries</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411502809_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="ReciprocatingCountry">The Chief Executive, if satisfied that, in the event of
                the benefits conferred by this Ordinance being applied to, or to particular classes
                of, maintenance orders made by the courts of any country or place other than Hong
                Kong, similar benefits will in that country or place be applied to, or to those
                classes of, maintenance order made by the courts of Hong Kong, may by order
                designate that country or place as a reciprocating country for the purposes of this
                Ordinance; and, subject to subsection (2), in this Ordinance
                    <term>reciprocating
                    country</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">交互執行國</term>) means a country or place that is for
                the time being so designated.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502825_004" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A country or place may be designated under subsection (1) as a reciprocating
                country either as regards maintenance orders generally, or as regards maintenance
                orders other than those of any specified class, or as regards maintenance orders of
                one or more specified classes only; and a country or place which is for the time
                being so designated otherwise than as regards maintenance orders generally shall for
                the purposes of this Ordinance be taken to be a reciprocating country only as
                regards maintenance orders of the class to which the designation extends.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811491_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Transmission of maintenance order made in Hong Kong for enforcement in
            reciprocating country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411502872_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), where the payer under a maintenance order made,
                whether before or after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, by a court in Hong Kong is residing in a reciprocating country,
                the payee under the order may apply for the order to be sent to that reciprocating
                country for enforcement.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502887_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection (1) shall not have effect in relation to a provisional
                order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502887_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Every application under this section shall be made in the prescribed manner to
                the Registrar of the court which made the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s.
                    6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502887_021" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>If, on an application duly made under this section to the Registrar, the
                Registrar is satisfied that the payer under the maintenance order to which the
                application relates is residing in a reciprocating country, the following
                documents—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411502887_029" name="a" temporalId="s4_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a certified copy of the maintenance order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502887_037" name="b" temporalId="s4_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a certificate, signed by the Registrar, certifying that the order is
                    enforceable in Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502887_045" name="c" temporalId="s4_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a certificate of arrears, so signed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502887_053" name="d" temporalId="s4_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a statement giving such information as the Registrar possesses as to the
                    whereabouts of the payer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502887_061" name="e" temporalId="s4_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a statement giving such information as the Registrar possesses for
                    facilitating the identification of the payer; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502903_006" name="f" temporalId="s4_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>where available, a photograph of the payer,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be sent by the Registrar to the Chief Executive with a view to their
                being transmitted by the Chief Executive to the responsible authority in the
                reciprocating country if the Chief Executive is satisfied that the statement
                relating to the whereabouts of the payer gives sufficient information to justify
                that being done.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502903_019" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall be taken as affecting any jurisdiction of a court
                in Hong Kong with respect to a maintenance order to which this section applies, and
                any such order may be enforced, varied or revoked accordingly.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of
                        1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1557112482181_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 31 January
                1979.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811507_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Power of District Court to make provisional order against person residing in
            reciprocating country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411502934_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where an application is made to a court in Hong Kong for a maintenance order
                against any person and it is proved that that person is residing in a reciprocating
                country and the application is one in which the court would have jurisdiction by
                virtue of any enactment to make a
                maintenance order if—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411502934_026" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that person were residing in Hong Kong; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502934_034" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a summons to appear before the court in response to the application had
                    been duly served on him,</content></paragraph><continued>the court shall have jurisdiction to hear the application and may, subject to
                subsection (2), make a maintenance order on the
                application.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502950_011" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A maintenance order made by virtue of this section shall be a provisional
                order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502950_019" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If the court hearing an application to which subsection (1) applies is
                satisfied—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411502950_027" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that there are grounds on which a
                    maintenance order containing a provision requiring the making
                    of payments for the maintenance of a child may be made on that application;
                    but</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502950_035" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that it has no jurisdiction to make that order unless it also makes an
                    order providing for the legal custody of that child,</content></paragraph><continued>then for the purpose of enabling the court to make the maintenance order, the
                applicant shall be deemed to be the person to whom the legal custody of that child
                has been committed by an order of the court which is for the time being in
                force.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502950_048" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>No enactment empowering the District Court to refuse to make an order on an
                application on the ground that the matter in question is one which would be more
                conveniently dealt with by the Court of First Instance shall apply in relation to an
                application to which subsection (1) applies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502965_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Where a court in Hong Kong makes a maintenance order which is by virtue of this
                section a provisional order, the following documents—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411502965_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a certified copy of the maintenance order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502965_021" name="b" temporalId="s5_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a document, authenticated in the prescribed manner, setting out or
                    summarizing the evidence given in the proceedings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502965_029" name="c" temporalId="s5_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a certificate, signed by the Registrar, certifying that the grounds stated
                    in the certificate are the grounds on which the making of the order might have
                    been opposed by the payer under the order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502965_037" name="d" temporalId="s5_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a statement giving such information as was available to the court as to the
                    whereabouts of the payer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502965_045" name="e" temporalId="s5_5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a statement giving such information as the Registrar possesses for
                    facilitating the identification of the payer; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411502965_053" name="f" temporalId="s5_5_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>where available, a photograph of the payer,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be sent by the Registrar to the Chief Executive with a view to their
                being transmitted by the Chief Executive to the responsible authority in the
                reciprocating country in which the payer is residing if the Chief Executive is
                satisfied that the statement relating to the whereabouts of the payer gives
                sufficient information to justify that being done.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411502981_004" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A maintenance order made by virtue of this section which has been confirmed by
                a competent court in a reciprocating country shall be treated for all purposes as if
                the court in Hong Kong which made the order had made it in the form in which it was
                confirmed and as if the order had never been a provisional order, and subject to
                    <ref>section 6</ref>, any such order may be enforced, varied or revoked
                    accordingly.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811569_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Variation and revocation of maintenance order made in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503028_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to a maintenance order a certified copy of which has been sent to a reciprocating country in pursuance of <ref>section 4</ref> and to a maintenance order made by virtue of <ref>section 5</ref> which has been confirmed by a competent court in such a country.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503028_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A court in Hong Kong having power to vary a maintenance order to which this section applies shall have power to vary that order by a provisional order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503028_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where the court hearing an application for the variation of a maintenance order to which this section applies, proposes to vary it by increasing the rate of the payments under the order then, unless either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503043_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>both the payer and the payee under the order appear in the proceedings; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503043_013" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the applicant appears and the appropriate process has been duly served on the other party,</content></paragraph><continued>the order varying the order shall be a provisional order.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503043_026" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a court in Hong Kong makes a provisional order varying a maintenance order to which this section applies, the Registrar shall send in the prescribed manner to the court in a reciprocating country having power to confirm the provisional order a certified copy of the provisional order together with a document, authenticated in the prescribed manner, setting out or summarizing the evidence given in the proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503043_034" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a certified copy of a provisional order made by a court in a reciprocating country, being an order varying or revoking a maintenance order to which this section applies, together with a document, duly authenticated, setting out or summarizing the evidence given in the proceedings in which the provisional order was made, is received by the court in Hong Kong which made the maintenance order, that court may confirm or refuse to confirm the provisional order and, if the order is an order varying the maintenance order, confirm it either without alteration or with such alterations as it thinks reasonable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503074_005" name="6" temporalId="s6_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>For the purposes of determining whether a provisional order should be confirmed under subsection (5), the court shall proceed as if an application for the variation or revocation, as the case may be, of the maintenance order in question had been made to it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503074_013" name="7" temporalId="s6_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where a maintenance order to which this section applies has been varied by an order (including a provisional order which has been confirmed) made by a court in Hong Kong or by a competent court in a reciprocating country, the maintenance order shall, as from the date on which under the provisions of the order the variation is to take effect, have effect as varied by that order and, where that order was a provisional order, as if that order had been made in the form in which it was confirmed and as if it had never been a provisional order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/31">31 of 1980 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503090_005" name="8" temporalId="s6_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Where a maintenance order to which this section applies has been revoked by an order made by a court in Hong Kong or by a competent court in a reciprocating country, including a provisional order made by the last-mentioned court which has been confirmed by a court in Hong Kong, the maintenance order shall, as from the date on which under the provisions of the order the revocation is to take effect, be deemed to have ceased to have effect except as respects any arrears due under the maintenance order at that date.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/31">31 of 1980 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503106_005" name="9" temporalId="s6_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>Where before a maintenance order made by virtue of <ref>section 5</ref> is confirmed a document, duly authenticated, setting out or summarizing evidence taken in a reciprocating country for the purpose of proceedings relating to the confirmation of the order is received by the court in Hong Kong which made the order, or that court, in compliance with a request made to it by a court in such a country, takes the evidence of a person residing in Hong Kong for the purpose of such proceedings, the court in Hong Kong which made the order shall consider that evidence and if, having done so, it appears to it that the order ought not to have been made—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503106_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it shall, in such manner as may be prescribed, give to the person on whose application the maintenance order was made an opportunity to consider that evidence, to make representations with respect to it and to adduce further evidence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503121_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>after considering all the evidence and any representations made by that person, it may revoke the maintenance order.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811600_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Registration in Hong Kong of maintenance order made in reciprocating
            country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503199_011" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to a maintenance order made, whether before or after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, by a court in a reciprocating country, including such an order
                made by such a court which has been confirmed by a court in another reciprocating
                country, but excluding a provisional order which has not been confirmed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503199_019" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a certified copy of an order to which this section applies is received by
                the Chief Executive from the responsible authority in a reciprocating country, and
                it appears to the Chief Executive that the payer under the order is residing in Hong
                Kong, he shall send the copy of the order to the Registrar of the District
                    Court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503215_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the Registrar receives from the Chief Executive a certified copy of an
                order to which this section applies, he shall, subject to subsection (4), register
                the order in the court in the prescribed manner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503215_013" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Before registering an order under this section the Registrar shall take such
                steps as he thinks fit for the purpose of ascertaining whether the payer under the
                order is residing in Hong Kong, and if after taking those steps he is satisfied that
                the payer is not so residing he shall return the certified copy of the order to the
                Chief Executive with a statement giving such information as he possesses as to the
                whereabouts of the payer.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1557112683760_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 31 January
                1979.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811616_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Confirmation by District Court of provisional order made in reciprocating
            country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503246_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to a
                maintenance order made, whether before or after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, by a court in a reciprocating country, being a provisional
                order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503246_019" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where a certified copy of an order to which this section applies together
                with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503246_027" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a document, duly authenticated, setting out or summarizing the evidence
                    given in the proceedings in which the order was made; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503246_035" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a statement of the grounds on which the making of the order might have been
                    opposed by the payer under the order,</content></paragraph><continued>is received by the Chief Executive from the responsible authority in a
                reciprocating country, and it appears to the Chief Executive that the payer under
                the order is residing in Hong Kong, he shall send the copy of the order and
                documents which accompanied it to the Registrar of the District Court, and the
                District Court shall—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s.
                        6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued><paragraph id="ID_1438411503246_049" name="i" temporalId="s8_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the payer under the order establishes any such defence as he might have
                    raised in the proceedings in which the order was made, refuse to confirm the
                    order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503262_006" name="ii" temporalId="s8_2_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in any other case, confirm the order without alteration or with such
                    alterations as it thinks reasonable.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503262_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In any proceedings for the confirmation under this section of a provisional
                order, the statement received from the court which made the order of the grounds on
                which the making of the order might have been opposed by the payer under the order
                shall be conclusive evidence that the payer might have raised a defence on any of
                those grounds in the proceedings in which the order was made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503262_021" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purposes of determining whether a provisional order should be confirmed
                under this
                section,
                the District Court shall proceed as if an application for a maintenance order
                against the payer under the provisional order had been made to it.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503277_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Registrar shall, if the District Court confirms the order, register the
                order in the court in the prescribed manner, or if the court refuses to confirm the
                order, return the certified copy of the order and the documents which accompanied it
                to the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503277_013" name="6" temporalId="s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If a summons to appear in the proceedings for the confirmation of the
                provisional order cannot be duly served on the payer under the order the Registrar
                shall return the certified copy of the order and the documents which accompanied it
                to the Chief Executive with a statement giving such information as he possesses as
                to the whereabouts of the payer.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 7 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574821700690_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 31 January
                1979.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811632_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Enforcement of maintenance order registered in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503308_050" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered order may be enforced in Hong Kong as if it had been made by the District Court and as if that court had had jurisdiction to make it; and proceedings for or with respect to the enforcement of any such order may be taken accordingly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503324_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person for the time being under an obligation to make payments in pursuance
                of a registered order shall give notice of any change of address to the Registrar of
                the District Court, and any person failing without reasonable excuse to give such a
                notice commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 1.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s.
                    6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503324_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438411503324_017" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>A sum ordered to be paid under a registered order shall be recoverable as a civil debt.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503324_023" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>If an application is made to the District Court alleging that default has
                    been made in paying a sum ordered to be paid under a registered order, the
                    District Court may, if it considers the circumstances require it, for the
                    purpose of securing the presence of the person alleged to be in default, issue a
                    warrant to arrest him and bring him before the court, whether or not a summons
                    has been issued previously.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>(cf.
                        Cap.
                        183
                        s. 13)</referenceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503340_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>On the hearing of an application for the enforcement of a registered order, the
                District Court may remit the whole or any part of the amount due under the
                    order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>(cf.
                    Cap.
                    183
                    s. 14)</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503340_013" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In any proceedings for or with respect to the enforcement of an order which is for the time being registered in the District Court under this Ordinance a certificate of arrears sent to the Registrar shall be evidence of the facts stated therein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503355_005" name="6" temporalId="s9_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Subject to subsection (7), sums of money payable under a registered order shall be payable in accordance with the order as from the date on which they are required to be paid under the provisions of the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/31">31 of 1980 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503355_013" name="7" temporalId="s9_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The District Court may, if it decides to confirm a provisional order under <ref>section 8</ref>, direct that the sums of money payable under the order shall be deemed to have been payable in accordance with the order as from the date on which they are required to be paid under the provisions of the order or such later date as the District Court may specify; and subject to any such direction, a maintenance order registered under <ref>section 8</ref> shall be treated as if it had been made in the form in which it was confirmed and as if it had never been a provisional order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/31">31 of 1980 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811647_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Variation and revocation of maintenance order registered in District Court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503402_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to this section, the District Court—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503402_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall have the like power, on an application made by the payer or payee under a registered order, to vary or revoke the order as if it had been made by the District Court and as if that court had had jurisdiction to make it; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503402_020" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall have power to vary or revoke a registered order by a provisional order.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503402_027" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The District court shall not vary a registered order otherwise than by a provisional order unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503402_035" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>both the payer and the payee under the registered order are for the time being residing in Hong Kong; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503402_043" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the application is made by the payee under the registered order; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503402_051" name="c" temporalId="s10_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the variation consists of a reduction in the rate of the payments under the registered order and is made solely on the ground that there has been a change in the financial circumstances of the payer since the registered order was made or, in the case of an order registered under <ref>section 8</ref>, since the registered order was confirmed, and the courts in the reciprocating country in which the maintenance order in question was made do not have power, according to the law in force in that country, to confirm provisional orders varying maintenance orders.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503418_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The District Court shall not revoke a registered order otherwise than by a provisional order unless both the payer and the payee under the registered order are for the time being residing in Hong Kong. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503433_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>On an application for the revocation of a registered order the District Court shall, unless both the payer and the payee under the registered order are for the time being residing in Hong Kong, apply the law applied by the reciprocating country in which the order was made, but where by virtue of this subsection the District Court is required to apply that law, the court may make a provisional order if it has reason to believe that the ground on which the application is made is a ground on which the order could be revoked according to the law applied by the reciprocating country, notwithstanding that it has not been established that it is such a ground. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503449_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the District Court makes a provisional order varying or revoking a registered order, the Registrar shall send in the prescribed manner to the court in the reciprocating country which made the registered order a certified copy of the provisional order together with a document, authenticated in the prescribed manner, setting out or summarizing the evidence given in the proceedings. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503464_005" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where a certified copy of a provisional order made by a court in a reciprocating country, being an order varying a registered order, together with a document, duly authenticated, setting out or summarizing the evidence given in the proceedings in which the provisional order was made, is received by the District Court, the court may confirm the order, either without alteration, or with such alterations as it thinks reasonable or refuse to confirm the order. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503464_013" name="7" temporalId="s10_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>For the purposes of determining whether a
                provisional order should be confirmed under subsection
                (6),
                the District Court shall proceed as if an application for the variation of the
                registered order had been made to it.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503464_021" name="8" temporalId="s10_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Where a registered order has been varied by an order (including a provisional
                order which has been confirmed) made by the District Court or by a competent court
                in a
                reciprocating country, the registered order shall, as from the
                date on which under the provisions of the order the variation is to take effect,
                have effect as varied by that order and, where that order was a provisional order,
                as if that order had been made in the form in which it was confirmed and as if it
                had never been a provisional order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/31">31 of 1980 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503480_005" name="9" temporalId="s10_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Where a registered order has been revoked by an order made by the District Court or by a competent court in a reciprocating country, including a provisional order made by the first-mentioned court which has been confirmed by a competent court in a reciprocating country, the registered order shall, as from the date on which under the provisions of the order the revocation is to take effect, be deemed to have ceased to have effect except as respects any arrears due under the registered order at that date.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/31">31 of 1980 </ref>s . 4)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503496_005" name="10" temporalId="s10_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>The Registrar shall register in the prescribed manner any order varying a registered order other than a provisional order which is not confirmed.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811663_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Cancellation of registration and transfer of order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503542_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503542_019" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a registered order is revoked by an order made by the District Court;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503542_027" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a registered order is revoked by a provisional order made by the District
                    Court which has been confirmed by a court in a reciprocating country and notice
                    of the confirmation is received by the District Court; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503542_035" name="c" temporalId="s11_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a registered order is revoked by an order made by a court in a
                    reciprocating country and notice of the revocation is received by the District
                    Court,</content></paragraph><continued>the Registrar shall cancel the registration but any arrears due under the
                registered order at the date when its registration is cancelled by virtue of this
                subsection shall continue to be recoverable as if the registration had not been
                cancelled.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503558_004" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Registrar is of opinion that the payer under a registered order has
                ceased to reside in Hong Kong, he shall cancel the registration of the order and
                shall send the certified copy of the order to the Chief Executive.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503558_012" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Registrar shall send to the Chief Executive with the certified copy of the
                order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503558_020" name="a" temporalId="s11_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a certificate of arrears signed by him;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503558_028" name="b" temporalId="s11_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a statement giving such information as he possesses as to the whereabouts
                    of the payer; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503558_036" name="c" temporalId="s11_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any relevant documents in his possession relating to the case.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811678_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Steps to be taken by the Chief Executive where payer under certain orders is not
            residing in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503589_011" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If it appears to the Chief Executive that the payer under a maintenance order, a
                certified copy of which has been received by him from a reciprocating country, is
                not residing in Hong Kong or, in the case of an order which subsequently became a
                registered order, has ceased to reside therein, he shall send to the responsible
                authority in that reciprocating country or, if having regard to all the
                circumstances he thinks it proper to do so, to the responsible authority in another
                reciprocating country—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503589_019" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the certified copy of the order in question and a certified copy of any
                    order varying that order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503589_027" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the order has at any time been a registered order, a certificate of
                    arrears signed by the Registrar of the District Court;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s.
                            6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503589_035" name="c" temporalId="s12_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a statement giving such information as the Chief Executive possesses as to
                    the whereabouts of the payer; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503589_043" name="d" temporalId="s12_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any other relevant documents in his possession relating to the
                    case.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503589_050" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the documents mentioned in subsection (1) are sent to the responsible
                authority in a reciprocating country other than that in which the order in question
                was made, the Chief Executive shall inform the responsible authority in the
                reciprocating country in which that order was made of what he has done.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 11 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811678_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Appeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503620_057" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No appeal shall lie from a provisional order made in pursuance of this Ordinance by a court in Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503620_065" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where in pursuance of this Ordinance a court in Hong Kong confirms or refuses to confirm a provisional order made by a court in a reciprocating country, whether a maintenance order or an order varying or revoking a maintenance order, the payer or payee under the maintenance order shall have the like right of appeal from the confirmation of, or refusal to confirm, the provisional order as he would have if that order were not a provisional order and such court in Hong Kong had made or, as the case may be, refused to make it.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503636_005" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where in pursuance of this Ordinance the District Court makes, or
                refuses
                to make, an order varying or revoking a maintenance order made by a court in a
                reciprocating country, then, subject to subsection (1), the payer or payee under the
                maintenance order shall have the like right of appeal from that order or from the
                refusal to make it as he would have if the maintenance order had been made by the
                District Court.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503652_005" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Nothing in this section except subsection (1) shall be construed as affecting any right of appeal conferred by any other enactment.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 12 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811710_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Admissibility of evidence given in a reciprocating country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503667_035" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A statement contained in a duly authenticated document which purports to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503667_043" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>set out or summarize evidence given in proceedings in a court in a reciprocating country; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503683_006" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>set out or summarize evidence taken in such a country for the purpose of proceedings in a court in Hong Kong under this Ordinance, whether in response to a request made by such court or otherwise; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503683_014" name="c" temporalId="s14_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>have been received in evidence in proceedings in a court in such a country or to be a copy of a document so received,</content></paragraph><continued>shall in any proceedings in a court in Hong Kong relating to a maintenance order to which this Ordinance applies be admissible as evidence of any fact stated therein to the same extent as oral evidence of that fact is admissible in those proceedings.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503683_027" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A document purporting to set out or summarize evidence given as mentioned in subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref>, or taken as mentioned in subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref>, shall be deemed to be duly authenticated for the purposes of subsection (1) if the document purports to be certified by the judge, magistrate or other person before whom the evidence was given, or, as the case may be, by whom it was taken, to be the original document containing or recording, or, as the case may be, summarizing, that evidence or a true copy of that document.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503698_005" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A document purporting to have been received in evidence as mentioned in subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref>, or to be a copy of a document so received, shall be deemed to be duly authenticated for the purposes of that subsection if the document purports to be certified by a judge, magistrate or officer of the court in question to have been, or to be a true copy of a document which has been, so received.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503714_005" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>It shall not be necessary in any such proceedings to prove the signature or official position of the person appearing to have given such a certificate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503714_013" name="5" temporalId="s14_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall prejudice the admission in evidence of any document which is admissible in evidence apart from this section.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 13 U.K.] </referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811741_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Obtaining of evidence needed for certain proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503761_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where for the purpose of any proceedings in a court in a reciprocating country relating to a maintenance order to which this Ordinance applies a request is made by or on behalf of that court for the taking in Hong Kong of the evidence of a person residing therein relating to matters specified in the request, the District Court shall have power to take that evidence and, after giving notice of the time and place at which the evidence is to be taken to such persons and in such manner as it thinks fit, shall take the evidence in such manner as may be prescribed. Evidence taken in compliance with such a request shall be sent in the prescribed manner by the Registrar to the court in the reciprocating country by or on behalf of which the request was made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503776_005" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any person, not being the payer or the payee under the maintenance order to which the proceedings in question relate, is required by virtue of this section to give evidence before the District Court, the court may order that there shall be paid out of the general revenue of the Government such sums as appear to the court reasonably sufficient to compensate that person for the expense, trouble or loss of time properly incurred in or incidental to his attendance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503792_005" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notwithstanding <ref>section 59</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>) a court in Hong Kong may for the purpose of any proceedings in that court under this Ordinance relating to a maintenance order request a court in a reciprocating country to take or provide evidence relating to such matters as may be specified in the request and may remit the case to that court for that purpose.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 14 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811756_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Order etc. made abroad need not be proved</heading><leadIn>For the purposes of this Ordinance, unless the contrary is shown—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503823_042" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any order made by a court in a reciprocating country purporting to bear the seal of that court or to be signed by any person in his capacity as a judge, magistrate or officer of the court shall be deemed without further proof to have been duly sealed or, as the case may be, to have been signed by that person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503839_006" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the person by whom the order was signed shall be deemed without further proof to have been a judge, magistrate or officer, as the case may be, of that court when he signed it and, in the case of an officer, to have been authorized to sign it; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503839_014" name="c" temporalId="s16_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a document purporting to be a certified copy of an order made by a court in a reciprocating country shall be deemed without further proof to be such a copy.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c.18 s. 15 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402811756_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Payment of sums under order made abroad: conversion of currency</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411503854_041" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Payment of sums due under a registered order shall, while the order is registered in the District Court, be made in such manner and to such person as may be prescribed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503854_049" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the sums required to be paid under a registered order are expressed in a currency other than the currency of Hong Kong, then, as from the relevant date, the order shall be treated as if it were an order requiring the payment of such sums in the currency of Hong Kong as, on the basis of the rate of exchange prevailing at that date, are equivalent to the sums so required to be paid.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503870_005" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the sum specified in any statement, being a statement of the amount of any arrears due under a maintenance order made by a court in a reciprocating country, is expressed in a currency other than the currency of Hong Kong, that sum shall be deemed to be such sum in the currency of Hong Kong as, on the basis of the rate of exchange prevailing at the relevant date, is equivalent to the sum so specified.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503886_004" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purposes of this
                section,
                a written certificate purporting to be signed by an officer of any bank in Hong Kong
                certifying that a specified rate of exchange prevailed between currencies at a
                specified date and that at such rate a specified sum in the currency of Hong Kong is
                equivalent to a specified sum in another specified currency shall be evidence of the
                rate of exchange so prevailing on that date and of the equivalent sums in terms of
                the respective currencies.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411503886_012" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="TheRelevantDate"><leadIn>In this section,
                    <term>the
                        relevant
                    date</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關日期</term>) means—
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503886_020" name="a" temporalId="s17_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to a registered order or to a statement of arrears due
                        under a maintenance order made by a
                        court in a reciprocating country, the date on which the
                        order first becomes a registered order or (if earlier) the date on which it
                        is confirmed by the District Court;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503901_006" name="b" temporalId="s17_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to a registered order which has been varied, the date on which the last order varying that order is registered in the District Court or (if earlier) the date on which the last order varying that order is confirmed by the District Court.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 16 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811772_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Absence of respondent</heading><leadIn>Where the respondent to an application for the variation or revocation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503932_012" name="a" temporalId="s18_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of a maintenance order made by a court in Hong Kong, being an order to which <ref>section 6</ref> applies; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503948_006" name="b" temporalId="s18_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>of a registered order,</content></paragraph><continued>does not appear at the time and place appointed for the hearing of the application, but the court is satisfied that the respondent is residing in a reciprocating country, the court may proceed to hear and determine the application at the time and place appointed for the hearing or for any adjourned hearing in like manner as if the respondent had appeared at that time and place.</continued><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 17(7) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811788_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Power to make rules</heading><leadIn>The Chief Justice may make rules for the better carrying out of the purposes and provisions of this Ordinance and in particular, but without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing, may make rules providing for all or any of the following matters—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411503964_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the orders made, or other things done, by a court in Hong Kong, or the Registrar, under this Ordinance, or by a court in a reciprocating country, notice of which is to be given to such person as the rules may provide and the manner in which notice shall be given;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503964_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the cases and manner in which courts in reciprocating countries are to be informed of orders made, or other things done, by a court in Hong Kong under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503964_028" name="c" temporalId="s19_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the circumstances and manner in which cases may be remitted by a court in Hong Kong to courts in reciprocating countries;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411503964_036" name="d" temporalId="s19_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the circumstances and manner in which a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>court in Hong Kong may for the purposes of this Ordinance communicate with courts in reciprocating countries.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 18(1) U.K.]</referenceNote></sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811803_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Application to certain orders and proceedings under repealed Ordinance</heading><leadIn>Where the Chief Executive proposes by an order under <ref>section 3</ref> to
            designate as a reciprocating country a country or place to which at the commencement of
            that section the repealed Ordinance extended, that Order may contain such provisions as
            the Chief Executive considers expedient for the purpose of securing—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411504010_019" name="a" temporalId="s20_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>that the provisions of this Ordinance apply, subject to such modifications as
                may be specified in the Order, to maintenance orders, or maintenance orders of a
                specified class—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411504010_027" name="i" temporalId="s20_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>made by a court in Hong Kong against a person residing in that country or
                    place;
                        or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/61">61 of 1981 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411504010_035" name="ii" temporalId="s20_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>made by a court in that country or place against a person residing in Hong
                    Kong,</content></subparagraph><continued>being orders to which immediately before the date of the coming into
                operation of the Order the repealed Ordinance applied;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504010_048" name="b" temporalId="s20_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that any maintenance order, or maintenance order of a specified class, made by
                a court in that country or place which has been confirmed by the District Court
                under <ref>section 6</ref> of the repealed Ordinance and is in force immediately
                before that date is registered under <ref>section 8</ref> of this
                Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504026_006" name="c" temporalId="s20_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that any proceedings brought under or by virtue of a provision of the repealed
                Ordinance in the District Court which are pending at that date, being proceedings
                affecting a person resident in that country or place, are continued as if they had
                been brought under or by virtue of the corresponding provision of this
                Ordinance.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1972 c. 18 s. 24 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811803_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Repeal</heading><content>The Maintenance Orders (Facilities for Enforcement) Ordinance
            (Cap.
            15,
            1964 Ed.) is repealed.</content></section></main></ordinance>