<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 254 sub. leg. I</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>254I</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap254I!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-04-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402903937_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-04-29">Auxiliary
            Forces Pay
            and
            Allowances
            (Pensions)
            Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap254/s16">Cap.
                254,
                section
            16</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[9 May 1997]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1997/ln226">L.N. 226 of 1997</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402903953_002" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402903968_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AnnualPay"><term>annual
                pay</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">年薪</term>) means 12 times the monthly rate of pay
            determined under <ref>section 8(2)</ref> of the Ordinance;</def><def name="DeathGratuity"><term>death
                gratuity</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">死亡恩恤金</term>) means a death gratuity payable under
                <ref>section 5</ref>;</def><def name="DependantPension"><term>dependant
                pension</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受養人撫恤金</term>) means a pension granted under
                <ref>section 6</ref> to a dependant of a deceased
            member;</def><def name="InjuryPension"><term>injury
                pension</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受傷撫恤金</term>) means a pension granted under
                <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="TerminationOfService"><term>termination
                of
            service</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">終止服務</term>), in relation to a member, means
            termination of his membership in the auxiliary forces of which he is a member.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402903968_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Injury pension</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411692443_053" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a member is permanently injured—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692443_061" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the actual discharge of his duty;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692443_069" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>without his own serious and wilful misconduct; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692443_077" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on account of circumstances specifically attributable to the nature of his
                    duty,</content></paragraph><continued>and termination of his service is thereby necessitated or materially
                accelerated, he shall be granted by the Chief Executive an injury pension at the
                annual rate of the proportion of his annual pay at the date of his injury which is
                in direct proportion to the percentage of permanent impairment to his capacity to
                contribute to his own support as a result of his injury.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692459_011" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The percentage of permanent impairment referred to in subsection (1) shall be
                assessed by a medical board appointed by the Secretary for Security.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692459_019" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If there is any subsequent variation in the degree of impairment, the rate at
                which the injury pension has been granted may be reassessed by the medical
                board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692459_027" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the Secretary for Security has decided the composition of the medical
                board, he shall as soon as may be cause to be published in the Gazette a notice
                giving particulars including the names, addresses and occupations of the members of
                the medical board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692459_035" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A member who is permanently injured while travelling by any means in pursuance
                of official instructions or in the course of his duties shall be deemed for the
                purposes of subsection (1) to have been so injured in the circumstances described in
                paragraphs (a) and (c) of that subsection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692474_005" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Subject to the approval of the Secretary for Security, an injury pension
                granted under subsection (1) shall be payable as soon as possible after the
                termination of service of the member and shall be paid in monthly instalments or
                less frequently if so requested by the member.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692474_013" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Notwithstanding subsection (6), where a member is granted a pension under the
                Pensions Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap89">Cap. 89</ref>), the Pension Benefits
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap99">Cap. 99</ref>) or the Pension Benefits (Judicial
                Officers) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap401">Cap. 401</ref>), an injury pension
                granted under subsection (1) shall be payable when the pension is paid to
                him.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904015_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Maximum pension</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411692521_020" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a member is granted any pension under the Pensions Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap89">Cap. 89</ref>), <ref>section 9(4)</ref> of that Ordinance
                applies to an injury pension granted to that member under <ref>section 3(1)</ref> as
                if the injury pension were an additional pension granted to that member under
                    <ref>regulation 31</ref> of the Pensions Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap89A">Cap. 89 sub. leg. A</ref>) in respect of injury but the words “for the first
                time” in that <ref>section 9(4)</ref> shall be construed as “in addition to any
                other pension or pensions for the first time”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692537_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a member is granted any pension under the Pension Benefits Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap99">Cap. 99</ref>), <ref>section 21(2)</ref> of that
                Ordinance applies to an injury pension granted to that member under <ref>section
                    3(1)</ref> as if the injury pension were an additional pension granted to that
                member under <ref>section 15(1)</ref> of that Ordinance or an additional pension
                granted to him under <ref>regulation 31</ref> of the Pensions Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap89A">Cap. 89 sub. leg. A</ref>) in respect of injury but the words
                “for the first time” in that <ref>section 21(2)</ref> shall be construed as “in
                addition to any other pension or pensions for the first time”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692568_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a member is granted any pension under the Pension Benefits (Judicial
                Officers) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap401">Cap. 401</ref>), <ref>section
                    22(2)</ref> of that Ordinance applies to an injury pension granted to that
                member under <ref>section 3(1)</ref> as if the injury pension were an additional
                pension granted to that member under <ref>section 15(1)</ref> of that Ordinance or
                of the Pension Benefits Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap99">Cap. 99</ref>) or an
                additional pension granted to him under <ref>regulation 31</ref> of the Pensions
                Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap89A">Cap. 89 sub. leg. A</ref>) in respect of injury
                but the words “for the first time” in that <ref>section 22(2)</ref> shall be
                construed as “in addition to any other pension or pensions for the first
                time”.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904031_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Death gratuity</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411692630_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a member dies as a result of any injury received—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692630_026" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the actual discharge of his duty;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692630_034" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>without his own serious and wilful misconduct; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692630_042" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on account of circumstances specifically attributable to the nature of his
                    duty,</content></paragraph><continued>there shall be paid a death gratuity of an amount calculated in accordance
                with subsection (2).</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692630_055" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A death gratuity payable under subsection (1) in respect of the death of a
                member shall be an amount equal to his annual pay at the date of his
                death.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692646_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A death gratuity shall be paid as soon as possible after the death of the member
                to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692646_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where he has nominated his spouse under subsection (5) to be the recipient
                    of the death gratuity, his spouse;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692646_021" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where there is no such nomination, his legal personal representative, and
                    shall form part of the estate of the member for the purposes of distribution but
                    no estate duty shall be payable in respect of the death gratuity and its
                    addition to the principal value of the estate shall not be taken in
                    consideration for the purpose of increasing the rate at which estate duty on the
                    remainder of the estate may be payable; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692646_029" name="c" temporalId="s5_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the death gratuity does not exceed such amount as may be determined
                    by the Chief Executive, a person named by the Chief Executive to be the
                        recipient.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692662_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A member who dies as a result of any injury received while travelling by any
                means in pursuance of official instructions or in the course of his duties shall be
                deemed for the purposes of subsection (1) to have died in circumstances described in
                paragraphs (a) and (c) of that subsection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692662_013" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A member may by notice in writing to the Secretary for Security nominate his
                spouse to be the recipient of the death gratuity payable under this section in
                respect of his death.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692662_021" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A member who makes a nomination under subsection (5) may at any time revoke the
                nomination by notice in writing to the Secretary for Security.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904046_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Dependant pension</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411692724_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (3), where a member dies as a result of any injury
                received—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692724_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the actual discharge of his duty;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692724_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>without his own serious and wilful misconduct; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692724_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on account of circumstances specifically attributable to the nature of his
                    duty,</content></paragraph><continued>there shall be granted by the Chief Executive, in addition to a death
                gratuity (if any)—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued><paragraph id="ID_1438411692724_042" name="i" temporalId="s6_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the deceased member leaves a spouse, a dependant pension to the spouse
                    at the rate of one-sixth of his annual pay at the date of the injury or $12,000
                    a year, whichever is the greater; but the Chief Executive may in his absolute
                    discretion grant a dependant pension under this paragraph at a rate not
                    exceeding one-fourth of the member’s annual pay;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692724_050" name="ii" temporalId="s6_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the deceased member leaves a spouse to whom a dependant pension is
                    granted under paragraph (i) and one or more children, a dependant pension to
                    each child of an amount of one-eighth of the dependant pension granted in
                    accordance with that paragraph;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692740_006" name="iii" temporalId="s6_1_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>if the deceased member leaves one or more children, but does not leave a
                    spouse or leaves a spouse to whom for whatever reason no dependant pension is
                    granted, a dependant pension to each child of double the amount determined, as
                    if paragraph (ii) had been applicable, under that paragraph; but the dependant
                    pension granted to a child or children under this paragraph shall not be less
                    than $6,000 in total a year where no other dependant pension is granted under
                    this section;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692740_014" name="iv" temporalId="s6_1_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>if the deceased member leaves one or more children and a spouse to whom a
                    dependant pension is granted, and the spouse subsequently dies or ceases for any
                    reason to receive the dependant pension, a dependant pension to each child, as
                    from the date of the death of the spouse or the date on which a dependant
                    pension to the spouse ceases, of double the amount determined, as if paragraph
                    (ii) had been applicable, under that paragraph; but the dependant pension
                    granted to a child or children under this paragraph shall not be less than
                    $6,000 in total a year where no other dependant pension is granted under this
                    section;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692771_006" name="v" temporalId="s6_1_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><leadIn>if the deceased member does not leave a spouse, or leaves a spouse to whom
                    for whatever reason no dependant pension is granted and—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411692771_014" name="A" temporalId="s6_1_v_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>if the mother or father of the deceased member was wholly or mainly
                        dependant on the deceased member financially, a dependant pension to the
                        mother or father, while she or he is without adequate means of support, of
                        an amount not exceeding the dependant pension which could have been granted
                        to the spouse under paragraph (i); but</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411692771_022" name="B" temporalId="s6_1_v_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>if both the mother and father of the deceased member are granted a
                        dependant pension under subparagraph (A), the dependant pension to each of
                        them shall not exceed half of the dependant pension which could have been
                        granted to the spouse under paragraph (i).</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692786_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to the approval of the Secretary for Security, a dependant pension
                shall be payable as soon as possible after the death of the member and shall be paid
                in monthly instalments or less frequently if so requested by the
                recipient.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692786_013" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A dependant pension—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692786_021" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall not be payable under subsection (1) at any time in respect of more
                    than 6 children, whether or not such children are the first 6 children of the
                    deceased member;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692786_029" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>when granted under subsection (1) ceases—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411692786_037" name="i" temporalId="s6_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of a child, at the appropriate time provided in subsection
                        (4);</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411692786_045" name="ii" temporalId="s6_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of the deceased member’s mother or father, as from such
                        date as the Chief Executive may determine if it appears to him at any time
                        that the mother or father, as the case may be, is adequately provided with
                        other means of support.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692786_051" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (5), a pension granted under this section to a child of a
                deceased member shall cease—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692802_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the age of 18 years unless at the time he attains that age he is
                    receiving continuous full-time education; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692802_013" name="b" temporalId="s6_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>at the time at which he has since attaining the age of 18 years ceased
                        to receive continuous full-time education:</leadIn>
                    <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_4_b_proviso">Provided that a pension that
                        has ceased under this paragraph may be paid again during the period when
                        such full-time education is resumed; or</proviso>
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692802_027" name="c" temporalId="s6_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>at the age of 23 years,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever first occurs.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692802_040" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Notwithstanding subsection (4), where a child to whom a dependant pension is
                granted under subsection (1) is accepted by the Secretary for Security as mentally
                or physically disabled to such extent that he cannot reasonably be expected to be
                financially independent, the dependant pension shall continue to be payable as long
                as he remains so disabled.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692802_048" name="6" temporalId="s6_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (4)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692802_056" name="a" temporalId="s6_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="FulltimeEducation"><term>full-time
                        education</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">全日制敎育</term>)
                    means full-time education at any university, college, school or other
                    educational establishment recognized as such by the Permanent Secretary for
                    Education; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/3">3 of 2003 s. 41</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N.
                            130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></def></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692818_005" name="b" temporalId="s6_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a child on normal university, college, school or other educational
                    establishment holidays or awaiting for a normal period for admission to a
                    university, college, school or other educational establishment is receiving
                    full-time education.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692818_012" name="7" temporalId="s6_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A member who dies as a result of any injury received while travelling by any
                means in pursuance of official instructions or in the course of his duties shall be
                deemed for the purposes of subsection (1) to have died in circumstances described in
                paragraphs (a) and (c) of that subsection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692818_020" name="8" temporalId="s6_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Legislative Council may, by resolution, vary in respect of members dying
                after a date that may be specified in the resolution, the sum of $12,000 specified
                in subsection <ref>(1)(i)</ref> and the sum of $6,000 specified in subsection
                    <ref>(1)(iii)</ref> and
                (iv);
                but the resolution shall not provide for a decrease in the minimum dependant pension
                in relation to members dying before the date of the resolution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692833_005" name="9" temporalId="s6_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>The recipient of a dependant pension may within 3 months after the commencement
                of the payment of the dependant pension, or such longer period
                as
                the Secretary for Security may approve, apply in writing to the Secretary for
                Security to commute the dependant pension payable into a lump sum.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692833_013" name="10" temporalId="s6_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>The lump sum referred to in subsection (9) shall be computed in accordance with
                an actuarial table prepared from time to time by an actuary appointed by the Chief
                    Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692833_021" name="11" temporalId="s6_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>Where an application is made under subsection (9), any amount paid in respect
                of the dependant pension before the commutation shall be deducted
                from
                the lump sum.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411692849_005" name="12" temporalId="s6_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>The lump sum referred to in subsection (9) may for the purposes of payment be
                divided into such number of parts as the Secretary for Security thinks
                fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904077_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Medical attention</heading><content>A member whose service is terminated in the circumstances described in <ref>section 3</ref> is after the termination entitled to free medical treatment by the Government medical services and the Hospital Authority, and, if admitted to a hospital under the management and control of the Hospital Authority, free maintenance in the hospital and during the period of the treatment in respect of the injury in relation to which his service is so terminated or of any condition arising from the injury.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402904077_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Exclusion from application</heading><leadIn>This Regulation does not apply—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411692927_019" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a member who, in consequence of any injury, is entitled to and has received compensation under the Employees’ Compensation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap282">Cap. 282</ref>), the Pneumoconiosis and Mesothelioma (Compensation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap360">Cap. 360</ref>) or the Occupational Deafness (Compensation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap469">Cap. 469</ref>); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411692942_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of the death of any member, if his member of the family as defined in <ref>section 3</ref> of the Employees’ Compensation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap282">Cap. 282</ref>) or <ref>section 2</ref> of the Pneumoconiosis and Mesothelioma (Compensation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap360">Cap. 360</ref>), are entitled to and have received compensation in respect of the death under the Employees’ Compensation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap282">Cap. 282</ref>) or the Pneumoconiosis and Mesothelioma (Compensation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap360">Cap. 360</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/52">52 of 2000 s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2008/6">6 of 2008 s. 44</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402904093_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-29" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><content>Nothing in the Employees’ Compensation (Amendment) (No. 2) Ordinance 2000 (<ref href="/hk/2000/52">52 of 2000</ref>)
          (<b><i>the
          amending
      Ordinance</i></b>)
      shall apply to claims for compensation in respect of accidents occurring before the
      commencement* of the amending Ordinance, and the provisions in force immediately before the
      commencement of
      the amending Ordinance shall continue to apply to such claims as if they had not been amended
      by the amending Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/52">52 of 2000 s. 34</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1605497922004_001"><content>Editorial Note:</content><content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement
                date:
                1
                August 2000.</content></editorialNote></section></main></subLeg>