<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 104 sub. leg. D</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>104D</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap104D!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-06-30</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402541033_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-06-30">Hong Kong
            and
            Yaumati
            Ferry
            Company
            By-laws</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap104/s45">Cap. 104, sections
                45</ref>
            &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap104/s46">46(2)</ref>)
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[4 June 1965]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1612321051658_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content>These by-laws
                shall
                continue in
                operation—see
                    <ref href="/hk/cap104/s45">sections 45</ref> and
                    <ref href="/hk/cap104/s46">46(2)</ref>
                of
                the
                Ferry Services
                Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap104">Cap. 104</ref>).</content>
        </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438402541049_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These by-laws may be cited as the Hong Kong and Yaumati Ferry Company By-laws.
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541065_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these by-laws—</leadIn><def name="FerryVessel"><term>Ferry
                vessel</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">渡輪</term>) means a ferry vessel belonging to the
            Company.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402541080_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Conduct of the public and provisions in respect of tickets, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410817219_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410817219_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>trespass on any part of the Company’s piers or other place exclusively reserved for the Company’s ferries or on any part of the Company’s premises; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817219_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>alight, or attempt to alight from, or enter, or attempt to enter, any ferry vessel while in motion or alight, or attempt to alight from, or enter, or attempt to enter, any ferry vessel except by the proper entrances or exits, and no person shall open or remove, or attempt to open or remove, or climb over, or attempt to climb over, any barrier or gate erected on any of the Company’s piers; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817219_028" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>travel, or attempt to travel, or bring any vehicle, on board the deck of any ferry vessel after being warned by any servant of the Company that such deck contains its full complement of passengers or vehicles; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817235_006" name="d" temporalId="s3_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>travel on a special ferry vessel, unless the same is advertised as being for the public use, except by permission of the person who hired or engaged such ferry vessel; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817235_014" name="e" temporalId="s3_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>embark on or disembark from any ferry vessel from or to any sampans, boats or other craft if any other means of embarkation or disembarkation is provided; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817235_022" name="f" temporalId="s3_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>embark on or travel by any ferry vessel without having first paid the proper fare; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817235_030" name="g" temporalId="s3_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>spit in or from or against any ferry vessel or any of the Company’s piers or premises; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817235_038" name="h" temporalId="s3_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>wilfully obstruct any person acting under the authority of the Company in the lawful discharge of his duties. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817235_045" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All tickets issued in exchange for payment of the fare (with the exception of
                monthly or season tickets) shall be handed unmutilated to the ticket collector on
                the pier for checking and must be surrendered to the ticket collector on board the
                ferry vessel or at the place of destination. In a class or classes for which no
                tickets are issued in exchange for payment of the fare, each passenger must, before
                embarking, pass through the appropriate turnstile situate on the Company’s piers.
                </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541096_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Conduct of passengers</heading><leadIn>No passenger shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410817282_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>stand upon any seat, or place his feet on any seat, on a ferry vessel or on any of the Company’s piers; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817282_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>smoke in any part of a ferry vessel marked “No Smoking”; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817282_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>smoke or carry a lighted pipe, cigar or cigarette in or upon any part of any ferry vessel in such a manner as to cause a nuisance or inconvenience to other passengers; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817282_036" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>travel in a class superior to that for which his ticket is issued; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817282_044" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><leadIn>except in cases of emergency—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410817282_052" name="i" temporalId="s4_e_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>pass from one deck to another unless he is the driver or passenger of a vehicle that is being carried on a ferry vessel in which he is travelling; or </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410817282_060" name="ii" temporalId="s4_e_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>open any grill or door on any ferry vessel in order to pass from one deck to another;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln171">L.N. 171 of 1967</ref>)</sourceNote> </content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817282_067" name="f" temporalId="s4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>enter or attempt to enter the engine room, wheel-house or bridge of any ferry vessel or any part of any ferry vessel which is marked “No Admittance”; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817297_006" name="g" temporalId="s4_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>swear or use obscene or offensive language while in or upon any ferry vessel or
                any of the Company’s piers or premises, or commit any nuisance in
                or
                from or against any ferry vessel or any of the Company’s piers or premises;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817297_014" name="h" temporalId="s4_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>stand upon or obstruct the approaches to the gangway or other appliance of any ferry vessel or impede or hamper in any way the movement of such gangway or appliance; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817297_022" name="i" temporalId="s4_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>gamble or attempt to gamble on any of the Company’s piers or on any ferry vessel;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln171">L.N. 171 of
                    1967</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817297_030" name="j" temporalId="s4_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>throw or attempt to throw any life buoy or any equipment on or from any of the Company’s piers or on or from any ferry vessel except in cases of emergency; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817297_038" name="k" temporalId="s4_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>throw or attempt to throw any rubbish from any of the Company’s piers or from any ferry vessel; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817297_046" name="l" temporalId="s4_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>beg or attempt to beg on any of the Company’s piers or on any ferry vessel; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817313_006" name="m" temporalId="s4_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>hawk or attempt to hawk, sell or attempt to sell any article or service,
                distribute or attempt to distribute any pamphlet on any of the Company’s piers or on
                any ferry vessel unless written authority has been obtained from the Company.
                </content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402541111_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Luggage</heading><content>No person shall take in any ferry vessel as personal luggage anything other than small
            handbaskets, bag or parcels of a form or description not calculated to annoy or
            inconvenience other passengers. The personal luggage taken by any one person shall not
            exceed in the aggregate 28 pounds in weight or 1 cubic foot in measurement. All such
            personal luggage shall be carried by hand and be under the personal care and control of
            the person taking the same. The Company shall not be responsible for its safe custody or
            any damage sustained by it. Such personal luggage shall not occupy any part of the
            seats.
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541111_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Monthly and season tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410817375_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every monthly or season ticket shall bear in legible form the name of the
                holder thereof and a recent photograph of the
                    holder.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln171">L.N. 171 of
                        1967</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817375_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every monthly or season ticket holder shall for the purpose of identification
                sign all monthly or season tickets purchased by him. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817375_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No passenger shall use, or attempt to use, any season ticket which is not
                issued in the passenger’s own name or upon the face of which the passenger’s own
                name and photograph do not appear, and no monthly ticket holder shall sell or
                transfer, or attempt to sell or transfer, a monthly ticket of which he is the holder
                to any other person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln171">L.N. 171 of 1967</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817391_004" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Holders of monthly or season tickets shall not travel on any special ferry
                vessels which are advertised as being for the public use without paying the same
                fare and in the same manner as persons other than monthly or season ticket holders.
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817391_012" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>All monthly and season tickets shall be produced for inspection by any of the
                Company’s servants whenever the holder is entering upon any of the Company’s piers,
                and every monthly or season ticket holder whenever travelling on any ferry vessel,
                or being on any of the Company’s piers, shall on demand by any servant of the
                Company produce his monthly or season ticket for examination or in default shall pay
                the same fare for the journey as that legally demandable from a passenger who is not
                a monthly or season ticket holder. </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541127_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Forfeiture and cancellation of monthly and season tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410817422_012" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the event of any monthly or season ticket holder contravening any of these
                by-laws in
                connexion
                with such monthly or season ticket, any servant of the Company shall be entitled, on
                being satisfied that an offence has been committed, to retain such ticket.
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410817438_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Company shall be entitled, on being satisfied that an offence has been
                committed against these by-laws, to forfeit such monthly or season ticket and shall
                not be under any liability to make any refund in respect thereof.
                </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402541143_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Dress</heading><content>No person whose dress or clothing may in the opinion of any servant of the Company soil or
            injure the seats or fittings of any ferry vessel or of the Company’s piers or the dress
            or clothing of any other passenger, and no person who in the opinion of any servant of
            the Company may for any other reason be offensive to passengers shall enter upon any of
            the Company’s piers or travel in any ferry vessel, and it shall be lawful for the
            Company’s servants to prevent any such person from so doing.
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541143_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Dogs or other animals</heading><content>No person shall take a dog or other animal in any ferry vessel or on any of the Company’s
                                    piers except on a lead and after first having obtained the
                                    permission of a servant of the Company on duty. Any dog or
                                    animal taken
                                    into
                                    or upon any ferry vessel or any of the Company’s piers shall be
                                    removed by the person in charge of such dog or other animal from
                                    the ferry vessel or pier immediately on request by any servant
                                    of the Company, and in default of compliance with such request
                                    may be removed by or under the direction of the Company’s
                                    servants.
                                    </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541158_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Intoxication</heading><content>No person who in the opinion of any servant of the Company is in such a state of
            intoxication as to render him or her unfit to travel on any ferry vessel shall enter
            upon any pier belonging to the Company or any ferry vessel, and any servant of the
            Company may refuse to allow any such person access to the Company’s piers or ferry
            vessels.
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541174_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Damage</heading><content>No person shall wilfully
            damage,
            injure or deface any of the Company’s property.
            </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541189_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Restriction on persons who may enter vessels or piers</heading><content>No person except a passenger or an intending passenger, or police or revenue officers in
            the active pursuance of their duty, shall enter upon any ferry vessel or any of the
            Company’s piers. Nothing contained in this by-law shall be deemed to authorize any
            police or revenue officer to enter upon any ferry vessel or upon any of the Company’s
            piers except upon duty and for the purpose of performing some act in pursuance of that
            duty.
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541189_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Vehicles</heading><content>Every vehicle, before embarkation on any ferry vessel provided for the transport of vehicles, shall pass over the weigh-bridge (if provided) and through the enclosed car park. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln171">L.N. 171 of 1967</ref>) </sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541205_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Duties of drivers of vehicles on ferry vessels</heading><leadIn>Every driver of any vehicle which is transported or is intended to be transported by any ferry vessel or is proceeding to or from any ferry vessel shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410817547_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>drive with due care and attention and with reasonable consideration for other persons using the ferry or approaching to or from the ferry; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817547_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>proceed at slow speed along any ramp and along the deck of a ferry vessel; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817547_028" name="c" temporalId="s14_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>obey all lawful instructions which may be given to him by any servant of the Company; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817547_036" name="d" temporalId="s14_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if the vehicle is a motor vehicle, stop the engine thereof as soon as the vehicle is on board and in position for transport; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410817547_044" name="e" temporalId="s14_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>pay the proper fare for the carriage of the vehicle, its freight (if any) and passengers. </content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln171">L.N. 171 of 1967</ref>) </sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541221_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Power of Company’s servants to demand name and address</heading><content>If any servant of the Company has reason to believe that any person has contravened or is
            contravening any of these by-laws, he may ask such person for his name and address, and
            such person shall then forthwith furnish to the servant of the Company his true name and
            his true address.
            </content></section><section id="ID_1438402541299_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Penalties</heading><content>Any person who contravenes any of these by-laws shall be guilty of an offence and
            shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
            at level
            1.
        </content></section><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></main></subLeg>