<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 188 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>188A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap188A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-09-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402811819_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-09-19">Maintenance
                        Orders (Reciprocal Enforcement)
                        Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap188/s19">Cap. 188,
                                section
                        19</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[31 January 1979]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of
                        2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402811819_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These rules may be cited as the Maintenance Orders (Reciprocal Enforcement) Rules.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402811834_002" name="s2" reason="repealed" role="rule" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1982</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811850_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Requirements for application under <ref>section 4</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504088_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An application under <ref>section 4</ref> of the Ordinance (transmission of maintenance order made in Hong Kong for enforcement in a reciprocating country) may be made in writing by or on behalf of the payee under the order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504088_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any application made in pursuance of paragraph (1) shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411504088_020" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>specify the date on which the order was made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504088_028" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>contain such particulars as are known to the applicant of the whereabouts of the payer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504104_006" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>specify any matters likely to assist in the identification of the payer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504104_014" name="d" temporalId="s3_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>where possible, be accompanied by a recent photograph of the payer.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504104_021" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="ThePayer">In this rule,
                    <term>the
                    payer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">付款人</term>) means the payer under the order to
                which the application relates.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811850_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Authentication of document setting out or summarizing evidence</heading><content>A document setting out or summarizing any evidence required by <ref>section 5(5)(b)</ref>, <ref>6(4)</ref> or <ref>10(5)</ref> of the Ordinance (provisional orders) to be authenticated shall be authenticated by a certificate, signed by the judge before whom that evidence was given, that the document is the original document containing or recording or, as the case may be, summarizing that evidence or a true copy of that document.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402811866_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Method of transmission of documents to reciprocating country</heading><content>Any documents required by <ref>section 6(4)</ref> or <ref>10(5)</ref> of the Ordinance to be sent to a court in a reciprocating country shall be sent to that court by post.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402811881_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Procedure upon revocation of a provisional order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504151_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of compliance with <ref>section 6(9)</ref> of the Ordinance (revocation by Hong Kong court of provisional order) there shall be served on the person on whose application the maintenance order was made a notice which shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411504151_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>set out the evidence received or taken, as the case may be, in pursuance of that subsection;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504151_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>inform that person that it appears to the court that the maintenance order ought not to have been made; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504151_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>inform that person that if he wishes to make representations with respect to the evidence set out in the notice he may do so orally or in writing and that if he wishes to adduce further evidence he should notify the Registrar.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504151_035" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Registrar receives notification that the person on whose application the maintenance order was made wishes to adduce further evidence, he shall fix a date for the hearing of such evidence and shall send that person written notice of the date fixed.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811881_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Registration of order other than provisional order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504182_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a certified copy of an order, not being a provisional order, is received
                by the Registrar of the District Court for registration in accordance with the
                Ordinance, he shall cause the order to be registered by means of a minute or
                memorandum entered and signed by him in a register kept by him for this purpose.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of
                1982</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504182_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the District Court makes or confirms an order which is required under
                    <ref>section 8(5)</ref> or <ref>10(10)</ref> of the Ordinance to be registered,
                the Registrar shall enter and sign a minute or memorandum thereof in his register.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of
                1982</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504198_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Every minute or memorandum entered in pursuance of paragraph (1) or (2) shall
                specify the section of the Ordinance under which the order in question is
                registered.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811912_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Method of payment of sums due under a provisional order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504213_026" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Payment of sums due under a registered order shall, while the order is
                registered in the District Court, be made to the Registrar during such hours and at
                such place as he may direct; and the Registrar shall send those payments by post to
                the court which made the order or to such other person or authority as that court or
                the Chief Executive may from time to time direct.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504229_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where it appears to the Registrar to whom payments under any maintenance order
                are made by virtue of paragraph (1) that any sums payable under the order are in
                arrear he may and, if such sums are in arrear to an amount equal to four times the
                sum payable weekly under the order, he shall, whether the person for whose benefit
                the payment should have been made requests him to do so or not, proceed in his
                office and title of Registrar for the recovery of those sums, unless it appears to
                him that it is unreasonable in the circumstances to do so.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811928_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Procedure for taking evidence in Hong Kong at the request of a court in a reciprocating country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504260_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a request is made by or on behalf of a court in a reciprocating country for the taking in Hong Kong of the evidence of a person residing therein then, subject to paragraph (2)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411504260_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the evidence shall be taken in the same manner as if that person were a witness in proceedings on a summons;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504260_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any oral evidence so taken shall be put into writing and read to the person who gave it, who shall be required to sign the document; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504260_028" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the judge by whom the evidence of any person is so taken shall certify at the foot of any document setting out the evidence of, or produced in evidence by, that person that such evidence was taken, or document received in evidence, as the case may be, by him.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504260_035" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where such a request as is mentioned in paragraph (1) includes a request that the evidence be taken in a particular manner, the judge by whom the evidence is taken shall, so far as circumstances permit, comply with that request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504260_043" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any document such as is mentioned in paragraph <ref>(1)(c)</ref> shall be sent to the court in the reciprocating country by or on behalf of which the request was made.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811944_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Transmission of orders varying, revoking or confirming maintenance orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504307_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a court in Hong Kong makes an order, not being a provisional order,
                varying a maintenance order to which <ref>section 6</ref> of the Ordinance
                (variation and revocation of maintenance order made in Hong Kong) applies the
                Registrar shall send written notice of the making of the order to the Chief
                Executive; and where the order is made by virtue of paragraph (a) or (b) of
                subsection (3) of that section, he shall send such written notice to the court in a
                reciprocating country which would, if the order had been a provisional order, have
                had power to confirm the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504322_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a court in Hong Kong revokes a maintenance order to which <ref>section
                    6</ref> of the Ordinance applies, the Registrar shall send written notice of the
                revocation to the Chief Executive and to the court in a reciprocating country which
                has power to confirm that maintenance order, or by which the order has been
                confirmed, or in which the order is registered for enforcement, as the case may
                    be.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of
                        1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504338_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where under <ref>section 10</ref> of the Ordinance (variation and revocation of
                maintenance order registered in the District Court in Hong Kong) the District Court
                makes an order, not being a provisional order, varying or revoking a registered
                order, the Registrar shall send written notice of the making of the order to the
                court in a reciprocating country which made the registered order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504338_013" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where under <ref>section 8(2)</ref> of the Ordinance (confirmation by District
                Court of a provisional maintenance order made in a reciprocating country) the
                District Court confirms an order to which <ref>section 8</ref> of the Ordinance
                applies, the Registrar shall send written notice of the confirmation to the court in
                a reciprocating country which made the order.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1982</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811944_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Notice to be given to Chief Executive where order is registered</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504369_034" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where the Registrar of the District Court—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1982</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411504369_042" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>registers under <ref>section 7(3)</ref> of the Ordinance (registration in
                    Hong Kong of a maintenance order made in a reciprocating country) an order to
                    which <ref>section 7</ref> applies; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504385_006" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>registers under <ref>section 8(5)</ref> of the Ordinance an order which has
                    been confirmed in pursuance of <ref>section 8(2)</ref> of the
                    Ordinance,</content></paragraph><continued>he shall send written notice to the Chief Executive that the order has been
                duly registered.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/27">27 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504385_019" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1982</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402811959_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Notice to be given to payer where order is registered or cancelled</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411504416_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where the Registrar of the District Court registers a maintenance order under <ref>section 7(3)</ref>, <ref>8(5)</ref> or <ref>10(10)</ref> of the Ordinance, he shall send to the payer under the order written notice stating—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411504416_012" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the order has been duly registered;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504416_020" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that sums due under the order should be paid to the Registrar; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411504416_028" name="c" temporalId="s12_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the hours during which and the place at which such payments should be made.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411504416_035" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Registrar of the District Court cancels the registration of a maintenance order under <ref>section 11(1)</ref> of the Ordinance (cancellation of registration of order) he shall send written notice of the cancellation to the payer under the order.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1982</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402811975_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Revocation and saving</heading><content>The Maintenance Orders (Facilities for Enforcement) Rules
            (Cap.
            15
            sub. leg. 1969 Ed.) are revoked, but shall continue to apply to such extent as may be
            necessary for giving effect to the savings and transitional provisions in the
            Maintenance Orders (Reciprocal Enforcement) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap188">Cap.
                188</ref>).</content></section></main></subLeg>