<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 116 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>116C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap116C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-05-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402626974_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-05-13">Rating
            (Effective Date of Interim Valuation) Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap116/s28">Cap.
                116,
                sections
                28</ref> and <ref href="/hk/cap116/s53">53</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 August 1995]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402626990_002" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402627021_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="BuildingLicence"><term>building
                licence</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築許可證</term>) means, in relation to any land the
            subject of a Government grant, a licence granted to any person by the Government under
            or by virtue of the Government grant permitting the erection on the land of a building
            or buildings;</def><def name="CertificateOfCompliance"><term>certificate
                of
            compliance</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合格證明書</term>) means, in relation to any land the
            subject of a Government grant, a document or instrument signed by the Director of Lands
            or any person authorized by him in that behalf certifying that all the positive
            obligations imposed on the grantee and his successors and assigns under the Government
            grant have been complied with to the satisfaction of the Director of Lands or of the
            person so authorized, as the case may be;</def><def name="EffectiveDate"><term>effective
                date</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">生效日期</term>) has the same meaning as in <ref>section
                28(1)</ref> of the Ordinance; </def><def name="GovernmentGrant"><leadIn><term>Government
                    grant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">政府批地書</term>) means, in relation to any land,
                any—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411084869_040" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>grant by the Government to any person of the land;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411084869_048" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>agreement for the grant by the Government to any person of the land; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411084884_006" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>lease expressed to be granted for a period of not more than 7 years by the Government to any person of the land;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411084884_014" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>licence issued by the Government for the occupation by any person of the land; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411084884_022" name="e" temporalId="s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>other document or instrument howsoever described under or by virtue of which the Government disposes or agrees to dispose of the land to any person;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Land"><term>land</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地</term>) includes a part of any land and any interest
            in land;</def><def name="RestrictionOnAlienation"><term>restriction
                on
            alienation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">讓與權的限制</term>) means, in relation to any land the
            subject of a Government grant, a condition contained in the Government grant restricting
            the alienation of the land by the grantee and his successors and assigns whether by way
            of an agreement, an assignment, a lease, a mortgage or otherwise prior to the compliance
            with the conditions of the Government grant save and except with the consent in writing
            of the Director of Lands and in accordance with the Government grant.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402627036_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Effective date of interim valuation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411084916_018" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (2), the effective date of an interim valuation in respect of a tenement in a newly constructed building shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411084916_026" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of such a tenement to be used wholly or primarily for domestic purposes, a date 90 days from the date of issue of the document specified in relation to the tenement in <ref>section 5</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411084931_006" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the case of any other such tenement—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411084931_014" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a date 180 days from the date of issue of the document specified in relation to the tenement in <ref>section 5</ref>; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411084931_022" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the date on which that tenement was first occupied,</content></subparagraph><continued>whichever is the earlier.</continued></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411084931_034" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The effective date of an interim valuation in respect of a tenement in a newly constructed building to which <ref>section 5(1)(a)</ref> applies and which was first occupied before the earliest issue of the document specified in relation to the tenement in that section shall be the date of such first occupation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411084931_042" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Section 71</ref> of the Interpretation and General Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>) does not apply to the determination of an effective date under this section.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/53">53 of 1997 s. 54</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402627036_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Application of <ref>section 3</ref></heading><content><ref>Section 3</ref> shall not apply as regards any tenement in respect of which the Commissioner has determined an effective date under <ref>section 28(1)(c)</ref> of the Ordinance. </content></section><section id="ID_1438402627068_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Documents relevant to determination of effective date of interim valuation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411084994_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The following documents are specified for the purposes of <ref>section 3</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411084994_026" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>as regards a tenement in a newly constructed building in respect of which a certificate of exemption has been issued under <ref>section 4</ref> or <ref>5</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (Application to the New Territories) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap121">Cap. 121</ref>), a certificate of compliance, document or instrument signed by the Director of Lands or any person authorized by him in that behalf certifying or stating that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411084994_034" name="i" temporalId="s5_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the conditions contained in the building licence or in the Government grant including those relating to the erection of the building, if any, have been complied with; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411085009_007" name="ii" temporalId="s5_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the Director of Lands or the person so authorized, as the case may be, has no objection to the building being occupied;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411085009_014" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>as regards a tenement that forms the whole or part of a building newly constructed by or on behalf of the Hong Kong Housing Authority for sale as a tenement to be used wholly or primarily for domestic purposes, a document or instrument signed by the Director of Housing or any person authorized by him in that behalf certifying that the building is completed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411085009_022" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>as regards a tenement in any other newly constructed building—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411085009_030" name="i" temporalId="s5_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>except as provided in subparagraph (ii), an occupation permit or temporary occupation permit issued under <ref>section 21</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>) and if more than one such permit is issued in respect of the tenement, the earliest such permit so issued; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411085025_007" name="ii" temporalId="s5_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if a restriction on alienation is contained in the Government grant in respect of the land on which the building is erected, but subject to subsection (2), a consent in writing signed by the Director of Lands or any person authorized by him in that behalf to the lease of the building or a part or parts thereof which include the tenement or to the assignment of an interest in the land upon which the building has been erected, or a certificate of compliance in respect of the land upon which the building has been erected, whichever is the earliest issued.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411085040_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subsection <ref>(1)(c)(ii)</ref> shall not apply if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411085040_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the consent in writing referred to in that subsection is issued earlier than the occupation permit or temporary occupation permit in respect of the tenement; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411085040_021" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>either that consent in writing or the certificate of compliance referred to in that subsection is issued subsequent to the first occupation of any tenement within the building,</content></paragraph><continued>and in any such case, the document specified for the purposes of <ref>section 3</ref> shall be the occupation permit or temporary occupation permit, whichever is the earliest issued.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402627068_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><content>This Regulation shall not apply to a tenement the notice of interim valuation of
            which was first served under <ref>section 26</ref> of the Ordinance before the
            commencement*
            of this Regulation.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1613700636877_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 August
                1995.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></main></subLeg>