<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 59 sub. leg. J</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>59J</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap59J!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-12-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403506188_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2024-12-19">Factories
                                    and Industrial Undertakings (Lifting Appliances and Lifting
                                    Gear) Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap59/s7">Cap. 59,
                                                section
                                    7</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 November 1974]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1974/ln211">L.N. 211 of
                                                  1974</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
                                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403506235_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403506251_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the <shortTitle>Factories and Industrial Undertakings (Lifting Appliances and Lifting Gear) Regulations</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403506266_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Application</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413663498_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>These regulations shall apply to lifting appliances and lifting gear used for raising or lowering or as a means of suspension in any industrial undertaking.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of 1978</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663498_012" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506266_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413663529_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><def name="AutomaticSafeLoadIndicator"><term>automatic
                    safe load
                indicator</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">安全負荷自動顯示器</term>) means a device intended to be
                fitted to a crane that automatically gives an audible and visible warning to the
                operator thereof that the crane is approaching its safe working load and that
                automatically gives a further audible and visible warning when the crane has
                exceeded its safe working
                    load;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of
                        1993</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="CompetentExaminer">
                <leadIn><term>competent
                        examiner</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合資格檢驗員</term>), in relation to the carrying out
                    of any test and examination required by these regulations, means a person who
                    is—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663529_026" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>appointed by the owner required by these regulations to ensure that the
                        test and examination is carried out;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of
                                1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663529_034" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a registered professional engineer registered under the Engineers
                        Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap409">Cap. 409</ref>) within a
                        relevant discipline specified by the Commissioner; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N.
                                285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663545_006" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by reason of his qualifications, training and experience, competent to
                        carry out the test and examination;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of
                                1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="CompetentPerson">
                <leadIn><term>competent
                        person</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合資格的人</term>), in relation to any duty required
                    to be performed by him under these regulations, means a person who is—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663545_020" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>appointed by the owner required by these regulations to ensure that the
                        duty is carried out by a competent person; and</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663545_028" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by reason of training and practical experience, competent to perform
                        the duty;</content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="ConstructionSite"><term>construction
                    site</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築地盤</term>) means a place where construction work
                is undertaken and includes any area in the immediate vicinity which is used for the
                storage of materials or plant used or intended to be used for the purpose of the
                construction work;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Crane">
                <leadIn><term>crane</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">起重機</term>) means any appliance equipped with
                    mechanical means of raising and lowering a load and for transporting the load
                    while suspended; and also all chains, ropes, swivels, or other tackle (down to
                    and including the hook), used in the operation of a crane; but does not
                    include—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663560_005" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a hoist block running on a fixed rail or wire;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663560_013" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a stacker or conveyer whereby a load is moved by means of a belt or
                        platform; or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663560_021" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an earth or mineral moving or excavating appliance not fitted with a
                        grab;</content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="LiftingAppliance"><term>lifting
                    appliance</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">起重機械</term>) means a crab, winch, teagle, pulley
                block or gin wheel used for raising or lowering, and a crane, sheerlegs, excavator,
                pile driver, pile extractor, dragline, aerial ropeway, aerial cableway transporter
                or overhead runway, and also any part of any such appliance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of
                    1993</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="LiftingGear"><term>lifting
                    gear</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">起重裝置</term>) means a chain sling, rope sling, ring
                or similar gear, and a link, hook, plate clamp, shackle, swivel or eyebolt;</def><def name="Maintained"><term>maintained</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">維修</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">保持</term>)
                means maintained in an efficient state, in efficient working order and good
                repair;</def><def name="Owner"><term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>), in relation to any lifting appliance
                or lifting gear, includes the lessee or hirer thereof, and any overseer, foreman,
                agent or person in charge or having the control or management of the lifting
                appliance or lifting gear, and the contractor who has control over the way any
                construction work which involves the use of the lifting appliance or lifting gear is
                carried out and, in the case of a lifting appliance or lifting gear situated on or
                used in connection with work on a construction site, also includes the contractor
                responsible for the construction site;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2003/ln260">L.N. 260 of 2003</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="RaisingOrLoweringOrAsAMeansOfSuspension"><term>raising
                    or lowering or as a means of
                suspension</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">升降或作懸吊之用</term>) means raising or lowering or as a
                means of suspension of a load on a lifting appliance or lifting gear;</def><def name="Repair"><term>repair</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">修理</term>) includes renewal, alteration or
                addition;</def><def name="SafeWorkingLoad">
                <leadIn><term>safe
                        working
                    load</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">安全操作負荷</term>), in relation to a lifting
                    appliance or to lifting gear, means either—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663591_005" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the appropriate safe working load for operating the lifting appliance
                        or lifting gear as specified in the current certificate of test and thorough
                        examination delivered in the approved form by a competent examiner in
                        respect of that lifting appliance or lifting gear for the purposes of these
                        regulations; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413663591_013" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where no such certificate is required, the relevant safe working load
                        shown in the table referred to in <ref>regulation 18(1)(b)</ref>;</content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="ThoroughExamination"><term>thorough
                    examination</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">徹底檢驗</term>) means a visual examination, carried
                out as carefully as the conditions permit in order to arrive at a reliable
                conclusion as to the safety of the parts examined, and if necessary for the purpose
                the visual examination shall be supplemented if necessary by other means such as a
                hammer test and, parts of the lifting appliance or lifting gear shall be
                dismantled.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663607_004" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of these regulations, a contractor is responsible for a construction site if he is undertaking construction work there or, where there is more than one contractor undertaking construction work at the site, if he is the principal contractor undertaking construction work there.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403506282_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Lifting
            Appliances</heading><section id="ID_1438403506298_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Construction</heading><leadIn>The owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413663685_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it is of good mechanical construction, made of strong and sound materials, and free from patent defect;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663701_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it is properly maintained;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663701_014" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the arrangements for fixing and anchoring the appliance are adequate to secure its safety;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663701_022" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>it is adequately and securely supported; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663701_030" name="e" temporalId="s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>every structure supporting it is of good construction and adequate strength, of sound materials and free from patent defect.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403506313_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Lifting appliances to be tested and examined prior to use</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413663732_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used unless it has been thoroughly examined by a competent examiner at least once in the preceding 12 months, and a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order has been obtained.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663732_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance other than a crane, crab or winch shall ensure that it is not used unless it has been tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner in the manner prescribed in the <ref>First Schedule</ref>, and a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order has been obtained.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663747_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The owner of any crane, crab or winch shall ensure that it is not used unless during the preceding 4 years it has been tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner in the manner prescribed in the <ref>First Schedule</ref>, and a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order has been obtained.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663763_004" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If any lifting appliance of the description mentioned in paragraph (1) or (2) has been thoroughly examined or tested and thoroughly examined, as the case may be, in accordance with those paragraphs but has since undergone substantial repair, re-erection, failure, overturning or collapse, the owner of the lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used unless it has been further tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner, and there has been obtained from him in respect of the test and thorough examination a certificate in the approved form in which he has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663779_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If any crane, crab or winch has been tested and thoroughly examined but has since undergone substantial repair, re-erection, failure, overturning or collapse, the owner of the crane, crab or winch shall ensure that it is not used unless it has been further tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner, and there has been obtained from him in respect of the test and thorough examination a certificate in the approved form in which he has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506313_003" name="s6" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506329_002" name="s6A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6A"><num value="6A">6A.</num><heading>Report by competent examiner</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413663857_004" name="1" temporalId="s6A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a test or a thorough examination under <ref>regulation 5</ref> shows that any lifting appliance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413663857_012" name="a" temporalId="s6A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is in safe working order, the competent examiner shall deliver the certificate issued under <ref>regulation 5(1)</ref>, (2), (3), (4) or (5) to the owner of the lifting appliance within 28 days after the test or the thorough examination; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663857_020" name="b" temporalId="s6A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>cannot be used safely unless certain repairs are carried out, the competent examiner shall immediately inform the owner of the lifting appliance of that fact and shall, within 14 days after the test or the thorough examination, deliver a report to the owner of the lifting appliance and a copy of it to the Commissioner.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663857_027" name="2" temporalId="s6A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the owner of the lifting appliance is informed under paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref> that repairs must be carried out he shall ensure that the lifting appliance is not used until the repairs have been effected.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506329_004" name="s7" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506344_002" name="s7A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7A"><num value="7A">7A.</num><heading>Periodical inspection by a competent person</heading><content>The owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used unless it has
            been inspected within the preceding 7 days by a competent person and the competent
            person has given the owner a certificate in the approved form in which he has made a
            statement to the effect that the lifting appliance is in safe working order.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506360_001" name="s7B" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7B"><num value="7B">7B.</num><heading>Automatic safe load indicator required</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413663935_004" name="1" temporalId="s7B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a crane shall ensure that it is not used unless it is fitted with an automatic safe load indicator that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413663935_012" name="a" temporalId="s7B_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>functions properly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663935_020" name="b" temporalId="s7B_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has been tested by a competent examiner on each occasion that a test and thorough examination of the crane is required under <ref>regulation 5</ref> and the competent examiner has given the owner a certificate in the approved form in which he has made a statement to the effect that the automatic safe load indicator is in good working order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663950_005" name="c" temporalId="s7B_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>has been inspected by a competent person and determined to be in safe working order during each inspection of the crane required under <ref>regulation 7A</ref> and the competent person has given the owner a certificate in the approved form in which he has made a statement to the effect that the automatic safe load indicator is in good working order.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413663950_012" name="2" temporalId="s7B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This regulation does not apply to a crane with a maximum safe working load of 1 tonne or less or a crane that operates with a grab or any electro magnetic means.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506360_003" name="s7C" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7C"><num value="7C">7C.</num><heading>Poles or beams supporting pulley blocks or gin wheels</heading><leadIn>The owner of any pulley block or gin wheel which is suspended from or supported by a pole or beam shall ensure that the block or wheel is not used for raising or lowering any load unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413663997_005" name="a" temporalId="s7C_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it is effectively secured to the pole or beam; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413663997_013" name="b" temporalId="s7C_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the pole or beam is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413663997_021" name="i" temporalId="s7C_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>of adequate strength for the purpose for which it is intended to be used; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413663997_029" name="ii" temporalId="s7C_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>adequately and properly secured so as to support the block or wheel and the load with safety and to prevent undue movement of the pole or beam.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506360_005" name="s7D" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7D"><num value="7D">7D.</num><heading>Stability of lifting appliances</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664028_004" name="1" temporalId="s7D_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Before a lifting appliance is used at or moved in an industrial undertaking, the owner of the appliance shall take appropriate precautions to ensure its stability.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664028_012" name="2" temporalId="s7D_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The owner of a crane shall, for the purpose of securing the stability of the crane, ensure that before use—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664028_020" name="a" temporalId="s7D_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the crane is securely anchored, or adequately weighted by suitable ballast which is properly placed on the structure of the crane and secured in a manner sufficient to prevent the ballast from being accidentally displaced; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664028_028" name="b" temporalId="s7D_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>no part of any rail on which the crane is mounted, or any sleeper supporting such rail, is used as an anchorage.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506376_002" name="s7E" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7E"><num value="7E">7E.</num><heading>Anchoring and ballasting of cranes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664059_011" name="1" temporalId="s7E_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a crane shall ensure that all of the devices used for the anchoring or ballasting of the crane are thoroughly examined by a competent examiner on each occasion before the crane is erected.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664059_019" name="2" temporalId="s7E_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>After each erection of a crane, and after each removal of a crane to a new location, or any adjustment to any component member of a crane (being a removal or adjustment which involves changes in the arrangements for anchoring or ballasting the crane), the owner of the crane shall, before it is taken into use, cause the crane to be tested by a competent examiner, by the imposition either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664075_005" name="a" temporalId="s7E_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of a load of 25% above the maximum load to be lifted by the crane as erected, at the positions where there is a maximum pull on each anchorage; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664075_013" name="b" temporalId="s7E_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>of a lesser load arranged to provide an equivalent test of the anchorage or ballasting arrangements.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664075_020" name="3" temporalId="s7E_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The owner shall obtain a certificate of the examination and test under
                paragraphs (1) and (2) from the competent examiner in the approved
                form
                in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that the crane is
                in safe working order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664075_028" name="4" temporalId="s7E_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If the competent examiner making the test under paragraph (2) considers that the maximum load which may safely be lifted by that crane as erected is less than the safe working load of the crane he shall specify the new maximum load in his certificate and in which case, the new maximum load shall be the modified safe working load.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664091_005" name="5" temporalId="s7E_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Where a maximum load has been specified under paragraph (4), the owner shall cause a loading diagram—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664091_013" name="a" temporalId="s7E_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>appropriate to the stability of the crane as at the time of the test (taking into account, in the case of a crane mounted on wheels, the conditions of the track); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664091_021" name="b" temporalId="s7E_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>indicating the modified safe working load,</content></paragraph><continued>to be affixed in a position where it can readily be seen by the crane driver.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664091_034" name="6" temporalId="s7E_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The modified safe working load referred to in paragraph <ref>(5)(b)</ref> shall, for the purpose of these regulations, be deemed to be the safe working load of the crane as erected.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506376_004" name="s7F" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7F"><num value="7F">7F.</num><heading>Stability of cranes secured by removable weights</heading><content>Where the stability of a crane is secured by means of removable weights, the owner of the crane shall, before it is used, cause a diagram or notice indicating the position and amount of the weights, to be affixed to the crane in a place where it can easily be seen.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506391_002" name="s7G" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7G"><num value="7G">7G.</num><heading>Use of cranes in bad weather</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664169_004" name="1" temporalId="s7G_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every owner of a crane shall ensure that no crane of his is used under weather conditions likely to endanger its stability.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664169_012" name="2" temporalId="s7G_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Before a crane is taken into use after exposure to weather conditions likely to have affected the stability of the crane, the owner shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664169_020" name="a" temporalId="s7G_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>cause the devices used for the anchoring or ballasting of the crane to be examined in the manner prescribed in <ref>regulation 7E(1)</ref> and cause the crane to be tested in the manner prescribed in <ref>regulation 7E(2)</ref>, by a competent examiner as soon as practicable after such exposure and obtain a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664184_006" name="b" temporalId="s7G_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the event of the anchorage or ballast being found on such test to be unsafe, take such steps as will again ensure the crane’s stability as soon as practicable.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506391_004" name="s7H" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7H"><num value="7H">7H.</num><heading>Erection, dismantling or alteration of cranes to be under supervision of a competent person</heading><leadIn>The owner of a crane shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664215_012" name="a" temporalId="s7H_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it is not erected, or dismantled; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664215_020" name="b" temporalId="s7H_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the structure thereof, as originally designed, is not altered,</content></paragraph><continued>except under the supervision of a competent person.</continued><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506407_001" name="s7I" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7I"><num value="7I">7I.</num><heading>Multiple lifting appliances</heading><leadIn>Where more than one lifting appliance is used to raise or lower one load, the owner of such lifting appliances shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664247_012" name="a" temporalId="s7I_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>each lifting appliance is so arranged and fixed that it is at no time loaded beyond its safe working load or rendered unstable in the raising or lowering of the load; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664247_020" name="b" temporalId="s7I_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a competent person is specially appointed to supervise the operation.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506407_003" name="s7J" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7J"><num value="7J">7J.</num><heading>Load to be safely secured</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664278_004" name="1" temporalId="s7J_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a lifting appliance shall, before it is used, ensure that every part of any load to be raised or lowered by the lifting appliance is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664278_012" name="a" temporalId="s7J_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>securely suspended or supported; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664278_020" name="b" temporalId="s7J_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>adequately secured so as to prevent danger arising to persons or property as a result of the slipping or displacement of any part of the load.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664278_027" name="2" temporalId="s7J_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where, by reason of the nature or position of the operation, a load is liable, while being moved on a lifting appliance or on lifting gear, to come into contact with any object so that the object may become displaced, the owner shall take all reasonable steps to ensure that no person lawfully on or near the industrial undertaking upon which the lifting appliance or lifting gear is being used is endangered by the displacement of the object.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664293_005" name="3" temporalId="s7J_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a receptacle is used in connection with any lifting appliance or lifting gear for raising or lowering stones, bricks, tiles, slates, or other objects, the owner of the lifting appliance or lifting gear shall cause the receptacle to be enclosed or to be so constructed or designed as to prevent the accidental fall of any of such objects.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664293_013" name="4" temporalId="s7J_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Paragraph (3) shall not apply to a grab, shovel or similar excavating receptacle if the owner takes effective steps to prevent persons being endangered by a fall of objects therefrom.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506407_005" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Precautions to be taken where lifting appliance has travelling or slewing motion</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664340_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (2), on every stage, gantry, or similar place where a lifting appliance having a travelling or slewing motion is in use, the owner of the appliance shall ensure that an unobstructed passageway, not less than 600 millimetres wide, is maintained between any part of the appliance liable so to move and any nearby guard rail, fence or other fixture.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664340_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If at any time it is impracticable to maintain any such passageway at any particular place, the owner shall ensure that all reasonable steps are taken to prevent persons from having access to that place when the appliance is in use.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506422_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Platforms for crane drivers and signallers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664371_012" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a crane has a platform for the use of the person driving or operating the crane, or for any signaller (where good safe working practice requires a signaller in connexion with the use of the crane), the owner shall ensure that it is not used unless the platform is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664387_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of sufficient area for the persons employed on it;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664387_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>either close planked or plated; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664387_021" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>provided with a safe means of access.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664387_028" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If any such platform has a side from which a person may fall a distance of more than 2 metres, the owner shall ensure that the crane is not used unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664387_036" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>there is affixed to the platform a suitable guard rail of adequate strength to a height of not less than 900 millimetres above the platform and above any raised standing place therein;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664387_044" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the side is provided with one or more toe boards placed—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413664387_052" name="i" temporalId="s9_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>at a height not less than 200 millimetres above the level of the platform and any raised standing place on it; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413664387_060" name="ii" temporalId="s9_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in a position that will prevent as far as possible the fall of persons, materials, and tools, from the platform; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664403_006" name="c" temporalId="s9_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the space between any toe board on the platform and the lowest guard rail above it does not exceed 700 millimetres.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664403_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notwithstanding anything in this regulation, a guard rail or toe board required under this regulation may be removed or remain unerected for such period and to such extent as is necessary for any person to gain access to and egress from the platform or for materials to be removed to it or from it.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506422_004" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Cabins for drivers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664434_028" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a power-driven lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used unless it is provided with a suitable cabin which—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664449_005" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>affords the driver or operator of the appliance adequate protection from the weather; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664449_013" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>is so constructed as to—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413664449_021" name="i" temporalId="s10_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>give him a clear and unrestricted view that will enable him to use the appliance safely; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413664449_029" name="ii" temporalId="s10_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>afford ready access to those parts of the appliance that are within the cabin and require periodic inspection or maintenance.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664449_035" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Paragraph (1) shall not apply—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664449_043" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the driver or operator is indoors or otherwise adequately protected from the weather;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664449_051" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to a lifting appliance mounted on wheels and having a maximum safe working load of 1 tonne or less;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664449_059" name="c" temporalId="s10_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to any machine incorporating a lifting appliance where the primary purpose of that machine is not that of a lifting appliance; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664465_006" name="d" temporalId="s10_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to a lifting appliance intended for occasional use or for use for only
                    short periods.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506438_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Marking of safe working loads</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664496_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that the appliance is not used unless the safe working load for the time being applicable to the appliance is clearly and legibly marked on it, in English and Chinese, together with an appropriate mark to distinguish it from other similar appliances.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664496_012" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The owner of a crane (including a crane with a derricking jib) which has a variable operating radius shall ensure that the crane is not used unless it—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664496_020" name="a" temporalId="s11_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has clearly and legibly marked on it the safe working load at various radii of the jib, trolley or crab, and, in the case of a crane with a derricking jib, the maximum radius at which the jib may be worked; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664512_006" name="b" temporalId="s11_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is fitted with an accurate indicator, clearly visible to the driver, which shows the radius of the jib, trolley or crab at any particular time and the safe working load applicable to that radius.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506438_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Load not to exceed the safe working load</heading><leadIn>The owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used if it is loaded beyond the maximum safe working load:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s12_proviso">Provided that, for the purpose of enabling tests of any such appliance to be carried out, the safe working load may be exceeded by such amount as the competent examiner appointed to carry out the test may authorize.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438403506454_001" name="s12A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12A"><num value="12A">12A.</num><heading>Competent person to be in charge if load left suspended</heading><content>The owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that no load is left suspended from a lifting appliance unless a competent person is in charge of the lifting appliance during the period of suspension.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of 1978</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506454_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Scotch and guy derrick cranes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664574_018" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a Scotch derrick crane shall ensure that it is not used—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664574_026" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the jib of the crane is erected between the crane’s backstays; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664590_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>unless appropriate measures are taken to prevent the foot of the king post of the crane from being lifted out of its socket or support when the crane is in use; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664590_014" name="c" temporalId="s13_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to move any load in the angle between the crane’s backstays.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664590_021" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where the guys of a guy derrick crane cannot be fixed—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664590_029" name="a" temporalId="s13_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at approximately equal angles to the mast of the crane; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664590_037" name="b" temporalId="s13_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>so that the angles between adjacent pairs of guys are approximately equal,</content></paragraph><continued>the owner of the crane shall take such other measures as will ensure its stability.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506469_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Cranes with derricking jibs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664621_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a crane having a derricking jib operated through a clutch mechanism shall ensure that the crane is not used unless it is provided with a properly maintained and effective locking arrangement, placed between the derricking clutch and the pawl sustaining the derricking drum, which will ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664621_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the clutch cannot be disengaged unless the pawl is effectively engaged with the derricking drum; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664621_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the pawl cannot be disengaged unless the clutch is effectively engaged with the derricking drum.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664637_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>This regulation shall not apply to a crane in which—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664637_013" name="a" temporalId="s14_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the hoisting drum and the derricking drum are independently driven; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664637_021" name="b" temporalId="s14_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the mechanism driving the derricking drum is self locking.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506469_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Restriction on the use of cranes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664668_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to paragraph (2), the owner of a crane shall ensure that the crane’s hoisting mechanism is not used for any purpose other than raising or lowering a load vertically unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664668_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he has taken all reasonable steps to see that no undue stress is imposed on any part of the structure or mechanism of the crane thereby endangering the stability of the crane; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1989/71">71 of 1989 s. 13</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664668_020" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>such use is supervised by a competent person.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664668_027" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner of a crane which has a derricking jib shall ensure that it is not used with the jib extended at a radius which exceeds the maximum radius specified for the jib in the current certificate of test and thorough examination relating to that crane.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506469_005" name="s15A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s15A"><num value="15A">15A.</num><heading>Operators of cranes and lifting appliances</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664730_004" name="1" temporalId="s15A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of a crane shall ensure that it is only operated by a person
                who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664730_012" name="a" temporalId="s15A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has attained the age of 18 years;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664730_020" name="b" temporalId="s15A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>holds a valid certificate issued by the specified body or by any other
                    person specified by the Commissioner; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2006/12">12 of 2006 s.
                        84</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664730_028" name="c" temporalId="s15A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the opinion of the owner, is competent to operate the crane by virtue of
                    his experience.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664730_035" name="2" temporalId="s15A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The owner of a power-driven lifting appliance, other than a crane, shall ensure
                that it is only operated by a person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664730_043" name="a" temporalId="s15A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has attained the age of 18 years; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664730_051" name="b" temporalId="s15A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the opinion of the owner, is trained and competent to operate the
                    appliance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664746_005" name="3" temporalId="s15A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>This regulation does not apply where a person undergoing training is operating
                a lifting appliance providing he does so under the supervision of a person who meets
                the requirements of paragraph (1) or (2) as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664746_013" name="4" temporalId="s15A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="SpecifiedBody">
                <leadIn>In this regulation,
                        <term>specified
                        body</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明機構</term>) means—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413664746_021" name="a" temporalId="s15A_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the body known as the Construction Industry Training Authority before
                        the commencement* of <ref>section 71</ref> of the Construction Industry
                        Council Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap587">Cap. 587</ref>); or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413664746_029" name="b" temporalId="s15A_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Construction Industry Council established by <ref>section 4</ref>
                        of the Construction Industry Council Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap587">Cap.
                            587</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2006/12">12 of 2006 s. 84</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
            </def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" class="font_size_9" id="ID_1722998792392_001">
            <content>
                
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="445" class="font_size_9">
                    <colgroup>
                        <col width="4%"></col>
                        <col width="96%"></col>
                    </colgroup>
                    <tbody>
                        
                        
                        <tr>
                            <td colspan="2">Editorial Note:</td>
                        </tr>
                        
                        
                        <tr>
                            <td><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="force_orig_font">*</inline></td>
                            <td class="align_justified">Commencement date: 1 January 2008.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506485_002" name="s15B" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15B"><num value="15B">15B.</num><heading>Operation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664793_004" name="1" temporalId="s15B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a person operating a lifting appliance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664793_012" name="a" temporalId="s15B_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>does not have a clear and unrestricted view of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413664793_020" name="i" temporalId="s15B_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the load carried by the lifting appliance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413664793_028" name="ii" temporalId="s15B_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>its vicinity;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413664793_036" name="iii" temporalId="s15B_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the point of attachment for a load where no load is being carried; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664808_006" name="b" temporalId="s15B_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>such view is necessary for the safe working of the appliance,</content></paragraph><continued>the owner of a lifting appliance shall, subject to paragraph (2), appoint and station such persons as may be necessary to give effective signals to the person operating the lifting appliance to ensure its safe working.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664808_019" name="2" temporalId="s15B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>No person appointed under paragraph (1) shall be under the age of 18 years unless he—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664808_027" name="a" temporalId="s15B_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is a person undergoing training to operate the appliance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664808_035" name="b" temporalId="s15B_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>acts under the supervision of a competent person.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664808_042" name="3" temporalId="s15B_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If it is impracticable to comply with paragraph (1), the owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that effective signalling arrangements or other means of communication exist between the person operating the appliance and the person employed in the loading or unloading of the appliance to ensure its safe working.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of 1978</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506485_004" name="s15C" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15C"><num value="15C">15C.</num><heading>Steam not to obscure workplace</heading><content>The owner of a crane or winch shall ensure that the exhaust steam from and, so far as practicable, live steam to any crane or winch does not obscure any workplace at which a workman is employed.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of 1978</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506500_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Brakes, controls, safety devices, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664917_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a crab, crane or winch shall ensure that it is not used unless it is fitted with one or more efficient brakes, or other similar safety devices, which will prevent a load suspended from the appliance from falling uncontrollably or dangerously.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664917_012" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to paragraph (3), the owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413664917_020" name="a" temporalId="s16_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>every lever, handle, switch or other device used for controlling the operation of any part of the appliance (being a lever, handle, switch or other device the accidental movement or displacement of which is liable to cause danger) is, where practicable (unless it is so placed or the appliance is so constructed as to prevent accidental movement or displacement), provided with a suitable spring or other locking arrangement to prevent any such accidental movement or displacement; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413664933_006" name="b" temporalId="s16_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>every lever, handle, switch or other device for controlling the operation of any part of the appliance has either on or adjacent to it clear markings to indicate its purpose and the mode of operation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664933_013" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Paragraph <ref>(2)(b)</ref> shall not apply to rotating handles for raising or lowering a load in the case of a winch or non-derricking jib crane operated by manual power.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664949_005" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If any person is employed or working on or near the wheel track of an overhead travelling crane in a place where he would be liable to be struck by the crane, the owner shall take effective measures, by warning the driver of the crane or otherwise, to ensure that the crane does not approach within 6 metres of that place.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413664949_013" name="5" temporalId="s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If any person is employed or working otherwise than mentioned in paragraph (4)
                but in a place above floor level where he would be liable to be struck by an
                overhead travelling crane, or by any load carried by such a crane, the owner of the
                crane shall take effective measures to ensure that such person is warned of the
                approach of the crane, unless his work is so connected with or dependent on the
                movements of the crane as to make a warning unnecessary.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506500_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Drums and pulleys</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413664995_016" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance which has a drum or pulley on which a rope is carried shall ensure that the appliance is not used unless the drum or pulley is of sufficient diameter and construction for the rope used.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665011_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If the rope terminates at the winding drum of the appliance, the owner shall ensure that the appliance is not used unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665011_013" name="a" temporalId="s17_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the rope is properly secured to the drum; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665011_021" name="b" temporalId="s17_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at least 2 turns of the rope remain on the drum at every operating position of the appliance.</content></paragraph></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403506500_005" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Chains,
            Ropes and Lifting Gear</heading><section id="ID_1438403506516_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Construction, testing, examination and safe working load of chains, ropes and lifting gear</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413665042_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The owner of any chain, rope or lifting gear used for raising or lowering or as a means of suspension shall ensure that the following provisions are complied with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665058_005" name="a" temporalId="s18_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>no chain, rope or lifting gear shall be used unless it is of good construction, sound material, and adequate strength, and is free from patent defect;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665058_013" name="b" temporalId="s18_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>subject to paragraph (2), a table, in English and Chinese, showing the safe working loads of each kind and size of chain, rope or lifting gear in use, and, in the case of a multiple sling, the safe working load at different angles of the legs, shall be posted in a prominent position in the premises or place where the chain, rope or lifting gear is kept; and no chain, rope or lifting gear not shown in the table shall be used;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665073_006" name="c" temporalId="s18_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>no chain, rope or lifting gear shall be used for any load exceeding its
                    safe working load as shown in the table referred to in
                    subparagraph
                    (b) or marked as mentioned in paragraph (2);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665073_014" name="d" temporalId="s18_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>no chain, rope or lifting gear (except a fibre rope or fibre-rope sling) shall be used unless it has been tested and thoroughly examined by a competent examiner in the manner prescribed in the <ref>First Schedule</ref> and a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order has been obtained;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665073_022" name="e" temporalId="s18_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>each chain, rope and lifting gear in use shall be thoroughly examined by a competent examiner in the preceding 6 months before it is used and a certificate in the approved form in which the competent examiner has made a statement to the effect that it is in safe working order has been obtained;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665089_006" name="ea" temporalId="s18_1_ea"><num value="ea">(ea)</num><content>each chain, rope and lifting gear shall be inspected before use on each occasion by a competent person;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of 1978</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665089_014" name="eb" temporalId="s18_1_eb"><num value="eb">(eb)</num><content>chains shall not be shortened by tying knots in them and adequate precautions shall be taken to prevent injury to them from sharp edges;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of 1978</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665089_022" name="f" temporalId="s18_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665089_030" name="g" temporalId="s18_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the chain, rope or lifting gear in use has clearly and legibly marked on it its safe working load together with an appropriate mark to distinguish it from other similar lifting gear;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665105_006" name="h" temporalId="s18_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the chain, rope or lifting gear is not loaded beyond its safe working load except for the purpose of testing or examination by a competent examiner; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665105_014" name="i" temporalId="s18_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>no wire rope shall be used for raising or lowering or as a means of suspension if in any length of 10 diameters, the total number of visible broken wires exceeds 5% of the total number of wires in the rope.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665105_021" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref> shall not apply in relation to any lifting gear if its safe working load, or in the case of a multiple sling, the safe working load at different angles of the legs, is plainly marked upon it in English and Chinese.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665105_029" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Paragraph <ref>(1)(g)</ref> shall not apply to a rope or sling if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665120_001" name="a" temporalId="s18_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>its safe working load is specified in a certificate required by paragraph <ref>(1)(d)</ref> and the rope or sling is so marked as to enable its safe working load to be ascertained from the certificate; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665120_009" name="b" temporalId="s18_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a fibre rope or fibre sling, its safe working load can be ascertained from a table of safe working load posted in accordance with paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506532_001" name="s18A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s18A"><num value="18A">18A.</num><heading>Multiple slings</heading><leadIn>The owner of any double or multiple sling shall ensure that it is not used in raising or lowering or as a means of suspension if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665183_005" name="a" temporalId="s18A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the upper ends of the sling legs are not connected by means of a shackle, ring or link of adequate strength; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665183_013" name="b" temporalId="s18A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the safe working load of any sling leg is exceeded as a result of the angle between the sling legs.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403506532_003" name="P3A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="P3A"><num value="3A">Part
            IIIA</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><sourceNote>(Part IIIA added <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403506532_005" name="s18B" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s18B"><num value="18B">18B.</num><heading>Carrying of persons by means of lifting appliances</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413665214_011" name="1" temporalId="s18B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person may be raised, lowered or carried by a power-driven lifting appliance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665229_005" name="a" temporalId="s18B_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on the driver’s platform in the case of a crane;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665229_013" name="b" temporalId="s18B_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on a suspended scaffold of such design and construction as ensures the safety of any person carried thereon;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665229_021" name="c" temporalId="s18B_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>without the use of a builder’s lift or tower working platform to which the Builders’ Lifts and Tower Working Platforms (Safety) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap470">Cap. 470</ref>) applies or a suspended scaffold where its use is impracticable, provided that—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln550">L.N. 550 of 1995</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413665229_029" name="i" temporalId="s18B_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the appliance can be operated from one position only;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413665229_037" name="ii" temporalId="s18B_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the appliance is so constructed that the brake is applied when the control lever, handle or switch is not held in the operating position;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413665229_045" name="iii" temporalId="s18B_1_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>where the person is carried in a chair, cage, skip or other receptacle at least 900 mm deep, the receptacle is of good construction, sound material and adequate strength, and is provided with suitable means to prevent any occupant from falling out and does not contain material or tools liable to interfere with his hand hold or otherwise endanger him, or where the person is carried in a boatswain’s chair or other similar plant or equipment less than 900 mm deep, a suitable safety belt attached to an independent lifeline is provided to and worn by the occupant and the lifeline is securely suspended;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413665245_007" name="iv" temporalId="s18B_1_c_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>suitable measures are taken to prevent such chair, cage, skip or other receptacle from spinning or tipping in a manner dangerous to any occupant; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413665261_007" name="v" temporalId="s18B_1_c_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>if a hook is fitted to the lifting appliance, it is so designed and maintained as to prevent the accidental displacement of such chair, cage, skip or other receptacle from the hook;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665261_014" name="d" temporalId="s18B_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>from an aerial ropeway or cableway or an overhead runway, provided that the provisions of subparagraph <ref>(c)(ii)</ref>, (iii), (iv) and (v) are complied with.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665261_021" name="2" temporalId="s18B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner of a power-driven lifting appliance shall ensure that it is not used for raising, lowering or carrying persons other than in accordance with paragraph (1).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506547_002" name="s18C" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2000-06-09" status="operational" temporalId="s18C"><num value="18C">18C.</num><heading>Keeping and displaying of certificates and reports</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413665307_004" name="1" temporalId="s18C_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance, or any chain, rope or lifting gear shall keep the certificates and reports issued in respect of any test, examination or inspection required by these regulations in a safe place and shall not dispose of any certificate or report until 2 years after the date on which the certificate or report of the subsequent test, examination or inspection, as the case may be, is received by the owner or until 2 years after the date on which the lifting appliance, or any chain, rope or lifting gear is disposed of.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665323_005" name="2" temporalId="s18C_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance shall ensure that a copy of the relevant and the most recent certificate or report is displayed in the driving cabin or other prominent place on the equipment to which it relates or in a prominent place nearby.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665339_005" name="3" temporalId="s18C_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Paragraph (1) applies whether or not the lifting appliance, chain, rope or lifting gear is still in use.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665339_013" name="4" temporalId="s18C_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance, or any chain, rope or lifting gear shall at all reasonable times make available for inspection by any occupational safety officer who requests to see them all certificates or reports required to be kept by him under paragraph (1).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665339_021" name="5" temporalId="s18C_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The owner of a lifting appliance, or any chain, rope or lifting gear shall, upon request in writing by an occupational safety officer within such period (being not less than 7 days) as may be specified in the request, deliver to the occupational safety officer a copy of or an extract from any certificate or report required to be kept by him under paragraph (1).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506563_001" name="s18D" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s18D"><num value="18D">18D.</num><heading>Forms</heading><content>Every form to be used in these regulations shall be in such form as the Commissioner for Labour may from time to time approve by notice in the Gazette.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403506563_003" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Offences
            and Penalties</heading><section id="ID_1438403506563_005" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Offences by owners</heading><leadIn>An owner who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1681973868522_001" name="a" temporalId="s19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>contravenes <ref>regulation 4</ref>, <ref>5</ref>,
                                <ref>6A(2)</ref>, <ref>7B</ref>, <ref>7C</ref>, <ref>7D</ref>,
                                        <ref>7E(1)</ref>, (2) or (3), 7H, 7I, 7J(1), (2) or (3), 8,
                                9(1) or (2), 12, 13, 15, 15B(1) or (3), 18(1)(a), (c), (d), (e),
                                (eb), (h) or (i) or 18A(b) commits an offence and is liable on
                                conviction to a fine of $400,000;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681973868532_002" name="b" temporalId="s19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>contravenes <ref>regulation 7A</ref> or <ref>18(1)(ea)</ref>
                                commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine of
                                $200,000;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681973868535_003" name="c" temporalId="s19_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>contravenes <ref>regulation 7E(5)</ref>, <ref>7F</ref>,
                                        <ref>10</ref>, <ref>11</ref>, <ref>12A</ref>,
                                        <ref>14(1)</ref>, <ref>15A(1)</ref> or (2), 15B(2), 15C,
                                16(1), (2), (4) or (5), 17, 18(1)(b) or (g) or 18A(a) commits an
                                offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 6;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681973868544_004" name="d" temporalId="s19_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>contravenes <ref>regulation 7G(1)</ref> or <ref>18B</ref> commits an
                                offence and is liable on conviction to—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1681973868548_005" name="1" temporalId="s19_d_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>if the offence was committed without reasonable excuse—a
                                        fine of $400,000 and to imprisonment for 12 months;
                                        or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1681973868548_006" name="2" temporalId="s19_d_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>in any other case—a fine of $400,000;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681973868549_007" name="e" temporalId="s19_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>contravenes <ref>regulation 7G(2)</ref> commits an offence and is
                                liable on conviction to a fine of $400,000 and to imprisonment for
                                12 months; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1681973868552_008" name="f" temporalId="s19_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>contravenes <ref>regulation 18C(1)</ref>, (2), (4) or (5) commits
                                an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level
                                4.</content></paragraph></section><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s. 30</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403506578_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Offences by persons employed</heading><content>Any workman employed or working on or near any lifting appliance or lifting gear to
            which these regulations apply, who wilfully and without reasonable cause does anything
            likely to endanger
            the
            workman or others commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level
            5.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln116">L.N. 116 of 1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of
            1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s. 31</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506578_004" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Offences by competent examiners</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413665495_016" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any competent examiner who having carried out any test, inspection or
                examination required by these regulations—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665495_024" name="a" temporalId="s21_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>fails or refuses to deliver forthwith, or within a reasonable time
                    thereafter, to an owner a report referred to in <ref>regulation
                    6A(1)(b)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665495_032" name="b" temporalId="s21_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fails or refuses to deliver forthwith, or within a reasonable time
                    thereafter, to an owner a certificate referred to in <ref>regulation 5(1)</ref>,
                    (2), (3), (4) or (5), 7B(1)(b), 7E(3), 7G(2) or 18(1)(d) or (e); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665510_006" name="c" temporalId="s21_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>fails to comply with <ref>regulation 6A(1)(b)</ref> or
                    <ref>7E(4)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>commits
                an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level
                    5.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of
                    1993</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s.
                32</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665510_019" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any such competent examiner who delivers to an owner a certificate or makes a
                report which is to his knowledge false as to a material particular shall be guilty
                of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine of $200,000 and to
                imprisonment for 12 months.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1989/71">71 of 1989 s. 13</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N.
                        285 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln116">L.N. 116 of 1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of
            1994</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403506594_002" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Offences by competent person</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413665541_025" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any competent person who having carried out any test, inspection or examination
                required by these regulations fails or refuses to deliver forthwith or within a
                reasonable time thereafter, to an owner a certificate referred to in <ref>regulation
                    7A</ref> or
                <ref>7B</ref>(1)(c)
                commits
                an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s.
                33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665557_005" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any such competent person who delivers to an owner a certificate which is to his knowledge false as to a material particular shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine of $200,000 and to imprisonment for 12 months.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln23">L.N. 23 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403506594_004" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-12-19" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">First
      Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap59J/s5">regs.
        5</ref> &amp;
        <ref href="/hk/cap59J/s18">18</ref>]</note><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
      2024</ref>)</sourceNote><heading>Procedure
      for Testing and Examining Lifting Appliances and Lifting
      Gear</heading><section id="ID_1438413665588_020" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><subsection id="ID_1438413665588_025" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every winch, together with its accessories, (including any derrick, gooseneck,
          eye-plate, eyebolt, or other attachments) shall be tested with a proof load which shall
          exceed the safe working load as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665588_031" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s1_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the safe working load is less than 20 tonnes, the proof load shall exceed the
            safe working load by at least 25 per cent;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665588_040" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s1_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the safe working load is 20 tonnes but not more than 50 tonnes, the proof load
            shall exceed the safe working load by at least 5 tonnes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665604_007" name="c" temporalId="sch1_s1_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the safe working load is more than 50 tonnes, the proof load shall exceed the
            safe working load by at least 10 per cent.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665604_015" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The proof load shall be applied either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665604_024" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s1_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by hoisting movable weights; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665604_033" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s1_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by means of a spring or hydraulic balance or a similar appliance, with a derrick
            at an angle to the horizontal which shall be specified in the certificate of the
            test.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665604_041" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s1_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In the case of a proof load applied under
          subparagraph
            <ref>(2)(a)</ref>, after the movable weights have been hoisted, or in the case of a
          proof load applied under
          subparagraph
            <ref>(2)(b)</ref>, after the proof load has been applied, the derrick shall be swung as
          far as practicable first in one direction and then in the
          other.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438413665619_004" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><subsection id="ID_1438413665619_009" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every crane and every lifting appliance, together with its accessories, other than a
          lifting appliance referred to in
          subparagraph
          (1), shall be tested with a proof load which shall exceed the safe working load as
          follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665619_015" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the safe working load is less than 20 tonnes, the proof load shall exceed the
            safe working load by at least 25 per cent;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665619_024" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the safe working load is 20 tonnes but not more than 50 tonnes, the proof load
            shall exceed the safe working load by at least 5 tonnes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665619_033" name="c" temporalId="sch1_s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the safe working load is more than 50 tonnes, the proof load shall exceed the
            safe working load by at least 10 per cent.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665619_041" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The proof load shall be hoisted and then swung as far as is practicable first in
          one direction and then in the other.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665635_006" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a crane with a jib which has a variable vertical operating radius is to be
          tested, the test shall be carried
          out
          by applying a proof load in accordance with
          subparagraph
          (1) at both the maximum radius and the minimum radius of the jib.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413665635_015" name="4" temporalId="sch1_s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where in testing a hydraulic crane it is, because of the limitation of pressure,
          impossible to hoist a load which exceeds the safe working load by 25 per cent, it is
          sufficient compliance with this paragraph if the crane has the greatest possible load
          applied to
          it.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438413665635_022" name="s3" temporalId="sch1_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><leadIn>Every item of lifting gear (whether an accessory to any lifting appliance or not)
        shall be tested with a proof load in accordance with the following provisions—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413665651_006" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the item is a chain sling, rope sling, ring, hook, shackle, or swivel, the proof
          load shall be at least twice the safe working load;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665651_015" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if 
          the item is a single sheave pulley block, the proof load shall be at
          least 4 times the safe working load;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of 1978</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665651_024" name="ba" temporalId="sch1_s3_ba"><num value="ba">(ba)</num><content>if the item is a multiple sheave pulley block with a safe working load of up to and
          including 20 tonnes, the proof load shall be at least twice the safe working load;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln191">L.N. 191 of
            1978</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665651_033" name="c" temporalId="sch1_s3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the item is a multiple sheave pulley block with a safe working load of more than
          20 tonnes, but not more than 40 tonnes, the proof load shall exceed the safe working load
          by at least 20 tonnes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413665651_042" name="d" temporalId="sch1_s3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if the item is a multiple sheave block with a safe working load of more than 40
          tonnes, the proof load shall be at least 1 1/2 times the safe working
          load.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438413665666_004" name="s4" temporalId="sch1_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><content>After being tested in accordance with <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, <ref>2</ref> or
          <ref>3</ref> each lifting appliance (including its accessories) and all loose gear shall
        be examined so as to ensure that no part of the lifting appliance or lifting gear has been
        damaged during the test. For the purpose of carrying out the examination of a pulley block
        the examiner shall remove the sheaves and pins of the
        block.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1438413665666_012" name="s5" temporalId="sch1_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><content>Where any wire rope is tested, a sample of the rope shall be tested to destruction,
        and the safe working load shall not exceed 20 per cent of the breaking load of the sample
        tested.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1984</ref>)</sourceNote></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403506610_002" name="sch2" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Second
                                    Schedule</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/ln285">L.N. 285 of
                                    1993</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></subLeg>