<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 190 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>190A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap190A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-08-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402813894_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-08-19">The Food
            and
            Agriculture
            Organization</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap190/s2">Cap. 190, section
                2</ref>)
            </enactingFormula><commencementNote>[19 May 1950]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><sourceNote class="align_left"><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>(Words repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">A.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>The
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402813909_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content><shortTitle>The Food and Agriculture Organization</shortTitle> (hereinafter
            referred to as
                    <b><i>the
                    Organization</i></b>) is an organization to which the Diplomatic Privileges
            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap190">Cap. 190</ref>) shall apply.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402813925_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The Organization shall have the legal capacities of a body corporate and, except in so far as in any particular case it has expressly waived its immunity, immunity from suit and legal process. No waiver of immunity shall be deemed to extend to any measure of execution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402813925_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The Organization shall have the like inviolability of official archives and premises occupied as offices as is accorded in respect of official archives and premises of an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402813940_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>The Organization shall have the like exemption or relief from taxes and rates, other than taxes on the importation of goods, as is accorded to a foreign sovereign power.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402813940_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>The Organization shall have exemption from taxes on the importation of goods directly imported by the Organization for its official use in Hong Kong or for exportation, or on the importation of any of the publications of the Organization directly imported by it, such exemption to be subject to compliance with such conditions as the Commissioner of Customs and Excise may prescribe for the protection of the revenue.
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1985/40">40 of 1985 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438402813972_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>The Organization shall have exemption from prohibitions and restrictions on the importation or exportation in the case of goods directly imported or exported by the Organization for its official use and in the case of any publications of the Organization directly imported or exported by it.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402813972_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><content>The Organization shall have the right to avail itself, for telegraphic communications sent by it and containing only matter intended for publication by the press or for broadcasting (including communications addressed to or dispatched from places outside Hong Kong), of any reduced rates applicable for the corresponding service in the case of press telegrams.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">B.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>Representatives
            of
            Members: Chairman
            of
            the<br></br>Council
            of
            the
            Organization</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402813987_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8"><inline class="not_bold">8.</inline></num><subsection id="ID_1438411509673_029" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Except in so far as any privilege or immunity is waived, in the case of
                representatives of member governments, by the Governments whom they represent and,
                in the case of the Chairman of the Council of the Organization, by the Council of
                    <shortTitle>the Food and Agriculture Organization</shortTitle>, representatives
                of member governments, and the Chairman of the Organization shall enjoy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411509673_038" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>while exercising their functions as such, and during their journey to and
                    from the place of meeting, immunity from personal arrest or detention and from
                    seizure of their personal baggage and inviolability for all papers and
                    documents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411509673_047" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or
                    written and all acts done by them in their capacity as
                    representatives;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411509673_056" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>while exercising their functions and during their journey to and from the
                    place of meeting, the like exemption or relief from taxes as is accorded to an
                    envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s
                    Republic of China, save that the relief allowed shall not include relief from
                    customs and excise duties except in respect of goods imported as part of their
                    personal baggage. They shall not, where the incidence of any form of taxation
                    depends upon residence, be deemed to be resident in Hong Kong during any period
                    when they are present in Hong Kong whilst exercising their functions and during
                    their journey to and from the place of meeting. The provisions of this paragraph
                    shall not apply to Chinese nationals whose usual place of abode is in Hong Kong.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/80">80 of 1982 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411509704_006" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="RepresentativesOfMemberGovernments">For the purpose of the application of
                this Order, the expression
                    <term>representatives
                    of member
                governments</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">成員政府代表</term>) shall be deemed to include their
                official staffs accompanying them as such representatives as delegates, deputy
                delegates, advisers, technical experts or secretaries of delegations.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411509720_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The provision of the preceding paragraph of this Article shall not confer any
                immunity or privilege upon any person as the representative of the Central People’s
                Government in Hong Kong or as a member of the staff of such a representative, or any
                person who is a Chinese national.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/80">80 of 1982 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">C.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>High
            Officials</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402814003_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9"><inline class="not_bold">9.</inline></num><content>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the Organization, officers of the Organization holding the offices of Director-General
            and Deputy Director-General shall be accorded in respect of themselves, their spouses
            and children under the age of twenty-one, the like immunity from suit and legal process,
            the like inviolability of residence and the like exemption or relief from taxes as is
            accorded to an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the
            People’s Republic of China, his spouse and children, including exemption from income tax
            in respect of emoluments received by them as officers of the Organization.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">D.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>Persons Employed
            on Missions
            on
            behalf of the
            <br></br>Organizations</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402814018_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the Organization, persons (other than officials of the Organization) serving on
            Committees of, or on behalf of the Organization shall enjoy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411509767_045" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>while exercising their functions as such, and during their journey to and from
                the place of meeting, immunity from personal arrest or detention and from seizure of
                their personal baggage and inviolability of all papers and documents relating to the
                work of the Organization;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411509767_054" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or written
                and all acts done by them in the exercise of their functions. Such immunity shall
                continue notwithstanding that the persons concerned are no longer employed on
                missions on behalf of the
                Organization.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">E.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>Other Officials
            of
            the
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402814018_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-19" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the Organization, all officials of the Organization (other than those referred to in
            Article 9 above or officials engaged locally and remunerated by payment calculated on
            the number of hours worked) shall enjoy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411509798_021" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>immunity from suit and legal process in respect of words spoken or written and
                all acts done by them in the course of the performance of their official
                duties;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411509798_030" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>exemption from income tax in respect of emoluments received by them as officers
                or servants of the Organization.</content></paragraph></section></main></subLeg>