<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 112 sub. leg. AS</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>112AS</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap112AS!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-08-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402590205_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-08-13">Specification
            of Arrangements (Government of the State of Kuwait) (Avoidance of Double Taxation on
            Income from Aircraft Operation) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap112/s49">Cap. 112, section
                49</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of
            2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[17 June
            2005]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402590220_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-13" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Declaration under <ref>section 49</ref></heading><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>section 49</ref> of the Ordinance, it is declared—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410940974_038" name="a" temporalId="s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the arrangements specified in <ref>section 2</ref> have been made with the Government of the State of Kuwait with a view to affording relief from double taxation in relation to income tax and other taxes of a similar character imposed by the laws of the State; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410940990_006" name="b" temporalId="s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that it is expedient that those arrangements should have effect.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402590236_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Arrangements specified</heading><content>The arrangements specified for the purposes of <ref>section 1(a)</ref> are the arrangements in Article 11 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the State of Kuwait concerning Air Services done in duplicate at Kuwait on 7 April 2004 in the English language, the text of which Article is reproduced in the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402590252_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-13" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap112AS/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Article
            11 of
            the Agreement
            between
            the
            Government of
            the
            Hong
            Kong
            Special
            Administrative Region
            of
            the
            People’s Republic
            of China
            and
            the Government
            of
            the State
            of Kuwait
            Concerning
            Air
            Services<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text class="align_center"><crossHeading> </crossHeading><ins><b>ARTICLE
                    11</b></ins><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><ins><b>Avoidance
                    of Double Taxation</b></ins></text><section id="ID_1438410941037_084" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Income or profits derived from the operation of aircraft in international
                traffic by an airline of one Contracting Party, including participation in a pool
                service, a joint air transport operation or an international operating agency, which
                are subject to tax in the area of that Contracting Party shall be exempt from income
                tax, profits tax and all other taxes on income or profits imposed in the area of the
                other Contracting Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410941052_006" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Capital and assets of an airline of one Contracting Party relating to the
                operation of aircraft in international traffic shall be exempt from taxes of every
                kind and description on capital and assets imposed in the area of the other
                Contracting Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410941052_014" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Gains from the alienation of aircraft operated in international traffic and
                movable property pertaining to the operation of such aircraft which are received by
                an airline of one Contracting Party shall be exempt from any tax on gains imposed in
                the area of the other Contracting Party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410941068_006" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this Article:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438410941068_015" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="IncomeOrProfits">
                    <content>the term “<term class="old_format">income or profits</term>” includes
                        revenues and gross receipts from the operation of aircraft for the carriage
                        of persons, livestock, goods, mail or merchandise in international traffic
                        including:</content>
                </def><paragraph id="ID_1438410941068_023" name="i" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch0_s4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the charter or rental of aircraft;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410941068_032" name="ii" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch0_s4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the sale of tickets or similar documents, and the provision of services
                        connected with such carriage, either for the airline itself or for any other
                        airline; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410941068_041" name="iii" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch0_s4_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>interest on funds directly connected with the operation of aircraft in
                        international traffic;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410941068_050" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="InternationalTraffic">the term “<term class="old_format">international
                        traffic</term>” means any carriage by an aircraft except when such carriage
                    is solely between places in the area of the other Contracting Party.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410941068_058" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><def name="AirlineOfOneContractingParty">the term “<term class="old_format">airline
                        of one Contracting Party</term>” means, in the case of the Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region, an airline incorporated and having its principal place of
                    business in Hong Kong Special Administrative Region and, in the case of the
                    State of Kuwait, an airline substantially owned and effectively controlled by
                    the Government of the State of Kuwait or its nationals;</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410941068_066" name="d" temporalId="sch0_s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><def name="CompetentAuthority">the term “<term class="old_format">competent
                        authority</term>” means, in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region, the Commissioner of Inland Revenue or his authorised representative, or
                    any person or body authorised to perform any functions at present exercisable by
                    the Commissioner or similar functions, and, in the case of the State of Kuwait,
                    the Ministry of Finance or their authorised representative.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410941083_006" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties shall, through
                consultation, endeavour to resolve by mutual agreement any disputes regarding the
                interpretation or application of this Article. Article 19 shall not apply to any
                such dispute.</content></section><section id="ID_1438410941083_014" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding Article 23 each Contracting Party shall notify to the other the
                completion of the procedures required by its law for the bringing into force of this
                Article and the Article shall enter into force on the date of the last written
                notification. The Article shall then be applied:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438410941083_023" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, for any year of assessment
                    beginning on or after 1st April in the calendar year next following that in
                    which this Agreement or this Article enters into force, whichever is the
                    later;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410941099_001" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the State of Kuwait, for any year of assessment beginning on or after
                    1st April in the calendar year next following that in which this Agreement or
                    this Article enters into force, whichever is the later.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410941099_008" name="s7" temporalId="sch0_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding Article 21 where notice of termination of this Agreement is
                given under that Article, this Article shall cease to have effect:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438410941099_017" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, for any year of assessment
                    beginning on or after 1st April in the calendar year next following that in
                    which notice is given;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410941099_026" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the State of Kuwait, for any year of assessment beginning on or after
                    1st April in the calendar year next following that in which notice is
                    given.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438410941099_033" name="s8" temporalId="sch0_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>This Article shall cease to have effect in the event that an agreement for the
                avoidance of double taxation with respect to taxes on income, providing for similar
                exemptions to those in this Article, enters into force between the Contracting
                Parties.</content></section></schedule></main></subLeg>