<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 114</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>114</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap114!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402604089_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-06-03">
            <content>To consolidate and amend the law relating to miscellaneous
                licences.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[27 October 1933]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402604089_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Miscellaneous Licences Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402604104_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="DancingSchool">
            <leadIn><term>dancing
                    school</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">舞蹈學校</term>) means any place opened, kept or used
                for the purpose of giving instruction in dancing except—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411037601_019" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a place of public entertainment licensed as such under the Places of Public
                    Entertainment Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap172">Cap. 172</ref>); or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411037601_027" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a public dance hall licensed as such under this Ordinance; or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411037601_035" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>dancing schools for children under the age of 16;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411037601_043" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a place used for the purpose of giving instruction in dancing where no
                    charge whatsoever to any person resorting thereto, whether for admittance or
                    instruction, or for food or drink supplied, or otherwise, is made; or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411037601_051" name="e" temporalId="s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a place used for the purpose of giving instruction in dancing by The Hong
                    Kong Academy for Performing Arts established by The Hong Kong Academy for
                    Performing Arts Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1135">Cap. 1135</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1984/38">38 of
                            1984 s. 28</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
        </def><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15 of 1952 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1965/27">27 of 1965 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1984/38">38 of 1984 s.
                28</ref>)</sourceNote><def name="Hawker"><term>hawker</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">小販</term>) means any person who trades in any street or
            public thoroughfare or goes from place to place, or goes on board any vessel, selling or
            exposing for sale any goods, wares or merchandise immediately to be delivered, or
            exposing samples or patterns of any goods, wares or merchandise to be afterwards
            delivered, or selling or offering for sale his skill in handicraft, except a person
            selling or seeking orders for goods, wares or merchandise to or from person who are
            dealers therein, and who buy to sell again;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1934/9">9 of 1934 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1871 c.
                96 s. 3
                U.K.;
                1888 c. 33 s. 2
                U.K.]</referenceNote></def><def name="Place"><term>place</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">場所</term>) includes any house, shop, room, office,
            boat, vehicle or vessel, or any erection movable or otherwise, or any spot on land or
            water;</def><def name="PublicDancehall">
            <leadIn><term>public
                    dance-hall</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公眾舞廳</term>) means any place opened, kept or used
                for the purpose of dancing to which the general public are admitted with or without
                payment for admission unless such place is a place of public entertainment licensed
                as such under the Places of Public Entertainment Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap172">Cap. 172</ref>):</leadIn>
            <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s2_proviso">Provided that a place shall not be
                deemed to be opened, kept or used for the purpose of dancing if it is opened, kept
                or used primarily for some other lawful purpose to which dancing is merely an
                incidental attraction for which no charge is made and no instructors or dancing
                partners are provided or made available;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15 of 1952 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
        </def><def name="Sale"><term>sale</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">出售</term>) includes exchange or
            barter.</def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1983/53">53 of 1983 s. 18</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/67">67 of 1985 s. 16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s. 24</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/11">11 of 1995 s. 16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of 1995 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604120_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411037663_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may by regulation provide
                    for—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/59">59 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411037663_019" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>licensing, regulation and control of any place, trade, business,
                    undertaking or occupation specified in the <ref>First Schedule</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15 of
                            1952 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1955/64">64 of 1955 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037663_027" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>classifying for the purposes of paragraph (a) any place, trade, business or
                    occupation for which a licence may be issued under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037663_035" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the particulars which an applicant for any licence granted under this
                    Ordinance shall furnish to any officer empowered to issue a licence
                        hereunder;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15 of 1952 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037679_006" name="d" temporalId="s3_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the form and conditions of any licence granted under this Ordinance, the
                    officers who may issue such licence and the fees therefor, the hours during
                    which such licence may be used and the period for which such licence shall be
                    issued;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037679_014" name="e" temporalId="s3_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the lighting to be used in any place licensed under this Ordinance and in
                    such regulations to provide the general specifications and requirements to be
                    satisfied in respect of such lighting, or to empower any officer specified
                    therein to determine, at the time of the issue or renewal of any licence under
                    this Ordinance, the particular specifications and requirements to be satisfied
                    in respect of such lighting in the place to which the licence relates;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1965/27">27 of
                            1965 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037679_022" name="f" temporalId="s3_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>precautions to be taken against fire in any place licensed under this
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037694_006" name="g" temporalId="s3_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>maintenance of peace and good order in any place licensed under this
                    Ordinance;<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037694_014" name="h" temporalId="s3_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>means of securing hygienic conditions and requiring the maintenance of such
                    conditions in any place licensed under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037694_022" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>entry and inspection of any place licensed under this Ordinance, by the
                    Commissioner of Police, the
                    Secretary
                    for Home and Youth Affairs or any other officer authorized by
                    the Chief Executive in that behalf;
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/ln120">L.N. 120 of 1995</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1996/ln372">L.N. 372 of 1996</ref>; <ref href="hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/ln192">L.N. 192 of 1998</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/ln206">L.N. 206 of 1998</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/59">59
                            of 2000 s.
                        3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037694_030" name="j" temporalId="s3_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>exempting any place, trade, business or occupation situated or carried on
                    within specified areas from the operation of this Ordinance or of any part
                    thereof or of any regulations made thereunder, and specifying and varying the
                    boundaries of such areas; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037694_038" name="k" temporalId="s3_1_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>generally, carrying into effect the provisions of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411037694_045" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Such regulations may provide that the contravention of any particular
                regulation shall constitute an offence and may prescribe penalties for breach of the
                regulations not exceeding a fine
                at
                level 3 or imprisonment for 6 months.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15 of 1952 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/11">11 of 1982 s.
                    3</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402604136_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Prohibition of trading, etc., without licence</heading><content>No person shall open or keep any place specified in the <ref>First Schedule</ref>, or conduct any trade, business or occupation specified in the <ref>First Schedule</ref> except under and in accordance with a licence issued under this Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1955/64">64 of 1955 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1983/53">53 of 1983 s. 18</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604151_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Grant of licences, revocation and appeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411037757_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The grant of any licence issued, or to be issued under this Ordinance and the grant of any renewal of any licence shall be in the absolute discretion of the officer authorized to issue such licence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411037757_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Such officer may revoke a licence granted to any person on proof to his satisfaction of an offence against this Ordinance or other misconduct by such person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411037757_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notice in writing of a decision of an officer under this section shall be given by such officer to the person in respect of whom it is made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411037757_028" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A notice under subsection (3) shall, except in the case of a decision to grant a licence or to grant a renewal of a licence or to permit the transfer of an existing licence or to impose other conditions, be accompanied by a statement of the reasons for the decision.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411037772_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person aggrieved by a decision of any officer made in respect of him under this section may, within 28 days from the date when he was informed of the decision, appeal to the Administrative Appeals Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411037772_013" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A decision that is appealed against under subsection (5) shall be suspended in its operation as from the day on which the appeal is made until such appeal is disposed of, withdrawn or abandoned unless such suspension would, in the opinion of any such officer, be contrary to the public interest and the notice of the decision contains a statement to that effect.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1994/6">6 of 1994 s. 41</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604151_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Search warrants</heading><content>If it is made to appear to a magistrate by information upon oath that there is reason to believe that an offence against this Ordinance is being committed in any place, the magistrate may issue a warrant authorizing any police officer to enter and search such place and to arrest such persons as may be found therein.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15 of 1952 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604167_002" name="s6A" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s6A"><num value="6A">6A.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s. 24</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604182_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411037819_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>contravenes the provisions of <ref>section 4</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037819_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fails to comply with any condition in a licence issued hereunder; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037819_028" name="c" temporalId="s7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in furnishing any particulars which he is required by regulation made hereunder
                to furnish, furnishes any information which he knows or has reason to believe to be
                false in any material particular or by reason of the omission of any material
                particular or furnishes any information without any belief in the truth or accuracy
                of the information supplied,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438411037835_012" name="i" temporalId="s7_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of an offence under paragraph (a), to a fine
                at
                level 5 or to imprisonment for 6 months; or
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411037835_020" name="ii" temporalId="s7_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of an offence under paragraph (b) or (c), to a fine
                at
                level 3 or to imprisonment for 6 months.
                </content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15 of 1952 s. 5</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/11">11 of 1982 s.
            5</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604182_003" name="s7A" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s7A"><num value="7A">7A.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s. 24</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604198_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Liability of agent</heading><content>Whenever any person to whom any licence or permit or authority has been issued or granted under this Ordinance would be liable under the provisions of this Ordinance or of any regulations made thereunder to any punishment, penalty or forfeiture for any act, omission, neglect or default, he shall be liable to the same punishment, penalty or forfeiture for every similar act, omission, neglect or default of any agent or servant employed by him in the course of his business, and every such agent or servant shall also be liable to every punishment, penalty or forfeiture prescribed for such acts, omissions, neglects or defaults contrary to the provisions of this Ordinance as fully and effectually as if he had been the person to whom the licence or permit or authority had been issued or granted.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402604198_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>The provisions of this Ordinance shall be in addition to and not in derogation of the provisions of any other enactment relating to or affecting any place, trade, business or occupation with respect to which this Ordinance applies.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1941/8">8 of 1941 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604214_002" name="s10" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s. 24</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402604260_001" name="s11" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s. 24</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402604260_003" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-03" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">First
            Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap114/s3">ss.
                3</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap114/s4">4</ref>]<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><content class="first_line_indent_0">Dancing
            school</content><content>Hawker
            of tobacco, cigars or
            cigarettes</content><content>Public
            dance-hall</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1935/22">22 of 1935 s. 7</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1941/8">8 of 1941 s.
                4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1947/42">42 of 1947 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1952/15">15
                of 1952 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1955/64">64 of 1955 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1956/50">50 of 1956 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1965/27">27 of 1965 s.
                5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1973/21">21 of 1973 s. 20</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1978/54">54
                of 1978 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1982/11">11 of 1982 s. 8</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1983/53">53 of 1983 s. 18</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/67">67 of 1985 s.
                16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s. 24</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/11">11
                of 1995 s. 17</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of 1995 s.
            2</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402604276_002" name="sch2" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1999-07-01" status="repealed" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Second
                                    Schedule</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1985/67">67 of 1985 s.
                                    16</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402604292_001" name="sch3" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="sch3"><num value="3">Third
                                    Schedule</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s.
                                    24</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402604292_003" name="sch4" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="sch4"><num value="4">Fourth
                                    Schedule</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/64">64 of 1993 s.
                                    24</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>