<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 86</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>86</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap86!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-09-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403567964_004" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-09-19">
            <content>To provide for commissions of inquiry and for purposes connected
                therewith.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[12 July 1968]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403567980_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Commissions of Inquiry Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403567980_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Appointment of Commission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068021_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may appoint one or more Commissioners
                (hereinafter referred to as a
                        <b><i>Commission</i></b>)
                to inquire into the conduct or management of any public body, the conduct of any
                public officer or into any matter whatsoever which is, in his opinion, of public
                    importance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068021_019" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>When appointing a Commission under subsection (1) the Chief Executive in Council
                    may—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414068021_027" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>nominate a Chairman if 2 or more Commissioners are appointed, and confer on
                    such Chairman a second or casting vote for use where the Commission shall, in
                    any case, be equally divided on any question arising during the
                    proceedings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068036_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fix the quorum at meetings thereof if 2 or more Commissioners are
                    appointed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068036_014" name="c" temporalId="s2_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>appoint a secretary to the Commission, assistant secretaries and other
                    staff;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068036_022" name="d" temporalId="s2_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>appoint a legal adviser to the Commission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068036_030" name="e" temporalId="s2_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>appoint additional Commissioners or persons in substitution for
                    Commissioners who may die, resign, refuse to act, or become incapable of
                    acting.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068036_037" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a new Commissioner has been appointed under subsection (2), it shall not
                be necessary for any evidence which may have been taken before the Commission prior
                to such appointment to be retaken.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068036_045" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The appointment of a Commission shall be published in the Gazette.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403567996_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Directions to Commission</heading><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may specify the subject of the inquiry and may
                direct—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414068083_019" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>when and where the inquiry is to be held, to whom and by what time a report
                thereon is to be rendered, and may from time to time enlarge the time within which
                such inquiry is to be held and such report rendered;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068099_006" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>without prejudice to the powers of the Commission to receive and consider such
                other evidence as it may think fit, what material should be received and considered
                by the Commission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068099_014" name="c" temporalId="s3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>what matters should be outside the terms of reference of the
                Commission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068099_022" name="d" temporalId="s3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that the evidence of certain persons or classes of persons be taken, either
                orally or in writing, and that certain documents or classes of documents be
                inspected by the Commission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068099_030" name="e" temporalId="s3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>without prejudice to the powers conferred upon the Commission by <ref>section
                    4(1)(i)</ref>, that the holding of the inquiry or parts thereof be in camera;
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of 1976 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068099_038" name="f" temporalId="s3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>that the Commissioners take the oath or affirmation in the form set out in the
                    <ref>Schedule</ref>; and
                    <i>(See
                    Form 1)</i></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068099_046" name="g" temporalId="s3_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>that the Commission shall have and exercise the powers conferred by
                    <ref>section 9</ref> to punish all or any of the contempts specified in
                    <ref>section 8</ref>.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403567996_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of Commission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068145_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Commission may, for the purpose of complying with the directions issued
                under <ref>section 3</ref> and for conducting the inquiry generally—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414068145_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>receive and consider any material whether by way of oral evidence, written
                    statements, documents or otherwise, notwithstanding that such material would not
                    be admissible as evidence in civil or criminal proceedings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068145_027" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>determine the manner in which such material shall be received and what
                    persons or class of persons shall be permitted or required to give
                    evidence:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_1_b_proviso">Provided that the contents of
                    any document submitted to the Commission, not being of a scurrilous or offensive
                    nature, shall be considered by the Commission, notwithstanding that the person
                    submitting such document is, in addition, permitted or required to give
                    evidence;</proviso></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068161_012" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>require any person who wishes to give evidence before the Commission to
                    submit a summary in writing of the evidence proposed to be given;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068161_020" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>summon any person in the form set out in the <ref>Schedule</ref> to attend
                    to give evidence or to produce any article or document;
                        <i>(See
                        Form 2)</i></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068161_028" name="e" temporalId="s4_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>issue warrants of arrest to compel the attendance of any person not
                    complying with a summons issued under paragraph (d);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068161_036" name="f" temporalId="s4_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>administer oaths and affirmations;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068161_044" name="g" temporalId="s4_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>examine on oath, affirmation or otherwise any person attending before the
                    Commission and require such person to answer all questions put by or with the
                    consent of the Commission and produce any article or document in his possession
                    or under his control;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068177_006" name="h" temporalId="s4_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>award any person attending before the Commission such sum as in the opinion
                    of the Commission represents the loss to that person occasioned by the time
                    spent in such attendance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068177_014" name="i" temporalId="s4_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><leadIn>hold in camera, or exclude any person (including any person implicated or
                    concerned therein and his legal representatives) from, the whole or any part of
                    the inquiry:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_1_i_proviso">Provided that any legal
                    representative entitled to appear by virtue of the provisions of <ref>section
                        6</ref>—</proviso><subparagraph id="ID_1438414068177_029" name="i" temporalId="s4_1_i_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>may only be excluded from such part of the inquiry as is held in
                        camera;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414068177_037" name="ii" temporalId="s4_1_i_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>shall not in any event be so excluded while his client is giving
                        evidence;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068177_044" name="j" temporalId="s4_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>prohibit the publication to or disclosure by any person attending before
                    the Commission of all or part of the material received by the
                    Commission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068177_052" name="k" temporalId="s4_1_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>enter and inspect any premises;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068192_006" name="l" temporalId="s4_1_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>issue warrants for the searching of premises and the seizure therein of any
                    article or document or any class of articles or documents specified in the
                    warrant (as being likely to be of evidential value for the purposes of the
                    inquiry);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068192_014" name="m" temporalId="s4_1_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>determine the procedure to be followed at the inquiry and the form of any
                    summons, warrant, or other document made or issued by the Commission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068192_022" name="ma" temporalId="s4_1_ma"><num value="ma">(ma)</num><leadIn>where the Commission has been appointed to inquire into the conduct or
                    management of a public body or any other body of persons, corporate or
                    unincorporate, then, subject to subsection (3), appoint, on such terms as to
                    remuneration as the Financial Secretary may approve, one or more
                    inspectors—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414068192_030" name="i" temporalId="s4_1_ma_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to inspect all the books and documents of or relating to the affairs of
                        such body; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414068192_038" name="ii" temporalId="s4_1_ma_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the Commission is satisfied that such body has, or has had, an
                        association with any other public body or body of persons, corporate or
                        unincorporate, which is or may be relevant to the subject of the
                        Commission’s inquiry, to inspect all the books and documents of or relating
                        to the affairs of such other body,</content></subparagraph><continued>and to report thereon to the Commission in such manner and within such
                    period or further period as the Commission may direct; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of
                            1976 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068208_012" name="n" temporalId="s4_1_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content>exercise such other powers as may be necessary for the purposes of the
                    inquiry.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068208_019" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to the powers conferred on a Commission by subsection
                    <ref>(1)(ma)</ref>, where the Commission consists of one Commissioner he may
                himself, and where the Commission consists of more than one Commissioner one or more
                of the Commissioners, selected by the Commission may, subject to subsection (3),
                inspect the books and documents referred to in subsection <ref>(1)(ma)</ref>, and in
                so doing he or they shall, for the purposes of this Ordinance, be deemed to have
                been duly appointed an inspector or inspectors, as the case may be, under subsection
                    <ref>(1)(ma)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of 1976 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068223_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The power to appoint an inspector or inspectors under subsection (1), and the
                powers conferred by subsection (2), shall not be exercised by a Commission or
                Commissioner without the consent of the Chief Executive in Council, and in giving
                such consent the Chief Executive in Council may limit the power of inspection to
                inspection only of the books and documents referred to in subsection
                    <ref>(1)(ma)(i)</ref> or, where consent is given in relation to the inspection
                of books and documents referred to in subsection <ref>(1)(ma)(ii)</ref>, may limit
                the power of inspection to inspection only of the books and documents of or relating
                to the affairs of a particular public body or other body of persons, corporate or
                    unincorporate.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of 1976 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25
                        of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568011_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Conduct of inquiry</heading><leadIn>Without derogating from the generality of the power conferred under <ref>section 4(1)(m)</ref> the Commission may—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of 1976 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414068333_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>order the manner in which any person shall give his oral evidence and may
                specify that this shall be by way of cross-examination without any
                examination-in-chief;
                and <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068348_005" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>determine who may address the Commission, on what matters and in what order.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403568027_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Right to representation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068364_011" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person whose conduct is the subject of an inquiry, or who is implicated or
                concerned in the subject matter of the inquiry, shall, subject to the provisions of
                    <ref>section 4</ref>, be entitled to be represented by a barrister or solicitor
                at the inquiry.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068364_019" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purpose of subsection (1), the Commission shall determine whether the
                conduct of any person is the subject of the inquiry or whether a person is in any
                way implicated or concerned in the subject matter of the inquiry.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068379_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive, any Government department and any public officer shall,
                notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (1) and (2) but subject to the
                provisions of <ref>section 4</ref>, be entitled to be represented at the inquiry by
                a legal officer, or by a barrister or solicitor who may—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414068379_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>address the Commission on any matter on which he is so instructed by the
                    Chief Secretary for Administration or by the Secretary for
                    Justice;
                    and <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226
                            of 1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                        1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of
                        2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068379_021" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>produce evidence in such form as the Commission may permit on any
                    matter.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068395_002" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Commission may appoint a legal officer nominated by the Secretary for
                Justice, a barrister or a solicitor to act as counsel for the Commission.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N.
                        362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568027_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Use of evidence in civil and criminal proceedings</heading><content>Evidence given by any person before the Commission shall not be admissible against him in any civil or criminal proceedings by or against him, except where he is charged with any offence under Part V (Perjury) of the Crimes Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap200">Cap. 200</ref>) or is proceeded against under <ref>section 8</ref> or <ref>9</ref>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403568058_002" name="s7A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7A"><num value="7A">7A.</num><heading>Production of documents, and evidence, to Commission’s inspectors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068442_011" name="1" temporalId="s7A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It shall be the duty of all officers and agents of a public body or other body of persons to produce to an inspector appointed under <ref>section 4(1)(ma)</ref> to inspect its books and documents, all books and documents in their custody or power of or relating to such body’s affairs or the affairs of any other body of persons the books and documents of which the inspector is appointed under <ref>section 4(1)(ma)</ref> to inspect, and otherwise to give to the inspector all assistance that they are reasonably able to give.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068457_005" name="2" temporalId="s7A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Agents">In this section, any reference to officers or to agents of a public
                body or other body of persons shall include past, as well as present, officers or
                agents, as the case may be, and for the purposes of this section
                    <term>agents</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">代理人</term>) shall include the bankers and
                solicitors of such body and any person employed by such body as auditor, whether
                such person is or is not an officer of such body.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of 1976 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568058_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Contempts to be offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068489_019" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414068504_005" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>fails without reasonable excuse to attend at the time and place specified
                    in a summons issued under <ref>section 4</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068504_013" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>refuses to take an oath or make an affirmation on being required to do so
                    under <ref>section 4</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068504_021" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>refuses to answer any question put by or with the consent of the Commission
                    or to produce any article or document in his possession or under his control on
                    being required to do so under <ref>section 4</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068504_029" name="ca" temporalId="s8_1_ca"><num value="ca">(ca)</num><leadIn>being an officer or agent of a public body or other body of persons within
                    the meaning of <ref>section 7A</ref>—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414068504_037" name="i" temporalId="s8_1_ca_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>after the appointment of a Commission and with intent to avoid or
                        prevent production, destroys, suppresses, defaces or makes away with any
                        book or document that it would be his duty to produce to an inspector in the
                        event of an inspector being appointed under <ref>section
                        4(1)(ma)</ref>;
                        or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414068520_007" name="ii" temporalId="s8_1_ca_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>refuses, without lawful authority or reasonable excuse, to produce any
                        such book or document to an inspector so
                        appointed;
                        or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414068520_015" name="iii" temporalId="s8_1_ca_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>refuses, without lawful authority or reasonable excuse, to answer any
                        question put to him by an inspector so appointed with respect to the affairs
                        of such body or any other body the books and documents of which the
                        inspector has been appointed to inspect;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of 1976 s.
                                6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068520_022" name="d" temporalId="s8_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>wilfully interrupts the proceedings of the Commission or otherwise
                    misbehaves during any hearing of the Commission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068520_030" name="e" temporalId="s8_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>having been summoned to attend, leaves the place in which a Commission is
                    being held without the permission of the Commission,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1 and to imprisonment for 3 months.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068535_011" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414068535_019" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>wilfully hinders or deters any person from attending, giving evidence or
                    producing any article or document;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068535_027" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>threatens, insults or causes any loss to be suffered by any person who has
                    attended before the Commission, on account of such attendance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068535_035" name="c" temporalId="s8_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>threatens, insults or causes a loss to be suffered by any Commissioner at
                    any time on account of the performance of his duties as a
                    Commissioner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068535_043" name="d" temporalId="s8_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>publishes or otherwise discloses any material which the Commission had
                    prohibited him from publishing or disclosing;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414068535_051" name="e" temporalId="s8_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>publishes or otherwise discloses any material received by the Commission in
                    camera,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and liable on conviction upon indictment to a
                fine
                at
                level 3 and to imprisonment for 1 year.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068551_004" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>It shall be a good defence in the case of a prosecution under subsection
                    <ref>(2)(e)</ref> for the person charged to prove to the satisfaction of the
                court that he did not know nor had any reason for knowing that the material
                published or disclosed had been received by the Commission in camera.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er4">E.R. 4 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568074_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Contempts dealt with by Commission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068598_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Commission may, if so empowered under <ref>section 3</ref>, deal summarily
                as a contempt with any offence specified in <ref>section 8</ref> which is committed
                in its presence, and may impose the sentence prescribed by that section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068613_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In the case of contempts not committed in the presence of the Commission, it
                may, if so empowered under <ref>section 3</ref>, summon the offender to appear
                before it at the time and place specified in the summons, there to show cause why
                the offender should not be sentenced for the contempt, and may impose the sentence
                prescribed by <ref>section 8</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068613_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Commission may issue warrants of arrest to compel the attendance of any
                person not complying with a summons issued under subsection (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068629_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any sentence of imprisonment imposed under this section may be remitted where
                the Commission is of the opinion that the contempt has been purged.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068629_013" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person aggrieved by any decision, order or sentence of the Commission in
                exercise of the powers conferred by subsection (1) or (2) may appeal to a judge of
                the Court of First Instance, in the same manner as if it were an order of a
                magistrate in respect of which an appeal lies under <ref>section 113</ref> of the
                Magistrates Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap227">Cap. 227</ref>), in accordance with
                rules made by the Chief Justice.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568074_004" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Commission to have powers of judge</heading><content>For the purposes of enforcing the payment of any fine imposed or giving effect to any warrant of arrest or sentence of imprisonment or for other like purposes, the Commission shall have the powers of a judge. In the exercise of such powers and for the purpose of issuing warrants, summoning persons and the exercise of other like powers the Chairman may do all necessary acts in the name of the Commission.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403568089_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Inquiry to be a judicial proceeding</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068691_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every inquiry held under this Ordinance shall be deemed to be a judicial
                proceeding.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068691_019" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any conduct which would constitute contempt of the Court of First Instance or
                of a judge, if it were committed towards the Court of First Instance or a judge as
                the case may be, shall be a contempt of a Commission and may be dealt with and
                punished by a judge of the Court of First Instance as a contempt of the Court of
                First Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568089_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Protection of Commission and witnesses</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414068738_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>No Commissioner shall be liable to any suit or other proceeding for any act
                    or thing done by him bona fide as such Commissioner:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s12_1_proviso">Provided that nothing in this
                    subsection shall be deemed to limit the power of the Court of First Instance to
                    make an order of mandamus, certiorari or prohibition in relation to proceedings
                    before a Commission.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068738_018" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All evidence given before a Commission shall be absolutely privileged, and no
                witness giving such evidence shall be liable to any suit or other civil proceeding
                in respect thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414068738_026" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A legal officer, barrister or solicitor appearing before a Commission, whether
                as counsel for the Commission or otherwise under or by virtue of <ref>section
                    6</ref>, shall be entitled to the same immunities as if he were appearing for a
                party in proceedings before the Court of First Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/49">49 of 1976 s.
                    7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568105_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Police and bailiffs to assist Commission</heading><content>Police officers and bailiffs of the court shall assist any Commission conducting an inquiry under this Ordinance for such purposes as the Commission may require and may do all such things as are necessary for the purpose of rendering such assistance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403568105_004" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Cost of inquiry</heading><content class="align_justified">The cost of any inquiry conducted under this Ordinance,
            including any sums awarded under <ref>section 4(1)(h)</ref>, shall be a charge on the
            general revenue of Hong Kong.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568120_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Protection of person publishing true account</heading><content class="align_justified">Subject to <ref>section 8(2)(d)</ref> no person shall be
            liable to any civil or criminal proceedings by reason of his publishing a true account
            of any evidence taken in public before a Commission or of any report of a Commission
            published by the authority of the Chief Executive.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438403568120_004" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-09-19" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Form 1</inline></crossHeading><note class="align_right">[<ref href="/hk/cap86/s3">s. 3</ref>]</note><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Form of oath or affirmation to be taken by
                a
            Commissioner</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">I, <fillIn class="width_106">.</fillIn>, swear by Almighty God (solemnly promise and declare) that I will
            diligently inquire into the matters prescribed in the instrument appointing this
            Commission and will truly and faithfully execute the powers and trusts vested in me by
            the Commissions of Inquiry Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap86">Chapter 86</ref>) according
            to the best of my knowledge and
            judgment.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_center"><fillIn class="width_57 align_center">_</fillIn></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Form
            2</inline></crossHeading><note class="align_right">[<ref href="/hk/cap86/s4">s.
            4</ref>]</note><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Summons to a
            witness</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text>To
                <i>A.B.</i> [<i>name of person summoned and his
            address</i>].<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">You are hereby summoned to
            appear before the Commission appointed by the Chief Executive to inquire [<i>state
                subject matter of inquiry</i>] <fillIn class=" width_45">.</fillIn> at
            [<i>place</i>] <fillIn class=" width_40">.</fillIn> upon the <fillIn class=" width_66">.</fillIn> day of <fillIn class=" width_55">.</fillIn> at <fillIn class=" width_25">.</fillIn> o’clock in the <fillIn class=" width_45">.</fillIn> noon and to give
            evidence respecting such inquiry, and you are required to bring with you [<i>specify
                documents, etc.</i>] <fillIn class=" width_75">.</fillIn><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Given under the hand of
                <fillIn class=" width_84">.</fillIn>, Commissioner, this <fillIn class=" width_43">.</fillIn> day of <fillIn class=" width_75">.</fillIn> 19 <fillIn class=" width_30">.</fillIn><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_right"><i>Signature</i>
            <fillIn class="width_110">.</fillIn></text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="445">
                
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td class="align_center"><span class="small_caps"></span></td>
                        
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            <content class="align_right"><i></i></content>
            
        </text></schedule></main></ordinance>