<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 32 sub. leg. K</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>32K</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap32K!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-04-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403014900_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-04-11">Companies (Disqualification
            of
            Directors)
            Proceedings
            Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap32/s168S">Cap. 32, section
                168S(1)</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2019</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[15 July 1994]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403014916_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these Rules—</leadIn><def name="Registrar"><term>Registrar</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">司法常務官</term>) means the Registrar of the High Court and
            includes a senior deputy registrar, deputy registrar or assistant registrar of the High Court.
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/10">10 of 2005 s.
            174</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section><section id="ID_1438403014931_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>These Rules apply with respect to an application for a disqualification order to
            which <ref>section 168P(1)</ref> of the Ordinance applies, where made on or after the
            date on which these Rules come into
            force*.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" orientation="portrait" id="ID_1545120523969_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 15 July
                1994.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403014931_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Form of application</heading><content>An application to which these Rules apply shall be made to the court by originating
            summons (Form No. 10 in Appendix A to the Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg. A</ref>), with such adaptation as may be appropriate), and the
            Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg. A</ref>) apply
            accordingly, except where these Rules make provision to inconsistent effect.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403014947_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>The case against the respondent</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411957675_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall, at the time when the summons is issued, be filed in court evidence in support of the application for a disqualification order; and copies of the evidence shall be served with the summons on the respondent.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957675_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The evidence shall be by one or more affidavits, except where the applicant is the Official Receiver, in which case it may be in the form of one or more written reports (with or without affidavits by other persons) which shall be treated as if it had been verified by affidavit by him and shall be prima facie evidence of any matter contained in it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957690_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In an application made under <ref>section 168I(1)</ref> of the
                                Ordinance or <ref>section 879(6)</ref> of the Companies Ordinance
                                        (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>), there shall in the
                                affidavit or affidavits or (as the case may be) the Official
                                Receiver’s report or reports (as the case may be) be included a
                                statement of the matters by reference to which the respondent is
                                alleged to be unfit to be concerned in the management of a
                                        company.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403014947_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Endorsement on summons</heading><leadIn>There shall on the summons be endorsed information to the respondent as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411957706_042" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the application is made in accordance with these Rules;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957706_050" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the maximum, and minimum if applicable, period of disqualification under the section under which the application is made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957722_008" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that the application for a disqualification order may, in accordance with these Rules, be heard and determined summarily, without further or other notice to the respondent, and that, if it is so heard and determined, the court may impose disqualification for a period of up to 5 years;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957722_016" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that if at the hearing of the application the court, on the evidence then before it, is minded to impose, in the respondent’s case, disqualification for any period longer than 5 years, it will not make a disqualification order on that occasion but will adjourn the application to be heard (with further evidence, if any) at a later date to be notified; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957722_024" name="e" temporalId="s5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>that any evidence which the respondent wishes to be taken into consideration by the court must be filed in court in accordance with the time limits imposed under <ref>rule 7</ref> (the provisions of which shall be set out on the summons).</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403014962_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Service and acknowledgment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411957753_011" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The summons shall be served on the respondent by sending it by post to his last
                known address; and the date of service shall, unless the contrary is shown, be
                deemed to be the 7th day next following that on which the summons was
                posted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957753_019" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any process or order of the court or other document is required under
                proceedings subject to these Rules to be served on any person who is not in Hong
                Kong, the court may order service on him of that process or order or other document
                to be effected within such time and in such manner as it thinks fit, and may also
                require such proof of service as it thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957768_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The summons served on the respondent shall be accompanied by a form of
                acknowledgment of service, to be returned by him to the court within 14 days from
                the date of service, and for this purpose the practice and procedure of the court
                relating to acknowledgments of service shall apply to an application for an order
                under these Rules in the court, save that any reference to Form No. 15 in Appendix A
                to the Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg. A</ref>)
                shall relate to the form as modified by these Rules.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957784_005" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The form of acknowledgment of service shall, where appropriate, state that the
                respondent should indicate—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411957784_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>whether he contests the application on the grounds that, in the case of any
                    particular company—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411957784_021" name="i" temporalId="s6_4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>he was not a director, shadow director, officer or liquidator of the
                        company, and neither was he a receiver or manager of its property, at a time
                        when conduct of his, or of other persons, in relation to that company is in
                        question; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411957784_029" name="ii" temporalId="s6_4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>his conduct as such director, shadow director, officer, liquidator,
                        receiver or manager was not as alleged in support of the application for a
                        disqualification order;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957784_036" name="b" temporalId="s6_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>whether, in the case of any conduct of his, he disputes the allegation that
                    such conduct makes him unfit to be concerned in the management of a company;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957784_044" name="c" temporalId="s6_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>whether he, while not resisting the application for a disqualification
                    order, intends to adduce mitigating factors with a view to justifying only a
                    short period of disqualification.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403014978_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Evidence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411957831_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The respondent shall, within 28 days from the date of service of the summons, file in court any affidavit evidence in opposition to the application he wishes the court to take into consideration and shall forthwith serve upon the applicant a copy of such evidence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957831_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The applicant shall, within 21 days from receiving the copy of the respondent’s evidence, file in court any further evidence in reply he wishes the court to take into consideration and shall forthwith serve a copy of that evidence upon the respondent.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403014994_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>The hearing of the application</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411957846_026" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The date fixed for the hearing of the application shall be not less than 8 weeks from the date of issue of the summons.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957846_034" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The hearing shall in the first instance be before the Registrar in open court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957846_042" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Registrar shall either determine the case on the date fixed or adjourn it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957846_050" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The Registrar shall adjourn the case for further consideration if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411957862_004" name="a" temporalId="s8_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he forms the provisional opinion that a disqualification order ought to be made, and that a period of disqualification longer than 5 years is appropriate; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957862_012" name="b" temporalId="s8_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he is of opinion that questions of law or fact arise which are not suitable for summary determination.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957862_019" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>If the Registrar adjourns the case for further consideration he shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411957862_027" name="a" temporalId="s8_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>direct whether the case is to be heard by a Registrar or, if he thinks it appropriate, by a judge, for determination by him;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957862_035" name="b" temporalId="s8_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>state the reasons for the adjournment; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411957862_043" name="c" temporalId="s8_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>give directions as to the following matters—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411957862_051" name="i" temporalId="s8_5_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the manner in which and the time within which notice of the adjournment and the reasons for it are to be given to the respondent;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411957862_059" name="ii" temporalId="s8_5_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the filing in court and the service of further evidence (if any) by the parties;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411957862_067" name="iii" temporalId="s8_5_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>such other matters as the Registrar thinks necessary or expedient with a view to an expeditious disposal of the application; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411957862_075" name="iv" temporalId="s8_5_c_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>the time and place of the adjourned hearing.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957862_081" name="6" temporalId="s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where a case is adjourned other than to a judge, it may be heard by the Registrar who originally dealt with the case or by another Registrar.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015009_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Making and setting aside of disqualification order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411957893_066" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The court may make a disqualification order against the respondent, whether or not the latter appears, and whether or not he had completed and returned the acknowledgment of service of the summons, or filed evidence in accordance with <ref>rule 7</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411957909_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any disqualification order made in the absence of the respondent may be set aside or varied by the court on such terms as it thinks just.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015009_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Commencement of disqualification order</heading><content>Unless the court otherwise orders, a disqualification order takes effect at the beginning of the 21st day after the day on which the order is made.</content></section></main></subLeg>