<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 21</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>21</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap21!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-03-03</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402832770_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-03-03">
            <content>To amend the law respecting defamatory words and
                libel.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[22 February 1887]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402832801_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Defamation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832816_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Broadcast,Broadcasting"><term>broadcast</term>
                                    or
                                                <term>broadcasting</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">廣播</term>) means
                                    publication for general reception, as part of any programme or
                                    service provided through a broadcasting station within Hong
                                    Kong, by means of telecommunications, within the meaning of the
                                    Telecommunications Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap106">Cap.
                                                106</ref>); and, where words broadcast by means of
                                    telecommunications are simultaneously transmitted by telegraph,
                                    as defined by the Telecommunications Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap106">Cap. 106</ref>), in accordance
                                    with a licence granted under such Ordinance, the provisions of
                                    this Ordinance shall apply as if the transmission were broadcast
                                    within the definition hereinbefore contained;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1986/23">23 of 1986 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/36">36 of 2000 s.
                                                28</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="BroadcastingStation"><term>broadcasting
                                                station</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">廣播電台</term>) means any
                                    station operated by Government or in respect of which a licence
                                    granted by the Governor in Council or the Authority under the
                                    Telecommunications Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap106">Cap.
                                                106</ref>) is in force, being a licence which (by
                                    whatever form of words) authorizes the use of the station for
                                    the purpose of providing broadcasting services for general
                                                reception;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/38">38 of 1993 s. 9</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/36">36 of 2000 s.
                                                28</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Information"><term>information</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">告發</term>) includes
                                    indictment;</def><def name="InternationalCourtOfJustice"><term>international
                                                court of
                                    justice</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">國際法院</term>) means the
                                    International Court of Justice and any other judicial or
                                    arbitral tribunal deciding matters in dispute between
                                    States;</def><def name="Legislature"><term>legislature</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">立法機構</term>),
                                    in relation to any part of the Commonwealth which is subject to
                                    a central and a local legislature, means either of those
                                    legislatures;</def><def name="Newspaper"><term>newspaper</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">報刊</term>) means any
                                    paper containing public news or observations thereon or
                                    consisting wholly or mainly of advertisements which is printed
                                    for sale and is published in Hong Kong either periodically or in
                                    parts or numbers at intervals not exceeding 36 days;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1986/23">23 of 1986 s.
                                                2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Proprietor"><term>proprietor</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">東主</term>) includes
                                    lessee;</def><def name="ReportOfTheLegislativeCouncil"><term>report
                                                of the Legislative
                                    Council</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">立法局報告</term>) includes
                                    any report, paper, vote or other proceeding of the
                                    Council;</def><def name="Words"><term>words</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">言詞</term>) includes
                                    pictures, visual images, gestures and other methods of
                                    signifying meaning.</def><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote> [cf. 1952 c. 66 ss. 7, 9 &amp; <ref>Schedule</ref> Part III U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832816_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Admissibility in evidence, in mitigation of damages in action for defamation, of apology</heading><content>In any action for defamation it shall be competent to the defendant (after notice in writing of his intention to do so duly given to the plaintiff within a reasonable time before the trial of the cause) to give in evidence in mitigation of damages that he made or offered an apology to the plaintiff for such defamation before the commencement of the action, or as soon afterwards as he had an opportunity of doing so in case the action has been commenced before there was an opportunity of making or offering such apology.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1843 c. 96 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832832_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Right of defendant in action for libel to plead absence of malice, etc. and
            apology</heading><leadIn>In an action for a libel contained in any newspaper it shall be competent to the
            defendant to set up as a defence that the libel was inserted in the newspaper without
            actual malice and without gross negligence, and that before the commencement of the
            action, or at the earliest opportunity afterwards, he inserted in the newspaper a full
            apology for the libel, or if the newspaper in which the libel appeared is ordinarily
            published at intervals exceeding 1 week, had offered to publish the said apology in any
            newspaper to be selected by the plaintiff in the action: and to such defence to the
            action it shall be competent to the plaintiff to reply generally denying the whole of
            such defence:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/ln307">L.N. 307 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_proviso">Provided that it shall not be competent to
            any defendant in such action to set up any defence as aforesaid without at the same time
            making a payment of money into court by way of amends, and every such defence so filed
            without such payment into court shall be deemed a nullity and may be treated as such by
            the plaintiff in the action. </proviso><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/62">62 of
                1911 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 3</ref>) </sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1843 c. 96 s. 2
            U.K.
            &amp;
            1845 c. 75 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832848_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Publishing libel known to be false</heading><content>Any person who maliciously publishes any defamatory libel, knowing the same to be false, shall be liable to imprisonment for 2 years, and, in addition, to pay such fine as the court may award.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/30">30 of 1911 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1843 c. 96 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832848_003" name="s6" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832879_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Trial of information for defamatory libel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411553915_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the trial of any information for a defamatory libel, the defendant having pleaded such plea as is hereinafter mentioned, the truth of the matters charged may be inquired into, but shall not amount to a defence, unless it was for the public benefit that the matters charged should be published.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411553931_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>To entitle the defendant to give evidence of the truth of the matters charged as a defence to the information, it shall be necessary for him, in pleading to the information, to allege the truth of the matters charged in the manner now required in alleging a justification to an action of defamation, and further to allege that it was for the public benefit that the matters charged should be published, and the particular fact or facts by reason whereof it was for the public benefit that the matters charged should be published, to which plea the prosecutor shall be at liberty to reply generally denying the whole thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411553946_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>If after such plea the defendant is convicted on the information, it shall be competent to the court, in pronouncing sentence, to consider whether the guilt of the defendant is aggravated or mitigated by the plea and by the evidence given to prove or to disprove the same: </leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_3_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411553946_020" name="a" temporalId="s7_3_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the truth of the matters charged in the alleged libel complained of by the information shall in no case be inquired into without such plea of justification; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411553946_028" name="b" temporalId="s7_3_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in addition to such plea it shall be competent to the defendant to plead a plea of not guilty;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411553946_036" name="c" temporalId="s7_3_proviso_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>further, nothing in this Ordinance shall take away or prejudice any defence under a plea of not guilty which it is now competent to the defendant to make under such plea to any information for defamatory words or libel. </content></paragraph></proviso></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1843 c. 96 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402832879_003" name="s7A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s7A"><num value="7A">7A.</num><heading>Functions of judge and jury on the trial of an indictment for libel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411553993_049" name="1" temporalId="s7A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On the trial of an indictment for publishing any libel, the jury sworn to try
                the matter may give a general verdict of guilty or not guilty on the
                matter.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411553993_057" name="2" temporalId="s7A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The judge before whom an indictment referred to in subsection (1) is tried
                shall not direct the jury to find a defendant guilty merely on the proof of the
                publication by the defendant of the matter charged to be a libel, and of the meaning
                ascribed to the libel in the indictment, but subject to this, the judge shall,
                according to his discretion, give his opinion and directions to the jury on the
                matter in issue in the same manner as in the trial of other criminal
                matters.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554009_005" name="3" temporalId="s7A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this section prevents the jury from finding a special verdict as in
                other criminal cases.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554009_013" name="4" temporalId="s7A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If the jury referred to in subsection (1) finds the defendant guilty, the
                defendant may move in arrest of judgment on such ground and in such manner as by law
                he could have done before the
                commencement*
                of this section.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/14">14 of 1997 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1792 c. 60 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1632733589338_001">
        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
        <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 May 1997.</content>
    </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438402832894_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Evidence to rebut prima facie case of publication by agent</heading><content>Whenever, on the trial of any information for the publication of a libel, under the plea of not guilty, evidence has been given which establishes a presumptive case of publication against the defendant by the act of any other person by his authority, it shall be competent to the defendant to prove that the publication was made without his authority, consent, or knowledge, and that the publication did not arise from want of due care or caution on his part.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1843 c. 96 s. 7 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832910_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Right of prosecutor and of defendant to costs on prosecution for private libel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554055_018" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the case of any information at the instance of a private prosecutor for the publication of any defamatory libel, if judgment is given for the defendant, he shall be entitled to recover from the prosecutor the costs sustained by the defendant by reason of the information, and upon a special plea of justification to the information, if the issue is found for the prosecutor, he shall be entitled to recover from the defendant the costs sustained by the prosecutor by reason of such plea.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554071_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Costs so to be recovered by the defendant or prosecutor respectively shall be taxed by the proper officer of the court before which the information is tried.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1843 c. 96 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402832910_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Stay of proceeding against person for publication of papers printed by order of Legislative Council upon certificate and affidavit of authority to publish</heading><content>It shall be lawful for any person who is a defendant in any civil or criminal proceeding, in whatever manner commenced for or on account or in respect of the publication by such person or by his servant of any report of the Legislative Council by or under the authority of such Council, to bring before the court in which such proceeding has been commenced, or before a judge, first giving 24 hours’ notice of his intention to do so to the plaintiff or prosecutor in such proceeding, a certificate under the hand of the President of such Council, or of the presiding member of such Council for the time being, or of the Clerk to the Legislative Council, stating that the report in respect whereof the proceeding has been commenced was published by such person or by his servant by order or under the authority of such Council, together with an affidavit verifying such certificate; and the court or judge shall thereupon immediately stay such proceeding, and the same, and every writ or process issued, shall be and shall be deemed and taken to be finally put an end to, determined, and superseded.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/14">14 of 1994 s. 24</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1840 c. 9 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832926_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Stay of proceeding when commenced in respect of copy of authenticated report,
            etc.</heading><content>In case of any civil or criminal proceeding to be commenced for or on account or in
            respect of the publication of any copy of any such report it shall be lawful for the
            defendant, at any stage of the proceeding, to lay before the court or judge the report,
            and the copy, together with an affidavit verifying the report, and the correctness of
            the copy; and the court or judge shall thereupon immediately stay such proceeding, and
            the same, and every writ or process issued therein, shall be and shall be deemed and
            taken to be finally put an end to, determined, and superseded.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/51">51 of
                1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/62">62 of 1911 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1911/63">63 of 1911 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1912/21">21 of 1912 s.
                2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1840 c. 9 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832941_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Defence in proceeding for printing extract from report, etc.</heading><content>It shall be lawful in any civil or criminal proceeding to be commenced for printing or broadcasting any extract from or abstract of any such report to give in evidence, in a civil case in support of any allegation in defence, and in a criminal case under the general issue, the report, and to show that the extract or abstract was published bona fide and without malice; and if such is the opinion of the jury, a verdict of not guilty shall be entered for the defendant.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/62">62 of 1911 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1840 c. 9 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832941_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Privilege of newspaper report of proceedings in court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554165_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>A fair and accurate report in any newspaper or broadcast of proceedings publicly heard before any court shall, if published contemporaneously with such proceedings, be privileged:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s13_1_proviso">Provided that nothing in this section shall authorize the publication of any blasphemous or indecent matter.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1901/9">9 of 1901 s. 3</ref> incorporated. Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/62">62 of 1911 </ref><ref>Schedule</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1888 c. 64 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554165_018" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any report in a newspaper, and any broadcast report, of committal proceedings in a case where publication is permitted by virtue only of <ref>section 87A(5)</ref> and (6) of the Magistrates Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap227">Cap. 227</ref>), published as soon as practicable after it is so permitted, shall be treated for the purposes of subsection (1) as having been published or broadcast contemporaneously with the committal proceedings.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/6">6 of 1971 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1967 c. 80 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402832957_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Qualified privilege of newspapers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554196_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this section, the publication in a newspaper or the broadcasting of any such report or other matter as is mentioned in the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall be privileged unless the publication is proved to be made with malice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554196_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In an action for libel in respect of the publication of any such report or matter as is mentioned in Part II of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, the provisions of this section shall not be a defence if it is proved that the defendant has been requested by the plaintiff to publish in the manner in which the original publication was made a reasonable letter or statement by way of explanation or contradiction, and has refused or neglected to do so, or has done so in a manner not adequate or not reasonable having regard to all the circumstances.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554211_005" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as protecting the publication of any matter the publication of which is prohibited by law, or of any matter which is not of public concern and the publication of which is not for the public benefit.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 7 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832957_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Inquiry by magistrate as to libel being true, etc.</heading><content>A magistrate, on the hearing of a charge against a proprietor, publisher, or
            editor, or any person responsible for the publication of a newspaper, for a libel
            published therein, may receive evidence as to the matter charged in the libel being
            true, and as to the report being fair and accurate and published without malice, and as
            to the publication being for the public benefit, and as to any matter which, under this
            or any other Ordinance or otherwise, might be given in evidence by way of defence by the
            person charged on his trial on information, and if the magistrate is of opinion that
            there is a strong or probable presumption that the jury on the trial would acquit the
            person charged he may dismiss the case.</content></section><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/51">51 of
            1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/62">62 of 1911 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1911/63">63 of 1911 </ref>Schedule) </sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1881 c. 60 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote><section id="ID_1438402832972_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Provision as to summary conviction for libel</heading><content>If a magistrate, on the hearing of such a charge is of opinion that, though the
            person charged is shown to have been guilty, the libel was of a trivial character, and
            that the offence may be adequately punished by virtue of the powers of this section, he
            shall cause the charge to be reduced into writing and read to the person charged, and
            then address a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>question to him to the following
            effect—“Do
            you desire to be tried by a jury or do you consent to the case being dealt with
            summarily?” and if such person assents to the case being dealt with summarily, the
            magistrate may summarily convict him and adjudge him to pay a fine of $250.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/51">51 of
                1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/62">62 of 1911 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1911/63">63 of 1911 </ref>Schedule) </sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1881 c. 60 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832972_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Evidence of other damages recovered by plaintiff</heading><content>In any action for libel or slander the defendant may give evidence in mitigation of damages that the plaintiff has recovered damages, or has brought actions for damages, for libel or slander in respect of the publication of words to the same effect as the words on which the action is founded, or has received or agreed to receive compensation in respect of any such publication.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 12 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402832988_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Order of judge required for prosecution of newspaper proprietor, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554289_025" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No criminal prosecution shall be commenced against any proprietor, publisher, editor, or any person responsible for the publication of a newspaper for any libel published therein without the order of a judge in chambers being first had and obtained.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/51">51 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/63">63 of 1911 </ref>Schedule)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554289_033" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The application for such order shall be made on notice to the accused person, who shall have an opportunity of being heard against such application.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1901/9">9 of 1901 s. 8</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1888 c. 64 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833004_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Consolidation of actions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554321_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It shall be competent for the Court of First Instance, on an application by or
                on behalf of 2 or more defendants in actions in respect to the same, or
                substantially the same, libel brought by one and the same person, to make an order
                for the consolidation of such actions; and after such order has been made, and
                before the trial of the said actions, the defendants in any new actions instituted
                in respect to the same, or substantially the same, libel shall also be entitled to
                be joined in a common action on a joint application being made by such new
                defendants and the defendants in the actions already consolidated.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of
                        1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554336_005" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In such consolidated action the jury shall assess the whole amount of the
                damages, if any, in one sum, but a separate verdict shall be taken for or against
                each defendant in the same way as if the actions had been tried separately; and if
                the jury have found a verdict against the defendant or defendants in more than one
                of the actions so consolidated, they shall proceed to apportion the amount of
                damages which they have so found between and against the said last-mentioned
                defendants; and similar provisions shall apply if the trial is before a judge
                without a jury. The judge at the trial, if he awards to the plaintiff the costs of
                the action, shall thereupon make such order as he may deem just for the
                apportionment of such costs between and against such
                defendants.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1540786725228_002" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>This section shall apply to actions for slander and to actions for slander of
                title, slander of goods or other malicious falsehood as it applies to actions for
                libel; and references to the same, or substantially the same, libel shall be
                construed accordingly.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_6"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 13
                    U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1901/9">9 of 1901 s. 5</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1888 c. 64 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833004_003" name="s20" reason="repealed" startPeriod="2003-07-04" status="repealed" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2003/23">23 of 2003 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833019_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Words imputing unchastity to woman or girl per se actionable</heading><leadIn>Words spoken and published which impute unchastity or adultery to any woman or girl
            shall not require special damage to render them actionable:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s21_proviso">Provided that, in any action for words
            spoken and made actionable by this Ordinance, a plaintiff shall not recover more costs
            than damages, unless the judge at the trial certifies that there was reasonable ground
            for bringing the action.</proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1901/9">9 of 1901 s. 10</ref> incorporated. Amended <ref href="/hk/1901/29">29 of 1901 s. 14</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911 s.
                4</ref>) </sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1891 c. 51 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833035_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Broadcast statements</heading><content>For the purposes of the law of libel and slander, the broadcasting of words shall be treated as publication in permanent form.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833050_001" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Slander affecting official, professional or business reputation</heading><content>In an action for slander in respect of words calculated to disparage the plaintiff in any office, profession, calling, trade or business held or carried on by him at the time of the publication, it shall not be necessary to allege or prove special damage, whether or not the words are spoken of the plaintiff in the way of his office, profession, calling, trade or business.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833050_003" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Slander of title, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554523_025" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In an action for slander of title, slander of goods or other malicious falsehood, it shall not be necessary to allege or prove special damage—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411554523_033" name="a" temporalId="s24_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the words upon which the action is founded are calculated to cause pecuniary damage to the plaintiff and are published in writing or other permanent form; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554523_041" name="b" temporalId="s24_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the said words are calculated to cause pecuniary damage to the plaintiff in respect of any office, profession, calling, trade or business held or carried on by him at the time of the publication.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554539_005" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Section 22</ref> shall apply for the purposes of this section as it applies for the purposes of the law of libel and slander.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833066_002" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Unintentional defamation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554555_018" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person who has published words alleged to be defamatory of another person may,
                if he claims that the words were published by him innocently in relation to that
                other person, make an offer of amends under this section; and in any such
                case—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411554555_026" name="a" temporalId="s25_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the offer is accepted by the party aggrieved and is duly performed, no
                    proceedings for libel or slander shall be taken or continued by that party
                    against the person making the offer in respect of the publication in question
                    (but without prejudice to any cause of action against any other person jointly
                    responsible for that publication);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554570_006" name="b" temporalId="s25_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the offer is not accepted by the party aggrieved, then, except as
                    otherwise provided by this section, it shall be a defence, in any proceedings by
                    him for libel or slander against the person making the offer in respect of the
                    publication in question, to prove that the words complained of were published by
                    the defendant innocently in relation to the plaintiff and that the offer was
                    made as soon as practicable after the defendant received notice that they were
                    or might be defamatory of the plaintiff, and has not been withdrawn.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554570_013" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An offer of amends under this section must be expressed to be made for the
                purposes of this section, and must be accompanied by an affidavit specifying the
                facts relied upon by the person making it to show that the words in question were
                published by him innocently in relation to the party aggrieved; and for the purposes
                of a defence under subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> no evidence, other than evidence of
                facts specified in the affidavit, shall be admissible on behalf of that person to
                prove that the words were so published.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554586_005" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>An offer of amends under this section shall be understood to mean an
                offer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411554586_013" name="a" temporalId="s25_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in any case, to publish or join in the publication of a suitable correction
                    of the words complained of, and a sufficient apology to the party aggrieved in
                    respect of those words;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554601_006" name="b" temporalId="s25_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where copies of a document or record containing the said words have been
                    distributed by or with the knowledge of the person making the offer, to take
                    such steps as are reasonably practicable on his part for notifying persons to
                    whom copies have been so distributed that the words are alleged to be defamatory
                    of the party aggrieved.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554601_013" name="4" temporalId="s25_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where an offer of amends under this section is accepted by the party
                aggrieved—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411554601_021" name="a" temporalId="s25_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any question as to the steps to be taken in fulfilment of the offer as so
                    accepted shall in default of agreement between the parties be referred to and
                    determined by the Court of First Instance, whose decision thereon shall be
                    final;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554601_029" name="b" temporalId="s25_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the power of the court to make orders as to costs in proceedings by the
                    party aggrieved against the person making the offer in respect of the
                    publication in question, or in proceedings in respect of the offer under
                    paragraph (a), shall include power to order the payment by the person making the
                    offer to the party aggrieved of costs on an indemnity basis and any expenses
                    reasonably incurred or to be incurred by that party in consequence of the
                    publication in question,</content></paragraph><continued>and if no such proceedings as aforesaid are taken, the Court of First
                Instance may, upon application made by the party aggrieved, make any such order for
                the payment of such costs and expenses as aforesaid as could be made in such
                    proceedings.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554617_011" name="5" temporalId="s25_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section words shall be treated as published by one
                person (in this subsection referred to as the
                        <b><i>publisher</i></b>)
                innocently in relation to another person if and only if the following conditions are
                satisfied, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411554617_019" name="a" temporalId="s25_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the publisher did not intend to publish them of and concerning that
                    other person, and did not know of circumstances by virtue of which they might be
                    understood to refer to him; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554633_006" name="b" temporalId="s25_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the words were not defamatory on the face of them, and the publisher
                    did not know of circumstances by virtue of which they might be understood to be
                    defamatory of that other person,</content></paragraph><continued>and in either case that the publisher exercised all reasonable care in
                relation to the publication; and any reference in this subsection to the publisher
                shall be construed as including a reference to any servant or agent of his who was
                concerned with the contents of the publication.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554633_019" name="6" temporalId="s25_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> shall not apply in relation to the publication by
                any person of words of which he is not the author unless he proves that the words
                were written by the author without malice.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833082_002" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Justification</heading><content>In an action for libel or slander in respect of words containing 2 or more distinct charges against the plaintiff, a defence of justification shall not fail by reason only that the truth of every charge is not proved if the words not proved to be true do not materially injure the plaintiff’s reputation having regard to the truth of the remaining charges.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833097_001" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Fair comment</heading><content>In an action for libel or slander in respect of words consisting partly of allegations of fact and partly of expression of opinion, a defence of fair comment shall not fail by reason only that the truth of every allegation of fact is not proved if the expression of opinion is fair comment having regard to such of the facts alleged or referred to in the words complained of as are proved.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833097_003" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Limitation on privilege at elections</heading><content>A defamatory statement published by or on behalf of a candidate in any election to
            the Legislative Council or to a District Council shall not be deemed to be published on
            a privileged occasion on the ground that it is material to a question in issue in the
            election, whether or not the person by whom it is published is qualified to vote at the
            election.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/39">39 of 1985 s. 60</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/23">23 of 1986 s.
                3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/8">8 of 1999 s. 89</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of
                1999 s. 7</ref>) </sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833113_002" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Agreements for indemnity</heading><content>An agreement for indemnifying any person against civil liability for libel in respect of the publication of any matter shall not be unlawful unless at the time of the publication that person knows that the matter is defamatory, and does not reasonably believe there is a good defence to any action brought upon it.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1952 c. 66 s. 11 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402833113_004" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap21/s14">s. 14</ref>]</note><heading>Newspaper
            Statements having Qualified
            Privilege<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><part id="ID_1438411554773_038" name="PI" temporalId="sch0_PI"><num value="I">Part
                I</num><heading>Statements
                Privileged without Explanation or
                Contradiction<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><section id="ID_1438411554773_057" name="s1" temporalId="sch0_PI_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>A fair and accurate report of any proceedings in public of the legislature
                    of any part of the Commonwealth outside Hong
                    Kong.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411554773_065" name="s2" temporalId="sch0_PI_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>A fair and accurate report of any proceedings in public of an international
                    organization of which the Government of Hong Kong or Her Majesty’s Government in
                    the United Kingdom is a member, or of any international conference to which the
                    Government of Hong Kong or Her Majesty’s Government in the United Kingdom sends
                    a
                    representative.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411554789_004" name="s3" temporalId="sch0_PI_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>A fair and accurate report of any proceedings in public of an international
                    court.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1438411554789_012" name="s4" temporalId="sch0_PI_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><content>A fair and accurate report of any proceedings before a court exercising
                    jurisdiction throughout any part of the Commonwealth outside Hong Kong or of any
                    proceedings before a court-martial of the Chinese People’s Liberation Army held
                    outside Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438411554789_020" name="s5" temporalId="sch0_PI_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><content>A fair and accurate report of any proceedings in public of a body or person
                    appointed to hold a public inquiry by the Government or legislature of any part
                    of the Commonwealth outside Hong
                    Kong.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411554789_028" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_PI_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><content>A fair and accurate copy of or extract from any register kept in pursuance
                    of any Ordinance which is open to inspection by<inline class="width_3"> </inline>the public, or of any other document which is required by the law of
                    Hong Kong to be open to inspection by the
                    public.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411554804_004" name="s7" temporalId="sch0_PI_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><content>A notice or advertisement published by or on the authority of any court
                    within Hong Kong or any judge or officer of such a
                    court.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438411554804_017" name="PII" temporalId="sch0_PII"><num value="II">Part
                II</num><heading>Statements
                Privileged subject to Explanation or
                Contradiction<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><section id="ID_1438411554804_036" name="s8" temporalId="sch0_PII_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><leadIn>A fair and accurate report of the findings or decision of any of the
                    following associations, or of any committee or governing body thereof, that is
                    to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411554804_046" name="a" temporalId="sch0_PII_s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an association formed in Hong Kong for the purpose of promoting or
                        encouraging the exercise of or interest in any art, science, religion or
                        learning, and empowered by its constitution to exercise control over or
                        adjudicate upon matters of interest or concern to the association, or the
                        actions or conduct of any persons subject to such control or
                        adjudication;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554804_055" name="b" temporalId="sch0_PII_s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an association formed in Hong Kong for the purpose of promoting or
                        safeguarding the interests of any trade, business, industry or profession,
                        or of the persons carrying on or engaged in any trade, business, industry or
                        profession, and empowered by its constitution to exercise control over or
                        adjudicate upon matters connected with the trade, business, industry or
                        profession, or the actions or conduct of those persons;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554820_007" name="c" temporalId="sch0_PII_s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an association formed in Hong Kong for the purpose of promoting or
                        safeguarding the interests of any game, sport or pastime to the playing or
                        exercise of which members of the public are invited or admitted, and
                        empowered by its constitution to exercise control over or adjudicate upon
                        persons connected with or taking part in the game, sport or
                        pastime,</content></paragraph><continued>being a finding or decision relating to a person who is a member of or is
                    subject by virtue of any contract to the control of the
                    association.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438411554835_012" name="s9" temporalId="sch0_PII_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><content>A fair and accurate report of the proceedings at any public meeting held in
                    Hong Kong, that is to say, a meeting bona fide and lawfully held for a
                        lawful<inline class="width_3"> </inline>purpose and for the furtherance or
                    discussion of any matter of<inline class="width_3"> </inline>public concern,
                    whether the admission to the meeting is general or
                    restricted.</content></section><section id="ID_1438411554835_020" name="s10" temporalId="sch0_PII_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><leadIn>A fair and accurate report of the proceedings at any meeting or sitting in
                    any part of Hong Kong of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411554835_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_PII_s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any body, board or authority formed or constituted under the provisions
                        of any Ordinance or of any committee appointed by such body, board or
                        authority;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554835_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_PII_s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s.
                        10</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554835_048" name="c" temporalId="sch0_PII_s10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any commission, tribunal, committee or person appointed for the
                        purposes of any inquiry by Letters Patent, Act of Parliament, Ordinance, by
                        Her Majesty, by the Governor or by the head of any department of
                        Government;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411554835_057" name="d" temporalId="sch0_PII_s10_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any other tribunal, board, committee or body constituted by or under,
                        and exercising functions under, an Ordinance,</content></paragraph><continued>not being a meeting or sitting admission to which is denied to
                    representatives of newspapers and other members of the
                    public.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438411554851_012" name="s11" temporalId="sch0_PII_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><content>A fair and accurate report of the proceedings at a general meeting of any
                    company or association constituted, registered or certified by or under any
                    Ordinance or Act of Parliament or incorporated by Royal Charter, not being a
                    private company within the meaning of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                            912</ref> &amp; 920)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438411554851_020" name="s12" temporalId="sch0_PII_s12" class="no_header"><num value="12">12.</num><content>A copy or fair and accurate report or summary of any notice or other matter
                    issued for the information of the public by or on behalf of any Government
                    department, or by or on behalf of the Commissioner of
                    Police.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1438411554851_028" name="s13" temporalId="sch0_PII_s13" class="no_header"><num value="13">13.</num><content>A copy or fair and accurate report or summary of any notice or other matter
                    issued for the information of the public by<inline class="width_3"> </inline>or
                    on behalf of the Consumer Council.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/23">23 of 1986 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438411554851_036" name="s14" temporalId="sch0_PII_s14" class="no_header"><num value="14">14.</num><content>A copy or fair and accurate report or summary of any report made or
                    published under <ref>section 16</ref> or <ref>16A</ref> of The Ombudsman
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap397">Cap. 397</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/44">44 of 1994 s.
                        19</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1996/74">74 of 1996 s.
                        12</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438411554867_004" name="s15" temporalId="sch0_PII_s15" class="no_header"><num value="15">15.</num><content>A copy of a fair and accurate report or summary of any report prepared and
                    supplied for the purposes of <ref>section 30</ref> of the Mandatory Provident
                    Fund Schemes Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap485">Cap. 485</ref>) or prepared and
                    published under <ref>section 32</ref> of that Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1998/4">4 of 1998 s.
                        9</ref>)</sourceNote></content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1961/33">33 of 1961 s. 12</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1986/23">23 of 1986 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></schedule></main></ordinance>