<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 59 sub. leg. L</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>59L</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap59L!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-04-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403506890_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-03-25">Factories
                                    and Industrial Undertakings (Abrasive Wheels)
                                    Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap59/s7">Cap. 59,
                                                section
                                    7</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 January 1976]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403506906_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403506906_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the Factories and Industrial Undertakings (Abrasive Wheels) Regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403506922_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AbrasiveWheel"><leadIn><term>abrasive
                    wheel</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">砂輪</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413666852_019" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a wheel, cylinder, disc or cone which consists wholly or partly of abrasive particles held together by mineral, metallic or organic bonds whether natural or artificial;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413666852_027" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>a—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413666852_035" name="i" temporalId="s2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>mounted wheel or point; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413666852_043" name="ii" temporalId="s2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>wheel or disc, having separate segments of abrasive material;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413666852_050" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>a wheel or disc—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413666852_058" name="i" temporalId="s2_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>made of metal, wood or rubber; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413666852_066" name="ii" temporalId="s2_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>having any surface consisting wholly or partly of abrasive material; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413666867_006" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a wheel, disc or saw to any surface of which, in each case, is attached a rim or segments consisting of diamond abrasive particles,</content></paragraph><continued>and which is, or is intended to be, power driven and which is for use in any grinding or cutting operation;</continued></def><def name="Employee"><term>employee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">僱員</term>) means a person who in an industrial
            undertaking is employed in using any abrasive wheel in any grinding or cutting
            operation;</def><def name="MountedWheelOrPoint"><term>mounted
                wheel or
            point</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">嵌固輪子或端點</term>) means a wheel or point consisting in
            either case of abrasive particles held together by mineral, metallic or organic bonds
            whether natural or artificial and securely and permanently mounted on the end of a
            mandrel or quill;</def><def name="Overhang"><term>overhang</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">外露軸段</term>), in relation to a mounted wheel or point,
            means that part of the mandrel or quill which is exposed between the collet in which the
            mandrel or quill is held and the part of the abrasive material nearest to that
            collet.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403506922_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>Subject to <ref>regulation 4</ref>, these regulations shall apply to any abrasive wheel used for any grinding or cutting operation in any industrial undertaking.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403506922_005" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Exceptions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413666930_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><ref>Regulations 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref>, <ref>9(a)</ref> and (b) and 10 shall not apply to any abrasive wheel manufactured of metal, wood or rubber and having any surface consisting wholly or partly of abrasive material.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413666930_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Regulations 9(a)</ref> and (b) and 10 shall not apply to any abrasive wheel which consists wholly of abrasive particles held together by natural bonds.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413666930_020" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Regulation 5</ref> shall not apply to any abrasive wheel having separate segments of abrasive material.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413666945_005" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn><ref>Regulations 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref>, <ref>8(1)</ref>, <ref>9</ref> and <ref>10</ref> shall not apply to any abrasive wheel which—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413666945_013" name="i" temporalId="s4_4_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>does not exceed 235 millimetres in diameter;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413666945_021" name="ii" temporalId="s4_4_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>is manufactured of rubber; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413666945_029" name="iii" temporalId="s4_4_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>has any surface consisting wholly or partly of abrasive material,</content></paragraph><continued>when that abrasive wheel is used in a portable machine.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413666945_042" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content><ref>Regulations 6</ref>, <ref>8(1)</ref>, <ref>9</ref> and <ref>10</ref> shall not apply to any abrasive wheel when it is used for the grinding of glass.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413666945_050" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content><ref>Regulations 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref> and <ref>10</ref> shall not apply to any wheel, disc or saw to any surface of which, in each case, is attached a rim or segments consisting of diamond abrasive particles.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403506937_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Duties
            of
            Proprietors</heading><section id="ID_1438403506937_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Speeds of abrasive wheels</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667008_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No abrasive wheel having a diameter of more than 55 millimetres shall be taken into use in any industrial undertaking for the first time in that industrial undertaking after the coming into operation of these regulations unless the abrasive wheel or its washer is clearly marked, in English or Chinese, with the maximum permissible speed in revolutions per minute specified by the manufacturer of that wheel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667023_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>No abrasive wheel having a diameter of 55 millimetres or less shall be taken into use in any industrial undertaking for the first time in that industrial undertaking after the coming into operation of these regulations unless there is kept permanently fixed in the room in which grinding is ordinarily carried out with that wheel a notice, in English and Chinese, stating the maximum permissible speed in revolutions per minute specified by the manufacturer for that abrasive wheel or for abrasive wheels of the class to which that abrasive wheel belongs and, in the case of mounted wheels and points, the overhang permissible at that speed:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_2_proviso">Provided that when grinding with such an abrasive wheel is not ordinarily carried out in any one room the notice shall be kept posted at a place and in a position where it may easily be read by employees employed in grinding with that abrasive wheel.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667023_019" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>No abrasive wheel shall be operated at a speed in excess of the maximum permissible speed in revolutions per minute specified under this regulation for that wheel:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_3_proviso">Provided that where the diameter of an abrasive wheel has been reduced its said maximum permissible speed may be increased to that speed which bears the same proportion to the said maximum permissible speed as the original diameter of the abrasive wheel bears to its reduced diameter.</proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506953_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Speeds of spindles</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667055_018" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>There shall be securely affixed to every power driven machine having any spindle on which an abrasive wheel is, or is intended to be, mounted a notice, in English and Chinese, specifying—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413667070_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of each such spindle (other than a spindle to which
                    subparagraph
                    (b) or (c) applies), its maximum working speed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413667070_013" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of any such spindle for which there are provided arrangements for operating the spindle at more than one specific working speed, each specific speed; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413667070_021" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of any such spindle for which there are provided arrangements for operating the spindle at an infinite number of working speeds within a specified range, the maximum and minimum working speeds of the spindle.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667070_028" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No spindle shall, while an abrasive wheel is mounted on it, be operated at a speed in excess of the maximum working speed specified under this regulation for that spindle.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667070_036" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The proprietor of an industrial undertaking shall, when so required by an occupational safety officer, provide the occupational safety officer with all such facilities and information as are necessary to enable him to determine the working speed of any spindle, shaft, pulley or other appliance which is used to operate an abrasive wheel.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667086_005" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The speed of every air driven spindle on which an abrasive wheel is mounted shall be controlled by a governor or other device so that the speed of the spindle does not at any time exceed the maximum working speed specified for that spindle in accordance with paragraph (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667086_013" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Every governor and other device used for controlling the speed of an air driven spindle on which an abrasive wheel is mounted shall be properly maintained.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506953_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Mounting</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667133_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every abrasive wheel shall be properly mounted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667133_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An abrasive wheel shall not be mounted except by a person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413667133_020" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has been appointed in writing for that purpose by the proprietor of an industrial undertaking; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413667133_028" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is, by reason of training and practical experience, competent to perform that operation.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506968_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Provision of guards</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667164_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a guard shall be provided and kept in position at every abrasive wheel in motion.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667164_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an abrasive wheel where, by reason of the work being done, or of the work which is ordinarily done (or, in the case of a new wheel, is intended ordinarily to be done), or the nature of the wheel, the use of a guard is impracticable.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506968_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Construction, maintenance, etc., of guards</heading><leadIn>Every guard provided in pursuance of these regulations shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413667195_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>so far as is reasonably practicable, be of such design and construction as to contain every part of the abrasive wheel in the event of fracture of the abrasive wheel or any part thereof occurring while the abrasive wheel is in motion;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413667195_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be properly maintained and so secured as to prevent its displacement in the event of fracture; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413667195_021" name="c" temporalId="s9_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>enclose the whole of the abrasive wheel except such part as is necessarily exposed for the purpose of work being done at that abrasive wheel or, where a guard which is not adjustable is used, for the purpose of the work which is ordinarily done thereat (or, in the case of a new abrasive wheel, is intended ordinarily to be done thereat).</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403506968_005" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Tapered wheels and protection flanges</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667226_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the work which is ordinarily done (or, in the case of a new abrasive wheel, is intended ordinarily to be done) at any abrasive wheel requires that the exposed area of the wheel shall exceed 180 degrees measured at the centre of the wheel then, where practicable, the wheel shall be tapered from its centre towards its periphery by at least 6 per cent on each side and shall be mounted between suitable protection flanges.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667242_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Protection flanges between which any abrasive wheel is mounted in accordance with paragraph (1) shall be of substantial construction and properly maintained and shall have the same degree of taper as the wheel and shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413667242_013" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a wheel of 300 millimetres or less in diameter, be of a diameter equal to at least half the diameter of the wheel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413667242_021" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a wheel of more than 300 millimetres but not exceeding 750 millimetres in diameter, be of a diameter equal to at least the diameter of the wheel less 150 millimetres; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413667242_029" name="c" temporalId="s10_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of a wheel of more than 750 millimetres in diameter, be of a diameter equal to at least the diameter of the wheel less 200 millimetres.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403506984_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Selection of abrasive wheels</heading><content>All practicable steps shall be taken to ensure that any abrasive wheel used is suitable for the work for which it is used to the extent necessary to reduce the risk of injury to employees.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403506984_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Machine controls</heading><content>No abrasive wheel shall be used in a machine unless the machine is provided with an efficient device for starting and cutting off the power to the machine and the control of the device shall be in such a position and of such design and construction as to be readily and conveniently operated by the person operating the machine.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403507000_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Rest</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667320_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where at an abrasive wheel there is a rest for supporting a workpiece, that rest shall at all times while the wheel is in motion be properly secured and adjusted so as to be as close as practicable to the exposed part of the abrasive wheel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667320_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every rest shall be of substantial construction and properly maintained.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403507000_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Warning notice</heading><content>A warning notice, in English and Chinese and in a form approved by the Commissioner, concerning the dangers arising from the use of abrasive wheels and the precautions to be observed shall be affixed in every room in which grinding or cutting by means of abrasive wheels is ordinarily carried out, or, where such grinding or cutting is not ordinarily carried out in a room, at a place and in such a position where it may be easily read by employees.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403507000_005" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Condition of floors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667367_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The floor immediately surrounding every fixed machine on which an abrasive wheel is, or is intended to be, mounted shall be maintained in good and even condition and shall, so far as practicable, be kept clear of loose material and prevented from becoming slippery.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667367_012" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All reasonably practicable steps shall be taken to ensure that the floor of any room or place in which any portable machine on which an abrasive wheel is mounted is in good and even condition, is kept clear of loose material and is prevented from becoming slippery.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403507015_002" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Duties
            of
            Persons
            Employed</heading><section id="ID_1438403507015_004" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Responsibilities of employees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667429_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No employee shall wilfully misuse or remove any guard, or wilfully misuse any protection flange, machine control, governor or other device provided in pursuance of these regulations or any rest for a workpiece.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667429_012" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every employee shall make full and proper use of guards, protection flanges,
                machine controls, governors and other devices provided in pursuance of these
                regulations and of rests for
                workpieces
                and if he discovers any defect in the same shall forthwith report such defect to the
                proprietor.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403507031_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-03-25" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Offences
            and
            Penalties</heading><section id="ID_1438403507031_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-04-28" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413667491_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The proprietor of any industrial undertaking in respect of which any of the
                provisions of <ref>regulation 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref>, <ref>7</ref>, <ref>8</ref>,
                    <ref>9</ref>, <ref>10</ref>, <ref>11</ref>, <ref>12</ref>, <ref>13</ref>,
                    <ref>14</ref> or <ref>15</ref> are contravened shall be guilty of an
                offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667491_012" name="1A" temporalId="s17_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><leadIn>A proprietor who is convicted of an offence under paragraph (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1683707620547_001" name="a" temporalId="s17_1A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in respect of a contravention of <ref>regulation 5(1)</ref> or (2) or
                        <ref>6(1)</ref> is liable to a fine at level 4;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1683707620551_002" name="b" temporalId="s17_1A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in respect of a contravention of <ref>regulation 5(3)</ref>,
                        <ref>6(2)</ref>, (3), (4) or (5), <ref>7</ref>, <ref>8</ref>, <ref>9</ref>,
                        <ref>10</ref>, <ref>11</ref>, <ref>12</ref>, <ref>13</ref> or <ref>15</ref>
                    is liable to a fine at level 6; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1683707620562_003" name="c" temporalId="s17_1A_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in respect of a contravention of <ref>regulation 14</ref> is liable to a
                    fine at level 4. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s.
                        35</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413667507_021" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any employee who contravenes any of the provisions of <ref>regulation 16</ref>
                commits
                an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/5">5 of 2023 s.
                35</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln322">L.N. 322 of
            1981</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></main></subLeg>