<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 123 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>123C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap123C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-05-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402646583_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-05-13">Building
                                    (Demolition Works) Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap123/s38">Cap.
                                                123, section
                                    38</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 October 1962]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402646599_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the Building (Demolition Works) Regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402646599_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>These regulations apply to the demolition of a building or of any substantial or significant part of a building.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln358">L.N. 358 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402646614_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Duties of authorized person and registered specialist contractor prior to commencement of demolition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411131029_018" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Before the demolition is commenced, the authorized person appointed in respect of the demolition works shall—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1974/ln190">L.N. 190 of 1974</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131029_026" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>cause all gas, electricity, water and other meters to be removed from the building and, save in so far as the same may be used in the demolition works, cause the supply of gas and electricity to the building to be disconnected; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131045_006" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>cause any fitting attached to the building in connexion with any tramway service, system of street lighting, supply of electricity or other service to be removed.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131045_013" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Before commencing the demolition, the registered specialist contractor appointed in respect of the demolition works shall—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131045_021" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>where a wall of the building abuts or fronts upon a street, service lane or other open area accessible to the public—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411131045_029" name="i" temporalId="s3_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>erect along that wall, at the level of the first floor of the building above the level of the street, fans or catch platforms;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411131045_037" name="ii" temporalId="s3_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>erect fans or catch platforms at the level of such other floors of the building as may be necessary to prevent any nuisance from dust or danger from debris or materials but so that such fans or catch platforms are sited at vertical intervals of not more than 10 m with the uppermost fan or catch platform not more than 10 m below the working level; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411131061_007" name="iii" temporalId="s3_2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>erect dust screens to cover the whole of the wall so as to prevent any nuisance from dust;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln358">L.N. 358 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131061_014" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>seal all sewer and drainage connexions; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131061_022" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>remove all glazed sashes and doors from the building.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402646630_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Provisions as to shoring, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411131076_058" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Save as provided in paragraph (2), before commencing the demolition and at such times during the carrying out of the demolition works as may be necessary, such precautions as may be necessary shall be taken, by the provision of adequate shoring or otherwise, to prevent, so far as is practicable, the accidental collapse of any part of the building, or of any adjoining or other building, the collapse of which may endanger any person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1964/ln112">L.N. 112 of 1964</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131092_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in relation to a person actually engaged in placing shoring or other safeguards for the purpose of compliance with paragraph (1), if such precautions as are practicable are taken to ensure the safety of that person.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402646677_001" name="s4A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s4A"><num value="4A">4A.</num><heading>Sequence of carrying out demolition works</heading><leadIn>A registered specialist contractor appointed in respect of demolition works is required to ensure that the demolition works are carried out—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131107_027" name="a" temporalId="s4A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the reverse order of construction of the building to be demolished unless it is not appropriate; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln609">L.N. 609 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131107_035" name="b" temporalId="s4A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>so that any collapse or fall of a part of the building is designed for in the plans for demolition works and controlled so as not to endanger any person.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402646817_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Electric cables, etc. not to be remain charged</heading><content>No electric cable or other apparatus, other than such a cable or apparatus used in the demolition works, that is liable to be a source of danger, shall, at any time during the carrying out of such works, remain electrically charged.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402646864_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Precautions to be taken to prevent danger from fire or explosion, etc.</heading><leadIn>At all times during the carrying out of any demolition works—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131139_026" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>the registered specialist contractor appointed in respect thereof shall take all practicable steps to prevent danger to persons employed therein—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411131139_034" name="i" temporalId="s6_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>from risk of fire or explosion through the leakage or accumulation of gas or vapour; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411131154_007" name="ii" temporalId="s6_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>from risk of flooding from water mains, sewers or culverts; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131154_014" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all external openings to or from the building shall be so protected as to prevent danger to persons employed in the demolition works.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402646880_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Provisions in relation to shutes for removal of materials, etc.</heading><content>Where shutes are provided for the removal of materials or debris, they shall be so situated and constructed as to avoid, so far as practicable, any danger to persons employed in the demolition works or to any other person.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402646895_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Demolition works to be carried out under supervision of technically competent person</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411131185_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The demolition and all works incidental thereto shall be specifically placed under the personal supervision of a technically competent person appointed by the registered specialist contractor appointed in respect of demolition works.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131185_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where 2 or more registered specialist contractors take part in the demolition works, each such contractor is required—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131185_020" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to appoint such number of technically competent persons as appropriate to supervise personally the demolition works; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131185_028" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to ensure that his workmen do not carry out an operation in the course of the demolition works until after he has consulted and agreed with the other contractors as to the method by which and the time at which the operation is to be carried out.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131185_035" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A notice in the specified form specifying the name of the technically competent person or persons appointed in accordance with paragraph (1) shall be posted up in a prominent position on the site of the demolition works.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln348">L.N. 348 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402646911_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Certain operations to be carried out only under competent supervision</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411131217_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The operations specified in paragraph (2) shall be carried out only—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131217_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>under the immediate supervision of a technically competent person appointed by the registered specialist contractor appointed in respect of demolition works; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131217_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by workmen experienced in demolition works and under the supervision of a technically competent person appointed by the registered specialist contractor appointed in respect of demolition works.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131217_027" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The following operations are specified for the purposes of paragraph (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131232_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the actual demolition of the framework of a building or of any floor, wall, roof or staircase, save where there is no risk of a collapse of any part of a building in the course of, or as a result of, the demolition works, so as to endanger any person employed in the demolition works, other than a risk which could not reasonably have been foreseen;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131232_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the actual demolition of any part of a building where there is a special risk of collapse, whether of that part of the building or of any part of a building, in the course of, or as a result of, the demolition works, so as to endanger any person employed in the demolition works;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131232_021" name="c" temporalId="s9_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the cutting or breaking up or dismantling of reinforced concrete, steelwork or ironwork forming part of the structure of a building;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131232_029" name="d" temporalId="s9_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the use of any powered mechanical plant or equipment in actual demolition work.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln358">L.N. 358 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131248_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The operator of powered mechanical plant or equipment used in demolition work shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411131248_013" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>have at least 3 years experience in operating the particular plant or equipment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131248_021" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>possess such other training, knowledge, skills and experience in the operation of the particular plant or equipment as the Building Authority may specify from time to time; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln609">L.N. 609 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411131248_029" name="c" temporalId="s9_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>operate under the immediate supervision of a technically competent person appointed by the registered specialist contractor appointed in respect of demolition works.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote> </content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402646958_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Floors, etc. not to be overloaded</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411131279_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No floor, roof or other part of a building that is being demolished shall be so overloaded with debris or materials as to render it unsafe or liable to become unsafe.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln358">L.N. 358 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131279_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No debris or materials from demolition shall be permitted to accumulate against any fence, hoarding or wall so as to render it unsafe or liable to become unsafe.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln358">L.N. 358 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131279_020" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No floor, roof or other part of a building that is being demolished shall be so overloaded with any plant or equipment as to render it unsafe or liable to become unsafe.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402646973_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Precautions to be taken in relation to cutting of steelwork, etc.</heading><content>Where, during the carrying out of any demolition works, steelwork or ironwork is being cut or released or dismantled, precautions shall be taken, so far as is practicable, to prevent any danger from a sudden twist, spring or collapse.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402646973_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Precautions to be taken in removing framing</heading><content>Where, during the carrying out of any demolition works, any part of the framing is being removed from a framed or partially framed building, all practicable precautions shall be taken to prevent danger from collapse of the structure.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402646989_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2021-05-13" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411131326_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An authorized person who contravenes <ref>regulation 3(1)</ref> shall be guilty
                of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 4.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1974/ln190">L.N. 190 of 1974</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131326_012" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A registered specialist contractor who contravenes <ref>regulation 3(2)</ref>
                shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 4.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131326_020" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A registered specialist contractor who contravenes <ref>regulation 6(a)</ref>
                or <ref>regulation 8(2)</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
                summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 6 and to imprisonment for 2 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411131326_028" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In the event of a contravention of <ref>regulation 4(1)</ref>, <ref>4A</ref>,
                    <ref>5</ref>, <ref>6(b)</ref>, <ref>7</ref>, <ref>8(1)</ref> or (3),
                    <ref>9(1)</ref>
                or (3),
                    <ref>10</ref>,
                    <ref>11</ref>
                or
                    <ref>12</ref>,
                the registered specialist contractor appointed in respect of, and any person
                directly concerned with, the demolition works shall be guilty of an offence and
                shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 6 and to imprisonment for 2 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln358">L.N. 358 of
                    1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln170">L.N. 170 of 1979</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln515">L.N. 515 of
            1997</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>