<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 158</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>158</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap158!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-10-20</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402746907_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-10-20">
            <content>To amend the law relating to inns and innkeepers.
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 February 1962]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402746907_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Hotel Proprietors Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402746923_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411392330_002" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/39">39 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><def name="Hotel"><term>hotel</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">酒店</term>) means an establishment held out by the
                proprietor as offering sleeping accommodation to any person presenting himself who
                appears able and willing to pay a reasonable sum for the services and facilities
                provided and who is in a fit state to be received.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1998/39">39 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392330_016" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="AnyPersonPresentingHimself"><leadIn>For the purposes of “any
                    person presenting
                    himself”
                    in the definition of
                            <b><i>hotel</i></b>
                    in subsection (1) and only for those purposes—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411392330_024" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>“any person” includes any person of any particular category, class, group or description;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411392330_032" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>“presenting himself” includes—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411392330_040" name="i" temporalId="s2_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any person presenting himself in person;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411392330_048" name="ii" temporalId="s2_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any person presenting himself through an agent or a representative;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411392330_056" name="iii" temporalId="s2_2_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>any person presenting himself, whether in person or through an agent or a representative, by facsimile, letter, telegram, telephone or any other means;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411392330_064" name="iv" temporalId="s2_2_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>any person presenting himself, whether in person or through an agent or a representative, with prior booking or notice;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411392330_072" name="v" temporalId="s2_2_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>any person presenting himself, whether in person or through an agent or a representative, without prior booking or notice.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1998/39">39 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1956 c. 62 s. 1(3) U.K.]</referenceNote></subparagraph></paragraph></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402746938_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Inns and innkeepers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411392361_019" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An hotel within the meaning of this Ordinance shall, and any other
                establishment shall not, be deemed to be an inn; and the duties, liabilities and
                rights which immediately before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance by law attached to an innkeeper as such shall, subject to the
                provisions of this Ordinance, attach to the proprietor of such an hotel and shall
                not attach to any other person. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392377_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The proprietor of an hotel shall, as an innkeeper, be under the like liability,
                if any, to make good to any guest of his any damage to property brought to the hotel
                as he would be under to make good the loss thereof. </content><referenceNote>[cf. 1956 c. 62 s. 1(1) &amp; (2) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1660271386912_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 February
                1962.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402746938_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-20" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Modifications of liabilities and rights of innkeepers as such</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411392392_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to any other liability incurred by him with respect to any
                property brought to the hotel, the proprietor of an hotel shall not be liable as an
                innkeeper to make good to any person any loss of or damage to such property except where—
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/39">39 of 1998 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411392392_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the time of the loss or damage sleeping accommodation at the hotel had
                    been engaged for the person; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411392392_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the loss or damage occurred during the period commencing with the midnight
                    immediately preceding, and ending with the midnight immediately following, a
                    period for which the person was a guest at the hotel and entitled to use the
                    accommodation so engaged.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/39">39 of 1998 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392392_027" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to any other liability of his or to the provisions of
                    <ref>section 5</ref> or other right of his with respect thereto, the proprietor
                of an hotel shall not as an innkeeper be liable to make good to any guest of his any
                loss of or damage to, or have any lien on, any vehicle or any property left
                therein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392408_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where the proprietor of an hotel is liable as an innkeeper to make good the loss
                of or any damage to property brought to the hotel, his liability to any one guest
                shall not exceed the sum of one thousand dollars in respect of any one article, or
                the sum of two thousand dollars in the aggregate, except where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411392408_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the property was stolen, lost or damaged through the default, neglect or
                    wilful act of the proprietor or some servant of his; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411392408_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the property was deposited by or on behalf of the guest expressly for safe
                    custody with the proprietor or some servant of his authorized, or appearing to
                    be authorized, for the purpose, and, if so required by the proprietor or that
                    servant, in a container fastened or sealed by the depositor and when property is
                    deposited in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph, the liability of
                    the proprietor as an innkeeper to any one guest in respect of the loss of or
                    damage to property so deposited shall not exceed the value thereof as declared
                    by or on behalf of the guest at the time of deposit; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411392423_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>at a time after the guest had arrived at the hotel, either the property in
                    question was offered for deposit as aforesaid and the proprietor or his servant
                    refused to receive it, or the guest or some other guest acting on his behalf
                    endeavoured to offer the property in question but, through the default of the
                    proprietor or a servant of his, was unable to do so: Provided that the
                    provisions of this paragraph shall not apply where the value of the property as
                    declared by or on behalf of the guest when offered for deposit exceeds the sum
                    of ten thousand dollars:</leadIn></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_3_c_proviso">Provided that the proprietor shall
                not be entitled to the protection of this subsection unless, at the time when the
                property in question was brought to the hotel, a copy of the notice set out in the
                    <ref>Schedule</ref> printed in plain type was conspicuously displayed in a place
                where it could conveniently be read by his guests at or near the reception office or
                desk or, where there is no reception office or desk, at or near the main entrance to
                the hotel.</proviso></subsection><referenceNote>[cf. 1956 c. 62 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402746954_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Power of sale</heading><leadIn>A proprietor of an hotel shall as an innkeeper, in addition to his ordinary lien,
            have the right absolutely to sell by public auction any property which may have been
            deposited with him or left in his hotel or in premises appurtenant or belonging thereto,
            where the guest depositing or leaving such property shall be or become indebted to him
            for any board or lodging: </leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_proviso">
            <leadIn>Provided however—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411392470_026" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that, except in the case of perishable property, no such sale shall be made
                    until after the property shall have been for the space of six weeks in such
                    charge or custody or in or upon such premises without such debt having been
                    satisfied; </content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411392470_034" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that such proprietor, after having, out of the proceeds of such sale, paid
                    himself the amount of any such debt together with the costs and expenses of such
                    sale, shall on demand pay to the guest depositing or leaving such property the
                    surplus, if any, remaining after such sale; </content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411392486_006" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that the debt for the payment of which a sale is made shall not be any
                    other or greater debt than the debt for which the property could have been
                    retained by the proprietor as an innkeeper under his lien; </content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438411392486_014" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that, in the case of perishable property, as soon as conveniently may be
                    either before or after such sale, and in the case of other property at least one
                    month before any such sale, the proprietor shall cause to be inserted in
                    a
                    newspaper circulating in Hong Kong an advertisement containing
                    a notice of such sale or intended sale and giving shortly a description of the
                    property sold or intended to be sold together with the name of the guest where
                    known who deposited or left it.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
        </proviso><referenceNote>[cf. 1878 c. 38 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438402746969_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-20" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap158/s4">s.
                4</ref>]</note><heading>Notice<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><crossHeading>Loss
            of or Damage to Guests’ Property
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn>The
            liability under the Hotel Proprietors Ordinance, <ref href="/hk/cap158">Cap. 158</ref>,
            of an hotel proprietor to make good loss or damage to a guest’s
            property—</leadIn><section id="ID_1552010743300_001" name="s0" temporalId="sch0_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438411392517_045" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>extends only to the property of guests who have engaged sleeping
                    accommodation at the hotel; </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392517_054" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>is limited to DOLLARS ONE THOUSAND ($1,000.00) for any one article and a
                    total of DOLLARS TWO THOUSAND ($2,000.00) in the case of any one guest,
                    except—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411392517_063" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of property which has been deposited for safe custody in
                        which case such liability is limited to the declared value of the property;
                        or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411392533_008" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_s0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of property, the declared value of which does not exceed
                        DOLLARS TEN THOUSAND ($10,000.00), which has been offered for deposit;
                    </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392533_016" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>does not cover motor-cars or other vehicles of any kind or any property
                    left in them.</content></subsection></section><text>This
            notice does not constitute an admission either that the Ordinance applies to this hotel
            or that liability thereunder attaches to the proprietor of this hotel in any particular
            case.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading>關於客人財物的損失或損毀事<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn>根據《酒店東主條例》(<ref href="/hk/cap158">第158章</ref>)，酒店東主對於補償客人財物的損失或損毀而負有的法律責任 ——</leadIn><section id="ID_1552010743300_002" name="s0" temporalId="sch0_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438411392533_049" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>只限於已在其酒店保留住宿地方的客人的財物；</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392533_058" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>就任何一名客人而言，每件物件以壹仟元($1,000.00)為限，而總額則以貳仟元($2,000.00)為限，但下列情況除外 ——</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411392533_067" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>對於已存放作安全保管的財物，上述法律責任以所報稱的財物價值為限；或</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411392533_076" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_s0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>對於已提出作存放的財物，所報稱的財物價值不超過壹萬元($10,000.00)者；</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411392533_084" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>並不包括汽車或任何種類的其他車輛或留在車輛內的任何財物。</content></subsection></section><text>本通告並不構成對上述條例適用於本酒店的承認，亦不構成對上述條例所訂的法律責任在任何個別個案中加於本酒店的東主身上的承認。</text><sourceNote><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1996/ln333">L.N. 333 of
        1996</ref>)</sourceNote></sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>