<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 190 sub. leg. J</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>190J</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap190J!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-08-26</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402815376_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-08-26">The
            Universal
            Postal
            Union</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap190/s2">Cap. 190, section
                2</ref>) <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[9 September 1955]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><text class="first_line_indent_0">
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><sourceNote class="align_left">(Words repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">A.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>The
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815376_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The Universal
            Postal
            Union
            (hereinafter referred to as
                    <b><i>the
                    Organization</i></b>) is an organization to which the Diplomatic Privileges
            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap190">Cap. 190</ref>) applies.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815391_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The Organization shall have the legal capacities of a body corporate and, except in so far as in any particular case it has expressly waived its immunity, immunity from suit and legal process. No waiver of immunity shall be deemed to extend to any measure of execution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815407_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The Organization shall have the like inviolability of official archives and premises occupied as offices as is accorded in respect of official archives and premises of an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402815407_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>The Organization shall have the like exemption or relief from taxes and rates, other than taxes on the importation of goods, as is accorded to a foreign sovereign power.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815422_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>The Organization shall have exemption from taxes on the importation of goods directly imported by the Organization for its official use in Hong Kong or for exportation, or on the importation of any publications of the Organization directly imported by it, such exemption to be subject to compliance with such conditions as the Commissioner of Customs and Excise may prescribe for the protection of the revenue.
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1985/40">40 of 1985 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438402815438_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>The Organization shall have exemption from prohibitions and restrictions on importation or exportation in the case of goods directly imported or exported by the Organization for its official use and in the case of any publications of the Organization directly imported or exported by it.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815438_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><content>The Organization shall have the right to avail itself, for telegraphic communications sent by it and containing only matter intended for publication by the press or for broadcasting (including communications addressed to or dispatched from places outside Hong Kong), of any reduced rates applicable for the corresponding service in the case of press telegrams.</content></section><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">B.<inline class="width_12"> </inline>Representatives, other
            than Representatives
            of<br></br>the
            Central
            People’s Government
            in
            Hong Kong,
            <br></br>on Organs
            or Committees
            of
            the
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><sourceNote startPeriod="2021-08-26">(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
        3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402815454_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><subsection id="ID_1438411513027_037" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived
                by the Governments whom they represent, representatives of members at Congresses, on
                the Executive and Liaison Committee, at administrative conferences or on commissions
                provided for in the constitution of the Organization, or on any committee of any of
                these bodies shall
                        enjoy— <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1955/gna99">G.N.A. 99 of 1955</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411513027_046" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>while exercising their functions as such and during their journeys to and
                    from the place of meeting, immunity from personal arrest or detention and from
                    seizure of their personal baggage and inviolability for all papers and
                    documents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411513027_055" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or
                    written and things done or omitted to be done by them in their capacity as
                    representatives.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411513027_063" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the incidence of any form of taxation depends upon residence,
                representatives shall not be deemed to be resident in Hong Kong during any period
                when they are present in Hong Kong for the discharge of their duties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411513043_006" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="Representatives">
                <content>For the purposes of the application of this Article the expression
                        <term>representatives</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">代表</term>) shall be deemed to include, in
                    addition to the representatives, the following members of their official staffs
                    accompanying them as such representatives—</content>
                <content>Alternate representatives,</content>
                
                <content>Advisers,</content>
                <content>Technical experts,</content>
                <content>Secretaries of Delegations,</content>
                
                <continued>and
                    Part IV of the <ref>First Schedule</ref> to the Ordinance shall not operate so
                    as to confer privileges or immunities on the staffs of representatives other
                    than on those persons falling within the above-mentioned descriptions.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln184">L.N. 184 of
                        1992</ref>)</sourceNote></continued>
            </def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411513043_054" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The provisions of the preceding paragraphs of this Article shall not confer any
                immunity or privilege on any person as the representatives of the Central People’s
                Government in Hong Kong or as a member of the staff of such representative or on any
                person who is a Chinese national.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/80">80 of 1982 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">C.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>High Officials
            of
            the
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815469_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><content>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the Organization, any officer of the Organization holding the office of
            Secretary-General (including any officer acting for him during his absence from duty)
            shall be accorded in respect of himself, his spouse and his children under the age of
            twenty-one, the like immunity from suit and legal process, the like inviolability of
            residence and the like exemption or relief from taxes, other than income tax, as is
            accorded to an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the
            People’s Republic of China, his spouse and children, and exemption from income tax in
            respect of emoluments received by him as an officer of the Organization.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">D.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>Other Officials
            of
            the
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815469_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the Organization, officials of the Organization of any category specified by it shall
            enjoy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411513168_021" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>immunity from suit and legal process in respect of words spoken or written and
                things done or omitted to be done by them in the course of the performance of their
                official duties;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln162">L.N. 162 of
                    1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411513168_030" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>exemption from income tax in respect of emoluments received by them as officers
                or servants of the Organization.</content></paragraph></section></main></subLeg>