<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 22</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>22</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap22!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-05-16</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402847278_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2017-02-15">
            <content>To repeal and replace existing provision for the compensation of dependants of
                persons killed as a result of tortious acts.</content>
            <content>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 November 1986]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1986/ln260">L.N. 260 of 1986</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><text><marker role="blank-line"></marker><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1
                    of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote></text><section id="ID_1438402847293_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Fatal Accidents Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402847309_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411590591_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Adopted"><term>adopted</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">領養</term>) means adopted in pursuance of an
                adoption order made under the Adoption Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap290">Cap.
                    290</ref>) or of any adoption recognized as valid by the law of Hong Kong;</def><def name="Dependant">
                <leadIn><term>dependant</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受養人</term>), in relation to a deceased person,
                    means—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590591_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the wife, husband, former wife or former husband of the deceased and
                        any person whose marriage to the deceased has been annulled or declared
                        void;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590591_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a concubine lawfully taken by the deceased before 7 October
                        1971;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590591_042" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>any person who—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411590591_050" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>was living with the deceased in the same household immediately
                            before the date of his death; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411590591_058" name="ii" temporalId="s2_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>had been living with the deceased in the same household for at
                            least 2 years before that date,</content></subparagraph><continued>as the husband or wife of the deceased;</continued></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_005" name="d" temporalId="s2_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any parent or other ascendant of the deceased;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_013" name="e" temporalId="s2_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>any person (not being a parent of the deceased) who, during any
                        marriage to which that person was a party, treated the deceased as a son or
                        daughter of the family in relation to that marriage;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_021" name="f" temporalId="s2_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>any child or other descendant of the deceased;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_029" name="g" temporalId="s2_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>any person (not being a child of the deceased) who, during any marriage
                        to which the deceased was at any time a party, was treated by the deceased
                        as a son or daughter of the family in relation to that marriage;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_037" name="h" temporalId="s2_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>any person who is, or is the issue of, a brother, sister, uncle or aunt
                        of the deceased;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_045" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any person who is, or is the issue of, a brother or sister of a
                        grandparent of the deceased;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_053" name="j" temporalId="s2_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>any godchild or godparent of the deceased according to Chinese
                        custom;</content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="Wife">
                <leadIn><term>wife</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">妻</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">妻子</term>)
                    means—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_067" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a-1"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a Christian marriage or its civil equivalent, the lawful
                        wife; and </content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411590606_075" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b-1"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the case of any other lawful marriage—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411590606_083" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the lawful wife of such marriage; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411590606_091" name="ii" temporalId="s2_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if there is more than one lawful wife, the lawful principal wife
                            recognized as such by the personal law of the husband of such marriage,
                            or if there is no lawful principal wife, the lawful wives so
                            recognized.</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
            </def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590622_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In deducing any relationship for the purposes of this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411590622_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an adopted person shall be treated as the child of the person or persons by
                    whom he was adopted and not as the child of any other person; and, subject
                    thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590622_021" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any relationship by affinity shall be treated as relationship by
                    consanguinity, any relationship of the half-blood as a relationship of the whole
                    blood, and the stepchild of any person as his child; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590622_029" name="c" temporalId="s2_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an illegitimate person shall be treated as the legitimate child of his
                    mother and reputed father.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402847309_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Right of action for wrongful act causing death</heading><content>If death is caused to any person
                (<term>the
                deceased</term>)
            by any wrongful act, neglect or default which is such as would (if death had not ensued)
            have entitled the deceased to maintain an action and recover damages in respect thereof,
            then subject to <ref>section 4(2)</ref> an action for damages may be brought for the
            benefit of the dependants of the deceased against the person who would have been liable
            in damages to the deceased in respect of that wrongful act, neglect or
            default.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 53 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402847324_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-05-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Bereavement</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411590684_025" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An action under this Ordinance may consist of or include a claim for damages for bereavement unless, by reason of the act, neglect or default referred to in <ref>section 3</ref>, any person has recovered, by action or otherwise, a sum in respect of loss of the deceased’s society under <ref>section 20C(1)</ref> of the Law Amendment and Reform (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap23">Cap. 23</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590700_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A claim for damages for bereavement shall only be for the benefit of such of the following persons as survive the deceased for not less than 30 days—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411590700_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the wife or husband of the deceased, unless they had been living apart for a continuous period of at least 2 years immediately preceding the death of the deceased; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590700_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where there is no spouse by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a), the children of the deceased; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590700_029" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a) or (b), the wife or husband of the deceased (notwithstanding that they had been living apart); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590700_037" name="d" temporalId="s4_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a), (b) or (c), any concubine taken by the deceased before 7 October 1971; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590700_045" name="e" temporalId="s4_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><leadIn>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a), (b), (c) or (d), any person who—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411590700_053" name="i" temporalId="s4_2_e_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>was living with the deceased in the same household immediately before the date of his death; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411590715_007" name="ii" temporalId="s4_2_e_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>had been living with the deceased in the same household for at least 2 years before that date,</content></subparagraph><continued>as the husband or wife of the deceased; or</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590715_020" name="f" temporalId="s4_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d) or (e), the parents of the deceased or (if the deceased was illegitimate) his mother; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590715_028" name="g" temporalId="s4_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e) or (f), but the deceased was at the date of his death a minor, any person who during any marriage to which that person was a party treated the deceased as a son or daughter of the family in relation to that marriage; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590715_036" name="h" temporalId="s4_2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>where there is no other person by or for whom a claim can be made under this subsection, any brother or sister of the deceased.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590715_043" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subsection (4), the sum to be awarded as damages under this section
                shall be
                    $253,500.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/ln205">L.N.
                        205 of 1991</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                    1997</ref>; <ref href="hk/2018/ln143">L.N. 143 of
                    2018</ref>; <ref href="hk/2020/ln134">L.N. 134 of
                    2020</ref>; <ref href="hk/2023/ln79">L.N. 79 of
                    2023</ref>; <ref href="hk/2025/ln80">L.N. 80 of
                    2025</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590715_051" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where there is a claim for damages under this section for the benefit of 2 or more persons, the sum awarded shall be divided equally between them (subject to any deduction falling to be made in respect of costs not recovered from the defendant).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590731_005" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Legislative Council may by resolution amend subsection (3) by varying the sum specified therein.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 53 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402847340_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Persons entitled to bring the action</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411590762_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An action under this Ordinance shall be brought by and in the name of the executor or administrator of the deceased.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590762_026" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411590762_034" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>there is no executor or administrator of the deceased; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411590762_042" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>no action is brought within 6 months after the death by and in the name of an executor or administrator of the deceased,</content></paragraph><continued>the action may be brought by and in the name of all or any of the persons for whose benefit an executor or administrator could have brought it.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590778_011" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Not more than one action shall lie for and in respect of the same subject-matter of complaint.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590778_019" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The plaintiff in the action shall be required to deliver to the defendant or his solicitor full particulars of the persons for whom and on whose behalf the action is brought and of the nature of the claim in respect of which damages are sought to be recovered.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 53 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402847356_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Assessment of damages</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411590809_070" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the action, such damages, other than damages for bereavement, may be awarded to dependants in such proportions as reflect their respective injuries as a result of the death.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590825_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where damages are awarded under subsection (1), any costs not recovered from the defendant shall be deducted from those damages and thereafter those damages shall be divided among the dependants in such proportions as has been decided under that subsection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590825_013" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In an action under this Ordinance, or under the Carriage by Air Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap500">Cap. 500</ref>), where there fall to be assessed damages payable to a widow in respect of the death of her husband there shall not be taken into account the re-marriage of the widow or her prospects of re-marriage.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/13">13 of 1997 s. 20</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590825_021" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In an action under this Ordinance where there fall to be assessed damages payable to a person who is a dependant within the meaning of paragraph (c) of the definition of that term in <ref>section 2</ref>, in respect of the death of the person with whom the dependant was living as husband or wife, there shall be taken into account (together with any other matter that appears to the court to be relevant to the action) the fact that the dependant had no enforceable right to financial support by the deceased as a result of their living together.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590840_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In assessing damages in any action brought under this Ordinance the funeral expenses of the deceased person, if such expenses have been incurred by the parties for whose benefit the action is brought, shall be taken into account.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411590840_013" name="6" temporalId="s6_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Money paid into court in satisfaction of a cause of action under this Ordinance may be in one sum without specifying any person’s share.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 53 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402847356_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Assessment of damages; disregard of benefits</heading><content>In assessing damages in respect of a person’s death in an action under this
            Ordinance or under the Carriage by Air Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap500">Cap.
            500</ref>), benefits which have accrued or will or may accrue to any person from his
            estate or otherwise as a result of his death shall be disregarded. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/13">13 of 1997 s. 20</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 53 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section></main></ordinance>