<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 112 sub. leg. AA</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>112AA</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap112AA!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-08-06</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402589128_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-08-06">Specification
      of
      Arrangements (Government
      of
      the Kingdom
      of
      Denmark
      Concerning
      Air
      Services)
      (Double
      Taxation)
      Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap112/s49">Cap. 112, section
      49</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of
      2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[10 November
      2000]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402589144_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-06" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Declaration under <ref>section 49</ref></heading><content>For the purposes of <ref>section 49</ref> of the Ordinance, it is declared that the arrangements referred to in <ref>section 2</ref> have been made with the Government of the Kingdom of Denmark with a view to affording relief from double taxation in relation to income tax and any tax of a similar character imposed by the laws of the Kingdom, and that it is expedient that those arrangements should have effect.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402589144_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-06" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Arrangements specified</heading><content>The arrangements mentioned in <ref>section 1</ref> are in Article 10 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the Kingdom of Denmark concerning <ref>Schedule</ref>d Air Services done in duplicate at Hong Kong on 14 March 2000 in the English language as specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> and having effect according to the tenor of that Agreement.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402589160_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-08-06" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap112AA/s2">s.
                2</ref>]<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><heading>Article
            10 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
            Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the Kingdom of Denmark
            Concerning Scheduled Air
            Services<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><quotedStructure>
            <content class="align_center">“<b>ARTICLE
                    10</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>Avoidance of
                    Double
                Taxation</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
            <text name="1" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(1)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>Income and profits derived from the operation of aircraft in
                international traffic by an airline of one Contracting Party, including
                participation in a pool service, a joint air transport operation or an international
                operating agency, which are subject to tax in the area of that Contracting Party
                shall be exempt from income tax, profits tax and all other taxes on income and
                profits imposed in the area of the other Contracting
                Party.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text>
            <text name="2" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(2)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>Capital and assets of an airline of one Contracting Party relating to the
                operation of aircraft in international traffic shall be exempt from taxes on capital
                and assets imposed in the area of the other Contracting
                Party.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text>
            <text name="3" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(3)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>Gains from the alienation of aircraft operated in international traffic
                and movable property pertaining to the operation of such aircraft which are received
                by an airline of one Contracting Party, the income and profits of which according to
                paragraph (1) are taxable only in the area of that Contracting Party, shall be
                exempt from any tax on gains imposed in the area of the other Contracting
                Party.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text>
            <text name="4" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(4)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>For the purposes of this Article:</text>
            <text class="align_justified left_indent_24">(a)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>the
                term “<term class="old_format">income and profits</term>” includes revenues and
                gross receipts from the operation of aircraft for the carriage of persons,
                livestock, goods, mail or merchandise in international traffic including:</text>
            <paragraph class="align_justified first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_72"><num value="b">(i)</num><content>the charter or rental of aircraft if such charter or rental is incidental
                    to the operation of aircraft in international traffic;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph class="align_justified first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_72"><num value="b">(ii)</num><content>the sale of tickets or similar documents, and the provision of services
                    connected with such carriage, for the airline itself or for other airlines, but
                    in the latter case only if such sales or provisions of services are incidental
                    to the operation of aircraft in international traffic; and</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph class="align_justified first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_72"><num value="b">(iii)</num><content>interest on funds directly connected with the operation of aircraft in
                    international traffic;</content></paragraph>
            <text class="align_justified left_indent_24">(b)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>the
                term “<term class="old_format">international traffic</term>” means any carriage by
                an aircraft except when such carriage is solely between places in the area of the
                other Contracting Party;</text>
            <text class="align_justified left_indent_24">(c)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>the
                term “<term class="old_format">airline of one Contracting Party</term>”
                means,</text>
            <paragraph class="align_justified first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_72"><num value="b">(i)</num><content>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, an airline
                    incorporated and having its principal place of business in the Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region; and</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph class="align_justified first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_72"><num value="b">(ii)</num><content>in the case of Denmark, any airline which, under the laws of Denmark, is
                    liable to tax therein by reason of domicile, residence, place of management or
                    any other criterion of a similar nature, and includes the joint Danish,
                    Norwegian and Swedish air transport consortium Scandinavian Airlines System
                    (SAS), but only insofar as profits derived by SAS Danmark A/S, the Danish
                    partner of the Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS), are in proportion to its
                    share in that consortium;</content></paragraph>
            <text class="align_justified left_indent_24">(d)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>the
                term “<term class="old_format">competent authority</term>” means,</text>
            <paragraph class="align_justified first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_72"><num value="b">(i)</num><content>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, the
                    Commissioner of Inland Revenue or his authorized representative, or any person
                    or body authorised to perform any functions at present exercisable by the
                    Commissioner or similar functions; and</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph class="align_justified first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_72"><num value="b">(ii)</num><content>in the case of Denmark, the Minister for Taxation or his authorised
                    representative.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph>
            <text name="5" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(5)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties shall, through
                consultation, endeavour to resolve by mutual agreement any disputes regarding the
                interpretation or application of this Article. Article 17 (Settlement of Disputes)
                shall not apply to any such
                dispute.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text>
            <text name="6" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(6)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>Notwithstanding Article 21 (Entry into Force) each Contracting Party
                shall in writing notify the other of the completion of the relevant procedures
                required by its law to bring this Article into force. The Article shall enter into
                force on the date of the receipt of the latter of these notifications and shall
                thereupon have effect in respect of income, profits and gains arising on or after
                the first day of January 1997 and on capital and assets held on or after that
                date.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text>
            <text name="7" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(7)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>Notwithstanding Article 19 (Termination) where notice of termination of
                this Agreement is given under that Article, this Article shall cease to have effect,
                in relation to income, profits and gains received as well as capital and assets held
                on or after the first day of January in the calendar year next following the expiry
                of a period of six months after the date when such notice is
                given.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text>
            <text name="8" class="align_justified left_indent_24">(8)<fillIn class="width_8"> </fillIn>This Article shall cease to have effect in the event that an agreement
                for the avoidance of double taxation with respect to taxes on income, providing for
                similar exemptions to those in this Article, enters into force between the
                Contracting Parties.”.</text>
        </quotedStructure></schedule></main></subLeg>