<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 273</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>273</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap273!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2018-12-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402918351_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2018-12-13">
            <content>To confer on third parties rights against insurers of third party risks in the
                event of the insured becoming insolvent, and in certain other events.</content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[9 November 1951]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2018/er5">E.R. 5 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402918367_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Third Parties (Rights against Insurers) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402918367_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Rights of third parties against insurers on bankruptcy, etc. of the
            insured</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411716155_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where under any contract of insurance a person (hereinafter referred to as
                        <i><b>the
                        insured</b></i>) is insured against liabilities to third parties which he
                may incur, then—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411716155_019" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the event of the insured becoming bankrupt or making a composition or
                    arrangement with his creditors; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411716155_027" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of the insured being a company, in the event of a winding-up
                    order being made, or a resolution for a voluntary winding-up being passed, with
                    respect to the company, or of a receiver or manager of the company’s business or
                    undertaking being duly appointed, or of possession being taken, by or on behalf
                    of the holders of any debentures secured by a floating charge, of any property
                    comprised in or subject to the charge; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411716171_006" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of the insured being a co-operative society in the event of an
                    order for cancellation of registration of such co-operative society being made
                    under the Co-operative Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap33">Cap.
                    33</ref>),</content></paragraph><continued>if, either before or after that event, any such liability as aforesaid is
                incurred by the insured, his rights against the insurer under the contract in
                respect of the liability shall, notwithstanding anything in any enactment or rule of
                law to the contrary, be transferred to and vest in the third party to whom the
                liability was so incurred.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411716171_019" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an order is made under <ref>section 112</ref> of the Bankruptcy Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>) for the administration of the estate of a
                deceased debtor according to the law of bankruptcy, then, if any debt provable in
                bankruptcy is owing by the deceased in respect of a liability against which he was
                insured under a contract of insurance as being a liability to a third party, the
                deceased debtor’s rights against the insurer under the contract in respect of that
                liability shall, notwithstanding anything in the said Ordinance, be transferred to
                and vest in the person to whom the debt is owing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411716202_005" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In so far as any contract of insurance made after the
                    commencement<sup>*</sup>
                of this Ordinance in respect of any liability of the insured to third parties
                purports, whether directly or indirectly, to avoid the contract or to alter the
                rights of the parties thereunder upon the happening to the insured of any of the
                events specified in paragraph (a), (b) or (c) of subsection (1) or upon the making
                of an order under <ref>section 112</ref> of the Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>) in respect of his estate, the contract shall be of
                no effect.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411716218_005" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Upon a transfer under subsection (1) or (2), the insurer shall, subject to the
                provisions of <ref>section 4</ref>, be under the same liability to the third party
                as he would have been under to the insured, but—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411716218_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the liability of the insurer to the insured exceeds the liability of the
                    insured to the third party, nothing in this Ordinance shall affect the rights of
                    the insured against the insurer in respect of the excess; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411716218_021" name="b" temporalId="s2_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the liability of the insurer to the insured is less than the liability
                    of the insured to the third party, nothing in this Ordinance shall affect the
                    rights of the third party against the insured in respect of the
                    balance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411716218_028" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="LiabilitiesToThirdParties">For the purposes of this Ordinance, the expression
                    <term>liabilities
                    to third
                parties</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">對第三者所負的法律責任</term>), in relation to a person
                insured under any contract of insurance, shall not include any liability of that
                person in the capacity of insurer under some other contract of insurance.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411716233_004" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>This Ordinance shall not apply where a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>company
                is wound up voluntarily merely for the purposes of reconstruction or amalgamation
                with another company.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1930 c. 25 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1538966085998_001">
        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
        <content><sup><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline></sup>Commencement date: 9 November
            1951.</content>
    </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438402918383_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Duty to give necessary information to third parties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411716264_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the event of any person becoming bankrupt or making a composition or arrangement with his creditors, or in the event of an order being made under <ref>section 112</ref> of the Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>) in respect of the estate of any person, or in the event of a winding-up order being made with respect to any company or of a receiver or manager of the company’s business or undertaking being duly appointed or of possession being taken by or on behalf of the holders of any debentures secured by a floating charge of any property comprised in or subject to the charge or of a resolution for a voluntary winding-up being passed with respect to any company, or in the event of an order for cancellation of registration of a co-operative society being made, it shall be the duty of the bankrupt, debtor, personal representative of the deceased debtor, or the company or co-operative society, and, as the case may be, of the trustee in bankruptcy, trustee, liquidator, receiver or manager, or person in possession of the property, to give, at the request of any person claiming that the bankrupt, debtor, deceased debtor, company, or co-operative society, is under a liability to him, such information as may reasonably be required by him for the purpose of ascertaining whether any rights have been transferred to and vested in him by this Ordinance and for the purpose of enforcing such rights, if any, and any contract of insurance, in so far as it purports, whether directly or indirectly to avoid the contract or to alter the rights of the parties thereunder upon the giving of any such information in the events aforesaid or otherwise to prohibit or prevent the giving thereof in the said events, shall be of no effect.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411716389_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the information given to any person in pursuance of subsection (1) discloses reasonable ground for supposing that there have or may have been transferred to him under this Ordinance rights against any particular insurer, that insurer shall be subject to the same duty as is imposed by the said subsection on the persons therein mentioned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411716389_013" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The duty to give information imposed by this section shall include a duty to allow all contracts of insurance, receipts for premiums, and other relevant documents in the possession or power of the person on whom the duty is so imposed to be inspected and copies thereof to be taken.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1930 c. 25 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402918398_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Settlement between insurers and insured persons</heading><content>Where the insured has become bankrupt or where, in the case of the insured being a company, a winding-up order has been made with respect to the company, or a resolution for a voluntary winding-up has been passed with respect to the company or where, in the case of the insured being a co-operative society, an order for cancellation of registration has been made, no agreement made between the insurer and the insured after liability has been incurred to a third party and after the commencement of the bankruptcy, winding-up or as from the date of such order for cancellation of registration, as the case may be, nor any waiver, assignment or other disposition made by, or payment made to, the insured after the commencement aforesaid shall be effective to defeat or affect the rights transferred to the third party under this Ordinance, but those rights shall be the same as if no such agreement, waiver, assignment, disposition or payment had been made.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1930 c. 25 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section></main></ordinance>