<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 53 sub. leg. B</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>53B</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap53B!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-10-10</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403394570_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2012-02-09">Antiquities and Monuments (Declaration
            of Monuments and Historical Buildings) (Consolidation) Notice</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap53/s3/1">Cap. 53, section 3(1)</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[20 October
            1978]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2012/er1">E.R. 1 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403394586_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2012-02-09" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>This notice may be cited as the Antiquities and Monuments (Declaration of Monuments and Historical Buildings) (Consolidation) Notice.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394586_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2020-05-22" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Declaration of monuments</heading><leadIn>The following places are declared to be monuments—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413122306_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the rock carving at Big Wave Bay, Hong Kong Island, and the adjoining land,
                which are more particularly delineated and edged red in plan No. HKM 1, signed by
                the Secretary for Home Affairs and deposited in the Land Registry, Victoria;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1978/ln247">L.N. 247 of
                    1978</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122306_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the rock carving and adjoining land at Tei Tong Tsui to the north-east of Tin
                Hau Kwo Miu temple delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 1 signed
                and deposited by the Secretary for the New Territories in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln34">L.N. 34 of
                    1979</ref>)<marker role="section-break"></marker></sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122321_006" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the rock carving and adjoining land on the north-west coast of Tung Lung Island
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 2 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for the New Territories in the Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln34">L.N. 34 of
                    1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122321_014" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the rock carving and adjoining land on the western coast of Kau Sai Chau
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 3 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for the New Territories in the Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln34">L.N. 34 of
                    1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122321_022" name="e" temporalId="s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the rock carving and adjoining land at Shek Pik on Lantau Island delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 4 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                the New Territories in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln111">L.N. 111 of
                    1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122337_006" name="f" temporalId="s2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the rock carvings and adjoining land on the south-west coast of Po Toi Island
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 5 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for the New Territories in the Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln111">L.N. 111 of
                    1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122337_014" name="g" temporalId="s2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the area of Government land on the north coast of Lantau Island comprising Tung
                Chung Fort, including the buildings and structures therein or thereon, delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 8 signed and deposited by the Secretary
                for the New Territories in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln201">L.N. 201 of 1979</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                    105</ref>)<marker role="section-break"></marker></sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122352_006" name="h" temporalId="s2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the flight of stone steps at the southern end of Duddell Street, Hong Kong
                Island, and the 4 gas lamps standing on the balustrades on either side of the steps,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 10 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1979/ln208">L.N. 208 of
                    1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122368_006" name="i" temporalId="s2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the ruins and remains situated on the north-eastern promontory of Tung Lung
                Island and known as Tung Lung Fort and the adjacent land, delineated and shown edged
                red on the plan marked NTM 11 signed and deposited by the Secretary for the New
                Territories in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln197">L.N. 197 of
                    1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122368_014" name="j" temporalId="s2_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>the walled village of Sam Tung Uk located to the North of the Castle Peak Road
                in Tsuen Wan District of the New Territories and the surrounding open space,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 12 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for the New Territories in the Land Registry in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln73">L.N. 73 of
                    1981</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122384_006" name="k" temporalId="s2_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>the District Office (North) located in Tai Po District of the New Territories
                and the adjacent land, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 14
                signed and deposited by the Secretary for the New Territories in the Land Registry,
                in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln356">L.N. 356 of
                    1981</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122384_014" name="l" temporalId="s2_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>the village of Sheung Yiu located on the eastern shore of Pak Tam Chung estuary
                near the western boundary of the Sai Kung East Country Park together with a stone
                kiln 50 metres north of the village, delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked NTM 17 signed and deposited by the Secretary for the New Territories in the
                Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln357">L.N. 357 of
                    1981</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122399_006" name="m" temporalId="s2_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>the Fan Lau Fort located on high ground about 60 metres above sea level on the
                south-west tip of Lantau and overlooking Lantau Channel, delineated and shown edged
                red on the plan marked NTM 15 signed and deposited by the Secretary for the New
                Territories in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/ln358">L.N. 358 of
                    1981</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122399_014" name="n" temporalId="s2_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content>the rock carvings and adjoining land overlooking Tung Wan on Cheung Chau,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 6 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for City and New Territories Administration in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln25">L.N. 25 of
                    1982</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122415_006" name="o" temporalId="s2_o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content>the Tin Hau Temple situated at No. 10 Tin Hau Temple Road, Causeway Bay,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan serial No. HKM 11 signed and deposited by
                the Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/ln102">L.N. 102 of 1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1982/ln170">L.N. 170 of
                1982</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122415_014" name="p" temporalId="s2_p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content>the rock carving located at Lung Ha Wan in Sai Kung District of the New
                Territories and the adjacent land, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked
                NTM 16 signed and deposited by the Director of Urban Services in the Land Registry,
                in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln75">L.N. 75 of
                    1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122430_006" name="q" temporalId="s2_q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content>the site of the Chinese Customs Station located on Fat Tau Chau (Junk Island)
                in Sai Kung District of the New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked NTM 22 signed and deposited by the Director of Urban Services in the
                Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln76">L.N. 76 of
                    1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122430_014" name="r" temporalId="s2_r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content>the Pottery Kilns at Wun Yiu Village, in Tai Po District of the New
                Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 21 signed and
                deposited by the Director of Urban Services in the Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln138">L.N. 138 of
                    1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122430_022" name="s" temporalId="s2_s"><num value="s">(s)</num><content>the Stone Circle at Fan Lau on Lantau Island of the New Territories, delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 23 signed and deposited by the Director
                of Urban Services in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln139">L.N. 139 of
                    1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122446_006" name="t" temporalId="s2_t"><num value="t">(t)</num><content>the Tung Chung Battery located in Tung Chung on Lantau Island, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 18 signed and deposited by the Director of
                Urban Services in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                    1983</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122446_014" name="u" temporalId="s2_u"><num value="u">(u)</num><content>the Royal Observatory, located in Kowloon, and the adjacent land, delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked KM 1 signed and deposited by the Director of
                Urban Services in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln161">L.N. 161 of
                    1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122462_006" name="v" temporalId="s2_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the Old Stanley Police Station located on Hong Kong Island, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 8 signed and deposited by the Director of
                Urban Services in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln161">L.N. 161 of
                    1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122462_014" name="w" temporalId="s2_w"><num value="w">(w)</num><content>the exterior of the Supreme Court Building located at Statue Square, Central
                District on Hong Kong Island, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM
                2 signed and deposited by the Director of Urban Services in the Land Registry,
                Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln161">L.N. 161 of 1984</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln446">L.N. 446 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122462_022" name="x" temporalId="s2_x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content>the rock carvings located at Wong Chuk Hang, Aberdeen on Hong Kong Island,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 14 signed and deposited by the
                Director of Urban Services in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln161">L.N. 161 of
                    1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122477_006" name="y" temporalId="s2_y"><num value="y">(y)</num><content>the Han Tomb at Lei Cheng Uk, Sham Shui Po, Kowloon, delineated and shown edged
                red on the plan marked KM 2a signed and deposited by the Secretary for Municipal
                Services in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln335">L.N. 335 of
                    1988</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122477_014" name="z" temporalId="s2_z"><num value="z">(z)</num><content>the former Kowloon-Canton Railway Clock Tower at Tsim Sha Tsui, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked KM 3 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln233">L.N. 233 of
                    1990</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122493_006" name="aa" temporalId="s2_aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content>the walls (including all the corner towers) of Kun Lung Wai (San Wai) in Lung
                Yeuk Tau, Fanling, New Territories delineated and shown in red, with the corner
                towers delineated and shown edged red, on the plan marked NTM 43 signed and
                deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln105">L.N. 105 of
                    1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122493_014" name="ab" temporalId="s2_ab"><num value="ab">(ab)</num><content>the entrance tower and the enclosing walls of Lo Wai in Lung Yeuk Tau, Fanling,
                New Territories delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 46 signed and
                deposited by the Secretary for Broadcasting, Culture and Sport in the Land Registry,
                in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln52">L.N. 52 of
                    1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122508_006" name="ac" temporalId="s2_ac"><num value="ac">(ac)</num><content>the dam, the valve house and the weir of the Wong Nai Chung Reservoir on Hong
                Kong Island, respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                HKM8609 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry
                in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln177">L.N. 177 of
                    2009</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122508_014" name="ad" temporalId="s2_ad"><num value="ad">(ad)</num><leadIn>the following building and structures constructed in connection with the Pok Fu
                Lam Reservoir on Hong Kong Island—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122508_022" name="i" temporalId="s2_ad_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the former Watchman’s Cottage, the gauge basin and the masonry bridge,
                    respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                    HKM8611-1 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land
                    Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122524_007" name="ii" temporalId="s2_ad_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the 3 masonry bridges, respectively delineated and shown edged red on the
                    plan marked Plan No. HKM8611-2 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                    Development in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                    the Ordinance;
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln177">L.N. 177 of
                        2009</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122524_014" name="ae" temporalId="s2_ae"><num value="ae">(ae)</num><leadIn>the following buildings and structures constructed in connection with the Tai
                Tam Group of Reservoirs on Hong Kong Island—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122524_022" name="i" temporalId="s2_ae_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the dam and the valve house of the Tai Tam Upper Reservoir, respectively
                    delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM8612-1 signed and
                    deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance
                    with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122540_007" name="ii" temporalId="s2_ae_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the masonry aqueduct of the Tai Tam Upper Reservoir and the adjacent
                    masonry bridge, respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked
                    Plan No. HKM8612-2 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the
                    Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                    Ordinance;<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122540_015" name="iii" temporalId="s2_ae_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the recorder house (together with the tunnel inlet) situated to the south
                    of the Tai Tam Upper Reservoir, and the dam and the valve house of the Tai Tam
                    Byewash Reservoir, respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                    marked Plan No. HKM8612-3 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development
                    in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                    Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122555_007" name="iv" temporalId="s2_ae_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>the 21-arch section of the aqueduct that forms part of the Bowen Road,
                    delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM8612-4 signed and
                    deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance
                    with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122555_015" name="v" temporalId="s2_ae_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the dam and the valve house of the Tai Tam Intermediate Reservoir,
                    respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                    HKM8612-5 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land
                    Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122555_023" name="vi" temporalId="s2_ae_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>the dam of the Tai Tam Tuk Reservoir, delineated and shown edged red on the
                    plan marked Plan No. HKM8612-6 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                    Development in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                    the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122571_007" name="vii" temporalId="s2_ae_vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content>the valve house and the memorial stone of the Tai Tam Tuk Reservoir,
                    respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                    HKM8612-7 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land
                    Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                    Ordinance;<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122571_015" name="viii" temporalId="s2_ae_viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content>the masonry bridge stretching across the Tai Tam Tuk Reservoir, delineated
                    and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM8612-8 signed and deposited
                    by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance with
                        <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122571_023" name="ix" temporalId="s2_ae_ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content>the masonry bridge stretching across the Tai Tam Tuk Reservoir, delineated
                    and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM8612-9 signed and deposited
                    by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance with
                        <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122586_007" name="x" temporalId="s2_ae_x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content>the 2 masonry bridges stretching across the Tai Tam Tuk Reservoir,
                    respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                    HKM8612-10 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land
                    Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122586_015" name="xi" temporalId="s2_ae_xi"><num value="xi">(xi)</num><content>the Tai Tam Tuk Raw Water Pumping Station, the Tai Tam Tuk Raw Water
                    Pumping Station Staff Quarters, the Tai Tam Tuk Raw Water Pumping Station No. 2
                    Staff Quarters, and the structure comprising a flue and a chimney shaft and
                    constructed in connection with the Tai Tam Tuk Raw Water Pumping Station,
                    respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                    HKM8612-11 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land
                    Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                    Ordinance;<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122602_007" name="xii" temporalId="s2_ae_xii"><num value="xii">(xii)</num><content>the Tai Tam Tuk Raw Water Pumping Station Senior Staff Quarters delineated
                    and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM8612-12 signed and deposited
                    by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance with
                        <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln177">L.N. 177 of
                        2009</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122618_006" name="af" temporalId="s2_af"><num value="af">(af)</num><leadIn>the following building and structures constructed in connection with the
                Aberdeen Reservoir on Hong Kong Island—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122618_014" name="i" temporalId="s2_af_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the dam of the Aberdeen Upper Reservoir, the bridge connecting to the dam
                    and the valve house of the Aberdeen Upper Reservoir, respectively delineated and
                    shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM8627-1 signed and deposited by
                    the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance with
                        <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122618_022" name="ii" temporalId="s2_af_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the dam of the Aberdeen Lower Reservoir, delineated and shown edged red on
                    the plan marked Plan No. HKM8627-2 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                    Development in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                    the Ordinance;
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln177">L.N. 177 of
                        2009</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122633_006" name="ag" temporalId="s2_ag"><num value="ag">(ag)</num><leadIn>the following buildings and structures constructed in connection with the
                Kowloon Reservoir in the New Territories—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122633_014" name="i" temporalId="s2_ag_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the main dam and the main dam valve house of the Reservoir, respectively
                    delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. STM8814c-1 signed and
                    deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance
                    with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122633_022" name="ii" temporalId="s2_ag_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the spillway dam and the spillway dam recorder house of the Reservoir,
                    respectively delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                    STM8814c-2 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land
                    Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413122633_030" name="iii" temporalId="s2_ag_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the recorder house of the Reservoir, delineated and shown edged red on the
                    plan marked Plan No. STM8814c-3 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                    Development in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                    the Ordinance;
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln177">L.N. 177 of
                        2009</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122649_006" name="ah" temporalId="s2_ah"><num value="ah">(ah)</num><content>the memorial stone of the Shing Mun Reservoir in the New Territories,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. KTM1414 signed and
                deposited by the Secretary for Development in the Land Registry in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln177">L.N. 177 of
                    2009</ref>; <ref href="hk/2019/ln156">L.N. 156 of
                    2019</ref>)<marker role="section-break"></marker></sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1572416518379_001" name="ai" temporalId="s2_ai"><num value="ai">(ai)</num><content>the rock carving and adjoining land at Cape Collinson, Eastern District on Hong
                Kong Island, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10443
                signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2019/ln156">L.N. 156 of
                        2019</ref>; <ref href="hk/2020/ln92">L.N. 92 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1590480633443_001" name="aj" temporalId="s2_aj"><num value="aj">(aj)</num><content>the masonry bridge of Pok Fu Lam Reservoir, Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong, as
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10608 signed and
                deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the
                Secretary for Development. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/ln92">L.N. 92 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 30</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/20">20 of
                2002 s.
            5</ref>)<br></br> </sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1590480633521_002">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content>For provisions for validation in relation to declarations made under
                    <ref>section 3</ref> of the Antiquities and Monuments Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap53">Cap. 53</ref>) and published after 31 December 1989 but before
                5 December 2014
                —
                see <ref>section 67</ref> of Ord. No. <ref href="/hk/2014/18">18 of
                2014</ref>.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403394633_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2024-10-10" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Declaration of historical buildings</heading><leadIn>The following places are declared to be historical buildings—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413122820_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Island House located in Tai Po District of the New Territories and the adjacent
                land, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 39 signed and deposited
                by the Director of Urban Services in the Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln77">L.N. 77 of 1983</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1988/ln266">L.N. 266 of
                    1988</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122820_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Man Lun Fung Ancestral Hall located in Fan Tin Tsuen, San Tin, in Yuen Long
                District of the New Territories and the adjacent forecourt, delineated and shown
                edged red on the plan marked NTM 13 signed and deposited by the Director of Urban
                Services in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln78">L.N. 78 of
                    1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453168158386_001" name="c...d" temporalId="s3_c...d"><num value="c...d" startValue="c" endValue="d">(c)-(d)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/ln161">L.N. 161 of 1984</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122836_012" name="e" temporalId="s3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the Man Mo Temple located at Fu Shin Street, Tai Po Market in Tai Po District
                of the New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 29
                signed and deposited by the Director of Urban Services in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln125">L.N. 125 of 1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122836_020" name="f" temporalId="s3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the facade, roof, main ceremonial grand staircase, external corridors and
                courtyards of the Main Building of the University of Hong Kong located on Hong Kong
                Island, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 7 signed and deposited
                by the Director of Urban Services in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance, the said parts being coloured pink,
                green and hatched yellow shown and described on the drawings numbered 1 to 4 and
                attached to the said plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln162">L.N. 162 of
                        1984</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122852_006" name="g" temporalId="s3_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the Old Tai Po Market Railway Station, Tai Po, New Territories, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 30 signed and deposited by the Director of
                Urban Services in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1984/ln385">L.N. 385 of
                    1984</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122867_005" name="h" temporalId="s3_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the Man Shek Tong (Ancestral Hall) located at Mun Hau Tsuen, Sheung Shui in
                North District of the New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked NTM 32 signed and deposited by the Director of Urban Services in the Land
                Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1985/ln10">L.N. 10 of
                1985</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122867_013" name="i" temporalId="s3_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the old house on a lot formerly known as Lot 917 at Hoi Pa Village, Tsuen Wan,
                New Territories, delineated and shown coloured pink on the plan marked NTM 35 signed
                and deposited by the Secretary for Municipal Services in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/ln170">L.N. 170 of 1986</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122867_021" name="j" temporalId="s3_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>the building known as the Tai Fu Tai (大夫第) at Wing Ping Tsuen, San Tin, Yuen
                Long, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 20
                signed and deposited by the Secretary for Municipal Services in the Land Registry,
                in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/ln215">L.N. 215 of 1987</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122883_006" name="k" temporalId="s3_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>the Kun Lung Gate Tower at San Wai, Fanling, New Territories, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 38 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Municipal Services in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln61">L.N. 61 of
                    1988</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122883_014" name="l" temporalId="s3_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>the Yeung Hau Kung Temple at Tung Tau Tsuen, Ha Tsuen, Yuen Long, New
                Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 40 signed and
                deposited by the Secretary for Municipal Services in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln307">L.N. 307 of
                1988</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122898_006" name="m" temporalId="s3_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>the former French Mission building on Battery Path, Hong Kong Island,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 15 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for Municipal Services in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1989/ln319">L.N. 319 of 1989</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122898_014" name="n" temporalId="s3_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content>Flagstaff House on Cotton Tree Drive, Hong Kong Island, delineated and shown
                edged red on the plan marked HKM 5 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Municipal Services in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1989/ln319">L.N. 319 of
                        1989</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122914_006" name="o" temporalId="s3_o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content>the old house known as Law Uk or Chai Wan House at Chai Wan on Hong Kong
                Island, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 6 signed and deposited
                by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1989/ln368">L.N. 368 of 1989</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122914_014" name="p" temporalId="s3_p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content>the old house at Wong Uk Village, Yuen Chau Kok, Sha Tin, delineated and shown
                edged red on the plan marked NTM 36 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1989/ln410">L.N. 410 of
                        1989</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122914_022" name="q" temporalId="s3_q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content>the Wan Chai Post Office on Hong Kong Island, delineated and shown edged red on
                the plan marked HKM 17 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and
                Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln160">L.N. 160 of
                    1990</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122930_006" name="r" temporalId="s3_r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content>the Western Market, Des Voeux Road Central, Hong Kong Island, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 20 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln209">L.N. 209 of 1990</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122930_014" name="s" temporalId="s3_s"><num value="s">(s)</num><content>the old Pathological Institute in Caine Lane, Hong Kong Island, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 19 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln209">L.N. 209 of 1990</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122945_006" name="t" temporalId="s3_t"><num value="t">(t)</num><content>the building known as Kang Yung Shu Uk at Sheung Wo Hang Village, Sha Tau Kok
                in the North District of the New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked NTM 41 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture
                in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1991/ln175">L.N. 175 of
                1991</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122945_014" name="u" temporalId="s3_u"><num value="u">(u)</num><content>the former Kowloon British School at Nathan Road, Tsim Sha Tsui, Kowloon,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked KM 4 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance
                with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1991/ln280">L.N. 280 of 1991</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122961_006" name="v" temporalId="s3_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the Main Building of St. Stephen’s Girls’ College at No. 2 Lyttelton Road, Hong
                Kong Island delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 16 signed and
                deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry,
                Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln40">L.N. 40 of
                1992</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122961_014" name="w" temporalId="s3_w"><num value="w">(w)</num><content>the building known as the Yi Tai Shu Yuen at Shui Tau Village, Kam Tin, New
                Territories delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 42 signed and
                deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln206">L.N. 206 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122961_022" name="x" temporalId="s3_x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content>the facade, roof, chimney stacks, parapets, balustrades, verandahs, balcony,
                external columns, staircases, entrance porch, main entrance doorway, courtyards and
                steps of the Main Building of The Helena May located at No. 35 Garden Road, Hong
                Kong Island, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 13 signed and
                deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry,
                Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance, the said
                parts being coloured red, green and hatched orange and blue shown and described on
                the drawings numbered 1 to 7 and attached to the said plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln388">L.N. 388 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122992_006" name="y" temporalId="s3_y"><num value="y">(y)</num><content>the building known as the Entrance Tower of Ma Wat Wai located at Lung Yeuk
                Tau, Fanling, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM
                44 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land
                Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln633">L.N. 633 of
                1994</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413122992_014" name="z" temporalId="s3_z"><num value="z">(z)</num><content>the Marine Police Headquarters building and compound located at Tsim Sha Tsui,
                Kowloon, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked KM 5 signed and deposited
                by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance, other than the structures
                (but not the land on which those structures are standing) located within that
                compound and hatched black on that plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln680">L.N. 680 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123008_006" name="aa" temporalId="s3_aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content>the building known as the Former Gate Lodge on Mount Austin Road, the Peak,
                Hong Kong, which is delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 21 signed
                and deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry,
                Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln128">L.N. 128 of
                1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123023_006" name="ab" temporalId="s3_ab"><num value="ab">(ab)</num><content>the buildings and compound at the Central Police Station Compound at No. 10
                Hollywood Road, Hong Kong, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 25
                signed and deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land
                Registry, Victoria; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln416">L.N. 416 of
                    1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123023_014" name="ac" temporalId="s3_ac"><num value="ac">(ac)</num><content>the former Central Magistracy at No. 1 Arbuthnot Road, Hong Kong, delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 26 signed and deposited by the Secretary
                for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln416">L.N. 416 of 1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123023_022" name="ad" temporalId="s3_ad"><num value="ad">(ad)</num><content>the buildings and compound at the Victoria Prison Compound at Old Bailey
                Street, Hong Kong, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 27 signed
                and deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry,
                Victoria; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln416">L.N. 416 of
                    1995</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123039_006" name="ae" temporalId="s3_ae"><num value="ae">(ae)</num><content>the exterior structure including the facade, roofs, chimney stacks, corner
                towers, parapets, balustrades, verandahs, balconies, external columns, staircases,
                main entrance doorway, courtyards and steps of University Hall, University of Hong
                Kong located at Pokfulam, Hong Kong Island, delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked HKM 28 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Recreation and Culture
                in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance, the said parts being coloured brown and hatched blue, purple and green
                shown and described on the drawings numbered 1 to 5 and attached to the said plan;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln421">L.N. 421 of
                1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123054_006" name="af" temporalId="s3_af"><num value="af">(af)</num><content>the exterior structure including the facade, roof, chimney stacks, parapets,
                balustrades, verandahs, balconies, external columns, entrance porch, main entrance
                doorway, courtyards and steps and internal elements including the floor, balustrades
                and ceiling of the open well and structural columns and walls of Hung Hing Ying
                Building, University of Hong Kong located at Pokfulam, Hong Kong Island, delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 24 signed and deposited by the Secretary
                for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance, the said parts being coloured brown,
                green, orange, yellow and hatched blue, purple and green shown and described on the
                drawings numbered 1 to 4 and attached to the said plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln422">L.N. 422 of
                1995</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123086_006" name="ag" temporalId="s3_ag"><num value="ag">(ag)</num><content>the exterior structure including the facade, roof, cornice, balustrades,
                balconies, main entrance doorway, courtyards and steps of Tang Chi Ngong Building,
                University of Hong Kong located at Pokfulam, Hong Kong Island, delineated and shown
                edged red on the plan marked HKM 23 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance, the said parts being coloured brown
                and hatched blue and green shown and described on the drawings numbered 1 to 3 and
                attached to the said plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln423">L.N. 423 of
                        1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123117_006" name="ah" temporalId="s3_ah"><num value="ah">(ah)</num><content>the building known as Government House at Upper Albert Road, Hong Kong, which
                is delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 22 signed and deposited by
                the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/ln442">L.N. 442 of 1995</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123117_014" name="ai" temporalId="s3_ai"><num value="ai">(ai)</num><content>St. John’s Cathedral on Garden Road, Central, Hong Kong, together with the land
                and buildings adjacent thereto, including St. John’s Hall but excluding the Lodge,
                as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 29 signed and deposited by
                the Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, Victoria, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1996/ln20">L.N. 20 of 1996</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123132_006" name="aj" temporalId="s3_aj"><num value="aj">(aj)</num><content>the temple known as I Shing Kung at Wang Chau, Yuen Long, New Territories,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked NTM 45 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for Recreation and Culture in the Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1996/ln265">L.N. 265 of
                1996</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123132_014" name="ak" temporalId="s3_ak"><num value="ak">(ak)</num><content>the building known as the former Yamen Building at Kowloon Walled City Park,
                Kowloon, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked KM 6 signed and deposited
                by the Secretary for Broadcasting, Culture and Sport in the Land Registry, in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1996/ln406">L.N. 406 of 1996</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123148_006" name="al" temporalId="s3_al"><num value="al">(al)</num><content>the building known as the Tang Chung Ling Ancestral Hall, at Lung Yeuk Tau,
                Fanling, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                DND 1 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Broadcasting, Culture and Sport in
                the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln530">L.N. 530 of
                1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123148_014" name="am" temporalId="s3_am"><num value="am">(am)</num><content>the temple known as Cheung Shang Tsz, also commonly known as Cheung Shan Kwu
                Tsz at Wo Keng Shan, Ping Che, Fanling, New Territories, delineated and shown edged
                red on the plan marked NTM 47 signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Broadcasting, Culture and Sport in the Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln39">L.N. 39 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123164_006" name="an" temporalId="s3_an"><num value="an">(an)</num><content>the building known as King Law Ka Shuk at Tai Po Tau Tsuen, Tai Po, New
                Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. TPM
                    3268<sup>b</sup> signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home Affairs in the
                Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/ln301">L.N. 301 of
                1998</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123164_014" name="ao" temporalId="s3_ao"><num value="ao">(ao)</num><content>the building known as Cheung Ancestral Hall at Shan Ha Tsuen, Ping Shan, Yuen
                Long, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                YLM 3252b signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land
                Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/ln328">L.N. 328 of
                1999</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123179_006" name="ap" temporalId="s3_ap"><num value="ap">(ap)</num><content>the building known as Fan Sin Temple, also known as Fan Sin Kung or Fan Sin
                Miu, at Sheung Wun Yiu, Tai Po, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on
                the plan marked Plan No. TPM 3513a signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home
                Affairs in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/ln329">L.N. 329 of
                    1999</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123179_014" name="aq" temporalId="s3_aq"><num value="aq">(aq)</num><content>the two buildings respectively known as the North Block and the West Block of
                St. Joseph’s College at No. 7 Kennedy Road, Hong Kong, delineated and shown edged
                red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM 5746c signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Home Affairs in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln255">L.N. 255 of
                    2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123195_006" name="ar" temporalId="s3_ar"><num value="ar">(ar)</num><content>the Waglan Lighthouse on Waglan Island, Hong Kong, and the adjacent land,
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked HKM 6436 signed and deposited by
                the Secretary for Home Affairs in the Urban Land Registry in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln368">L.N. 368 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123195_014" name="as" temporalId="s3_as"><num value="as">(as)</num><content>the Tang Lung Chau Lighthouse, commonly known as Kap Sing Lighthouse, and the
                former light keeper’s house on Tang Lung Chau, Kap Shui Mun, Hong Kong, delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked TWM 2582a signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln368">L.N. 368 of
                        2000</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123210_006" name="at" temporalId="s3_at"><num value="at">(at)</num><content>the Tang Ancestral Hall at Ping Shan Hang Mei Lot No. 1 in D.D. 122, Yuen Long,
                New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. YLM 4538
                signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land Registry in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2001/ln272">L.N. 272 of 2001</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123210_014" name="au" temporalId="s3_au"><num value="au">(au)</num><content>the Yu Kiu Ancestral Hall at Ping Shan Hang Mei Lot No. 2 in D.D. 122, Yuen
                Long, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                YLM 4537 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land Registry
                in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2001/ln272">L.N. 272 of 2001</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123226_006" name="av" temporalId="s3_av"><num value="av">(av)</num><content>the Tsui Sing Lau Pagoda at Lot No. 384 in D.D. 122, Yuen Long, New
                Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. YLM 4540
                signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land Registry in
                accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2001/ln272">L.N. 272 of 2001</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123226_014" name="aw" temporalId="s3_aw"><num value="aw">(aw)</num><content>the Hung Shing Temple (also known as Hung Shing Miu) at Lot No. 73 in D.D. 265,
                Kau Sai Chau, Sai Kung, New Territories, and the adjoining land, delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. SKM 5179 signed and deposited by the
                Secretary for Home Affairs in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/ln167">L.N. 167 of
                        2002</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123242_004" name="ax" temporalId="s3_ax"><num value="ax">(ax)</num><content>the Tin Hau Temple at Lo Tsun Tsz Tong Tsun Lot No. 1 in D.D. 83, Lung Yeuk
                Tau, Fanling, New Territories, and the adjoining land, delineated and shown edged
                red on the plan marked Plan No. DNM 937a signed and deposited by the Secretary for
                Home Affairs in the Land Registry in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/ln167">L.N. 167 of
                    2002</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123242_012" name="ay" temporalId="s3_ay"><num value="ay">(ay)</num><content>the Hau Ku Shek Ancestral Hall at Ho Sheung Heung Lot No. 8 in D.D. 95, Ho
                Sheung Heung, Sheung Shui, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked Plan No. DNM 1291 signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home Affairs
                in the Land Registry, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2003/ln270">L.N. 270 of
                2003</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123257_006" name="az" temporalId="s3_az"><num value="az">(az)</num><content>“馬禮遜樓” and its adjoining land within the Hoh Fuk Tong Centre (also known as Ho
                Fuk Tong Centre) situated at the Remaining Portion of Tuen Mun Town Lot No. 117, No.
                28 Castle Peak Road, Tuen Mun, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on
                the plan marked Plan No. TMM 2045e signed and deposited by the Secretary for Home
                Affairs in the Tuen Mun New Territories Land Registry, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2004/ln48">L.N. 48 of 2004</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123257_014" name="ba" temporalId="s3_ba"><num value="ba">(ba)</num><content>Cape D’ Aguilar Lighthouse at Cape D’ Aguilar, Hong Kong, and its adjoining
                land, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM7688 signed and
                deposited in the Land Registry by the Secretary for Home Affairs, in accordance with
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/ln236">L.N. 236 of 2005</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123273_006" name="bb" temporalId="s3_bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content>Leung Ancestral Hall at Yun Kong Tsun Lot No. 1 in D.D. 106, 62 Yuen Kong
                Tsuen, Pat Heung, Yuen Long, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked Plan No. YLM 6526 signed and deposited in the Land Registry by the
                Secretary for Home Affairs, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2006/ln253">L.N. 253 of
                    2006</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123273_014" name="bc" temporalId="s3_bc"><num value="bc">(bc)</num><content>Chik Kwai Study Hall at Sheung Tsun Lot No. 406 in D.D. 112, Sheung Tsuen, Pat
                Heung, Yuen Long, New Territories, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked
                Plan No. YLM6230 signed and deposited in the Land Registry by the Secretary for Home
                Affairs, in accordance with <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln76">L.N. 76 of
                2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123288_006" name="bd" temporalId="s3_bd"><num value="bd">(bd)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438413123288_009" name="i" temporalId="s3_bd_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the building known as Tang Ancestral Hall on Ha Tsun Shi Lot No. 44 in D.D.
                    125 and Lot No. 1722 in D.D. 125, Ha Tsuen, Yuen Long, New Territories, and its
                    adjoining land, delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                    YLM6911 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                    of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413123288_016" name="ii" temporalId="s3_bd_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>all other buildings on such land (other than the structure on the area
                    hatched black on the plan); <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln227">L.N. 227 of
                            2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123304_006" name="be" temporalId="s3_be"><num value="be">(be)</num><content>the buildings and the adjoining land situated within the Maryknoll Convent
                School at the Remaining Portion of New Kowloon Inland Lot No. 1419, No. 5 Ho Tung
                Road and No. 130 Waterloo Road, Kowloon, delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. KM7459b signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development, other than the
                structures situated within the area hatched black on the plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2008/ln135">L.N. 135 of
                2008</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123304_014" name="bf" temporalId="s3_bf"><num value="bf">(bf)</num><content>the buildings and the adjoining land situated within the Inland Lot No. 7327,
                No. 45 Stubbs Road, Hong Kong as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked
                Plan No. HKM8358 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development, together with all
                structures erected on such lot; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2008/ln201">L.N. 201 of
                        2008</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123320_006" name="bg" temporalId="s3_bg"><num value="bg">(bg)</num><content>the buildings, including the two buildings respectively known as the Old Green
                Island Lighthouse and the New Green Island Lighthouse, and the adjoining land,
                situated on Green Island, Hong Kong and within the area as delineated and shown
                edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM7691a signed and deposited in the Land
                Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2008/ln241">L.N. 241 of
                    2008</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123335_006" name="bh" temporalId="s3_bh"><num value="bh">(bh)</num><content>the Residence of Ip Ting-sz at Lot Nos. 462, 467 and 468 in D.D. 47, Lin Ma
                Hang Tsuen, Sha Tau Kok, New Territories as delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked Plan No. DNM2250 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln220">L.N. 220 of
                2009</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123335_014" name="bi" temporalId="s3_bi"><num value="bi">(bi)</num><content>the Yan Tun Kong Study Hall at Ping Shan Hang Tau Lot Nos. 126 and 148 in D.D.
                122 and Lot Nos. 515 and 1600 in D.D. 122, Hang Tau Tsuen, Ping Shan, Yuen Long, New
                Territories, and the adjoining land, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. YLM6953a signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2009/ln220">L.N. 220 of
                2009</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123351_006" name="bj" temporalId="s3_bj"><num value="bj">(bj)</num><content>the Tung Wah Museum in Kwong Wah Hospital at Kowloon Inland Lot No. 10748, 25
                Waterloo Road, Yau Ma Tei, Kowloon, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. KM8223 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2010/ln149">L.N. 149 of 2010</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453168159902_002" name="bk" temporalId="s3_bk"><num value="bk">(bk)</num><content>the Man Mo Temple Compound at Inland Lot No. 338, 124–126, 128 and 130
                Hollywood Road, Sheung Wan, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. HKM8879 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section
                    3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2010/ln149">L.N. 149 of 2010</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453168159918_003" name="bl" temporalId="s3_bl"><num value="bl">(bl)</num><content>the Tang Kwong U Ancestral Hall at Kam Tin Pak Pin Lot No. 3 in D.D. 109, 32
                Shui Tau, Kam Tin, Yuen Long, New Territories, as delineated and shown edged red on
                the plan marked Plan No. YLM7622a signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2010/ln149">L.N. 149 of
                2010</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453168159949_004" name="bm" temporalId="s3_bm"><num value="bm">(bm)</num><content>the Kom Tong Hall at 7 Castle Road, Mid-levels, Hong Kong, as delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM8865b signed and deposited in the
                Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2010/ln149">L.N. 149 of
                    2010</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123382_005" name="bn" temporalId="s3_bn"><num value="bn">(bn)</num><content>the fortified structure at No. 55 Ha Pak Nai, Yuen Long, New Territories, as
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. YLM7759 signed and
                deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the
                Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/ln109">L.N. 109 of
                        2011</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123382_013" name="bo" temporalId="s3_bo"><num value="bo">(bo)</num><content>the School House of St. Stephen’s College at the Remaining Portion of Rural
                Building Lot No. 432 and the Extensions thereto, 22 Tung Tau Wan Road, Stanley, Hong
                Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM9166a signed
                and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by
                the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/ln172">L.N. 172 of
                        2011</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123398_006" name="bp" temporalId="s3_bp"><num value="bp">(bp)</num><content>the east, south and north wings of the school building together with parts of
                the retaining walls and boundary walls of King’s College at 63A Bonham Road, Hong
                Kong, as delineated and shown edged red (other than the parts coloured green and
                marked with the letter “G”) on the plan marked Plan No. HKM7124 signed and deposited
                in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary
                for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/ln172">L.N. 172 of
                    2011</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123413_006" name="bq" temporalId="s3_bq"><num value="bq">(bq)</num><content>the Cenotaph and its adjoining land in Central, Hong Kong, as delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM9524a signed and deposited in the
                Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2013/ln186">L.N. 186 of
                    2013</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123413_014" name="br" temporalId="s3_br"><num value="br">(br)</num><content>the Bethanie at 139 Pok Fu Lam Road, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown edged
                red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM9387a signed and deposited in the Land Registry
                under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2013/ln186">L.N. 186 of
                2013</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123429_006" name="bs" temporalId="s3_bs"><num value="bs">(bs)</num><content>Fat Tat Tong at 1–5 Ha Wo Hang, Sha Tau Kok, New Territories, as delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. DNM2872a signed and deposited in the
                Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2013/ln206">L.N. 206 of
                    2013</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123429_014" name="bt" temporalId="s3_bt"><num value="bt">(bt)</num><content>Tat Tak Communal Hall at Ping Shan, Yuen Long, New Territories, as delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. YLM8035a signed and deposited in the
                Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2013/ln206">L.N. 206 of
                    2013</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123444_006" name="bu" temporalId="s3_bu"><num value="bu">(bu)</num><content>the building known as Lin Fa Temple (also known as Lin Fa Kung) at Inland Lot
                No. 8365 and the Extension thereto, Lily Street, Tai Hang, Hong Kong, as delineated
                and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM9740a signed and deposited in the
                Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2014</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123444_014" name="bv" temporalId="s3_bv"><num value="bv">(bv)</num><content>the building known as Hung Shing Temple at Aplichow Inland Lot No. 23, Hung
                Shing Street, Ap Lei Chau, Hong Kong, and a pair of timber poles on the land in
                front of the building, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                HKM9737a signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2014</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413123460_006" name="bw" temporalId="s3_bw"><num value="bw">(bw)</num><content>the building known as Hau Wong Temple, and its adjoining land, at the Remaining
                Portion of New Kowloon Inland Lot No. 3811, corner of Junction Road and Tung Tau
                Tsuen Road, Kowloon City, Kowloon, and a stone with an inscription on the land at
                the rear of the building, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan
                No. KM9161 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2014/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2014; L.N. 213 of
                2015</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453798556893_001" name="bx" temporalId="s3_bx"><num value="bx">(bx)</num><content>the Signal Tower at Blackhead Point, Tsim Sha Tsui, Kowloon, as delineated and
                shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. KM9364 signed and deposited in the Land
                Registry under section 3(4) of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                    Development;<sourceNote> (<ref href="hk/2015/ln213">L.N. 213 of
                    2015</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453798556900_002" name="by" temporalId="s3_by"><num value="by">(by)</num><content>the Race Course Fire Memorial and its adjoining land within Inland Lot No.
                2384, So Kon Po, Hong Kong, together with all structures erected on that lot, as
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM9905 signed and
                deposited in the Land Registry under section 3(4) of the Ordinance by the Secretary
                for Development; <sourceNote> (<ref href="hk/2015/ln213">L.N. 213 of
                    2015</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453798556900_003" name="by" temporalId="s3_by"><num value="by">(bz)</num><content>the facade of the Old Mental Hospital at 2 High Street, Sai Ying Pun, Hong
                Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM9895 signed
                and deposited in the Land Registry under section 3(4) of the Ordinance by the
                Secretary for Development;<sourceNote> (<ref href="hk/2015/ln213">L.N. 213 of
                        2015</ref>; <ref href="hk/2016/ln89">L.N. 89 of
                2016</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1478663408894_001" name="ca" temporalId="s3_ca"><num value="ca">(ca)</num><content>Block 7 of the old Lei Yue Mun Barracks at 75 Chai Wan Road, Chai Wan, Hong
                Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10000a signed
                and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by
                the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2016/ln89">L.N. 89 of
                        2016</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1478663408894_002" name="cb " temporalId="s3_cb "><num value="cb ">(cb)</num><content>Block 10 of the old Lei Yue Mun Barracks at 75 Chai Wan Road, Chai Wan, Hong
                Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10001a signed
                and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by
                the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2016/ln89">L.N. 89 of
                        2016</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph name="cc" temporalId="s3_cc" id="ID_1508307628073_001"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content>Block 25 of the old Lei Yue Mun Barracks at 75 Chai Wan Road, Chai Wan, Hong
                Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10002a signed
                and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by
                the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2016/ln89">L.N. 89 of
                        2016</ref>; <ref href="hk/2017/ln170">L.N. 170 of
                2017</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1508307628136_002" name="cd" temporalId="s3_cd"><num value="cd">(cd)</num><content>the building known as Tung Lin Kok Yuen at Inland Lot No. 3645, 15 Shan Kwong
                Road, Happy Valley, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked
                Plan No. HKM10171 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under section 3(4) of
                the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2017/ln170">L.N. 170 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1508307628136_003" name="ce" temporalId="s3_ce"><num value="ce">(ce)</num><content>the building known as Kowloon Union Church at the Remaining Portion of Kowloon
                Inland Lot No. 2174, 4 Jordan Road, Yau Ma Tei, Kowloon, as delineated and shown
                edged red on the plan marked Plan No. KM9818 signed and deposited in the Land
                Registry under section 3(4) of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2017/ln170">L.N. 170 of
                2017</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1508307628136_004" name="cf" temporalId="s3_cf"><num value="cf">(cf)</num><content>the building known as Yeung Hau Temple at Lot No. 1 in D.D. 313, Po Chue Tam,
                Tai O, Lantau Island, New Territories, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. ISM2803 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under section 3(4)
                of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2017/ln170">L.N. 170 of 2017</ref>; <ref href="hk/2018/ln224">L.N.
                        224 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1542340055551_001" name="cg" temporalId="s3_cg"><num value="cg">(cg)</num><content>the exterior structure (including the facade, roof, skylight, chimney stack,
                parapets with decorations, external columns, main entrance doorway and steps) of the
                building known as Fung Ping Shan Building of The University of Hong Kong at the
                Remaining Portion of Inland Lot No. 8482, Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong, the building being
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10300, with the
                exterior structure being coloured pink or green or hatched orange shown and
                described on the drawings numbered F01, F02, F03 and F04 attached to the plan,
                signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2018/ln224">L.N. 224 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1542340055551_002" name="ch" temporalId="s3_ch"><num value="ch">(ch)</num><content>the exterior structure (including the facade, roofs, chimney stacks, parapets,
                balconies, canopy, staircases, external columns, entrance porch, main entrance
                doorway and steps) of the building known as Eliot Hall of The University of Hong
                Kong at the Remaining Portion of Inland Lot No. 8482, Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong, the
                building being delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10301,
                with the exterior structure being coloured pink, blue, orange or green or hatched
                orange shown and described on the drawings numbered E01, E02, E03 and E04 attached
                to the plan, signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2018/ln224">L.N. 224 of
                2018</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1542340055551_003" name="ci" temporalId="s3_ci"><num value="ci">(ci)</num><content>the exterior structure (including the facade, roofs, chimney stacks, parapets,
                balconies, canopy, staircases, external columns, entrance porch, main entrance
                doorway and steps) of the building known as May Hall of The University of Hong Kong
                at the Remaining Portion of Inland Lot No. 8482, Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong, the building
                being delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10302, with the
                exterior structure being coloured pink, blue, orange or green or hatched orange
                shown and described on the drawings numbered M01, M02, M03 and M04 attached to the
                plan, signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the
                Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2018/ln224">L.N. 224 of 2018</ref>; <ref href="hk/2019/ln156">L.N. 156 of
                    2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1572421343566_001" name="cj" temporalId="s3_cj"><num value="cj">(cj)</num><content>the building known as Yuk Hui Temple (also known as Pak Tai Temple) at Inland
                Lot No. 8355, Wan Chai, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. HKM10488 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2019/ln156">L.N. 156 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1572421343582_002" name="ck" temporalId="s3_ck"><num value="ck">(ck)</num><content>the building known as Hau Mei Fung Ancestral Hall at Kam Tsin Lot No. 1 in D.D.
                92, Kam Tsin, Sheung Shui, New Territories, as delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked Plan No. DNM3812b signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2019/ln156">L.N. 156 of 2019</ref>; <ref href="hk/2020/ln92">L.N. 92 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1590480725621_001" name="cl" temporalId="s3_cl"><num value="cl">(cl)</num><content>the buildings and the adjoining land within Tung Wah Coffin Home at Inland Lot
                No. 8720, 9 Sandy Bay Road, Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong and <i>Pai Lau</i> of Tung Wah
                Coffin Home situated on an access road off Victoria Road, Hong Kong, leading to that
                lot, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10604 signed
                and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by
                the Secretary for Development, other than the structures situated within the area
                hatched black on the plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/ln92">L.N. 92 of
                        2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1590480725636_002" name="cm" temporalId="s3_cm"><num value="cm">(cm)</num><content>the building known as Tin Hau Temple and the adjoining buildings at Kowloon
                Inland Lot No. 10308, Yau Ma Tei, Kowloon, as delineated and shown edged red on the
                plan marked Plan No. KM10414 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/ln92">L.N. 92 of 2020</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/ln121">L.N. 121 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1626746997803_001" name="cn" temporalId="s3_cn"><num value="cn">(cn)</num><content>the buildings and the adjoining land situated within the Bonham Road Government
                Primary School at 9A Bonham Road, Sai Ying Pun, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown
                edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM10840 signed and deposited in the Land
                Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for
                Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/ln121">L.N. 121 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1626746997803_002" name="co" temporalId="s3_co"><num value="co">(co)</num><content>the Old Tai Po Police Station and the adjoining land at 11 Wan Tau Kok Lane,
                Tai Po, New Territories, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan
                No. TPM6626a signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref>
                of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/ln121">L.N. 121 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1626746997818_003" name="cp" temporalId="s3_cp"><num value="cp">(cp)</num><content>the building known as Hip Tin Temple and the adjoining land at Lot No. 353 in
                D.D. 40, Shan Tsui, Sha Tau Kok, New Territories, as delineated and shown edged red
                on the plan marked Plan No. DNM4014d signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/ln121">L.N. 121 of 2021</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/ln107">L.N. 107 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1653288997905_001" name="cq" temporalId="s3_cq"><num value="cq">(cq)</num><content>the building known as Jamia Mosque at Inland Lot No. 268, 30 Shelley Street,
                Central, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No.
                HKM10980 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of
                the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development, other than the temporary canopy
                situated within the area hatched black on the plan; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2022/ln107">L.N. 107 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1653288997910_002" name="cp" temporalId="s3_cp"><num value="cp">(cr)</num><content>the building known as Lui Seng Chun at 119 Lai Chi Kok Road, Mong Kok, Kowloon,
                as delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. KM10792 signed and
                deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the
                Secretary for Development; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2022/ln107">L.N. 107 of
                        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1653288997914_003" name="cs" temporalId="s3_cs"><num value="cs">(cs)</num><content>the buildings, structures and the adjoining land within Hong Kong City Hall at
                5 Edinburgh Place, Central, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. HKM10981 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2022/ln107">L.N. 107 of 2022</ref>; <ref href="hk/2023/ln145">L.N. 145 of
                2023</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1698223756502_001" name="ct" temporalId="s3_ct"><num value="ct">(ct)</num><content>the Tin Hau Temple, Joss House Bay, Sai Kung at Lot No. 92 in D.D. 240, Tei
                Tong Tsui, Sai Kung, New Territories, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. SKM10300 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/ln145">L.N. 145 of
                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1698223756505_002" name="cu" temporalId="s3_cu"><num value="cu">(cu)</num><content>the Chinese YMCA of Hong Kong at 51 Bridges Street, Sheung Wan, Hong Kong, as
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. HKM11235 signed and
                deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the
                Secretary for Development;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/ln145">L.N. 145 of
                    2023</ref>; <ref href="hk/2024/ln131">L.N. 131 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1728888852683_001" name="cv" temporalId="s3_cv"><num value="cv">(cv)</num><content>the building known as Lo Pan Temple at Inland Lot No. 2705, 15 Ching Lin
                Terrace, Kennedy Town, Hong Kong, as delineated and shown edged red on the plan
                marked Plan No. HKM11448 signed and deposited in the Land Registry under
                    <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the Secretary for Development;
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2024/ln131">L.N. 131 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1728888852683_002" name="cw" temporalId="s3_cw"><num value="cw">(cw)</num><content>the Residence of Tang Pak Kau at Kat Hing Wai Lot Nos. 183, 184, 185, 186 and
                187 in D.D. 109, Sections A and B of Lot No. 409 in D.D. 109 and Section B of Lot
                No. 417 in D.D. 109, 20 Tsz Tong Tsuen, Kam Tin, Yuen Long, New Territories, as
                delineated and shown edged red on the plan marked Plan No. YLM11510 signed and
                deposited in the Land Registry under <ref>section 3(4)</ref> of the Ordinance by the
                Secretary for Development. <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2024/ln131">L.N. 131 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 30</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/20">20 of
                2002 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1728888852746_003">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content>For provisions for validation in relation to declarations made under
                    <ref>section 3</ref> of the Antiquities and Monuments Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap53">Cap. 53</ref>) and published after 31 December 1989 but before
                5 December 2014 — see <ref>section 67</ref> of Ord. No. <ref href="/hk/2014/18">18
                    of 2014</ref>.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></main></subLeg>