<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 78</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>78</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap78!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-08-18</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403563206_004" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-10-21">
            <content>To control contracts of employment entered into in Hong Kong by employees
                performing primarily manual work and certain other employees who are proceeding
                outside Hong Kong for employment.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 ss. 2</ref> &amp; 15; <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
            2</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 November 1965]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1965/ln135">L.N. 135 of 1965</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403563222_001" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403563222_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Contracts for Employment Outside Hong Kong Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563238_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Commissioner"><term>Commissioner</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">處長</term>) means the Commissioner for Labour;</def><def name="Dependant"><term>dependant</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受養人</term>) means the spouse of an employee, and his or
            her children, step-children, and lawfully adopted children, who are unmarried and under
            the age of 16 years;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
            3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Employee"><term>employee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">僱員</term>) means a person who has entered or is about
            to enter the employment of another under a contract to which this Ordinance applies;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ManualWork"><term>manual
                work</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">體力勞動工作</term>) includes personal and domestic service.
            <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s.
            4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563238_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Delegation by Commissioner</heading><content>The Commissioner may, in writing, delegate to any public officer, either generally or for any particular purpose and either by name or by reference to a public office, such of his powers and functions under this Ordinance, other than the power conferred on him by <ref>section 11(2)(b)</ref>, as he may consider expedient.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/39">39 of 1971 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563238_005" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Contracts to which the Ordinance applies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414046992_018" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), this Ordinance applies to contracts of employment
                entered into in Hong Kong after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, by which a person in Hong Kong enters or agrees to enter into the
                service of another person who is not in Hong Kong and not carrying on a business in
                Hong Kong where the contract is to be performed, whether wholly or partially,
                outside Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s.
                    15</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414047007_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>This Ordinance shall not apply in respect of—
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
                4</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047007_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>persons employed for service as members of the crews of ships or
                    aircraft;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047007_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047007_029" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any person or class of persons migrating for employment whose admission to
                    the place of immigration will be granted on a permanent
                        basis;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of
                            1985 s.
                        5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047023_005" name="d" temporalId="s4_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any person who does not perform primarily manual work and whose wages
                    exceed an amount set by the Secretary for Labour and Welfare by notice in the
                        Gazette.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 4</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1634005543427_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1965.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403563253_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Control
            of Contracts
            for
            Employment
            Outside
            Hong
            Kong</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403563253_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Contracts to be in writing and to contain certain particulars</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414047070_032" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every contract to which this Ordinance applies shall be in writing, and, before
                the departure of the employee from Hong Kong, shall be signed by the employee and by
                the employer or other person acting on behalf of the
                    employer.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of
                        1985 ss. 7</ref> &amp; 15)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414047085_004" name="1A" temporalId="s5_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>An employee who is unable to sign a contract may indicate his assent by
                affixing his thumb print in ink.
                <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
                5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414047085_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Every contract to which this Ordinance applies shall contain all such
                particulars as may be necessary to define the rights and obligations of the parties
                thereto, and shall in all cases include the following—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047085_020" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the name of the employer and where applicable the name<inline class="width_3"> </inline>of the business or undertaking;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047085_028" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the name of the employee and particulars of the place of engagement and the
                    place of origin of the employee and any other particulars necessary for his
                    identification;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047085_036" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the name of the place at which the contract is to be performed and
                    particulars of the nature of the employment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047101_006" name="d" temporalId="s5_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>particulars of the rates of wages, including rates for overtime work where
                    applicable, and the manner and periodicity of payment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047101_014" name="e" temporalId="s5_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>particulars governing the advances of wages, if any, and the manner of
                    repayment of any such advances;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047101_022" name="f" temporalId="s5_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>except in the case of a contract for employment in domestic service,
                    particulars of the days and hours during which the employee may be called on to
                    work and of his entitlement in respect of rest days, paid holidays and annual
                    leave, the terms of which shall not be less favourable than those laid down in
                    the Employment Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap57">Cap. 57</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047101_030" name="g" temporalId="s5_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>particulars of the duration of the contract, the grounds of, provision for,
                    and manner of, terminating the contract, provisions for varying the contract and
                    provisions for re-engagement of the employee, including that the employer shall
                    give the employee a minimum of 1 month’s notice or wages in lieu of notice to
                    terminate the contract otherwise than by a summary dismissal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047117_006" name="h" temporalId="s5_2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>a stipulation that the contract shall not be transferred from the employer
                    to any other employer except with the consent of the employee freely given and
                    not obtained by or as a result of any threat, intimidation, bribery, deceit,
                    undue influence, misrepresentation or mistake, and except with the endorsement
                    of the transfer upon the contract by an officer or official of the place in
                    which the contract is performed for the time being responsible for matters
                    pertaining to employment;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047132_006" name="i" temporalId="s5_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>particulars of the measures to be taken to provide for the welfare of the
                    employee and any dependants who may accompany him under the terms of the
                    contract, including particulars as to medical treatment, compensation in the
                    event of the death of or injury to, or incapacity due to occupational disease
                    of, the employee arising out of and in the course of the employment, and the
                    provision of food and quarters;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047148_006" name="ia" temporalId="s5_2_ia"><num value="ia">(ia)</num><content>in addition to the particulars required under paragraph (i), the contract
                    shall provide that where the employee suffers personal injury by accident or
                    occupational disease arising out of or in the course of employment, the employer
                    shall defray the expenses necessarily incurred by the employee on account of
                    medical treatment, including maintenance in hospital, during the employee’s
                    incapacity, pay or arrange with the appropriate authority for payment of
                    compensation in accordance with the law of the place of employment or, if no law
                    on compensation exists, the employer shall pay compensation not less favourable
                    than that laid down in the Employees’ Compensation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap282">Cap. 282</ref>) and be responsible for all expenses
                    incurred whenever the employee is required to undergo a medical assessment for
                    the purpose of employees’ compensation and that where the employee is ill or
                    suffers from an accident not attributable to his employment, the employer shall
                    provide free medical attention and maintenance in hospital to the employee while
                    he is incapacitated. In the event of illness or incapacity not attributable to
                    the employee’s employment, the employer shall pay the employee, as a minimum,
                    full wages for the first month of incapacity and half wages for at least 3
                    months thereafter;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 5</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047226_006" name="j" temporalId="s5_2_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>particulars relating to the passage of the employee and his dependants to
                    and from the place at which the contract is to be performed and an undertaking
                    that the passage of the employee and his dependants to the place at which the
                    contract is to be performed and all necessary documents, including travel and
                    employment permits, for the employee and his dependants shall be provided by or
                    on behalf of the employer free of charge to the employee and his
                    dependants;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047226_014" name="k" temporalId="s5_2_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>an undertaking that, upon the termination of contract, the employee, if he
                    so requests the employer within 3 months after such termination, shall be
                    repatriated at the employer’s expense (which shall include travelling and
                    subsistence expenses during the journey and subsistence expenses during the
                    period, if any, between the date of such termination and the date of
                    repatriation other than a period during which repatriation has been delayed by
                    the employee’s own choice<inline class="width_3"> </inline>or for reasons of
                    force majeure) to his place of engagement or, at the employee’s request, to his
                    place of origin if such place is nearer to the place at which the contract was
                    performed, together with his dependants (if any) who were brought to the place
                    at which the contract was performed by or on behalf of the employer;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of
                            1985 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047273_004" name="l" temporalId="s5_2_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>an undertaking that in the event of the death of the employee his
                    dependants (if any) who were brought to the place at which the contract was
                    being performed by or on behalf of the employer shall, if they so request within
                    3 months after the death of the employee, be repatriated at the employer’s
                    expense (which shall include travelling and subsistence expenses referred to in
                    paragraph (k)) to the employee’s place of engagement or, at their request, to
                    the employee’s place of origin if such place is nearer to the place at which the
                    contract was being performed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047288_006" name="m" temporalId="s5_2_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>a stipulation that the employer shall provide free of charge facilities for
                    the employee to make remittances to his family or dependants in Hong
                        Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 15</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047288_014" name="n" temporalId="s5_2_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><leadIn>an undertaking that, on the expiry of the contract, the employee will not be
                    required to begin the employment stipulated in any re-engagement contract
                    if—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414047288_022" name="i" temporalId="s5_2_n_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>on the expiry of the contract, he has been separated from all his
                        dependants for more than 18 months; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414047288_030" name="ii" temporalId="s5_2_n_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the period served under such contract together with the duration
                        stipulated in the re-engagement contract will involve the separation of the
                        employee from all his dependants for more than 18 months,</content></subparagraph><continued>until he has had the opportunity of returning, at the employer’s expense,
                    to the place stipulated in the contract as his home, being the place at which
                    his dependants or the majority of his dependants are at the date when he entered
                    into the contract or such other place as the Commissioner in the special
                    circumstances of the case may approve;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047304_005" name="o" temporalId="s5_2_o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content>any other special conditions of the contract.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563269_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Presentation of contract for attestation</heading><content>Every contract to which this Ordinance applies shall be presented to the Commissioner for attestation before the departure of the employee from Hong Kong.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 ss. 8</ref> &amp; 15; <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563284_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Effect of non-compliance with <ref>section 5</ref> or <ref>6</ref></heading><leadIn>Where a contract to which this Ordinance applies—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047475_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is not in writing in accordance with <ref>section 5(1)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047475_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has not been presented to the Commissioner for attestation before the departure of the employee from Hong Kong,</content></paragraph><continued>it shall not be enforceable against the employee and no action shall be maintainable against the employee for breach or non-fulfilment thereof, and, where the omission to make the contract in writing or to present the contract for attestation, as the case may be, is due to wilful omission or neglect on the part of the employer or any person acting on the employer’s behalf, the employee may, without prejudice to any right he may have to sue for damages for breach of contract, sue the employer or such person for any expenses reasonably incurred by him in the return of himself and any dependants accompanying him to Hong Kong.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 ss. 9</ref> &amp; 15; <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563284_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Power to require bond or guarantee for due performance of contract</heading><leadIn>The Commissioner may require, as a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>condition precedent to the attestation of any contract to which this Ordinance applies, that a person approved by him and permanently resident in Hong Kong shall—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 ss. 10</ref> &amp; 15)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047522_012" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>furnish a bond in such sum and in such form as he may require, with or without sureties; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047522_020" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>sign a guarantee in such form as he may require,</content></paragraph><continued>generally for the performance of the contract by the employer, and, in particular, for performance by the employer of his undertaking respecting repatriation of the employee and his dependants (if any) contained in the contract pursuant to paragraph (k) or (l), as the case may be, and, as regards provision of travel documents, pursuant to paragraph (j), of <ref>section 5(2)</ref>, whether, as regards any such undertaking, the contract is or may be or becomes void or unenforceable for any reason.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563284_005" name="s9" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1981/31">31 of 1981 s. 65</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563300_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Medical examination prior to attestation</heading><content>Every employee who enters into a contract to which this Ordinance applies shall, at the expense of the employer or other person acting on the employer’s behalf, be medically examined prior to the attestation of the contract as to his fitness to perform the work contemplated by the contract.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 11</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563300_004" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Attestation of contracts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414047600_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Before attesting any contract pursuant to <ref>section 6</ref>, the Commissioner
                shall satisfy himself that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047600_019" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the employee has freely consented to the contract and that the consent has
                    not been obtained by or as a result of any threat, intimidation, bribery,
                    deceit, undue influence, misrepresentation or mistake;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047600_027" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the employee has fully understood the terms of the contract;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047600_035" name="c" temporalId="s11_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the contract is in accordance with the requirements of this
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047600_043" name="d" temporalId="s11_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in relation to the employee, there has been no contravention of any of the
                    provisions of <ref>section 51</ref> of the Employment Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap57">Cap. 57</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1968/38">38 of 1968 s.
                            37</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047616_006" name="e" temporalId="s11_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the provisions relating to medical examination set out in <ref>section
                        10</ref> have been complied with and the employee is in a fit condition to
                    perform the contract;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047616_014" name="f" temporalId="s11_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>any bond or guarantee required to be furnished has been furnished in
                    accordance with <ref>section
                    8</ref>;
                    and <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2024/21">21 of 2024 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047616_022" name="g" temporalId="s11_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the employee has declared himself not bound by a previous
                    engagement.
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2024/21">21 of 2024 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047616_030" name="h" temporalId="s11_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="hk/2024/21">21 of 2024 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414047631_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Commissioner may refuse to attest any such contract—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047631_013" name="a" temporalId="s11_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if he is not satisfied in regard to any of the matters specified in
                    subsection (1); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047631_021" name="b" temporalId="s11_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if he is satisfied that the terms thereof are unfair to the employee or do
                    not adequately protect the employee’s interest,</content></paragraph><continued>and any contract which the Commissioner has refused to attest, being a
                contract required to be presented to him for attestation pursuant to <ref>section
                    6</ref>, shall have no further validity.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/39">39 of 1971 s.
                    5</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414047631_034" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where the Commissioner attests any such contract, he shall attest not less than
                2 copies in addition to the original and shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047631_042" name="a" temporalId="s11_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>deliver one copy to the employee; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047647_006" name="b" temporalId="s11_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>retain one copy in safe custody for a period of not less than 6
                    years.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563316_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Capacity to enter into contract</heading><leadIn>A person shall not be capable of entering into a contract to which this Ordinance
            applies if he is less than either of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047694_019" name="a" temporalId="s12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>18 years of age; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047694_027" name="b" temporalId="s12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the minimum age of capacity for entering into such a contract allowed by the
                law of the place in which the contract is to be performed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 12</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563316_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Maximum duration of contract</heading><leadIn>The maximum duration which may be stipulated in any contract to which this Ordinance
            applies shall in no case exceed—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of
                    1985 s. 13</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047741_019" name="a" temporalId="s13_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>2 years if the employee is not accompanied by any dependants, or 3 years if the
                employee is accompanied by a dependant or dependants; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
                    11</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047741_027" name="b" temporalId="s13_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the maximum period prescribed by the law of the place in which the contract is
                to be performed,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the less.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403563331_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Offence where contract not attested etc. before departure of employee</heading><leadIn>Subject to <ref>section 16</ref>, where a contract to which this Ordinance
            applies—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047772_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is not in writing; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047772_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is not attested by the Commissioner under <ref>section 11</ref> before the
                departure of the employee from Hong Kong to take up employment under the contract,
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s.
                12</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>the employer and, if the contract has been entered into by another person acting
            on the employer’s behalf, that person, commits an offence and is liable to a fine
            at
            level 5.</continued><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s.
            14</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563331_004" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Counselling etc., persons to evade Ordinance</heading><leadIn>Subject to <ref>section 16</ref>, any person who counsels, solicits, procures or
            induces any other person in Hong Kong—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414047803_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to enter into a contract to which this Ordinance applies other than a contract
                which complies with <ref>section 5</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414047803_020" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to depart from Hong Kong to take up employment under a contract to which this
                Ordinance applies before the contract is attested by the Commissioner under
                    <ref>section 11</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable to a fine
            at
            level 5.</continued><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s.
            14</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563347_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Defence</heading><text>A defendant shall not be convicted of an offence under <ref>section 14</ref> or
                <ref>15</ref> in relation to a person migrating for employment if he satisfies the
            magistrate that at the time the offence is alleged to have been committed he believed on
            reasonable grounds that in relation to the person migrating admission to the place of
            immigration would be granted on a permanent basis.</text><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 14</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 13</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563347_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Applications to contracts of re-engagement</heading><content>For the avoidance of doubt, this Ordinance, save where the context otherwise requires, applies to contracts of re-engagement as it applies to contracts of engagement in the first instance. </content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1985/48">48 of 1985 s. 14</ref>) </sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403563362_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-21" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Limitation on commencement of proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414047897_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An information or complaint relating to an offence under this Ordinance may be
                tried if it is laid or made, as the case may be, at any time within 1 year after the
                commission of the offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414047897_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section shall not apply in relation to an offence committed before the
                commencement*
                of the Contracts for Employment Outside Hong Kong (Amendment) Ordinance 1992 (<ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1992/33">33 of 1992 s. 14</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1634005630120_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 May
                1992.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part></main></ordinance>