<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 256</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>256</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap256!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-08-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402904265_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2023-01-20">
            <content>To give effect to voluntary transactions affecting land during the Japanese
                occupation.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[16 July 1948]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402904265_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Land Transactions (Enemy Occupation) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402904280_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Assignor,Assignee"><term>assignor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">轉讓人</term>) and
                <term>assignee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">承讓人</term>) mean respectively the persons purporting to
            dispose of or acquire the property to which an instrument relates and include the
            executors, administrators or assigns of an assignor or assignee, as the case may be, and
            in the case of an assignor or assignee who disposed of or acquired any property as
            trustees of any trust, the persons from time to time lawfully acting as trustees of such
            trust;</def><def name="GreenInkEntries"><term>green
                ink
            entries</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">綠墨記項</term>) means the entries made in green ink in the
            Land Registry registers recording particulars of transactions registered in the Japanese
            registers and identified in the Land Registry registers by the initials of the Land
                Registrar;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 ss.
                    2 &amp;
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="JapaneseAssignment"><term>Japanese
                assignment</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">日佔期轉讓契</term>) means an instrument registered or
            recorded in the Japanese registers purporting to relate to a disposition of any land,
            house or building otherwise than by way of mortgage or reassignment;</def><def name="JapaneseHouseRegistrationOffice"><term>Japanese
                house registration
            office</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">日本房屋登錄所</term>) means the office in which during the
            Japanese occupation were kept registers or records of houses and buildings and documents
            in relation thereto;</def><def name="JapaneseOccupation"><term>Japanese
                occupation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">日佔時期</term>) means the period from 25 December 1941, to
            1 September 1945;</def><def name="JapaneseRegisters"><term>Japanese
                registers</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">日佔期註冊紀錄冊</term>) means the registers kept by the
            Japanese house registration office and now lodged in the Land Registry in which were
            recorded particulars of houses and buildings and transactions in
            connexion
                therewith;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="LandRegistryRegisters"><term>Land
                Registry
            registers</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地註冊處註冊紀錄冊</term>) means the volumes kept in the Land
            Registry,
            wherein are entered, under headings descriptive of the properties to which the same
            relate, particulars of transactions and matters affecting leased Government
                lands.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                105</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 85</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section><section id="ID_1438402904296_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Legalization of green ink entries and their effect as notice</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411693442_039" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The green ink entries shall be deemed to have been lawfully made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693442_047" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 4</ref> of the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>), a green ink entry, including any variation or addition made by virtue of this Ordinance, shall, save in so far as any such entry, variation or addition is lawfully deleted, constitute actual notice of the transaction particulars of which are recorded by the entry.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1956/25">25 of 1956 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904327_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Construction of instrument registered in Japanese registers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411693488_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A Japanese assignment shall be construed and take effect as a valid and subsisting agreement by the assignor to assign on demand without further consideration and (save in so far as such agreement or other instrument otherwise provides) at the cost of the assignee or other person lawfully requiring the same the property to which such assignment relates in the form which would have been directed by the court prior to the Japanese occupation in a successful action for the specific performance of such an agreement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693504_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (1) unless the Japanese assignment otherwise provides or the context thereof or the true intention of the parties otherwise requires, a reference to a house or building in such an assignment shall be deemed to include the land enjoyed with such house or building at the date of the execution of such assignment, together with all rights, members, easements or appurtenances belonging or appertaining to such land, house or building.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904327_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Provision in case of successive transactions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411693535_002" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any property, or part thereof, has during the Japanese occupation been the subject matter of successive Japanese assignments, then, the assignee under the last of such assignments may at his own expense require the assignor on the last and any prior assignment to confirm unto the assignee under the last of such assignments, or as he may direct, the property or part thereof, as the case may be, the subject matter of the last of such assignments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693535_010" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any property was assigned by way of mortgage before the Japanese occupation and the mortgage debt has been validly discharged, then if the property has been the subject matter of a Japanese assignment or of successive Japanese assignments, the assignee under such assignment or the last of such successive assignments, as the case may be, may require the mortgagee at the expense of such assignee to reassign the property to him or as he may direct.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693551_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any requirement lawfully made under this section may be enforced by action commenced by writ of summons in the original jurisdiction of the court in like manner as if the liability to comply therewith had been included in a contract relating to the property in respect of which such requirement had lawfully been made under this section.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904343_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Proceedings in relation to disputes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411693582_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If proceedings have been commenced in the original jurisdiction in relation to
                any dispute or difference between any persons as to the construction or effect of
                any instrument registered or recorded in the Japanese registers, or as to the
                liability of any person to assign or reassign or confirm the assignment of any
                property to which any such instrument purports or is alleged to relate, or as to the
                form or content of any assignment, reassignment or deed of confirmation to be
                executed or made by any such person, or as to any other matter or thing arising out
                of any such instrument or out of the provisions of this Ordinance, the court may, on
                the application of any party to such dispute or difference—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411693582_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with the written consent of all the parties to such dispute or difference;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693582_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if no defendant to such proceedings has entered an appearance therein;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693582_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the court is of the opinion that the action may more conveniently or
                    expeditiously be tried in the District Court,</content></paragraph><continued>at any stage of the proceedings order that the entry of such action in the
                original jurisdiction register be transferred to the Register of Civil Actions,
                District Court, and thereupon the District Court, shall have and may exercise the
                like jurisdiction both at law and in equity in relation to the said dispute or
                difference as might have been exercised by the court in its original
                jurisdiction.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693598_004" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In the event of a person who seeks redress under this section being unable to
                issue a writ because he is unable to ascertain any person who may properly be joined
                as a defendant he may apply to the court by petition without preliminary service and
                if it appears to the court by evidence upon affidavit that all reasonable inquiries
                have been made and that the case is one to which this subsection applies then the
                case shall proceed on petition and—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411693598_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>unless the court otherwise directs it shall not be necessary to serve the
                    proceedings upon any person or to have recourse to any form of substituted
                    service;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693598_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Order 9, <ref>rule 2</ref> of the Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub.
                        leg.
                        A</ref>) shall apply;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                            2</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/er6">E.R. 6 of
                        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693598_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the court shall give all necessary and consequential directions.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693613_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In dealing with any proceedings under this section the court shall have power
                to order that the Registrar should execute in lieu of any defendant, including a
                defendant who cannot be ascertained within the meaning of subsection (2), any deed
                which such defendant could be required to execute under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693613_013" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Every judgment of the court in an action relating to any such dispute or
                difference shall be reduced into writing and shall forthwith be registered in the
                Land Registry by the successful party in such action.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402904358_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Deletion, etc., of green ink entries by Land Registrar</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411693644_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Land Registrar may, and shall be deemed always to have had power to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411693644_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>delete any green ink entry which he is satisfied should not have been made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693644_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>make any green ink entry which he is satisfied should have been made; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693644_028" name="c" temporalId="s7_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>vary or add to any such entry when he is satisfied that such variation or addition is necessary,</content></paragraph><continued>and any such deletion, variation or addition shall be attested and verified by the signature of the Land Registrar.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693644_041" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Land Registrar shall delete any green ink entry recording or evidencing the purported discharge of a debt which by reason of the Debtor and Creditor (Occupation Period) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/1948/24">24 of 1948</ref>), is deemed to have been wholly or partly undischarged or any green ink entry depending for its validity on the valid discharge of such a debt.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693660_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person aggrieved on the ground that a green ink entry should not have been made or is incorrect or on the ground that the appropriate green ink entry has not been made or is no longer subsisting may apply for redress to the court by summary petition verified upon oath and the court may thereupon take such evidence as it thinks fit, and may make any order in relation to the matter which the justice of the case requires. A copy of every such petition shall be delivered to the Land Registrar as soon as may be after the issue thereof.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904358_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Saving</heading><leadIn>Notwithstanding anything hereinbefore contained, in any action for specific performance founded on this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411693691_062" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it shall be a valid defence for a person who has been required to assign or confirm in accordance with the provisions hereof, to show that the Japanese assignment in respect of which such assignment or confirmation was required is void or voidable at his instance or would have been void or voidable at his instance but for the enactment of this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693707_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a defendant shall be entitled to rely upon any defence not inconsistent with this Ordinance upon which he would have been entitled to rely had this Ordinance not been passed.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402904374_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411693722_026" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Justice may make general rules and orders subject to the approval of
                the Legislative Council, for regulating—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411693722_034" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the practice and procedure of the court in respect of proceedings of any
                    kind under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693738_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the forms to be used;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693738_014" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>court fees, the fees of counsel and the costs of solicitors;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411693738_022" name="d" temporalId="s9_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>generally, for the better carrying out of the provisions of this Ordinance
                    relating to legal proceedings and relating to the carrying out of the orders and
                    directions of the High Court.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411693738_029" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Until such rules and orders are made and in so far as the same may make no
                provision the rules and orders, practice and procedure, forms and fees for the time
                being in force in the High Court in its original jurisdiction or in the District
                Court, as the case may be, shall be deemed to be in force with such modifications as
                the circumstances may require.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402904389_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-01-20" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Provision for certain instruments not registered in the Japanese house registration
            office</heading><text>Whenever, by reason of the regulations, practice or procedure applicable to the
            Japanese house registration office, or by reason of the absence of parties, or for any
            other reason which the court shall deem sufficient, a conveyance, assignment or other
            disposition of any land house or building, executed during the Japanese occupation
            otherwise than by way of mortgage or re-assignment, was not registered at the Japanese
            house registration office and such conveyance, assignment or other disposition was, by
            reason of not being under seal, or owing to the parcels being incorrectly described, or
            through any defect in form or otherwise, inoperative according to the law in force in
            Hong Kong immediately prior to the Japanese occupation to carry out the true intention
            of the parties, then the provisions of <ref>sections 4</ref>, <ref>5</ref>,
            <ref>6</ref>, <ref>8</ref> and <ref>9</ref> shall apply to such conveyance, assignment
            or disposition in like manner as if it had been a Japanese assignment within the meaning
            of this Ordinance.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>