<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 10 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>10A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap10A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-01-16</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402570159_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-01-16">Non-Contentious
            Probate
            Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap10/s72">Cap. 10, section
                72</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[7 October 1971]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402570174_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These rules may be cited as the Non-Contentious Probate Rules.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570174_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880743_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Interpretation and General Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap.
                    1</ref>) shall apply to the interpretation of these rules as it applies to the
                interpretation of an Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880743_019" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In these rules, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AuthorizedOfficer"><term>authorized
                    officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">獲授權人員</term>) means any person who is for the time
                being authorized by the Chief Justice to administer any oath or to take any
                affidavit required for any purpose connected with his duties;</def><def name="GrossValue"><term>gross
                    value</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總值</term>) in relation to any estate means the
                value of the estate without deduction for debts, incumbrances, funeral expenses, or
                estate duty (if any);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/21">21 of 2005 s. 32</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Oath"><term>oath</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">誓言</term>) means the oath required by <ref>rule
                    6</ref> to be sworn by every applicant for a grant;</def><def name="PersonalApplicant,PersonalApplication"><term>personal
                    applicant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">個人申請人</term>) means a person other than a trust
                corporation who seeks to obtain a grant without employing a solicitor, and
                    <term>personal
                    application</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">個人申請</term>) has a corresponding meaning;</def><def name="SpecifiedForm"><term>specified
                    form</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明表格</term>) means a form specified by the
                Registrar under <ref>rule 2A(1)</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of
                    1992</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TheOrdinance"><term>the Ordinance</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">本條例</term>) means the Probate and Administration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap10">Cap. 10</ref>);</def><def name="UnionOfConcubinage"><term>union
                    of
                concubinage</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">夫妾關係</term>) shall have the same meaning ascribed
                to it as is contained in the Intestates’ Estates Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap73">Cap. 73</ref>);</def><def name="Will"><term>will</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">遺囑</term>) includes a nuncupative will or a will
                which is valid according to the provisions contained in the Wills Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap30">Cap. 30</ref>) and any testamentary document or copy or
                reconstruction thereof.</def><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880758_032" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570190_002" name="s2A" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2A"><num value="2A">2A.</num><heading>Forms</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880789_004" name="1" temporalId="s2A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar may by general notice published in the Gazette specify the forms for use in connection with these rules.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880789_012" name="2" temporalId="s2A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The specified form shall be adhered to with such variations or additions as circumstances may require.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570206_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Applications for grants through solicitors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880805_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person applying for a grant through a solicitor may apply at the Registry.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880805_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every solicitor through whom an application for a grant is made shall give the address of his place of business within the jurisdiction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880805_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No application for a grant shall be made by post.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln266">L.N. 266 of 1983</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570221_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Personal applications</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880821_034" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A personal applicant may apply for a grant at the Registry.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880821_042" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A personal applicant may not apply through an agent, whether paid or unpaid, and may not be attended by any person acting or appearing to act as his adviser.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880821_050" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>No personal application shall be received or proceeded with if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410880821_058" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it becomes necessary to bring the matter before the court on motion or by action;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410880821_066" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an application has already been made by a solicitor on behalf of the applicant and has not been withdrawn;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410880836_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Registrar otherwise directs.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880836_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>After a will has been deposited in the Registry by a personal applicant, it may not be delivered to the applicant or to any other person unless in special circumstances the Registrar so directs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880836_021" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A personal applicant shall produce a certificate of the death of the deceased or such other evidence of the death as the Registrar may approve.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880836_029" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A personal applicant may prepare the papers leading to the grant himself and lodge them in the Registry unsworn, or if the Registrar so directs shall supply all information necessary to enable such papers to be prepared in the Registry.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880836_037" name="7" temporalId="s4_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Unless the Registrar otherwise directs, every oath, affidavit or guarantee required on a personal application shall be sworn or executed by all the deponents or obligors before an authorized officer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880836_045" name="8" temporalId="s4_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>No legal advice shall be given to a personal applicant by any person in the Registry and every such person shall be responsible only for embodying in proper form the applicant’s instructions for a grant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880852_005" name="9" temporalId="s4_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>No application for a grant shall be made by post.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880852_013" name="10" temporalId="s4_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Where the gross amount of an estate does not exceed $150,000 a personal applicant may make an informal application to the official administrator requesting him to administer the estate informally.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln358">L.N. 358 of 1983</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln125">L.N. 125 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570221_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Duty of Registrar on receiving application for grant</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880883_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar shall not allow any grant to issue until all inquiries which he may see fit to make have been answered to his satisfaction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880883_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Registrar may require proof of the identity of the deceased or of the applicant for the grant beyond that contained in the oath.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880883_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Except with the leave of the Registrar, no grant of probate or of administration with the will annexed shall issue within 7 days of the death of the deceased and no grant of administration shall issue within 14 days thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880883_028" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Registrar shall not require a guarantee under <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance as a condition of granting administration to any person, without giving that person or, where the application for the grant, is made through a solicitor, the solicitor an opportunity of being heard with respect to the requirement.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570252_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Oath in support of grant</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880914_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every application for a grant shall be supported by an oath in the specified form applicable to the circumstances of the case, which shall be contained in an affidavit sworn by the applicant, and by such other papers as the Registrar may require.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880914_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On an application for a grant of administration the oath shall state whether, and if so, in what manner, persons having a prior right to a grant in accordance with the provisions contained in <ref>rule 21</ref> have been cleared off, and whether any minority or life interest arises under the will or intestacy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880914_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the deceased died domiciled outside Hong Kong, the oath shall state where the deceased died domiciled.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880914_028" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If the oath states where the deceased died domiciled (whether in or outside Hong Kong) a statement as to the country in which he died domiciled may be included in the grant.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570268_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Grant in additional name</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880945_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (2), where it is necessary to describe the deceased in a grant by some name in addition to his true name, the applicant shall state in the oath the true name of the deceased and shall depose that some part of the estate, specifying it, was held in the other name, or as to any other reason that there may be for the inclusion of the other name in the grant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880945_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the name of the deceased is in accordance with the International Code for Chinese names this name shall be accepted as being the correct name of the deceased.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570268_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Marking of wills</heading><leadIn>Every will in respect of which an application for a grant is made shall be marked by
            the signatures of the applicant and the person before whom the oath is sworn, and shall
            be exhibited to any affidavit which may be required under these rules as to the
            validity, terms, condition or date of execution of the will:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s8_proviso">
            <content>Provided that where the Registrar is satisfied that compliance with this rule
                might result in the loss of the will, he may allow a photographic copy thereof to be
                marked or exhibited in lieu of the original document:</content>
        </proviso><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s8_proviso-1">Provided also that if a will is not in the
            English or Chinese language a translation into one of those languages certified to the
            satisfaction of the Registrar shall also be filed with the original will.</proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/67">67 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570284_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Engrossments for purposes of record</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410880992_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the Registrar considers that in any particular case a photographic copy of the original will would not be satisfactory for purposes of record, he may require an engrossment suitable for photographic reproduction to be lodged.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880992_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a will contains alterations which are not admissible to proof, there shall be lodged an engrossment of the will in the form in which it is to be proved.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880992_020" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any engrossment lodged under this rule shall reproduce the punctuation, spacing and division into paragraphs of the will and, if it is one to which paragraph (2) of this rule applies, it shall be made bookwise on durable paper following continuously from page to page on both sides of the paper.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410880992_028" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where any pencil writing appears on a will, there shall be lodged a copy of the will or of the pages or sheets containing the pencil writing, in which there shall be underlined in red ink those portions which appear in pencil in the original.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570299_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Evidence as to due execution of will</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881023_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Where a will contains no attestation clause or the attestation clause is insufficient or where it appears to the Registrar that there is some doubt about the due execution of the will, he shall, before admitting it to proof, require an affidavit as to due execution from one or more of the attesting witnesses or, if no attesting witness is conveniently available, from any other person who was present at the time the will was executed:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s10_1_proviso">Provided always that if a will is in Chinese characters and appears to be satisfactorily executed by the testator the Registrar may assume without further inquiry that the will has been properly executed.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881023_018" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If no affidavit can be obtained in accordance with the last foregoing paragraph, the Registrar may, if he thinks fit having regard to the desirability of protecting the interests of any person who may be prejudiced by the will, accept evidence on affidavit from any person he may think fit to show that the signature on the will is in the handwriting of the deceased, or of any other matter which may raise a presumption in favour of the due execution of the will.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881039_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If the Registrar, after considering the evidence—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881039_013" name="a" temporalId="s10_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is satisfied that the will was not duly executed, he shall refuse probate and shall mark the will accordingly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881039_021" name="b" temporalId="s10_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is doubtful whether the will was duly executed, he may require the matter to be referred to the court on motion.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570299_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Execution of will of blind or illiterate testator</heading><content>Before admitting to proof a will in the English or Chinese language which appears to have been signed by a blind or illiterate testator or a testator not having a literate knowledge of that language or by another person by direction of the testator, or which for any other reason gives rise to doubt as to the testator having had knowledge of the contents of the will at the time of its execution, the Registrar shall satisfy himself that the testator had such knowledge.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/67">67 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570315_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Evidence as to terms, condition and date of execution of will</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881070_018" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Where there appears in a will any obliteration, interlineation, or other alteration which is not authenticated in the manner prescribed by the Wills Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap30">Cap. 30</ref>) or by the reexecution of the will or by the execution of a codicil, the Registrar shall require evidence to show whether the alteration was present at the time the will was executed and shall give directions as to the form in which the will is to be proved:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s12_1_proviso">Provided that this paragraph shall not apply to any alteration which appears to the Registrar to be of no practical importance.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881070_032" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If from any mark on a will it appears to the Registrar that some other document has been attached to the will, or if a will contains any reference to another document in such terms as to suggest that it ought to be incorporated in the will, the Registrar may require the document to be produced and may call for such evidence in regard to the attaching or incorporation of the document as he may think fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881086_005" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where there is doubt as to the date on which a will was executed, the Registrar may require such evidence as he thinks necessary to establish the date.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570330_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Attempted revocation of will</heading><content>Any appearance of attempted revocation of a will by burning, tearing, or otherwise, and every other circumstance leading to a presumption of revocation by the testator, shall be accounted for to the Registrar’s satisfaction.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570330_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Affidavit as to due execution, terms, etc. of will</heading><content>The Registrar may require an affidavit from any person he may think fit for the purpose of satisfying himself as to any of the matters referred to in <ref>rules 11</ref>, <ref>12</ref> and <ref>13</ref>, and in any such affidavit sworn by an attesting witness or other person present at the time of the execution of a will the deponent shall depose to the manner in which the will was executed.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570346_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Wills of persons on military service and seamen</heading><content>If it appears to the Registrar that there is prima facie evidence that a will is one to which <ref>section 6</ref> of the Wills Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap30">Cap. 30</ref>), as amended by any subsequent enactment, applies, the will may be admitted to proof if the Registrar is satisfied that it was signed by the testator or, if unsigned, that it is in the testator’s handwriting.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570346_004" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Evidence of foreign law</heading><text>Where evidence of the law of a country or place outside Hong Kong is required on any
            application for a grant the affidavit of any person who is an expert of the law of that
            country or place may be accepted by the Registrar.</text><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/23">23 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570377_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Order of priority for grant where deceased left a will</heading><leadIn>The person or persons entitled to a grant of probate or administration with the will annexed shall be determined in accordance with the following order of priority, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881164_012" name="i" temporalId="s19_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the executor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881164_020" name="ii" temporalId="s19_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any residuary legatee or devisee holding in trust for any other person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881164_028" name="iii" temporalId="s19_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>any residuary legatee or devisee for life;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881164_036" name="iv" temporalId="s19_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content><leadIn>the ultimate residuary legatee or devisee or, where the residue is not wholly disposed of by the will, any person entitled to share in the residue not so disposed of (including the Official Administrator) or, subject to <ref>rule 25(3)</ref>, the personal representative of any such person:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s19_iv_proviso">Provided that where the residue is not in terms wholly disposed of, the Registrar may, if he is satisfied that the testator has nevertheless disposed of the whole or substantially the whole of the estate as ascertained at the time of the application for the grant, allow a grant to be made (subject however to <ref>rule 37</ref>) to any legatee or devisee entitled to, or to a share in, the estate so disposed of, without regard to the persons entitled to share in any residue not disposed of by the will;</proviso></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881179_005" name="v" temporalId="s19_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>any specific legatee or devisee or any creditor or, subject to <ref>rule 25(3)</ref>, the personal representative of any such person or, where the estate is not wholly disposed of by the will, any person who, notwithstanding that the amount of the estate is such that he has no immediate beneficial interest therein, may have a beneficial interest in the event of an accretion thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881179_013" name="vi" temporalId="s19_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>any legatee or devisee, whether residuary or specific, entitled on the happening of any contingency, or any person having no interest under the will of the deceased who would have been entitled to a grant if the deceased had died wholly intestate.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402570377_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Grants to attesting witnesses etc.</heading><content>Where a gift to any person fails by reason of <ref>section 10</ref> of the Wills Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap30">Cap. 30</ref>) (which provides that gifts to attesting witnesses or their spouses shall be void), such person shall not have any right to a grant as a beneficiary named in the will, without prejudice to his right to a grant in any other capacity.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570393_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Order of priority for grant in case of intestacy</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881226_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a person dies wholly intestate, the persons having a beneficial interest in the estate shall be entitled to a grant to administration in the following order of priority, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881226_012" name="i" temporalId="s21_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the surviving spouse or the surviving partner or partners to a union of concubinage entered into before 7 October 1971;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881226_020" name="ii" temporalId="s21_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the children of the deceased including any children born of a union of concubinage entered into before 7 October 1971, or the issue of any such child who has died during the lifetime of the deceased;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881226_028" name="iii" temporalId="s21_1_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the father or mother of the deceased;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881226_036" name="iv" temporalId="s21_1_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>brothers and sisters of the deceased or the issue of any deceased brother or sister of the deceased who has died during the lifetime of the deceased.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881226_043" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If no person in any of the classes mentioned in
                subparagraphs
                (ii) and (iii) of the last foregoing paragraph has survived the deceased, then, the
                following persons hereinafter described shall, if they have a beneficial interest in
                the estate, be entitled to a grant in the following order of priority,
                namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881242_005" name="i" temporalId="s21_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>grandparents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881242_013" name="ii" temporalId="s21_2_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>uncles and aunts of the deceased, or the issue of any deceased uncle or
                    aunt of the deceased who has died during the lifetime of the deceased.</content></paragraph><continued>All of the persons referred to in classes (i) and (ii) of this paragraph
                shall be entitled to a grant notwithstanding that the relationship referred to shall
                have been established by or resulted from a union of concubinage.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881242_026" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In default of any person having a beneficial interest in the estate, the Official Administrator.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881242_034" name="4" temporalId="s21_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If all persons entitled to a grant under the foregoing provisions of this rule have been cleared off, a grant may be made to a creditor of the deceased or to any person who, notwithstanding that he has no immediate beneficial interest in the estate, may have a beneficial interest in the event of an accretion thereto, or is, by virtue of <ref>section 3</ref> of the Inheritance (Provision for Family and Dependants) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap481">Cap. 481</ref>), entitled to apply to the court for an order under <ref>section 4</ref> of that Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/58">58 of 1995 s. 32</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881257_005" name="5" temporalId="s21_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content><leadIn>Subject to <ref>rule 25(3)</ref>, the personal representative of a person in any of the classes mentioned in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this rule or the personal representative of a creditor shall have the same right to a grant as the person whom he represents:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s21_5_proviso">Provided that the persons mentioned in paragraph (1) and in paragraph (2) of this rule shall be preferred to the personal representative of a spouse who had died without taking a beneficial interest in the whole estate of the deceased as ascertained at the time of the application for the grant.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881257_019" name="6" temporalId="s21_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The provisions of the Adoption Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap290">Cap. 290</ref>) shall apply in determining the entitlement to a grant as they apply to the devolution of property on intestacy.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570408_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Right of assignee to a grant</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881289_048" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where all the persons entitled to the estate of the deceased (whether under a will or on intestacy) have assigned their whole interest in the estate to one or more persons, the assignee or assignees shall replace, in the order of priority for a grant of administration, the assignor or, if there are 2 or more assignors, the assignor with the highest priority.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881304_005" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where there are 2 or more assignees, administration may be granted with the consent of the others to any one or more (not exceeding 4) of them.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881304_013" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In any case where administration is applied for by an assignee, a copy of the instrument of assignment shall be lodged in the Registry.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570408_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Joinder of administrator</heading><content>An application to join with a person entitled to a grant of administration a person
            entitled in a lower degree shall, in default of renunciation by all persons entitled in
            priority to such last-mentioned person, be made to the Registrar and shall be supported
            by an affidavit by the person entitled by the consent of the person proposed to be
            joined as personal representative and by such other evidence as the Registrar may
            require.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570424_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Additional personal representatives</heading><content>An application under <ref>section 25(2)</ref> of the Ordinance to add a personal
            representative shall be made to the Registrar and shall be supported by an affidavit by
            the applicant by the consent of the person proposed to be added as personal
            representative and by such other evidence as the Registrar may require.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570424_004" name="s25" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Grants where two or more persons entitled in same degree</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881367_004" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A grant may be made to any person entitled thereto without notice to any other persons entitled in the same degree.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881367_012" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A dispute between persons entitled to a grant in the same degree shall be brought by summons before the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881367_020" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Unless the Registrar otherwise directs, administration shall be granted to a living person in preference to the personal representative of a deceased person who would, if living, be entitled in the same degree and to a person not under disability in preference to an infant entitled in the same degree.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881367_028" name="4" temporalId="s25_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Upon the issue of a summons under paragraph (2) of this rule the person issuing such summons shall enter a caveat.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881367_036" name="5" temporalId="s25_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If a summons is issued under paragraph (2) of this rule the Registrar shall not allow any grant to be sealed until such summons is finally disposed of.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570440_002" name="s26" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Exceptions to rules as to priority</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881398_004" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in <ref>rule 19</ref>, <ref>21</ref>, <ref>23</ref> or <ref>25</ref> shall operate to prevent a grant being made to any person to whom a grant may or may require to be made under any enactment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881398_012" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The rules mentioned in the last foregoing paragraph shall not apply where the deceased died domiciled outside Hong Kong, except in a case to which the proviso to <ref>rule 29</ref> applies.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570455_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Grants to persons having spes successionis</heading><leadIn>When the beneficial interest in the whole estate of the deceased is vested absolutely in a person who has renounced his right to a grant and has consented to administration being granted to a person or persons who would be entitled to his estate if he himself had died intestate, administration may be granted to such person or one or more (not exceeding 4) of such persons:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s27_proviso">Provided that a surviving spouse shall not be regarded as a person in whom the estate has vested absolutely unless he would be entitled to the whole of the estate, whatever its value may be.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402570471_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Grants where deceased died outside Hong Kong</heading><leadIn>Where the deceased died domiciled outside Hong Kong, the Registrar may order that a grant do issue—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881429_026" name="a" temporalId="s29_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to the person entrusted with the administration of the estate by the court having jurisdiction at the place where the deceased died domiciled;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881429_034" name="b" temporalId="s29_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to the person entitled to administer the estate by the law of the place where the deceased died domiciled;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881429_042" name="c" temporalId="s29_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if there is no such person as is mentioned in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this rule or if in the opinion of the Registrar the circumstances so require to such person as the Registrar may direct;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881429_050" name="d" temporalId="s29_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>
                <leadIn>if, by virtue of <ref>section 25</ref> of the Ordinance, a grant is required to be made to, or if the Registrar in his discretion considers that a grant should be made to, not less than two administrators, to such person as the Registrar may direct jointly with any such person as is mentioned in paragraph (a) or (b) of this rule or with any other person:</leadIn>
                
            </content></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s29_d_proviso">
            <content>Provided that without any such order—</content>
        </proviso><paragraph id="ID_1438410881445_012" name="a" temporalId="s29_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>probate of any will which is admissible to proof may be granted—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438410881445_020" name="1" temporalId="s29_a_1"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the will is in the English or Chinese language, to the executor named therein;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438410881445_028" name="2" temporalId="s29_a_2"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the will describes the duties of a named person in terms sufficient to constitute him executor according to the tenor of the will, to that person;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881445_035" name="b" temporalId="s29_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the whole of the estate in Hong Kong consists of immovable property, a grant limited thereto may be made in accordance with the law which would have been applicable if the deceased had died domiciled in Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1976/ln31">L.N. 31 of 1976</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402570471_003" name="s30" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Grants to attorneys</heading><leadIn>Where a person entitled to a grant resides outside Hong Kong, administration may be granted to his lawfully constituted attorney for his use and benefit, limited until such person shall obtain a grant or in such other way as the Registrar may direct:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s30_proviso">Provided that where the person so entitled is an executor, administration shall not be granted to his attorney without notice to the other executors, if any, unless such notice is dispensed with by the Registrar.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402570486_002" name="s31" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Grants
            on behalf of
            person under
            21</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881491_004" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a person to whom a grant would otherwise be made is under the age of 21
                years, administration for his use and benefit until he attains that age shall,
                subject to paragraphs (3) and (5) of this rule, be granted—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881491_012" name="a" temporalId="s31_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to the parents of the person jointly or to any guardian appointed by the
                    court; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881491_020" name="b" temporalId="s31_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if there is no such guardian able and willing to act and the person has
                    attained the age of 16 years, to any next of kin nominated by the person or,
                    where the person is a married woman, to any such next of kin or to her husband
                    if nominated by her.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881491_027" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any next of kin or husband nominated under
                subparagraph
                (b) of the last foregoing paragraph may represent any other person whose next of kin
                he is, being a person below the age of 16 years entitled in the same degree as the
                person who made the nomination.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881491_035" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notwithstanding anything in this rule, administration for the use and benefit
                of the person under the age of 21 years until he attains that age may be granted to
                any person assigned as guardian by order of the Registrar in default of, or jointly
                with, or to the exclusion of, any such person as is mentioned in paragraph (1) of
                this rule; and such an order may be made on application by the intended guardian,
                who shall file an affidavit in support of the application and, if required by the
                Registrar, an affidavit of fitness sworn by a responsible person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881507_005" name="4" temporalId="s31_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where by virtue of <ref>section 25</ref> of the Ordinance, a grant is required
                to be made to not less than 2 administrators and there is only one person competent
                and willing to take a grant under the foregoing provisions of this rule,
                administration may, unless the Registrar otherwise directs, be granted to such
                person jointly with any other person nominated by him as a fit and proper person to
                take the grant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881523_005" name="5" temporalId="s31_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a person under the age of 21 years who is sole executor has no interest
                in the residuary estate of the deceased, administration for the use and benefit of
                the person until he attains the age of 21 years shall, unless the Registrar
                otherwise directs, be granted to the person entitled to the residuary
                estate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881523_013" name="6" temporalId="s31_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The right to administration of a person under the age of 21 years may be
                renounced only by a person assigned as guardian under paragraph (3) of this rule and
                authorized to renounce by the Registrar.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln231">L.N. 231 of 1990</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570502_001" name="s32" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Grants
            where co-executor
            is
            a person
            under
            21</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438410881569_003" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where one of 2 or more executors is a person under the age of 21 years, probate
                may be granted to the other executor or executors not under the age of 21 years nor
                under disability, with power reserved of making the like grant to the first
                mentioned executor on his attaining the age of 21 years, and administration for the
                use and benefit of the first mentioned executor until he attains the age of 21 years
                may be granted under <ref>rule 31</ref> if and only if the executors who are not
                under the age of 21 years nor under disability renounce, or, on being cited to
                accept or refuse a grant, fail to make an effective application therefor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881585_005" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The right of an executor under the age of 21 years to be granted probate on
                attaining that age may not be renounced by any person on his behalf.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln231">L.N. 231 of 1990</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570518_001" name="s33" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Grants in case of mental or physical incapacity</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881601_019" name="1" temporalId="s33_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where the Registrar is satisfied that a person entitled to a grant is by reason of mental or physical incapacity incapable of managing his affairs administration for his use and benefit limited during his incapacity or in such other way may be granted—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881601_027" name="i" temporalId="s33_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the person incapable is entitled as executor, to the person entitled to the residuary estate of the deceased;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881601_035" name="ii" temporalId="s33_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the person incapable is entitled otherwise than as an executor, to the person who would be entitled to a grant in respect of his estate if he had died intestate.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881616_005" name="2" temporalId="s33_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No grant of administration shall be made under this rule unless all persons entitled in the same degree as the person incapable have been cleared off.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881616_013" name="3" temporalId="s33_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In the case of physical incapacity, notice of intended application under this rule shall be given to the person alleged to be incapable.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570518_003" name="s34" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Grants to trust corporations and other corporate bodies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881632_004" name="1" temporalId="s34_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Where a trust corporation applies for a grant through one of its officers such officer shall lodge a certified copy of the resolution authorizing him to make the application and shall depose in the oath that the corporation has been certified as being a trust corporation as provided by <ref>section 78</ref> of the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>) and that it has power to accept a grant:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s34_1_proviso">Provided that it shall not be necessary to lodge a certified copy of the resolution where the trust corporation is represented by a person holding an official position if the person through whom the application is made is included in a list filed with the Registrar of persons authorized to make such applications.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881632_018" name="2" temporalId="s34_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a trust corporation applies for a grant of administration otherwise than as attorney for some person, there shall be lodged with the application the consents of all persons entitled to a grant and of all persons interested in the residuary estate of the deceased, unless the Registrar directs that such consents be dispensed with on such terms, if any, as he may think fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881647_005" name="3" temporalId="s34_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a corporation (not being a trust corporation) would, if an individual, be entitled to a grant, administration for its use and benefit, limited until further representation is granted, may be granted to its nominees or, if the corporation has its principal place of business outside Hong Kong, its nominees or lawfully constituted attorney, and a copy of the resolution appointing the nominee or, as the case may be, the power of attorney sealed by the corporation or otherwise authenticated to the Registrar’s satisfaction, shall be lodged with the application for a grant, and the oath shall state that the corporation is not a trust corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881663_005" name="4" temporalId="s34_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a corporation (not being a trust corporation) applies for a grant the Registrar may, in his discretion, grant administration to its nominee, for its use and benefit, limited until further representation is granted, and a copy of the resolution appointing the nominee sealed by the corporation or otherwise authenticated to the Registrar’s satisfaction, shall be lodged with the application for a grant, and the oath shall state that the corporation is not a trust corporation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570533_002" name="s35" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Renunciation of probate and administration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881694_020" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Renunciation of probate by an executor shall not operate as renunciation of any right which he may have to a grant of administration in some other capacity unless he expressly renounces such right.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881710_005" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Unless the Registrar otherwise directs, no person who has renounced administration in one capacity may obtain a grant thereof in some other capacity.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570549_001" name="s37" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Notice to Government of intended application for grant</heading><text>In any case in which it appears that the Government is or may be beneficially
            interested in the estate of a deceased person, notice of intended application for a
            grant shall be given by the applicant to the Official Administrator, and the Registrar
            may direct that no grant shall issue within a specified time after the notice has been
            given.</text><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/67">67 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570549_003" name="s38" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Guarantee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881741_004" name="1" temporalId="s38_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Registrar shall not require a guarantee under <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance as a condition of granting administration except where it is proposed to grant it—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881741_012" name="a" temporalId="s38_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by virtue of <ref>rule 19(v)</ref> or <ref>rule 21(4)</ref> to a creditor or the personal representative of a creditor or to a person who has no immediate beneficial interest in the estate of the deceased but may have such an interest in the event of an accretion to the estate;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881741_020" name="b" temporalId="s38_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>under <ref>rule 27</ref> to a person or some of the persons who would, if the person beneficially entitled to the whole of the estate died intestate, be entitled to his estate;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881741_028" name="c" temporalId="s38_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>under <ref>rule
                        30</ref>
                    to the attorney of a person entitled to a grant;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881741_036" name="d" temporalId="s38_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>under <ref>rule 31</ref> for the use and benefit of a person under the age of 21 years;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln231">L.N. 231 of 1990</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881741_044" name="e" temporalId="s38_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>under <ref>rule 33</ref> for the use and benefit of a person who is by reason of mental or physical incapacity incapable of managing his affairs;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881757_006" name="f" temporalId="s38_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to an applicant who appears to the Registrar to be resident
                                        elsewhere than in Hong
                                        Kong,</content></paragraph><continued>or except where the Registrar considers that there are special circumstances making it desirable to require a guarantee.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881757_019" name="2" temporalId="s38_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding that it is proposed to grant administration as aforesaid, a guarantee shall not be required, except in special circumstances, on an application for administration where the applicant or one of the applicants is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881757_027" name="a" temporalId="s38_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a trust corporation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881757_035" name="b" temporalId="s38_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a solicitor holding a current practising certificate under the Legal Practitioners Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap159">Cap. 159</ref>).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881757_042" name="3" temporalId="s38_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Every guarantee entered into by a surety for the purposes of <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance shall be in the specified form.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881757_050" name="4" temporalId="s38_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Except where the surety is a corporation, the signature of the surety on every such guarantee shall be attested by an authorized officer, commissioner for oaths or other person authorized by law to administer an oath.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881757_058" name="5" temporalId="s38_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Unless the Registrar otherwise directs—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881757_066" name="a" temporalId="s38_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if it is decided to require a guarantee, it shall be given by two sureties, except where the gross value of the estate does not exceed $7,000 or a corporation is a proposed surety, and in those cases one will suffice;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881772_006" name="b" temporalId="s38_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>no person shall be accepted as a surety unless he is resident in Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881772_014" name="c" temporalId="s38_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>no officer of the Registry shall become a surety;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881772_022" name="d" temporalId="s38_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the limit of the liability of the surety or sureties under a guarantee given for the purposes of <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance shall be the gross amount of the estate as sworn on the application for the grant;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881772_030" name="e" temporalId="s38_5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>every surety, other than a corporation shall justify.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881772_037" name="6" temporalId="s38_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content><leadIn>Where the proposed surety is a corporation there shall be filed an affidavit by the proper officer of the corporation to the effect that it has power to act as surety and has executed the guarantee in the manner prescribed by its constitution, and containing sufficient information as to the financial position of the corporation to satisfy the Registrar that its assets are sufficient to satisfy all claims which may be made against it under any guarantee which it has given or is likely to give for the purposes of <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s38_6_proviso">Provided that the Registrar may, instead of requiring an affidavit in every case, accept an affidavit made not less often than once in every year together with an undertaking by the corporation to notify the Registrar forthwith in the event of any alteration in its constitution affecting its power to become surety under that subsection.</proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570564_002" name="s41" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s41"><num value="41">41.</num><heading>Sureties on resealing</heading><leadIn>On an application for the resealing of a grant of administration under Part IV of the Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881819_019" name="a" temporalId="s41_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Registrar shall not require sureties under <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance as a condition of sealing the grant except where it appears to him that the grant is made to a person or for a purpose mentioned in paragraphs (a) to (f) of <ref>rule 38(1)</ref> or except where he considers that there are special circumstances making it desirable to require sureties;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881835_006" name="b" temporalId="s41_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><ref>rules 5(4)</ref> and <ref>38(2)</ref>, (4), (5) and (6) shall apply with any necessary modifications; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881835_014" name="c" temporalId="s41_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a guarantee entered into by a surety for the purposes of the said <ref>section 46</ref> shall be in the specified form.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402570580_002" name="s41A" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s41A"><num value="41A">41A.</num><heading>Application for leave to sue on guarantee</heading><content>An application for leave under <ref>section 47(2)</ref> of the Ordinance to sue a surety on a guarantee given for the purposes of <ref>section 46</ref> of the Ordinance shall, unless the Registrar otherwise directs under <ref>rule 60</ref>, be made by summons to the Registrar, and notice of the application shall in any event be served on the administrator, the surety and any co-surety.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570596_001" name="s43" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s43"><num value="43">43.</num><heading>Application for grant to be supported by documents required under the Estate Duty Ordinance</heading><content>Where the Estate Duty Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap111">Cap. 111</ref>) applies in relation to the estate of a person, an application for the grant in respect of the estate shall be supported by such documents as may be required under that Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/21">21 of 2005 s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570611_001" name="s44" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s44"><num value="44">44.</num><heading>Caveats</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410881881_011" name="1" temporalId="s44_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who wishes to ensure that no grant is sealed without notice to
                himself may enter a caveat in the Registry.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881881_019" name="2" temporalId="s44_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who wishes to enter a caveat (in this rule called
                        <b><i>the
                        caveator</i></b>)
                may do so by completing an appropriate specified form in the appropriate book at the
                Registry and obtaining an acknowledgment of entry from the proper officer, or by
                sending through the post at his own risk a notice in the specified form addressed to
                the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881881_027" name="3" temporalId="s44_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the caveat is entered by a solicitor on the caveator’s behalf, the name
                of the caveator shall be stated in the form completed in accordance with paragraph
                (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881897_005" name="4" temporalId="s44_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Except as otherwise provided by this rule, a caveat shall remain in force for 6
                months from the date on which it is entered and shall then cease to have effect,
                without prejudice to the entry of a further caveat or caveats.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881897_013" name="5" temporalId="s44_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Registrar shall maintain an index of caveats entered in the Registry and on
                receiving an application for a grant, he shall cause the index to be
                searched.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881897_021" name="6" temporalId="s44_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>
                <leadIn>The Registrar shall again cause the index to be searched before he shall
                    allow any grant to be sealed and shall not allow any grant to be sealed if there
                    is an effective caveat in respect thereof:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s44_6_proviso">Provided that no caveat shall
                    operate to prevent the sealing of a grant on the day on which the caveat is
                    entered.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881897_035" name="7" temporalId="s44_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A caveat may be warned by the issue from the Registry of a warning in the
                specified form at the instance of any person interested (in this rule called
                        <b><i>the
                        person
                warning</i></b>)
                which shall state his interest and, if he claims under a will, the date of the will,
                and shall require the caveator to give particulars of any contrary interest which he
                may have in the estate of the deceased; and every warning shall be served on the
                caveator.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881913_005" name="8" temporalId="s44_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>A caveator who has not entered an appearance to a warning may at any time
                withdraw his caveat by giving notice at the Registry and the caveat shall thereupon
                cease to have effect and, if it has been warned, the caveator shall forthwith give
                notice of withdrawal of the caveat to the person warning.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881913_013" name="9" temporalId="s44_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>A caveator having an interest contrary to that of the person warning may,
                within 8 days of service of the warning upon him inclusive of the day of such
                service, or at any time thereafter if no affidavit has been filed under paragraph
                (11) of this rule, enter an appearance in the Registry by filing an appropriate
                specified form and making an entry in the appropriate book, and shall forthwith
                thereafter serve on the person warning a copy of that form sealed with the seal of
                the court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881928_005" name="10" temporalId="s44_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>A caveator having no interest contrary to that of the person warning but
                wishing to show cause against the sealing of a grant to that person may, within 8
                days of service of the warning upon him inclusive of the day of such service, or at
                any time thereafter if no affidavit has been filed under paragraph (11) of this
                rule, enter an appearance to the warning and issue and serve a summons for
                directions, which shall be returnable before the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881944_005" name="11" temporalId="s44_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>If the time limited for appearance has expired and the caveator has not entered
                an appearance, the person warning may file in the Registry an affidavit showing that
                the warning was duly served and that he has not received a summons for directions
                under the last foregoing paragraph, and thereupon the caveat shall cease to have
                    effect.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln266">L.N. 266 of 1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881944_013" name="11A" temporalId="s44_11A"><num value="11A">(11A)</num><content>Upon the commencement of a probate action the Registrar shall, in respect of
                each caveat then in force (other than a caveat entered by the plaintiff), give to
                the caveator notice of the commencement of the action and, upon the subsequent entry
                of a caveat at any time when the action is pending shall likewise notify the
                caveator of the existence of the action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881959_005" name="12" temporalId="s44_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><leadIn>Unless the Registrar otherwise directs—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410881959_013" name="a" temporalId="s44_12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any caveat in force at the commencement of proceedings by way of citation
                    or motion shall, unless withdrawn pursuant to paragraph (8) of this
                    rule,
                    remain in force until an application for a grant is made by the person shown to
                    be entitled thereto by the decision of the court in such proceedings, and upon
                    such application any caveat entered by a party who had notice of the proceedings
                    shall cease to have
                        effect;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                            2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881959_021" name="b" temporalId="s44_12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any caveat in respect of which an appearance to a warning has been entered
                    shall remain in force until the commencement of a probate action;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410881959_029" name="c" temporalId="s44_12_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the commencement of a probate action shall, whether or not any caveat has
                    been entered, operate to prevent the sealing of a grant (other than a grant
                    under <ref>section 40</ref> of the Ordinance) until application for a grant is
                    made by the person shown to be entitled thereto by the decision of the court in
                    such action, and upon such application any caveat entered by a party who had
                    notice of the action, or by a caveator who was given notice under paragraph
                    (11A) of this rule, shall cease to have effect.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881975_005" name="13" temporalId="s44_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>Except with the leave of the Registrar, no further caveat may be entered by or
                on behalf of any caveator whose caveat has ceased to have effect under paragraph
                (11) or (12) of this rule.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881975_013" name="14" temporalId="s44_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><def name="Grant">In this rule,
                    <term>grant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">授予</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">授予書</term>)
                includes a grant made by any court outside Hong Kong which is produced for resealing
                by the court.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410881991_004" name="15" temporalId="s44_15"><num value="15">(15)</num><def name="ProbateAction">In this rule,
                <term>probate
                    action</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">遺囑認證訴訟</term>) shall bear the meaning ascribed to
                it in Order 76 of the Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub.
                    leg. A</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>; <ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570658_001" name="s45" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s45"><num value="45">45.</num><heading>Citations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882037_004" name="1" temporalId="s45_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every citation shall be settled by the Registrar before being issued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882037_012" name="2" temporalId="s45_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>Every averment in a citation, and such other information as the Registrar may require, shall
                    be verified by an affidavit sworn by the person issuing the citation (in these
                    rules called
                            <b><i>the
                            citor</i></b>)
                    or, if there are two or more citors, by one of them:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s45_2_proviso">Provided that the Registrar may in special circumstances accept an affidavit sworn by the citor’s solicitor.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882037_026" name="3" temporalId="s45_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The citor shall enter a caveat before issuing a citation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882037_034" name="4" temporalId="s45_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Every citation shall be served personally on the person cited unless the Registrar, on cause shown by the affidavit, directs some other mode of service, which may include notice by advertisement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882053_005" name="5" temporalId="s45_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Every will referred to in a citation shall be lodged in the Registry before the citation is issued, except where the will is not in the citor’s possession and the Registrar is satisfied that it is impracticable to require it to be lodged.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882053_013" name="6" temporalId="s45_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A person who has been cited to appear may, within eight days of service of the citation upon him inclusive of the day of such service, or at any time thereafter if no application has been made by the citor under <ref>rule 46(5)</ref> or <ref>rule 47(2)</ref>, enter an appearance in the Registry by filing an appropriate specified form and making an entry in the appropriate book, and shall forthwith thereafter serve on the citor a copy of that form sealed with the seal of the court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570658_003" name="s46" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s46"><num value="46">46.</num><heading>Citation to accept or refuse or to take a grant</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882084_012" name="1" temporalId="s46_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A citation to accept or refuse a grant may be issued at the instance of any person who would himself be entitled to a grant in the event of the person cited renouncing his right thereto.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882084_020" name="2" temporalId="s46_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where power to make a grant to an executor has been reserved, a citation calling on him to accept or refuse a grant may be issued at the instance of the executors who have proved the will or of the executors of the last survivor of deceased executors who have proved.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882100_005" name="3" temporalId="s46_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>A citation calling on an executor who has intermeddled in the estate of the deceased to show cause why he should not be ordered to take a grant may be issued at the instance of any person interested in the estate at any time after the expiration of 6 months from the death of the deceased:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s46_3_proviso">Provided that no citation to take a grant shall issue while proceedings as to the validity of the will are pending.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882100_019" name="4" temporalId="s46_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person cited who is willing to accept or take a grant may apply ex parte to the Registrar for an order for a grant on filing an affidavit showing that he has entered an appearance and that he has not been served by the citor with notice of any application for a grant to himself.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882100_027" name="5" temporalId="s46_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>If the time limited for appearance has expired and the person cited has not entered an appearance, the citor may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410882100_035" name="a" temporalId="s46_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a citation under paragraph (1) of this rule, apply to the Registrar for an order for a grant to himself;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410882100_043" name="b" temporalId="s46_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a citation under paragraph (2) of this rule, apply to the Registrar for an order that a note be made on the grant that the executor in respect of whom power was reserved has been duly cited and has not appeared and that all his rights in respect of the executorship have wholly ceased;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410882115_006" name="c" temporalId="s46_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of a citation under paragraph (3) of this rule, apply to the Registrar by summons (which shall be served on the person cited) for an order requiring such person to take a grant within a specified time, or for a grant to himself or to some other person specified in the summons.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882115_013" name="6" temporalId="s46_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>An application under the last foregoing paragraph shall be supported by an affidavit showing that the citation was duly served and that the person cited has not entered an appearance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882115_021" name="7" temporalId="s46_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>If the person cited has entered an appearance but has not applied for a grant under paragraph (4) of this rule, or has failed to prosecute his application with reasonable diligence, the citor may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410882115_029" name="a" temporalId="s46_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a citation under paragraph (1) of this rule, apply by summons to the Registrar for an order for a grant to himself;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410882115_037" name="b" temporalId="s46_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a citation under paragraph (2) of this rule, apply by summons to the Registrar for an order striking out the appearance and for the endorsement on the grant of such a note as is mentioned in paragraph <ref>(5)(b)</ref> of this rule;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410882131_006" name="c" temporalId="s46_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of a citation under paragraph (3) of this rule, apply by summons to the Registrar for an order requiring the person cited to take a grant within a specified time, or for a grant to himself or to some other person specified in the summons,</content></paragraph><continued>and the summons shall be served on the person cited.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570674_002" name="s47" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s47"><num value="47">47.</num><heading>Citation to propound a will</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882178_004" name="1" temporalId="s47_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A citation to propound a will shall be directed to the executors named in the will and to all persons interested thereunder, and may be issued at the instance of any citor having an interest contrary to that of the executors or such other persons.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882178_012" name="2" temporalId="s47_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the time limited for appearance has expired and no person cited has entered an appearance, or if no person who has appeared proceeds with reasonable diligence to propound the will, the citor may apply on motion for an order for a grant as if the will were invalid.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570689_001" name="s48" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s48"><num value="48">48.</num><heading>Address for service</heading><content>All caveats, citations, warnings and appearances shall contain an address for service within the jurisdiction.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570689_003" name="s49" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s49"><num value="49">49.</num><heading>Application for order to bring in a will or to attend for examination</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882209_011" name="1" temporalId="s49_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An application under <ref>section 7(1)</ref> of the Ordinance for an order requiring a person to bring in a will or to attend for examination may be made to a judge by summons, which shall be served on every such person as aforesaid.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882209_019" name="2" temporalId="s49_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An application under <ref>section 7(3)</ref> of the Ordinance for the issue by the Registrar of a subpoena to bring in a will shall be supported by an affidavit setting out the grounds of the application, and if any person served with the subpoena denies that the will is in his possession or control he may file an affidavit to that effect.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570705_002" name="s51" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s51"><num value="51">51.</num><heading>Grants of administration under discretionary powers of court, and grants ad colligenda bona</heading><leadIn>An application for an order for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410882256_012" name="a" temporalId="s51_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a grant of administration under <ref>section 36</ref> of the
                Ordinance;
                    or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                        2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410882256_020" name="b" temporalId="s51_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a grant of administration ad colligenda bona,</content></paragraph><continued>may be made to the Registrar, and shall be supported by an affidavit setting out the grounds of the application.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438402570720_001" name="s52" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s52"><num value="52">52.</num><heading>Applications for leave to swear to death</heading><content>An application for leave to swear to the death of a person in whose estate a grant is sought may be made to the Registrar and shall be supported by an affidavit setting out the grounds of the application and containing particulars of any policies of insurance effected on the life of the presumed deceased.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570720_003" name="s53" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s53"><num value="53">53.</num><heading>Grants in respect of nuncupative wills and of copies of wills</heading><leadIn>An application for an order admitting to proof a nuncupative will, or a will which
            it is claimed is valid according to the provisions contained in the Wills Ordinance
                (<ref href="/hk/cap30">Cap. 30</ref>) or a will contained in a copy, a completed
            draft, a reconstruction or other evidence of its contents where the original will is not
            available, may be made to the Registrar:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s53_proviso">Provided that where a will is not available
            owing to its being retained in the custody of a court of justice outside Hong Kong or of
            an official of a government other than the Government of the Hong Kong Special
            Administrative Region, a duly authenticated copy of the will may be admitted to proof
            without any such order as aforesaid.</proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/23">23 of 1998 s.
            2</ref>; <ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570736_002" name="s54" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s54"><num value="54">54.</num><heading>Grants durante absentia</heading><content>An application for an order for a grant of special administration under <ref>section 37</ref> of the Ordinance where a personal representative is residing outside Hong Kong shall be made to the court on motion.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570736_004" name="s58" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s58"><num value="58">58.</num><heading>Issue of copies of original wills and other documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882318_004" name="1" temporalId="s58_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where copies are required of original wills or other documents deposited under <ref>section 74</ref> of the Ordinance, such copies may be photographic copies sealed with the seal of the court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882318_012" name="2" temporalId="s58_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Copies not being photographic copies, of original wills or other documents deposited under the said section shall be examined against the documents of which they purport to be copies only if so required by the person demanding the copy, and in such case the copy shall be certified under the hand of the Registrar and may in addition be sealed with the seal of the court.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570767_001" name="s59" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s59"><num value="59">59.</num><heading>Taxation of costs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882334_026" name="1" temporalId="s59_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every bill of costs (other than a bill delivered by a solicitor to his client
                which falls to be taxed under the Legal Practitioners Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap159">Cap. 159</ref>)) shall be referred to the Registrar for
                taxation and shall be taxed in accordance with the provisions contained in Order 62
                of the Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg.
                    A</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882349_005" name="2" temporalId="s59_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The fees payable on taxation shall be paid by the party on whose application
                the bill is taxed and shall be allowed as part of the bill.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570767_003" name="s60" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s60"><num value="60">60.</num><heading>Power to require application to be made by summons or motion</heading><content>The Registrar may require any application made to him to be brought before him by summons, and may require any application made to him, whether by summons or otherwise, to be brought before a judge by summons or before the court on motion.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570783_002" name="s60A" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s60A"><num value="60A">60A.</num><heading>Time limit for claims</heading><content>An executor or administrator may apply to the Registrar by ex parte summons for an order limiting the time for creditors or other persons to make claims against the estate of the testator or intestate and the Registrar shall make such order as he thinks fit specifying what notices are to be given of the making of such order and the time thereby limited and make such order thereon as he thinks proper.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570798_001" name="s62" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s62"><num value="62">62.</num><heading>Appeals from Registrar</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882396_018" name="1" temporalId="s62_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person aggrieved by a decision of the Registrar may appeal by summons to a judge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882412_005" name="2" temporalId="s62_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any person besides the appellant appeared or was represented before the Registrar from whose decision or requirement the appeal is brought, the summons shall be issued within 7 days thereof for hearing on the first available day and shall be served on every such person as aforesaid.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570798_003" name="s63" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s63"><num value="63">63.</num><heading>Service of notice of motion and summons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882427_004" name="1" temporalId="s63_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A judge or the Registrar may direct that a notice of motion or summons for the service of which no other provision is made by these rules shall be served on such person or persons as the judge or the Registrar may direct.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882427_012" name="2" temporalId="s63_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where by these rules or by any direction given under the last foregoing paragraph a notice of motion or summons is required to be served on any person, it shall be served—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410882427_020" name="a" temporalId="s63_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a notice of motion, not less than 5 clear days before the day named in the notice for hearing of the motion;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410882427_028" name="b" temporalId="s63_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a summons, not less than 2 clear days before the day appointed for the hearing, unless a judge or the Registrar at or before the hearing, dispenses with service on such terms, if any, as he may think fit.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402570830_001" name="s64" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s64"><num value="64">64.</num><heading>Notices etc.</heading><content>Unless the Registrar otherwise directs, or these rules otherwise provide, any notice or other document required to be given to or served on any person may be given or served by leaving it at, or by sending it by prepaid registered post to, that person’s address for service or, if he has no address for service, his last known address.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402570830_003" name="s65" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s65"><num value="65">65.</num><heading>Affidavits</heading><subsection id="ID_1438410882459_025" name="1" temporalId="s65_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every affidavit used in non-contentious probate business shall be in the form
                required by the Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg.
                    A</ref>) in the case of affidavits to which those rules apply.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438410882474_005" name="2" temporalId="s65_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding Order 41 <ref>rule 11</ref> of the Rules of the High Court
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg. A</ref>), a copy of a document to be
                used in conjunction with an affidavit need not, unless the Registrar otherwise
                directs, be exhibited to the affidavit if the original document is already filed in
                the Registry.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln266">L.N. 266 of 1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                2</ref>;<ref>E.R.
                1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570845_002" name="s66" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s66"><num value="66">66.</num><heading>Time</heading><text>The provisions of Order 3 and Order 65 <ref>rule 7</ref> of the Rules of the High
            Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg. A</ref>) shall apply to the computation,
            enlargement, and abridgement of time under these rules except that nothing in Order 3
            shall prevent time from running in the Long Vacation.</text><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln266">L.N. 266 of 1983</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25
                of 1998 s.
            2</ref>; <ref>E.R.
                1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402570861_001" name="s67" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2020-01-16" status="operational" temporalId="s67"><num value="67">67.</num><heading>Application to pending proceedings</heading><content>Subject in any particular case to any direction given by a judge or the Registrar, these rules shall apply to any proceeding which is pending on the date on which they come into operation as well as to any proceeding commenced on or after that date.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402570876_001" name="sch0" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1992/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></subLeg>