<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 267</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>267</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap267!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2018-12-13</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402911893_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2018-12-13">
            <content>To confer upon the consular officers of foreign States with which consular
                conventions are concluded by the Government of the People’s Republic of China
                certain powers relating to the administration of the estates and property of
                deceased persons.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[20 April 1951]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2018/er5">E.R. 5 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402911893_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Consular Conventions Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402911909_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ConsularOffice"><term>consular
                office</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">領事辦事處</term>) means any building or part of a building
            which is exclusively occupied for the purposes of the official business of a consular
            officer.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1949 c. 29 s. 4(3) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402911909_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Powers of consular officers in relation to property in Hong Kong of deceased
            persons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411708386_025" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any person who is a national of a State to which this section applies is
                named as executor in the will of a deceased person disposing of property in Hong
                Kong, or is otherwise a person to whom a grant of representation to the estate in
                Hong Kong of a deceased person may be made, then if the court is satisfied, on the
                application of a consular officer of the said State, that the said national is not
                resident in Hong Kong, and if no application for a grant of such representation is
                made by a person duly authorized by power of attorney to act for him in that behalf,
                the court shall make to that officer any such grant of representation to the estate
                of the deceased as would be made to him if he were so authorized as
                aforesaid.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411708418_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where any person who is a national of a State to which this section
                applies—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411708418_013" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is entitled to any money or other property in Hong Kong forming part of the
                    estate of a deceased person, or to receive payment in Hong Kong of any money
                    becoming due on the death of a deceased person; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411708418_021" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is among the persons to whom any money or other property of a deceased
                    person may under any Ordinance, whether passed before or after the
                        commencement<inline class="force_orig_font"><sup>*</sup></inline> of this
                    Ordinance, be paid or delivered without grant of probate or other proof of
                    title,</content></paragraph><continued>then if the said national is not resident in Hong Kong a consular officer of
                that State shall have the like right and power to receive and give a valid discharge
                for any such money or property as if he were duly authorized by power of attorney to
                act for him in that behalf:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s3_2_proviso">Provided that no person shall be
                authorized or required by this subsection to pay or deliver any money or property to
                a consular officer if it is within his knowledge that any other person in Hong Kong
                has been expressly authorized to receive that money or property on behalf of the
                said national.</proviso></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/26">26 of 1971 s. 76</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1949 c. 29 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1538713782293_001">
        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
        <content><inline class="force_orig_font"><sup>*</sup></inline> Commencement date: 20 April
            1951.</content>
    </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438402911924_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Supplementary provisions as to <ref>section 3</ref></heading><content>Notwithstanding any rule of law conferring immunity or privilege in respect of the official acts and documents of consular officers, a consular officer shall not be entitled to any immunity or privilege in respect of any act done by virtue of powers conferred on him by or under <ref>section 3</ref> or in respect of any document for the time being in his possession relating thereto.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1949 c. 29 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402911924_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-12-13" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading><ref>Section 3</ref> to apply to any foreign State by order of the Chief
            Executive</heading><text>The Chief Executive may by order signified in the Gazette direct that <ref>section
                3</ref> shall apply to any foreign State specified in the Order, being a State with
            which a consular convention providing for matters for which provision is made by that
            section has been concluded by the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1970/17">17 of 1970 s. 14</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1949 c. 29 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></section></main></ordinance>