<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 300</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>300</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap300!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-12-12</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402957648_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-12-12">
            <content>To amend the law relating to the civil liabilities and rights of the Crown and
                to civil proceedings by and against the Crown, to amend the law relating to the
                civil liabilities of persons other than the Crown in certain cases involving the
                affairs or property of the Crown, and for purposes connected with the matters
                aforesaid.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 November 1957]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1957/gna81" class="font_size_10">G.N.A. 81 of
            1957</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438402957663_001" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438402957663_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Crown Proceedings Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402957679_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411835636_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any reference in this Ordinance to the provisions of this Ordinance shall, unless the context otherwise requires, include a reference to rules of court made for the purposes of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835636_012" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, except in so far as the context otherwise requires, or it is
                otherwise expressly provided, the following expressions have the meanings hereby
                respectively assigned to them, that is to say—</leadIn><def name="Agent"><term>agent</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">代理人</term>), when used in relation to the Crown,
                includes an independent contractor employed by the Crown;</def><def name="CivilProceedings"><term>civil
                    proceedings</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">民事法律程序</term>) includes proceedings in the Supreme
                Court or the District Court for the recovery of fines or penalties, but does not
                include proceedings of a nature such as in England are taken on the Crown side of
                the Queen’s Bench Division of Her Majesty’s High Court of Justice;</def><def name="Officer"><term>officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">人員</term>), in relation to the Crown, includes any
                servant of the Crown;</def><def name="Order"><term>order</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">命令</term>) includes a judgment, decree, rule, award
                or declaration;</def><def name="Prescribed"><term>prescribed</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訂明</term>) means prescribed by rules of
                court;</def><def name="ProceedingsAgainstTheCrown"><term>proceedings
                    against the
                Crown</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">針對官方提出的法律程序</term>)
                includes a claim by way of set-off or counterclaim raised in proceedings by the
                Crown;</def><def name="RulesOfCourt"><term>rules of court</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院規則</term>) means rules made by the authority having for the time being power
                to make rules and orders regulating the practice and procedure of the Supreme Court
                or the District Court, as the case may be;</def><def name="Ship"><term>ship</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船舶</term>) includes every description of vessel
                used in navigation not propelled by oars;</def><def name="StatutoryDuty"><term>statutory
                    duty</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法定責任</term>) means any duty imposed by or under any
                Act of Parliament or Ordinance.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835651_032" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any reference in this Ordinance to Her Majesty in Her private capacity shall be construed as including a reference to Her Majesty in right of Her Duchy of Lancaster.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835651_040" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><leadIn>Any reference in Part IV or V of this Ordinance to civil proceedings by or against the
                    Crown, or to civil proceedings to which the Crown is a party, shall be construed
                    as including a reference to civil proceedings to which the Secretary for
                    Justice, or any Government department, or any officer of the Crown as such, is a
                    party:<marker role="section-break"></marker></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s2_4_proviso">Provided that the Crown shall not for the purposes of Parts IV and V of this Ordinance be deemed to be a party to any proceedings by reason only that they are brought by the Secretary for Justice upon the relation of some other person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835651_054" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>References in this Ordinance to any enactment shall be construed as references to that enactment as amended by or under any enactment, including this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 38 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438402957695_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Substantive
            Law</heading><section id="ID_1438402957695_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Right to sue the Crown</heading><content>Where any person has a claim against the Crown after the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance and, if this Ordinance had not been passed, the claim might have been
            enforced, subject to the consent of the Governor, under the rules of the Supreme Court,
            or might have been enforced by the proceedings provided by any statute ceasing to have
            effect in the Colony by virtue of this Ordinance, or by any enactment repealed by this
            Ordinance, then, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, the claim may be enforced
            as of right, and without the consent of the Governor, by proceedings taken against the
            Crown for that purpose in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147482943_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957710_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Liability of the Crown in tort</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411835729_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, the Crown shall be subject to all
                those liabilities in tort to which, if it were a private person of full age and
                capacity, it would be subject—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411835729_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in respect of torts committed by its servants or agents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411835729_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in respect of any breach of those duties which a person owes to his
                    servants or agents at common law by reason of being their employer;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411835729_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>in respect of any breach of the duties attaching at common law to the
                        ownership, occupation, possession or control of property:</leadIn>
                    
                </content></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_1_c_proviso">Provided that no proceedings shall
                lie against the Crown by virtue of paragraph (a) in respect of any act or omission
                of a servant or agent of the Crown unless the act or omission would apart from the
                provisions of this Ordinance have given rise to a cause of action in tort against
                that servant or agent or his estate.</proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835729_041" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Crown is bound by a statutory duty which is binding also upon persons other than the Crown and its officers, then, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, the Crown shall, in respect of a failure to comply with that duty, be subject to all those liabilities in tort (if any) to which it would be subject if it were a private person of full age and capacity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835745_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where any functions are conferred or imposed upon an officer of the Crown as such either by any rule of the common law or by enactment or statute, and that officer commits a tort while performing or purporting to perform those functions, the liabilities of the Crown in respect of the tort shall be such as they would have been if those functions had been conferred or imposed solely by virtue of instructions lawfully given by the Crown.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835761_005" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any enactment which negatives or limits the amount of the liability of any Government department or officer of the Crown in respect of any tort committed by that department or officer shall, in the case of proceedings against the Crown under this section in respect of a tort committed by that department or officer, apply in relation to the Crown as it would have applied in relation to that department or officer if the proceedings against the Crown had been proceedings against that department or officer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835761_013" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>No proceedings shall lie against the Crown by virtue of this section in respect
                of anything done or omitted to be done by any person while discharging or purporting
                to discharge any responsibilities of a judicial nature vested in him, or any
                responsibilities which he has in
                connexion
                with the execution of judicial process.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835776_005" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438411835776_009" name="a" temporalId="s4_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, no liability shall be imposed thereby upon the Crown in respect of any ship, dock or harbour owned by the Crown.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411835776_015" name="b" temporalId="s4_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>This subsection shall continue in force until a day to be appointed by the
                    Governor by Proclamation in the Gazette and shall then expire.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957726_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Provisions as to industrial property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411835807_020" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance any servant or agent of the Crown infringes a patent, or infringes
                a registered trade mark, or infringes any copyright, or infringes any registered
                design, and the infringement is committed with the authority of the Crown, then,
                subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, civil proceedings in respect of this
                infringement shall lie against the Crown.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835823_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in subsection (1) or in any other provision of this Ordinance shall
                affect the rights of the Crown under <ref>sections 36 to 40</ref> of the Registered
                Designs Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap522">Cap. 522</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1979/25">25 of 1979 s. 12</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/52">52 of 1997 s. 162</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835823_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Save where it is expressly provided by this section, no proceedings shall lie
                against the Crown by virtue of this Ordinance in respect of the infringement of a
                patent, in respect of the infringement of a registered trade mark, or in respect of
                the infringement of any such copyright or registered design as is mentioned in
                subsection (1) of this section.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/64">64 of 1997 s. 94</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147544457_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957726_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Application of law as to indemnity, contribution, joint and several tortfeasors, and contributory negligence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411835854_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the Crown is subject to any liability by virtue of this part of this Ordinance, the law relating to indemnity and contribution shall be enforceable by or against the Crown in respect of liability to which it is so subject as if the Crown were a private person of full age and capacity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835854_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/77">77 of 1984 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835854_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Without prejudice to the general effect of <ref>section 4</ref> of this
                Ordinance, <ref>section 21</ref> of the Law Amendment and Reform (Consolidation)
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap23">Cap. 23</ref>) (which amends the law relating to
                contributory negligence) shall bind the Crown.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957741_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Liability in
            connexion
            with postal packets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411835870_034" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject as hereinafter provided, no proceedings in tort shall lie against the
                Crown for anything done or omitted to be done in relation to a postal packet by any
                person while employed as a servant or agent of the Crown; nor shall any officer of
                the Crown be subject, except at the suit of the Crown, to any civil liability for
                any of the matters aforesaid.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835885_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 7</ref> of the Post Office
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap98">Cap. 98</ref>), proceedings shall lie against
                    the Crown under this subsection in respect of loss of or damage to a registered
                    inland postal packet in so far as the loss or damage is due to any wrongful act
                    done or any neglect or default committed by a person employed as a servant or
                    agent of the Crown while performing or purporting to perform his functions as
                    such in relation to the receipt, carriage, delivery or other dealing with the
                    packet:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_2_proviso">
                    <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438411835885_020" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>no proceedings shall lie under this subsection in respect of any
                            postal packet registered before the
                            commencement*
                            of this Ordinance;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438411835885_028" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the amount recoverable in any proceedings under this subsection
                            shall not exceed the market value of the packet in question (excluding
                            the market value of any message or information which it bears) at the
                            time when the cause of action arises;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438411835901_006" name="c" temporalId="s7_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the amount recoverable in any such proceedings shall not in any
                            event exceed the maximum amount which, under the Post Office Regulations
                                (<ref href="/hk/cap98A">Cap. 98 sub. leg. A</ref>), is available for
                            compensating the persons aggrieved having regard to the fee paid in
                            respect of the registration of the packet; and
                            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438411835901_014" name="d" temporalId="s7_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the Crown shall not be liable under this subsection in respect of
                            any packet unless such conditions as are prescribed by the Post Office
                            Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap98A">Cap. 98 sub. leg. A</ref>) in
                            relation to registered inland postal packets have been complied with in
                            relation to that packet.
                            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                </proviso>
            </content><content>
                <continued>For the purposes of any proceedings under this subsection it shall be
                    presumed, until the contrary is shown on behalf of the Crown, that the loss of
                    or damage to the packet was due to some wrongful act done, or some neglect or
                    default committed, by a person employed as a servant or agent of the Crown while
                    performing or purporting to perform his functions as such in relation to the
                    receipt, carriage, delivery or other dealing with the packet.</continued>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835901_027" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                <leadIn>No relief shall be available under subsection (2) except upon a claim by the
                    sender or the addressee of the packet in question; and the sender or addressee
                    of the packet shall be entitled to claim any relief available under the said
                    subsection in respect of the packet, whether or not he is the person damnified
                    by the injury complained of, and to give a good discharge in respect of all
                    claims in respect of the packet under the said subsection:</leadIn>
                
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_3_proviso">Provided that where the court is
                    satisfied, upon an application by any person who is not the sender or addressee
                    of the packet, that the sender and the addressee are unable or unwilling to
                    enforce their remedies in respect of the packet under the said subsection, the
                    court may, upon such terms as to security for costs and otherwise as the court
                    thinks just, allow that other person to bring proceedings under the said
                    subsection in the name of the sender or the addressee of the packet.</proviso>
            </content><content>Any reference in this subsection to the sender or addressee of the packet
                includes a reference to his personal representative.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835917_018" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where by virtue of subsection (3) any person recovers any money or property
                which, apart from that subsection, would have been recoverable by some other person,
                the money or property so recovered shall be held on trust for that person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835917_026" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Post Office Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap98A">Cap. 98 sub. leg. A</ref>) may
                be made for prescribing the conditions to be observed for the purposes of this
                section in relation to registered inland postal packets.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835932_005" name="6" temporalId="s7_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="InlandPostalPacket"><term>inland postal packet</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">本地郵包</term>) means a postal packet which is posted in Hong
                Kong for delivery in Hong Kong to the person to whom it is addressed;</def><def name="PostOfficeRegulations"><term>Post
                    Office
                Regulations</term>
                    (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">郵政署規例</term>》) has the same meaning as in the Post
                Office Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap98">Cap. 98</ref>);</def><def name="PostalPacket"><term>postal packet</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">郵包</term>) has, subject as hereinafter provided, the same meaning as in the
                Post Office Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap98">Cap. 98</ref>);</def><def name="Sender"><term>sender</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">寄件人</term>), in relation to a postal packet, has
                such meaning as may be assigned to it by Post Office Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap98A">Cap. 98 sub. leg. A</ref>).
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835932_040" name="7" temporalId="s7_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Any reference in this section to a postal packet shall be construed as
                including a reference to the contents of such a packet.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c.44 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147591798_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957757_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Provisions relating to the armed forces</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411835979_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Nothing done or omitted to be done by a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>member
                of the armed forces of the Crown while on duty as such shall subject either him or
                the Crown to liability in tort for causing the death of another person, or for
                causing personal injury to another person, in so far as the death or personal injury
                is due to anything suffered by that other person while he is a member of the armed
                forces of the Crown if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411835979_012" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the time when that thing is suffered by that other person, he is either
                    on duty as a member of the armed forces of the Crown or is, though not on duty
                    as such, on any land, premises, ship, aircraft or vehicle for the time being
                    used for the purposes of the armed forces of the Crown; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411835979_020" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411835995_001" name="i" temporalId="s8_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>where that other person is a member of the armed forces of the Crown in
                        right of Her Majesty’s Government in the United Kingdom, the Minister of
                        Pensions certifies that his suffering that thing has been or will be treated
                        as attributable to service for the purposes of entitlement to an award under
                        the Royal Warrant, Order in Council or Order of Her Majesty relating to the
                        disablement or death of members of the force of which he is a
                        member;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411835995_008" name="ii" temporalId="s8_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>
                        <leadIn>where that other person is a member of the armed forces of the Crown
                            in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the Colony, the Governor in
                            Council certifies that his suffering that thing has been or will be
                            treated as attributable to service for the purposes of entitlement to a
                            gratuity or pension under any enactment relating to the disablement or
                            death of members of the force of which he is a member:</leadIn>
                        
                    </content></subparagraph></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s8_1_b_ii_proviso">Provided that this subsection
                shall not exempt a member of the said forces from liability in tort in any case in
                which the court is satisfied that the act or omission was not connected with the
                execution of his duties as a member of those forces.</proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411835995_020" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>No proceedings in tort shall lie against the Crown for death or personal injury due to anything suffered by a member of the armed forces of the Crown if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411835995_028" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that thing is suffered by him in consequence of the nature or condition of any such land, premises, ship, aircraft or vehicle as aforesaid, or in consequence of the nature or condition of any equipment or supplies used for the purposes of those forces; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836010_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411836010_009" name="i" temporalId="s8_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of a member of the armed forces of the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the United Kingdom, the Minister of Pensions certifies as mentioned in subsection (1);</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411836010_016" name="ii" temporalId="s8_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of a member of the armed forces of the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the Colony, the Governor in Council certifies as mentioned in subsection (1);</content></subparagraph></paragraph><continued>nor shall any act or omission of an officer of the Crown subject him to liability in tort for death or personal injury, in so far as the death or personal injury is due to anything suffered by a member of the armed forces of the Crown being a thing as to which the conditions aforesaid are satisfied.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836010_028" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Chief Secretary for Administration, if satisfied that it is the fact—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of 1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836010_036" name="a" temporalId="s8_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that a person was or was not on any particular occasion on duty as a member of the armed forces of the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the Colony; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836026_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that at any particular time any land, premises, ship, aircraft, vehicle, equipment or supplies was or was not, or were or were not, used for the purposes of the said forces,</content></paragraph><continued>may issue a certificate certifying that to be the fact; and any such certificate shall, for the purposes of this section, be conclusive as to the fact which it certifies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836026_019" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A certificate of The Ministry of Defence or a Secretary of State—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836026_027" name="a" temporalId="s8_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that a person was or was not on any particular occasion on duty as a member of the armed forces of the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the United Kingdom; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836026_035" name="b" temporalId="s8_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that at any particular time any land, premises, ship, aircraft, vehicle, equipment or supplies was or was not, or were or were not, used for the purposes of the said forces,</content></paragraph><continued>shall, for the purposes of this section, be conclusive as to the fact which it certifies.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836026_048" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="MemberOfTheArmedForcesOfTheCrown">For the purposes of this section,
                    <term>member
                    of the armed forces of the
                Crown</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">官方武裝部隊成員</term>), unless the context otherwise
                requires, means a member of the armed forces of the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s
                Government in the Colony or in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the United
                Kingdom.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836041_004" name="6" temporalId="s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall be deemed by implication or otherwise to confer any right of action against the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the United Kingdom.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957757_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Saving in respect of acts done under prerogative and statutory powers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836088_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in Part II of this Ordinance shall extinguish or abridge any powers or authorities which, if this Ordinance had not been passed, would have been exercisable by virtue of the prerogative of the Crown or any powers or authorities conferred on the Crown or the Governor by any statute or enactment, and, in particular, nothing in the said Part II shall extinguish or abridge any powers or authorities exercisable by the Crown, whether in time of peace or of war, for the purpose of the defence of the realm or of training, or maintaining the efficiency of, any of the armed forces of the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the United Kingdom or in the Colony.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836104_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where in any proceedings under this Ordinance it is material to determine whether anything was properly done or omitted to be done in the exercise of the prerogative of the Crown, the Governor may, if satisfied that the act or omission was necessary for any such purpose as is mentioned in subsection (1), issue a certificate to the effect that the act or omission was necessary for that purpose; and the certificate shall, in those proceedings, be conclusive as to the matter so certified.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 11 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438402957773_002" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Jurisdiction
            and
            Procedure</heading><section id="ID_1438402957788_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Civil proceedings in the Supreme Court</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, all such civil proceedings by or
            against the Crown as are mentioned in the <ref>First Schedule</ref> are hereby
            abolished, and all civil proceedings by or against the Crown in the Supreme Court shall
            be instituted and proceeded with in accordance with rules of
                court.<continued name="RulesOfCourt">In this section, <term>rules of court</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院規則</term>) means, in relation to any claim against the
                Crown in the Supreme Court which falls within the jurisdiction of that court as a
                prize court, rules of court made under <ref>section 3</ref> of the Prize Courts Act
                1894 (1894 c. 39 U.K.).</continued></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 13 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957788_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Civil proceedings in the District Court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836166_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, and to any enactment limiting the jurisdiction of the District Court (whether by reference to the subject matter of the proceedings to be brought or the amount sought to be recovered in the proceedings or otherwise) any civil proceedings by or against the Crown may be instituted in the District Court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836166_012" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any proceedings by or against the Crown in the District Court shall be instituted and proceeded with in accordance with rules of court.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1962/22">22 of 1962 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957804_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Interpleader</heading><content>The Crown may obtain relief by way of interpleader proceedings, and may be made a party to such proceedings, in the same manner in which a subject may obtain relief by way of such proceedings or be made a party thereto; and all rules of court relating to interpleader proceedings shall, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, have effect accordingly.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c.44 s. 16 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957804_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Parties to proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836197_025" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Civil proceedings by or against the Crown instituted under the provisions of this Ordinance shall be instituted by or against the Secretary for Justice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836197_033" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No proceedings instituted in accordance with this Part of this Ordinance by or against the Secretary for Justice shall abate or be affected by any change in the person holding the office of Secretary for Justice.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 17 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957819_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Service of documents</heading><content>All documents required to be served on the Crown for the purpose of or in connexion with any civil proceedings by or against the Crown shall be served on the Secretary for Justice.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 18 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957835_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Removal and transfer of proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836244_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If in a case where proceedings are instituted against the Crown in the District
                Court an application in that behalf is made by the Crown to the Supreme Court, and
                there is produced to the court a certificate of the Secretary for Justice to the
                effect that the proceedings may involve an important question of law, or may be
                decisive of other cases arising out of the same matter, or are for other reasons
                more fit to be tried in the Supreme Court, the proceedings shall be removed into the
                Supreme Court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                    1997</ref>)</sourceNote><continued>Where
                    any proceedings have been removed into the Supreme Court on the production of
                    such a certificate as aforesaid, and it appears to the court by whom the
                    proceedings are tried that the removal has occasioned additional expense to the
                    person by whom the proceedings are brought, the court may take account of the
                    additional expense so occasioned in exercising its powers in regard to the award
                    of costs.</continued></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836260_004" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>Without prejudice to the rights of the Crown under subsection (1), all rules of law and enactments relating to the removal or transfer of proceedings from the District Court to the Supreme Court, or the transfer of proceedings from the Supreme Court to the District Court, shall apply in relation to proceedings against the Crown:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s15_2_proviso">Provided that an order for the transfer to the District Court of any proceedings against the Crown in the Supreme Court shall not be made without the consent of the Crown.</proviso></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 20 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957835_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Nature of relief</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836275_018" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>In any civil proceedings by or against the Crown the court shall, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, have power to make all such orders as it has power to make in proceedings between subjects, and otherwise to give such appropriate relief as the case may require:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s16_1_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836275_033" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where in any proceedings against the Crown any such relief is sought as might in proceedings between subjects be granted by way of injunction or specific performance, the court shall not grant an injunction or make an order for specific performance, but may in lieu thereof make an order declaratory of the rights of the parties; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836291_006" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in any proceedings against the Crown for the recovery of land or other property the court shall not make an order for the recovery of the land or the delivery of the property, but may in lieu thereof make an order declaring that the plaintiff is entitled as against the Crown to the land or property or to the possession thereof.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836291_013" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The court shall not in any civil proceedings grant any injunction or make any order against an officer of the Crown if the effect of granting the injunction or making the order would be to give any relief against the Crown which could not have been obtained in proceedings against the Crown.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 21 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957851_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Costs in civil proceedings to which the Crown is a party</heading><leadIn>In any civil proceedings or arbitration to which the Crown is a party, the costs of and incidental to the proceedings shall be awarded in the same manner and on the same principles as in cases between subjects, and the court or arbitrator shall have power to make an order for the payment of costs by or to the Crown accordingly :</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s17_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836322_060" name="a" temporalId="s17_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of proceedings to which by reason of any enactment or otherwise the Secretary for Justice is authorized to be made a party, the court or arbitrator shall have regard to the nature of the proceedings and the character and circumstances in which the Secretary for Justice appears, and may in the exercise of its or his discretion order any other party to the proceedings to pay the costs of the Secretary for Justice whatever may be the result of the proceedings; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836338_006" name="b" temporalId="s17_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>nothing in this section shall affect the power of the court or arbitrator to order, or any enactment providing for, the payment of costs out of any particular fund or property, or any enactment expressly relieving any department or officer of the Crown of the liability to pay costs.</content></paragraph></proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402957851_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Appeals and stay of execution</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, all enactments and rules of court relating to appeals and stay of execution shall, with any necessary modifications, apply to civil proceedings by or against the Crown as they apply to proceedings between subjects.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 22 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957866_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Scope of Part III</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836400_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of this section, any reference in this Part of this
                Ordinance to civil proceedings by the Crown shall be construed as a reference to the
                following proceedings only—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836400_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>proceedings for the enforcement or vindication of any right or the
                    obtaining of any relief which, if this Ordinance had not been passed, might have
                    been enforced or vindicated or obtained by any such proceedings as are mentioned
                    in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of the <ref>First Schedule</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836400_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>proceedings for the enforcement or vindication of any right or the
                    obtaining of any relief which, if this Ordinance had not been passed, might have
                    been enforced or vindicated or obtained by an action at the suit of any
                    Government department or any officer of the Crown as such;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836400_028" name="c" temporalId="s19_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><text>all such proceedings as the Crown is entitled to bring by virtue of this
                    Ordinance;</text></paragraph><continued name="CivilProceedingsByOrAgainstTheCrown">and the expression
                    <term>civil
                    proceedings by or against the
                Crown</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">由官方提出或針對官方提出的民事法律程序</term>) shall be construed
                accordingly.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836416_004" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of this section, any reference in this Part of this
                Ordinance to civil proceedings against the Crown shall be construed as a reference
                to the following proceedings only—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836416_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>proceedings for the enforcement or vindication of any right or the
                    obtaining of any relief which, if this Ordinance had not been passed, might have
                    been enforced or vindicated or obtained by any such proceedings as are mentioned
                    in <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of the <ref>First Schedule</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836416_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>proceedings for the enforcement or vindication of any right or the
                    obtaining of any relief which, if this Ordinance had not been passed, might have
                    been enforced or vindicated or obtained by any action against the Secretary for
                    Justice, any Government department or any officer of the Crown as
                    such;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836416_028" name="c" temporalId="s19_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><text>all such proceedings as any person is entitled to bring against the Crown by
                    virtue of this Ordinance;</text></paragraph><continued name="CivilProceedingsByOrAgainstTheCrown">and the expression
                    <term>civil
                    proceedings by or against the
                Crown</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">由官方提出或針對官方提出的民事法律程序</term>) shall be construed
                accordingly.<marker role="section-break"></marker></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836431_004" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding anything in subsections (1) and (2), the provisions of this Part
                of this Ordinance shall not have effect with respect to any of the following
                proceedings, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836431_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>proceedings brought by the Secretary for Justice on the relation of some
                    other person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836431_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>proceedings by or against the Official Trustee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836431_028" name="c" temporalId="s19_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>proceedings by the Secretary for Justice or other person under Order 120,
                        <ref>rules 3</ref> and <ref>4</ref> of the Rules of the Supreme Court
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap.
                        4 sub.
                        leg.</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/ln117">L.N. 117 of 1988</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln282">L.N. 282 of
                            1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/ln162">L.N. 162 of
                        1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402957897_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Judgments
            and
            Execution</heading><section id="ID_1438402957913_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Interest on debts, damages and costs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836478_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The provisions of any law relating to the payment of interest on judgment debts
                in proceedings between subjects shall apply to judgment debts due from or to the
                Crown.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836478_012" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any costs are awarded to or against the Crown in the Supreme Court,
                interest shall be payable upon those costs unless the court otherwise orders, and
                any interest so payable shall be at the same rate as that at which interest is
                payable upon judgment debts due from or to the Crown.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836478_020" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The provisions of any law empowering a Court of Record to award interest on
                debts and damages shall apply to judgments given in the proceedings by and against
                the Crown.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836478_028" name="4" temporalId="s20_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>This section shall apply both in relation to proceedings pending at the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance and in relation to proceedings instituted thereafter.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 24 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147675100_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957913_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Satisfaction of orders against the Crown</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836509_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                                                  <leadIn>Where in any civil proceedings by or
                                                  against the Crown, or in any proceedings such as
                                                  in England are taken on the Crown side of the
                                                  Queen’s Bench Division of Her Majesty’s High Court
                                                  of Justice, or in
                                                  connexion
                                                  with any arbitration to which the Crown is a
                                                  party, any order (including an order for costs) is
                                                  made by any court in favour of any person against
                                                  the Crown or against a Government department or
                                                  against an officer of the Crown as such, the
                                                  proper officer of the court shall, on an
                                                  application in that behalf made by or on behalf of
                                                  that person at any time after the expiration of
                                                  twenty-one days from the date of the order or, in
                                                  case the order provides for the payment of costs
                                                  and the costs require to be taxed, at any time
                                                  after the costs have been taxed, whichever is the
                                                  later, issue to that person a certificate in the
                                                  prescribed form containing particulars of the
                                                  order:</leadIn>
                                                  <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s21_1_proviso">Provided that, if the court so directs, a
                                                  separate certificate shall be issued with respect
                                                  to the costs (if any) ordered to be paid to the
                                                  applicant.</proviso>
                                                  </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836509_018" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A copy of any certificate issued under
                                                  this section may be served by the person in whose
                                                  favour the order is made upon the Secretary for
                                                  Justice.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                                                  1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836509_026" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                                                  <leadIn>If the order provides for the payment of
                                                  any money by way of damages or otherwise, or of
                                                  any costs, the certificate shall state the amount
                                                  so payable, and the Director of Accounting
                                                  Services shall, subject as hereinafter provided,
                                                  pay to the person entitled or to his solicitor the
                                                  amount appearing by the certificate to be due to
                                                  him together with the interest, if any, lawfully
                                                  due thereon:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/ln16">L.N. 16 of 1977</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/ln453">L.N. 453 of
                                                  1993</ref>)</sourceNote>
                                                  </leadIn>
                                                  <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s21_3_proviso">Provided that the court by which any such order
                                                  as aforesaid is made or any court to which an
                                                  appeal against the order lies may direct that,
                                                  pending an appeal or otherwise, payment of the
                                                  whole of any amount so payable or any part
                                                  thereof, shall be suspended, and if the
                                                  certificate has not been issued may order any such
                                                  directions to be inserted therein.</proviso>
                                                  </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836525_004" name="4" temporalId="s21_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Save as aforesaid no execution or
                                                  attachment or process in the nature thereof shall
                                                  be issued out of any court for enforcing payment
                                                  by the Crown of any such money or costs as
                                                  aforesaid, and no person shall be individually
                                                  liable under any order for the payment by the
                                                  Crown, or any Government department, or any
                                                  officer of the Crown as such, of any such money or
                                                  costs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836525_012" name="5" temporalId="s21_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>This section shall apply both in relation
                                                  to proceedings pending at the
                                                  commencement*
                                                  of this Ordinance and in relation to proceedings
                                                  instituted thereafter.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 25
                                                  U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147794456_001">
                                                  <content>Editorial Note:</content>
                                                  <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                                                  1957.</content>
                                        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957929_002" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Execution by the Crown</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836556_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, any order made in favour of the
                Crown against any person in any civil proceedings to which the Crown is a party may
                be enforced in the same manner as an order made in an action between subjects and
                not otherwise.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836556_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall affect any procedure which immediately before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance was available for enforcing an order made in favour of the Crown
                in proceedings brought by the Crown for the recovery of any fine or penalty, or the
                forfeiture or condemnation of any goods, or the forfeiture of any ship or any share
                in a ship.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 26 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147847195_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957929_004" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Attachment of moneys payable by the Crown</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836587_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Where any money is payable by the Crown to some person who, under any order of any court, is liable to pay any money to any other person, and that other person would, if the money so payable by the Crown were money payable by a subject, be entitled under rules of court to obtain an order for the attachment thereof as a debt due or accruing due, or an order for the appointment of a sequestrator or receiver to receive the money on his behalf, the Supreme Court may, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance and in accordance with rules of court, make an order restraining the first-mentioned person from receiving that money and directing payment thereof to that other person, or to the sequestrator or receiver:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s23_1_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that no such order shall be made in respect of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836587_019" name="a" temporalId="s23_1_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any wages or salary payable to any officer of the Crown as such;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836587_027" name="b" temporalId="s23_1_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any money which is subject to the provisions of any enactment prohibiting or restricting assignment or charging or taking in execution.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836587_034" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The provisions of subsection (1) shall, so far as they relate to forms of relief falling within the jurisdiction of the District Court, have effect in relation to the District Court as they have effect in relation to the Supreme Court.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 27 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438402957944_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Miscellaneous
            and
            Supplemental</heading><section id="ID_1438402957960_001" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Discovery</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836619_004" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to and in accordance with rules of court—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836619_012" name="a" temporalId="s24_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in any civil proceedings in the Supreme Court or the District Court to
                    which the Crown is a party, the Crown may be required by the court to make
                    discovery of documents and produce documents for inspection; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836619_020" name="b" temporalId="s24_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>in any such proceedings as aforesaid, the Crown may be required by the
                        court to answer interrogatories:</leadIn>
                    
                </content></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s24_1_b_proviso">Provided that this section shall be
                without prejudice to any rule of law which authorizes or requires the withholding of
                any document or the refusal to answer any question on the ground that the disclosure
                of the document or the answering of the question would be injurious to the public
                interest.</proviso><continued>Any order of the court made under the powers conferred by paragraph (b) shall
                direct by what officer of the Crown the interrogatories are to be
                answered.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836634_011" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to the proviso to subsection (1), any rules made for the purposes of this section shall be such as to secure that the existence of a document will not be disclosed if, in the opinion of the Governor, it would be injurious to the public interest to disclose the existence thereof.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 28 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957960_003" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Exclusion of proceedings in rem against the Crown</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836650_054" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall authorize proceedings in rem in respect of any
                claim against the Crown, or the arrest, detention or sale of any ships or aircraft
                belonging to Her Majesty or the Government, or of any cargo or other property
                belonging to the Crown, or give to any person any lien on any such ship, aircraft,
                cargo or other property.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836665_005" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where proceedings in rem have been instituted in the Supreme Court or the
                District Court against any such ship, aircraft, cargo or other property, the court
                may, if satisfied, either on an application by the plaintiff for an order under this
                subsection or an application by the Crown to set aside the proceedings, that the
                proceedings were so instituted by the plaintiff in the reasonable belief that the
                ship, aircraft, cargo or other property did not belong to the Crown, order that the
                proceedings shall be treated as if they were in personam duly instituted against the
                Crown in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance, or duly instituted
                against any other person whom the court regards as the proper person to be sued in
                the circumstances, and that the proceedings shall continue
                    accordingly.<continued>Any
                    such order may be made upon such terms, if any, as the court thinks just; and
                    where the court makes any such
                    order,
                    it may make such consequential orders as the court thinks expedient.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 29 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957975_002" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Limitation of actions</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall prejudice the right of the Crown to rely upon the law relating to the limitation of time for bringing proceedings against public authorities.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 30 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402957975_004" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Application to the Crown of certain statutory provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836728_018" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance shall not prejudice the right of the Crown to take advantage of the provisions of a statute or enactment although not named therein; and it is hereby declared that in any civil proceedings against the Crown the provisions of any statute or enactment which could, if the proceedings were between subjects, be relied upon by the defendant as a defence to the proceedings, whether in whole or in part, or otherwise, may, subject to any express provision to the contrary, be so relied upon by the Crown.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836743_005" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Order 44A, <ref>rule 1</ref> of the Rules of the Supreme Court
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap.
                    4 sub.
                    leg.</ref>)
                (which empowers the court in certain circumstances to order the defendant about to
                leave the jurisdiction of the court to furnish security) shall, with any necessary
                modifications, apply to civil proceedings in the Supreme Court by the
                Crown.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402957991_002" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>No abatement on demise of Crown</heading><content>No claim by or against the Crown, and no proceedings for the enforcement of any such claim, shall abate or be affected by the demise of the Crown.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 32 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402958007_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Abolition of certain writs</heading><content>No writ of extent or of diem clausit extremum shall issue after the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 33 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147927929_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402958007_003" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Rules of court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836790_018" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any power to make rules of court shall include power to make rules for the
                purpose of giving effect to the provisions of this Ordinance, and any such rules may
                contain provisions to have effect in relation to any proceedings by or against the
                Crown in substitution for or by way of addition to any of the provisions of the
                rules applying to proceedings between subjects.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836806_005" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Provision shall be made by rules of court with respect to the following
                matters—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411836806_013" name="a" temporalId="s30_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for providing for service of process, or notice thereof, in the case of
                    proceedings by the Crown against persons, whether Commonwealth citizens or not,
                    who are not resident in Hong Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/80">80 of 1982 s.
                            2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836806_021" name="b" temporalId="s30_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for securing that where any civil proceedings are brought against the Crown
                    in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance the plaintiff shall, before
                    the Crown is required to take any step in the proceedings, provide the Crown
                    with such information as the Crown may reasonably require as to the
                    circumstances in which it is alleged that the liability of the Crown has arisen
                    and as to the departments and officers of the Government concerned;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836821_006" name="c" temporalId="s30_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>for providing that in the case of proceedings against the Crown the
                    plaintiff shall not enter judgment against the Crown in default of appearance or
                    pleading without the leave of the court to be obtained on an application of
                    which notice has been given to the Crown;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836821_014" name="d" temporalId="s30_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>for excepting proceedings brought against the Crown from the operation of
                    any rule of court providing for summary judgment without trial, and for enabling
                    any such proceedings to be put in proper cases into any special list which may
                    be kept for the trial of short causes in which leave to defend is given under
                    any such rule of court as aforesaid;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836821_022" name="e" temporalId="s30_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>for authorizing the Crown to deliver interrogatories without the leave of a
                    court in any proceedings for the enforcement of any right for the enforcement of
                    which proceedings by way of English information might have been taken if this
                    Ordinance had not been passed, so, however, that the Crown shall not be entitled
                    to deliver any third or subsequent interrogatories without the leave of the
                    court;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836837_006" name="f" temporalId="s30_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>for enabling evidence to be taken on commission in proceedings by or
                    against the Crown;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411836837_014" name="g" temporalId="s30_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><leadIn>for providing—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411836837_022" name="i" temporalId="s30_2_g_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>that a person shall not be entitled to avail himself of any set-off or
                        counterclaim in any proceedings by the Crown for the recovery of taxes,
                        duties or penalties, or to avail himself in proceedings of any other nature
                        by the Crown of any set-off or counterclaim arising out of a right or claim
                        to repayment in respect of any taxes, or penalties;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411836837_030" name="ii" temporalId="s30_2_g_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that the Crown, when sued in the name of the Secretary for Justice,
                        shall not be entitled to avail itself of any set-off or counterclaim without
                        the leave of the court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                                1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836853_005" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Provision may be made by rules of court for regulating any appeals to the
                Supreme Court, whether by way of case stated or otherwise, under enactments relating
                to the revenue, and any rules made under this subsection may revoke any enactments
                or rules in force immediately before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance so far as they regulate any such appeals, and may make provision
                for any matters for which provision was made by any enactments or rules so in
                force.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 35 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574147993682_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402958022_002" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Pending proceedings</heading><content>Save as otherwise expressly provided, the provisions of this Ordinance shall not
            affect proceedings by or against the Crown which have been instituted before the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance; and for the purpose of this section proceedings against the Crown
            shall be deemed to have been so instituted if a statement of claim with respect to the
            matter in question has been filed and a sealed copy thereof has been served upon the
            Attorney General before the commencement of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 36 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574148035587_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402958022_004" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Financial provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411836962_018" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any expenditure incurred by or on behalf of the Crown in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the Colony by reason of the passing of this Ordinance shall be defrayed out of moneys provided by the Legislative Council.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411836962_026" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any sums payable to the Crown by reason of the passing of this Ordinance shall be paid into the Treasury.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 37 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402958038_002" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Statutes no longer effective</heading><content>The statutes set out in the <ref>Second Schedule</ref> to this Ordinance shall no longer have effect in the Colony to the extent specified in the third column of that <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 39 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402958053_001" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Saving</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411837055_004" name="1" temporalId="s34_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall apply to proceedings by or against, or
                authorize proceedings in tort to be brought against, Her Majesty in Her private
                capacity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837055_012" name="2" temporalId="s34_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Except as therein otherwise expressly provided, nothing in this Ordinance
                shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411837055_020" name="a" temporalId="s34_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>affect the law relating to prize salvage, or apply to proceedings in causes
                    or matters within the jurisdiction of any court as a prize court or to any
                    criminal proceedings; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837071_006" name="b" temporalId="s34_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>authorize proceedings to be taken against the Crown under or in accordance
                    with the provisions of this Ordinance in respect of any alleged liability of the
                    Crown arising otherwise than in respect of Her Majesty’s Government in the
                    Colony, or affect proceedings against the Crown in respect of any such alleged
                    liability as aforesaid; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837087_006" name="c" temporalId="s34_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>authorize proceedings to be taken against the Crown under or in accordance
                    with the provisions of this Ordinance in respect of any act, neglect, or default
                    of any officer or agent of the Crown, unless—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411837087_014" name="i" temporalId="s34_2_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>such officer has been directly or indirectly appointed by the Crown and
                        was at the material time paid in respect of his duties as an officer of the
                        Crown wholly out of the revenues of the Colony or any other fund certified
                        by the Governor for the purposes of this paragraph or was at the material
                        time holding an office in respect of which the Governor certifies that the
                        holder thereof would normally be so paid;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411837087_022" name="ii" temporalId="s34_2_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>such agent was at the material time acting for and on behalf of the
                        Government; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837087_029" name="d" temporalId="s34_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>affect any proceedings by the Crown otherwise than in right of Her
                    Majesty’s Government in the Colony; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837087_037" name="e" temporalId="s34_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>subject the Crown to any greater liabilities in respect of the acts or
                    omissions of any independent contractor employed by the Crown than those to
                    which the Crown would be subject in respect of such acts or omissions if it were
                    a private person; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837102_006" name="f" temporalId="s34_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>affect any rules of evidence or any presumption relating to the extent to
                    which the Crown is bound by any statute or enactment; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837102_014" name="g" temporalId="s34_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>affect any right of the Crown to demand a trial at bar or to control or
                    otherwise intervene in proceedings affecting its rights, property or profits;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837102_022" name="h" temporalId="s34_2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>affect any right of the Secretary for Justice, any Government department or
                    any officer of the Crown as such to institute proceedings under or in accordance
                    with the provisions of any other enactment;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                            1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>and, without prejudice to the general effect of the foregoing provisions,
                Part IV of this Ordinance shall not apply to the Crown except in right of Her
                Majesty’s Government in the Colony.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837102_035" name="3" temporalId="s34_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A certificate of the Chief Secretary for Administration—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of 1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln242">L.N. 242 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411837102_043" name="a" temporalId="s34_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to the effect that any alleged liability of the Crown arises otherwise than
                    in respect of Her Majesty’s Government in the Colony;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411837118_006" name="b" temporalId="s34_3_b"><num value="b"><marker role="section-break"></marker>(b)</num><content>to the effect that any proceedings by the Crown are proceedings otherwise
                    than in right of Her Majesty’s Government in the Colony,</content></paragraph><continued>shall, for the purposes of this Ordinance, be conclusive as to the matter so
                certified.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837118_019" name="4" temporalId="s34_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where any property vests in the Crown by virtue of any rule of law which
                operates independently of the acts or the intentions of the Crown, the Crown shall
                not by virtue of this Ordinance be subject to any liabilities in tort by reason only
                of the property being so vested; but the provisions of this subsection shall be
                without prejudice to the liabilities of the Crown under this Ordinance in respect of
                any period after the Crown or any person acting for the Crown has in fact taken
                possession or control of any such property, or entered into occupation
                thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837133_005" name="5" temporalId="s34_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>This Ordinance shall not operate to limit the discretion of the court to grant
                relief by way of mandamus in cases in which such relief might have been granted
                before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, notwithstanding that by reason of the provisions of this
                Ordinance some other and further remedy is available.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1947 c. 44 s. 40 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1574149634068_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 November
                1957.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438402958053_003" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">First
            Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap300/s10">s. 10</ref>]</note><heading>Proceedings Abolished
            by
            this
            Ordinance</heading><section id="ID_1438411837180_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_s1"><num value="1">1.</num><subsection id="ID_1438411837180_017" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Latin informations and English
                    informations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837180_021" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Writs of
                    capias
                    ad
                    respondendum,
                    writs of subpoena
                    ad
                    respondendum,
                    and writs of appraisement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837180_029" name="3" temporalId="sch1_s1_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Writs of
                    scire
                    facias.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837180_037" name="4" temporalId="sch1_s1_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Proceedings for the determination of any issue upon a writ of extent or of
                    diem
                    clausit
                    extremum.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438411837180_045" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_s2"><num value="2">2.</num><subsection id="ID_1438411837180_050" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Proceedings by way of petition of right under <ref>section 52</ref> of the
                    Naval Prize Act 1864 (1864 c. 25
                    U.K.).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411837180_054" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Proceedings against Her Majesty by way of
                    monstrans
                    de
                    droit.</content></subsection></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438402958069_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Second
            Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap300/s33">s. 33</ref>]</note><heading>Statutes
            No
            Longer
            Having Effect
            in
            the
            Colony</heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="450">
                
                <col width="30%"></col>
                
                <col width="45%"></col>
                
                <col width="25%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p>Session and Chapter</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Title or Short
                            title</center>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_right">Extent of
                            Repeal<br xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"></br></p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p>1297 c. 18 U.K.</p>
                        
                        <p>1785 c. 35 U.K.</p>
                        
                        <p>1817 c. 117 U.K.</p>
                        
                        <p>1842 c. 86 U.K.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p>The King’s Tenant his
                            Debtor</p>
                        
                        <p>The Crown Debtors Act 1785</p>
                        
                        <p>The Extents in Aid Act 1817</p>
                        
                        <p>The Exchequer Court Act 1842</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p>The whole Act</p>
                        
                        <p>The whole Act</p>
                        
                        <p>The whole Act</p>
                        
                        <p><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section 9</ref></p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            
        </text></schedule></main></ordinance>