<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 152</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>152</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap152!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-05-20</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402725894_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-05-20">
            <content>To make provision for the renewal of certain Government leases of land in the
                New Territories.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote> (Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
            46</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[9 May 1969]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er2">E.R. 2 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402725894_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>New Territories (Renewable
                Government Leases) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 47</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402725909_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ExistingGovernmentLease"><term>existing
                Government
            lease</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">現行政府租契</term>) means such a Government lease as is
            referred to in <ref>section 3</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                48</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Lot"><term>lot</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">地段</term>) means any piece or parcel of ground demised
            under a Government lease;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="NewGovernmentLease"><term>new
                Government
            lease</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">新政府租契</term>) means such a Government lease as is
            deemed to be granted under <ref>section 4</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                48</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Section"><leadIn><term>section</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">分段</term>) means any portion of a lot which has
                been—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411305048_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>assigned or alienated for the whole of the term created by the existing Government lease of the lot; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411305048_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>declared to have been divided or severed from the remainder of the lot,</content></paragraph><continued>by or under an instrument which is registered in the Land Registry and also means any portion of a lot retained following such assignment or alienation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/20">20 of 2002 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></def></section><section id="ID_1438402725941_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>This Ordinance applies to every Government lease existing immediately before the
            expiration of the 30th day of June 1973 under which land in the New Territories is
            demised for a term of seventy-five years from the 1st day of July 1898 and which
            contains a right of renewal for a further term of twenty-four years less three days,
            other than leases of land exempted from Part II of the New Territories Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap97">Cap. 97</ref>) under subsection (2) or (3) of <ref>section 7</ref>
            thereof.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402725956_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-20" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>New Government leases deemed to be granted on 1st July 1973</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411305094_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the case of an existing Government lease of a lot which has not been divided into sections before the 1st day of July 1973, the right of renewal contained in the lease shall be deemed to have been exercised by the person entitled to that right and on that date there shall be deemed to be granted to such person a new Government lease of the land held by him immediately before that date under the existing Government lease. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411305094_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In the case of an existing Government lease of a lot which has been divided into sections before the 1st day of July 1973, the right of renewal contained in the lease shall be deemed to have been exercised by the persons entitled to that right and on that date there shall be deemed to be granted to such persons separate new Government leases of the land respectively held by them immediately before that date under the existing Government lease. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411305110_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Every new Government lease shall be deemed to be for a term of twenty-four years less three days from the 1st day of July 1973, and shall be deemed to contain—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411305110_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the new Government lease is deemed to be granted under subsection (1), a reservation of the same annual Government rent as was payable for the year ending on the 30th day of June 1973 in respect of the land to which the new Government lease relates; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411305110_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the new Government lease is deemed to be granted under subsection (2), a reservation of the same annual Government rent as may appear from the Government Rent Roll in the appropriate District Office to have been payable for the year ending on the 30th day of June 1973 in respect of the land to which the new Government lease relates; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411305126_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a covenant by the lessee to pay in the same manner and on the same days as are specified in the existing Government lease whichever of the annual Government rents referred to in paragraphs (a) and (b) is applicable; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411305126_014" name="d" temporalId="s4_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>the same covenants, exceptions, reservations, stipulations, provisos and declarations (including the right of re-entry) mutatis mutandis as are contained in the existing Government lease of the land to which the new Government lease relates other than—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411305126_022" name="i" temporalId="s4_3_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the covenant to pay the Government rent; and </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411305126_030" name="ii" temporalId="s4_3_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the provision (if any) for fixing a new Government rent at the expiration of the first ten years of the term; and </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411305126_038" name="iii" temporalId="s4_3_d_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the right of renewal on the expiration of the term; </content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411305126_045" name="e" temporalId="s4_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a covenant by the lessee to perform, observe and comply with the covenants, exceptions, reservations, stipulations, provisos and declarations deemed to be contained in the new Government lease by virtue of paragraph (d). </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411305141_005" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Every new Government lease and the land thereby deemed to be demised shall be deemed to be subject to such of the following encumbrances and interests as the land and the existing Government lease relating thereto were subject to immediately before the 1st day of July 1973—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411305141_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any mortgage, whether legal or equitable, and whether registered in the Land Registry or not;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/20">20 of 2002 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote> </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411305141_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any public rights; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411305141_029" name="c" temporalId="s4_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any other rights, easements, tenancies or other burdens or encumbrances of whatsoever kind or nature, except such as were created by an instrument and were not thereby expressed to continue after the 30th day of June 1973.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402725972_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-05-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Saving of Government rights</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411305172_064" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall be construed as a waiver by the Government of
                any of its rights in respect of any breach of covenant in any existing Government
                lease.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411305188_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any breach of covenant existing immediately before the 1st day of July 1973 in
                respect of an existing Government lease shall be deemed to be a breach of covenant
                in respect of the new Government lease and the Government may exercise its rights
                (including the right of re-entry) in relation to the new Government lease in the
                same manner and to the same extent as they could have been exercised or enforced
                before the said date in relation to the existing Government lease.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>