<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 210</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>210</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap210!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-06-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402833144_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2017-02-15">
            
            <content>To revise the law as to theft and similar or associated offences, and in connexion
                 therewith to make provision as to criminal proceedings by one
                party to a marriage against the other; and for other purposes connected
                therewith.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 September 1970]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1970/ln124">L.N. 124 of 1970</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Preliminary</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402833160_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title and application</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411554991_027" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Theft
                                        Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411554991_035" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Save as otherwise provided by this Ordinance, this Ordinance shall
                                have effect only in relation to offences wholly or partly committed
                                on or after the commencement thereof.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 35(1) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833160_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Basic definition of theft</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555038_033" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="Thief,Steal">A person commits theft if he dishonestly appropriates property
                belonging to another with the intention of permanently depriving the other of it;
                and
                    <term>thief</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">竊賊</term>) and
                    <term>steal</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">偷竊</term>) shall be construed accordingly.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555038_040" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>It is immaterial whether the appropriation is made with a view to gain, or is made for the thief’s own benefit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555054_005" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Sections 3<inline class="width_3"> </inline>to 7</ref><inline class="width_3"> </inline>shall have effect as regards the interpretation and operation of this section (and except as otherwise provided by this Ordinance shall apply only for purposes of this section).<inline class="width_3"> </inline></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833175_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading><term>Dishonestly</term>
            (不誠實地)</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555069_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person’s appropriation of property belonging to another is not to be regarded
                as dishonest—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555069_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if he appropriates the property in the belief that he has in law the right
                    to deprive the other of it, on behalf of himself or of a third person;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555069_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if he appropriates the property in the belief that he would have the
                    other’s consent if the other knew of the appropriation and the circumstances of
                    it; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555069_028" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>(except where the property came to him as trustee or personal
                    representative) if he appropriates the property in the belief that the person to
                    whom the property belongs cannot be discovered by taking reasonable
                    steps.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555069_035" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person’s appropriation of property belonging to another may be dishonest
                notwithstanding that he is willing to pay for the property.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833191_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading><term>Appropriates</term>
            (挪佔)</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555147_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any assumption by a person of the rights of an owner amounts to an
                appropriation, and this includes, where he has come by the property (innocently or
                not) without stealing it, any later assumption of a right to it by keeping or
                dealing with it as owner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555147_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where property or a right or interest in property is or purports to be
                transferred for value to a person acting in good faith, no later assumption by him
                of rights which he believed himself to be acquiring shall, by reason of any defect
                in the transferor’s title, amount to theft of the property.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833191_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading><term>Property</term>
            (財產)</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555163_026" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="Property"><term>Property</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">財產</term>) includes money and all other property,
                real and personal, including things in action and other intangible property.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555163_033" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A person cannot steal land, or things forming part of land and severed from it
                by him or by his directions, except in the following cases, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555163_041" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>when he is a trustee or personal representative, or is authorized by power
                    of attorney, or as liquidator of a company, or otherwise, to sell or dispose of
                    land belonging to another, and he appropriates the land or anything forming part
                    of it by dealing with it in breach of the confidence reposed in him;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555179_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>when he is not in possession of the land and appropriates anything forming
                    part of the land by severing it or causing it to be severed, or after it has
                    been severed; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555179_014" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>when, being in possession of the land under a tenancy, he appropriates the
                    whole or part of any fixture or structure let to be used with the
                    land.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555179_021" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (2)—</leadIn><def name="Land"><term>land</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地</term>) does not include incorporeal
                hereditaments;</def><def name="Tenancy,Let"><term>tenancy</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">租賃</term>) means a tenancy for years or for any
                less period and includes an agreement for such a tenancy, but a person who after the
                end of a tenancy remains in possession by virtue of any Ordinance or otherwise is to
                be treated as having possession under the tenancy, and
                    <term>let</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">租</term>) shall be construed accordingly.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555179_042" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person who picks mushrooms growing wild on any land, or who picks flowers,
                fruit or foliage from a plant growing wild on any land, does not (although not in
                possession of the land) steal what he picks, unless he does it for reward or for
                sale or other commercial purpose.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555194_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="Mushroom,Plant">For the purposes of subsection (4)
                    <term>mushroom</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">菌類植物</term>) includes any fungus, and
                    <term>plant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">植物</term>) includes any shrub or tree.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555194_012" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Wild creatures, tamed or untamed, shall be regarded as property; but a person
                cannot steal a wild creature not tamed nor ordinarily kept in captivity, or the
                carcass of any such creature, unless either it has been reduced into possession by
                or on behalf of another person and possession of it has not since been lost or
                abandoned, or another person is in course of reducing it into possession.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833206_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading><term>Belonging
                to
            another</term>
            (屬於另一人)</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555225_026" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Property shall be regarded as belonging to any person having possession or
                control of it, or having in it any proprietary right or interest (not being an
                equitable interest arising only from an agreement to transfer or grant an
                interest).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555225_034" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where property is subject to a trust, the person to whom it belongs shall be
                regarded as including any person having a right to enforce the trust, and an
                intention to defeat the trust shall be regarded accordingly as an intention to
                deprive of the property any person having that right.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555241_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a person receives property from or on account of another, and is under an
                obligation to the other to retain and deal with that property or its proceeds in a
                particular way, the property or its proceeds shall be regarded (as against him) as
                belonging to the other.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555241_013" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a person gets property by another’s mistake, and is under an obligation
                to make restoration (in whole or in part) of the property or its proceeds or of the
                value thereof, then to the extent of that obligation the property or its proceeds
                shall be regarded (as against him) as belonging to the person entitled to
                restoration, and an intention not to make restoration shall be regarded accordingly
                as an intention to deprive that person of the property or proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555257_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Property of a corporation sole shall be regarded as belonging to the
                corporation notwithstanding a vacancy in the corporation.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833222_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading><term>With
                the intention of permanently depriving the other of
            it</term>
            (意圖永久地剝奪他人財產 )</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555272_035" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person appropriating property belonging to another without meaning the other
                permanently to lose the thing itself is nevertheless to be regarded as having the
                intention of permanently depriving the other of it if his intention is to treat the
                thing as his own to dispose of regardless of the other’s rights; and a borrowing or
                lending of it may amount to so treating if, but only if, the borrowing or lending of
                it is for a period and in circumstances making it equivalent to an outright taking
                or disposal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555288_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (1), where a person, having
                possession or control (lawfully or not) of property belonging to another, parts with
                the property under a condition as to its return which he may not be able to perform,
                this (if done for purposes of his own and without the other’s authority) amounts to
                treating the property as his own to dispose of regardless of the other’s
                rights.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833222_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Other definitions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555319_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><ref>Section 5(1)</ref> and <ref>section 6(1)</ref> shall apply generally for the purposes of this Ordinance as they apply for the purposes of <ref>section 2</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555319_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this Ordinance—</leadIn><def name="Gain,Loss"><leadIn><term>gain</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">獲益</term>) and <term>loss</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">損失</term>) are, except in <ref>section 16A</ref>, to
                    be construed as extending only to gain or loss in money or other property, but
                    as extending to any such gain or loss whether temporary or permanent;
                    and—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555319_027" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content><term>gain</term>
                        includes a
                        gain by keeping what one has, as well as a gain by getting
                        what one has not; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555319_035" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><term>loss</term>
                        includes a loss by not getting what one might get, as well as a loss by
                        parting with what one has;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/45">45 of 1999 s.
                                2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def><def name="Goods"><term>goods</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">貨品</term>) except in so far as the context
                otherwise requires, includes money and every other description of property except
                land, and includes things severed from the land by stealing.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 34 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Theft,
        Robbery,
        Burglary,
        etc.</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402833238_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Theft</heading><content>Any person who commits theft shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
            conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 7 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833238_004" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Robbery</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555366_046" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person commits robbery if he steals, and immediately before or at the time of doing so, and in order to do so, he uses force on any person or puts or seeks to put any person in fear of being then and there subjected to force.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555381_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who commits robbery, or an assault with intent to rob, shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for life.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833253_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Burglary</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555397_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person commits burglary if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555397_012" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he enters any building or part of a building as a trespasser and with intent to commit any such offence as is mentioned in subsection (2); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555397_020" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>having entered any building or part of a building as a trespasser he steals or attempts to steal anything in the building or that part of it or inflicts or attempts to inflict on any person therein any grievous bodily harm.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555397_027" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The offences referred to in subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555397_035" name="a" temporalId="s11_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>stealing anything in the building or part of a building in question;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555397_043" name="b" temporalId="s11_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>inflicting on any person therein any grievous bodily harm or raping any woman therein; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555397_051" name="c" temporalId="s11_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>doing unlawful damage to the building or anything therein.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555397_058" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>References in subsections (1) and (2) to a building shall apply also to an inhabited vehicle or vessel, and shall apply to any such vehicle or vessel at times when the person having a habitation in it is not there as well as at times when he is.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555413_005" name="3A" temporalId="s11_3A"><num value="3A">(3A)</num><leadIn>The reference in subsection <ref>(2)(c)</ref> to doing unlawful damage to anything in a building includes—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555413_013" name="a" temporalId="s11_3A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>unlawfully causing a computer in the building to function other than as it has been established by or on behalf of its owner to function, notwithstanding that the unlawful action may not impair the operation of the computer or a program held in the computer or the reliability of data held in the computer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555413_021" name="b" temporalId="s11_3A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>unlawfully altering or erasing any program, or data, held in a computer in the building or in a computer storage medium in the building; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555413_029" name="c" temporalId="s11_3A_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>unlawfully adding any program or data to the contents of a computer in the building or a computer storage medium in the building.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1993/23">23 of 1993 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555413_036" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person who commits burglary shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 14 years.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833269_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Aggravated burglary</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555444_035" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person commits aggravated burglary if he commits any burglary and at the time has with him any firearm or imitation firearm, any weapon of offence, or any explosive.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555444_043" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (1)—</leadIn><def name="Firearm"><term>firearm</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">火器</term>) includes an airgun or air pistol;</def><def name="ImitationFirearm"><term>imitation
                    firearm</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">仿製火器</term>) means anything which has the
                appearance of being a firearm, whether capable of being discharged or not;</def><def name="WeaponOfOffence"><term>weapon
                    of
                offence</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">攻擊性武器</term>) means any article made or adapted for
                use for causing injury to or incapacitating a person, or intended by the person
                having it with him for such use;</def><def name="Explosive"><term>explosive</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">炸藥</term>) means any article manufactured for the
                purpose of producing a practical effect by explosion, or intended by the person
                having it with him for that purpose.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555459_018" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person who commits aggravated burglary shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for life.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833284_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Removal of articles from places open to the public</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555475_046" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsections (3) and (4), where the public have access to a building in order to view the building or part of it or a collection housed in it, any person who without lawful authority removes from the building or its grounds the whole or part of any article displayed or kept for display to the public in the building or that part of it or in its grounds, shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 5 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555491_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (1)—</leadIn><def name="Collection"><term>collection</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">收藏品</term>) includes a collection got together for
                    a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>temporary purpose, but references in this
                section to a collection do not apply to a collection made or exhibited for the
                purpose of effecting sales or other commercial dealings.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555491_019" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>It is immaterial for the purposes of subsection (1) that the public’s access to a building is limited to a particular period or particular occasion; but where anything removed from a building or its grounds is there otherwise than as forming part of, or being on loan for exhibition with, a collection intended for permanent exhibition to the public, the person removing it does not thereby commit an offence under this section unless he removes it on a day when the public have access to the building as mentioned in subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555506_005" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person does not commit an offence under this section if he believes that he has lawful authority for the removal of the thing in question or that he would have it if the person entitled to give it knew of the removal and the circumstances of it.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 11 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833284_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-24" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Taking conveyance without authority</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555537_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsections (2) and (3), any person who, without having the consent of the owner or other lawful authority, takes any conveyance for his own or another’s use, or knowing that any conveyance has been taken without such authority, drives it or allows himself to be carried on or in it, shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 7 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/7">7 of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555537_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection (1) shall not apply in relation to pedal cycles or rickshaws, but,
                subject to subsection (3), any person who, without having the consent of the owner
                or other lawful authority, takes a pedal cycle or rickshaw for his own or another’s
                use, or rides a pedal cycle or rickshaw knowing it to have been taken without such
                authority, shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555553_005" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person does not commit an offence under this section by anything done in the belief that he has lawful authority to do it or that he would have the owner’s consent if the owner knew of his doing it and the circumstances of it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555553_013" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><def name="Conveyance"><term>conveyance</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">運輸工具</term>) means any conveyance constructed or
                adapted for the carriage of a person whether by land, water or air, except that it
                does not include a conveyance constructed or adapted for use only under the control
                of a person not carried in or on it, and
                    <term>drive</term>
                shall be construed accordingly; and</def><def name="Owner"><term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>) in relation to a conveyance which is
                the subject of a hiring agreement or hire-purchase agreement means the person in
                possession of the conveyance under that agreement.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 12 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833300_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Abstracting of electricity</heading><content>Any person who dishonestly uses without due authority, or dishonestly causes to be wasted or diverted, any electricity shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 5 years.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 13 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833316_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Dishonest use of public telephone or telex system</heading><content>Any person who dishonestly uses a public telephone or telex system with intent to
            avoid payment shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to
            imprisonment for 2 years.</content><referenceNote>[cf.
            1968 c. 60 Sch. 2 Pt. I Para. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Fraud and Blackmail</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402833316_003" name="s16A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s16A"><num value="16A">16A.</num><heading>Fraud</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555615_032" name="1" temporalId="s16A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If any person by any deceit (whether or not the deceit is the sole or main
                inducement) and with intent to defraud induces another person to commit an act or
                make an omission, which results either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555631_005" name="a" temporalId="s16A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in benefit to any person other than the second-mentioned person;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555631_013" name="b" temporalId="s16A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in prejudice or a substantial risk of prejudice to any person other than
                    the first-mentioned person,</content></paragraph><continued>the first-mentioned person commits the offence of fraud and is liable on
                conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 14 years.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555631_026" name="2" temporalId="s16A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (1), a person shall be treated as having an
                intent to defraud if, at the time when he practises the deceit, he intends that he
                will by the deceit (whether or not the deceit is the sole or main inducement) induce
                another person to commit an act or make an omission, which will result in either or
                both of the consequences referred to in paragraphs (a) and (b) of that
                subsection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555631_034" name="3" temporalId="s16A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><def name="Act,Omission"><term>act</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">作為</term>) and
                    <term>omission</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">不作為</term>) include respectively a series of acts
                and a series of omissions;</def><def name="Benefit"><term>benefit</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">利益</term>) means any financial or proprietary gain,
                whether temporary or permanent;</def><def name="Deceit"><term>deceit</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欺騙</term>) means any deceit (whether deliberate or
                reckless) by words or conduct (whether by any act or omission) as to fact or as to
                law, including a deceit relating to the past, the present or the future and a deceit
                as to the intentions of the person practising the deceit or of any other
                person;</def><def name="Gain"><term>gain</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">獲益</term>) includes a gain by keeping what one has,
                as well as a gain by getting what one has not;</def><def name="Loss"><term>loss</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">損失</term>) includes a loss by not getting what one
                might get, as well as a loss by parting with what one has;</def><def name="Prejudice"><term>prejudice</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">不利</term>) means any financial or proprietary loss,
                whether temporary or permanent.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555647_046" name="4" temporalId="s16A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>This section shall not affect or modify the offence at common law of conspiracy
                to defraud.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1999/45">45 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833331_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Obtaining property by deception</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555678_011" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who by any deception (whether or not such deception was the sole or
                main inducement) dishonestly obtains property belonging to another, with the
                intention of permanently depriving the other of it, shall be guilty of an offence
                and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10
                years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555678_019" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this section a person is to be treated as obtaining
                property if he obtains ownership, possession or control of it, and
                    <term>obtain</term>
                (取得) includes obtaining for another or enabling another to obtain or to
                retain.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555693_005" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Section 7</ref> shall apply for the purposes of this section, with the
                necessary adaptation of the reference to appropriating as it applies for the
                purposes of <ref>section 2</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555693_013" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><def name="Deception"><term>deception</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欺騙手段</term>) means any deception (whether
                deliberate or reckless) by words or conduct (whether by any act or omission) as to
                fact or as to law, including a deception relating to the past, the present or the
                future and a deception as to the intentions of the person using the deception or any
                other person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2005/10">10 of 2005 s. 37</ref>)</sourceNote></def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 15 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833347_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Obtaining pecuniary advantage by deception</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555709_048" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who by any deception (whether or not such deception was the sole or main inducement) dishonestly obtains for himself or another any pecuniary advantage shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555725_005" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The cases in which a pecuniary advantage within the meaning of this section is to be regarded as obtained for a person are cases where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555725_013" name="a" temporalId="s18_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>he is granted by a bank or deposit-taking company, or any subsidiary thereof the principal business of which is the provision of credit—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555725_021" name="i" temporalId="s18_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a credit facility or credit arrangement;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555725_029" name="ii" temporalId="s18_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>an improvement to, or extension of, the terms of a credit facility or credit arrangement; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555725_037" name="iii" temporalId="s18_2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a credit to, or a set off against, an account,</content></subparagraph><continued>whether any such credit facility, credit arrangement or account—</continued><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555725_051" name="A" temporalId="s18_2_a_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>is in his name or the name of another person; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555725_059" name="B" temporalId="s18_2_a_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>is legally enforceable or not;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555725_066" name="b" temporalId="s18_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>he is allowed to borrow by way of overdraft, or to take out any policy of insurance or annuity contract, or obtains an improvement on the terms on which he is allowed to do so, whether any such overdraft, policy of insurance or annuity contract—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555725_074" name="i" temporalId="s18_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>is in his name or the name of another person; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555725_082" name="ii" temporalId="s18_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>is legally enforceable or not; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555740_006" name="c" temporalId="s18_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>he is given the opportunity to earn remuneration or greater remuneration in an office or employment, or to win money by betting.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555740_013" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><def name="Bank"><leadIn><term>bank</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">銀行</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555740_028" name="a" temporalId="s18_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a bank within the meaning of <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Banking Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555740_036" name="b" temporalId="s18_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>a bank—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555740_044" name="i" temporalId="s18_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><def name="Incorporated">incorporated by or under the law or other authority
                            in any place outside Hong Kong, and in this respect
                                <term>incorporated</term>
                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">成立為法團</term>) includes established;
                            and</def></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555740_051" name="ii" temporalId="s18_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>which is not a bank within the meaning of <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Banking Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/49">49 of 1995 s. 53</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></def><def name="Deception"><term>deception</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欺騙手段</term>) has the same meaning as in
                    <ref>section 17</ref>;</def><def name="DeposittakingCompany"><term>deposit-taking
                    company</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">接受存款公司</term>) means a deposit-taking company or
                restricted licence bank within the meaning of <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Banking
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/49">49 of 1995 s.
                    53</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Subsidiary"><term>subsidiary</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附屬公司</term>) has the same meaning as in the
                Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; 920)</sourceNote></def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 16 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833362_001" name="s18A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18A"><num value="18A">18A.</num><heading>Obtaining services by deception</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555787_004" name="1" temporalId="s18A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who by any deception (whether or not such deception was the sole or main inducement) dishonestly obtains services from another shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555787_012" name="2" temporalId="s18A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>It is an obtaining of services where the other is induced to confer a benefit by doing some act, or causing or permitting some act to be done, on the understanding that the benefit has been or will be paid for.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555787_020" name="3" temporalId="s18A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="Deception">For the purposes of this section,
                    <term>deception</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欺騙手段</term>) has the same meaning as in
                    <ref>section 17</ref>.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1980/45">45 of 1980 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1978 c. 31 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833362_003" name="s18B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18B"><num value="18B">18B.</num><heading>Evasion of liability by deception</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555803_041" name="1" temporalId="s18B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (2), where a person by any deception (whether or not such
                deception was the sole or main inducement)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555803_049" name="a" temporalId="s18B_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>dishonestly secures the remission of the whole or part of any existing
                    liability to make a payment, whether his own liability or another’s;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555818_006" name="b" temporalId="s18B_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>with intent to make default (whether the default is permanent or otherwise)
                    in whole or in part on any existing liability to make a payment, or with intent
                    to let another do so, dishonestly induces the creditor or any person claiming
                    payment on behalf of the creditor to wait for payment (whether or not the due
                    date for payment is deferred) or to forgo payment; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555818_014" name="c" temporalId="s18B_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>dishonestly obtains any exemption from or abatement of liability to make a
                    payment,</content></paragraph><continued>he shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon
                indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555818_027" name="2" temporalId="s18B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Liability">For the purposes of this section
                    <term>liability</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法律責任</term>) means legally enforceable liability;
                and subsection (1) shall not apply in relation to a liability that has not been
                accepted or established to pay compensation for a wrongful act or omission.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555818_034" name="3" temporalId="s18B_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> a person induced to take in
                payment a cheque or other security for money by way of conditional satisfaction of a
                pre-existing liability is to be treated not as being paid but as being induced to
                wait for payment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555834_005" name="4" temporalId="s18B_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="Obtains">For the purposes of subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref>
                <term>obtains</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">取得</term>) includes obtaining for another or
                enabling another to obtain.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555834_012" name="5" temporalId="s18B_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="Deception">For the purposes of this section,
                    <term>deception</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欺騙手段</term>) has the same meaning as in
                    <ref>section 17</ref>.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1980/45">45 of 1980 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf.
            1978 c. 31 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833378_002" name="s18C" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18C"><num value="18C">18C.</num><heading>Making off without payment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555865_004" name="1" temporalId="s18C_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (3), a person who, knowing that payment on the spot for any goods supplied or service done is required or expected from him, dishonestly makes off without having paid as required or expected and with intent to avoid payment of the amount due shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 3 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555881_005" name="2" temporalId="s18C_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="PaymentOnTheSpot">For the purposes of this section
                    <term>payment
                    on the
                spot</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">即場付款</term>) includes payment at the time of
                collecting goods on which work has been done or in respect of which service has been
                provided.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555881_012" name="3" temporalId="s18C_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subsection (1) shall not apply where the supply of the goods or the doing of the service is contrary to law, or where the service done is such that payment is not legally enforceable.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1980/45">45 of 1980 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1978 c. 31 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833394_002" name="s18D" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18D"><num value="18D">18D.</num><heading>Procuring entry in certain records by deception</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555896_040" name="1" temporalId="s18D_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who dishonestly, with a view to gain for himself or another or with intent to cause loss to another, by any deception (whether or not such deception was the sole or main inducement) procures the making, omission, altering, abstracting, concealing or destruction of an entry in a record of a bank or deposit-taking company, or any subsidiary thereof the principal business of which is the provision of credit, shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555912_005" name="2" temporalId="s18D_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><def name="Bank"><leadIn><term>bank</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">銀行</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555912_020" name="a" temporalId="s18D_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a bank within the meaning of <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Banking Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555912_028" name="b" temporalId="s18D_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>a bank—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555912_036" name="i" temporalId="s18D_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><def name="Incorporated">incorporated by or under the law or other authority
                            in any place outside Hong Kong, and in this respect
                                <term>incorporated</term>
                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">成立為法團</term>) includes established;
                            and</def></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411555912_043" name="ii" temporalId="s18D_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>which is not a bank within the meaning of <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Banking Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/49">49 of 1995 s. 53</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></def><def name="Deception"><term>deception</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欺騙手段</term>) has the same meaning as in
                    <ref>section 17</ref>;</def><def name="DeposittakingCompany"><term>deposit-taking
                    company</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">接受存款公司</term>) means a deposit-taking company or
                restricted licence bank within the meaning of <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Banking
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap155">Cap. 155</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/49">49 of 1995 s.
                    53</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Record"><leadIn><term>record</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">紀錄</term>) includes—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555927_026" name="a" temporalId="s18D_2_a-1"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any document or record used in the ordinary business of a bank or deposit-taking company, or any subsidiary thereof the principal business of which is the provision of credit; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555927_034" name="b" temporalId="s18D_2_b-1"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any document or record so used which is kept otherwise than in a legible form and is capable of being reproduced in a legible form;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Subsidiary"><term>subsidiary</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附屬公司</term>) has the same meaning as in the
                Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; 920)</sourceNote></def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833409_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>False accounting</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411555959_048" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a person dishonestly, with a view to gain for himself or another or with intent to cause loss to another—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411555959_056" name="a" temporalId="s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>destroys, defaces, conceals or falsifies any account or any record or document made or required for any accounting purpose; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411555959_064" name="b" temporalId="s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in furnishing information for any purpose produces or makes use of any account, or any such record or document as aforesaid, which to his knowledge is or may be misleading, false or deceptive in a material particular,</content></paragraph><continued>he shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555974_011" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this section a person who makes or concurs in making in an account, record or document an entry which is or may be misleading, false or deceptive in a material particular, or who omits or concurs in omitting a material particular from an account, record or document, is to be treated as falsifying the account, record or document.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/23">23 of 1993 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411555974_019" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="Record">For the purposes of this section,
                    <term>record</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">紀錄</term>) includes a record kept by means of a
                    computer.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1993/23">23 of 1993 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 17 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833425_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Liability of company officers for certain offences by company</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556005_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an offence committed by a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>body corporate under <ref>section 17</ref>, <ref>18</ref>, <ref>18A</ref>, <ref>18B</ref>, <ref>18D</ref>, <ref>19</ref> or <ref>22(2)</ref> is proved to have been committed with the consent or connivance of any director, manager, secretary or other similar officer of the body corporate, or any person who was purporting to act in any such capacity, he as well as the body corporate shall be guilty of that offence, and shall be liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/45">45 of 1980 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1991/ln16">L.N. 16 of 1991</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556005_012" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the affairs of a body corporate are managed by its members, this section
                shall apply in relation to the acts and defaults of a member in
                connexion
                with his functions of management as if he were a director of the body
                corporate.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 18 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833440_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>False statements by company directors, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556037_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an officer of a body corporate or unincorporated association (or person purporting to act as such) with intent to deceive members or creditors of the body corporate or association about its affairs, publishes or concurs in publishing a written statement or account which to his knowledge is or may be misleading, false or deceptive in a material particular, he shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/13">13 of 1974 s. 9</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556052_005" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this section a person who has entered into a security for the benefit of a body corporate or association is to be treated as a creditor of it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556052_013" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the affairs of a body corporate or association are managed by its
                members, this section shall apply to any statement which a member publishes or
                concurs in publishing in
                connexion
                with his functions of management as if he were an officer of the body corporate or
                association.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 19 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833456_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Suppression, etc. of documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556068_027" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who dishonestly, with a view to gain for himself or another or with intent to cause loss to another, destroys, defaces or conceals any valuable security, any will or other testamentary document or any original document of or belonging to, or filed or deposited in, any court or any government department shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556083_005" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who dishonestly, with a view to gain for himself or another or with intent to cause loss to another, by any deception (whether or not such deception was the sole or main inducement) procures the execution of a valuable security shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1986/46">46 of 1986 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556083_013" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subsection (2) shall apply in relation to the making, acceptance, indorsement, alteration, cancellation or destruction in whole or in part of a valuable security, and in relation to the signing or sealing of any paper or other material in order that it may be made or converted into, or used or dealt with as a valuable security, as if that were the execution of a valuable security.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556099_005" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><def name="Deception"><term>deception</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">欺騙手段</term>) has the same meaning as in
                    <ref>section 17</ref>; and</def><def name="ValuableSecurity"><term>valuable
                    security</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有價產權書</term>) means any document creating,
                transferring, surrendering, or releasing any right to, in or over property, or
                authorizing the payment of money or delivery of any property, or evidencing the
                creation, transfer, surrender or release of any such right, or the payment of money
                or delivery of any property, or the satisfaction of any obligation.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 20 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833456_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Blackmail</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556130_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person commits blackmail if, with a view to gain for himself or another or with intent to cause loss to another, he makes any unwarranted demand with menaces; and for this purpose a demand with menaces is unwarranted unless the person making it does so in the belief—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556130_012" name="a" temporalId="s23_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that he has reasonable grounds for making the demand; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556130_020" name="b" temporalId="s23_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the use of the menaces is a proper means of reinforcing the demand.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556130_027" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The nature of the act or omission demanded is
                immaterial,
                and it is also immaterial whether the menaces relate to action to be taken by the
                person making the demand.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556130_035" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person who commits blackmail shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 14 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556130_043" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person who has in his possession or under his control any letter or writing making any unwarranted demand of any person with menaces shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 10 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556146_005" name="5" temporalId="s23_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person does not commit an offence under subsection (4) if he proves that he had the letter or writing in his possession or control otherwise than with intent to utter it.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 21 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Offences
        relating
        to Goods Stolen, etc.</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402833472_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Handling stolen goods</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556161_026" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person handles stolen goods if (otherwise than in the course of the stealing)
                knowing or believing them to be stolen goods he dishonestly receives the goods, or
                dishonestly undertakes or assists in their retention, removal, disposal or
                realization by or for the benefit of another person, or if he arranges to do
                so.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556161_034" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who handles stolen goods shall be guilty of an offence and shall be
                liable on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 14 years.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 22 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833487_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-24" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Advertising rewards for return of goods stolen or lost</heading><content>Where any public advertisement of a reward for the return of any goods which have
            been stolen or lost uses any words to the effect that no questions will be asked, or
            that the person producing the goods will be safe from apprehension or inquiry, or that
            any money paid for the purchase of the goods or advanced by way of loan on them will be
            repaid, the person advertising the reward and any person who prints or publishes the
            advertisement shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
            at
            level 1.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 23 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402833487_003" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Scope of offences relating to stolen goods</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556208_004" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The provisions of this Ordinance relating to goods which have been stolen shall apply whether the stealing occurred in Hong Kong or elsewhere, and whether it occurred before or after the commencement of this Ordinance, provided that the stealing (if not an offence under this Ordinance) amounted to an offence where and at the time when the goods were stolen; and references to stolen goods shall be construed accordingly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556208_012" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of those provisions references to stolen goods shall include, in addition to the goods originally stolen and parts of them (whether in their original state or not)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556208_020" name="a" temporalId="s26_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any other goods which directly or indirectly represent or have at any time represented the stolen goods in the hands of the thief as being the proceeds of any disposal or realization of the whole or part of the goods stolen or of goods so representing the stolen goods; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556224_006" name="b" temporalId="s26_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any other goods which directly or indirectly represent or have at any time represented the stolen goods in the hands of a handler of the stolen goods or any part of them as being the proceeds of any disposal or realization of the whole or part of the stolen goods handled by him or of goods so representing them.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556224_013" name="3" temporalId="s26_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No goods shall be regarded as having continued to be stolen goods after they have been restored to the person from whom they were stolen or to other lawful possession or custody, or after that person and any other person claiming through him have otherwise ceased as regards those goods to have any right to restitution in respect of the theft.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556224_021" name="4" temporalId="s26_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="Steal,Theft,Thief">For the purposes of the provisions of this Ordinance
                relating to goods which have been stolen (including subsections (1) to (3)) goods
                obtained in Hong Kong or elsewhere either by blackmail or in the circumstances
                described in <ref>section 17(1)</ref> shall be regarded as stolen; and
                    <term>steal</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">偷竊</term>),
                    <term>theft</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">盜竊罪</term>) and
                    <term>thief</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">竊賊</term>) shall be construed accordingly.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 24 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Possession of Housebreaking
        Implements, etc.</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402833503_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Going equipped for stealing, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556255_049" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who, when not at his place of abode, has with him any article for
                use in the course of or in
                connexion
                with any burglary, theft or cheat shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable
                on conviction upon indictment to imprisonment for 3 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556271_005" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a person is charged with an offence under this section, proof that he had
                with him any article made or adapted for use in committing a burglary, theft or
                cheat shall be evidence that he had it with him for such use.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556271_013" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="Cheat">For the purposes of this section an offence under <ref>section
                    14</ref> of taking a conveyance shall be treated as theft, and
                    <term>cheat</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">行騙</term>) means an offence under <ref>section
                    17</ref>.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 25 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Enforcement and Procedure</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402833503_004" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Search for stolen goods</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556286_041" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If it is made to appear by information on oath before a magistrate that there is reasonable cause to believe that any person has in his custody or possession or on his premises any stolen goods, the magistrate may grant a warrant to search for and seize the same.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556286_049" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of 1995 s. 52</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556302_005" name="3" temporalId="s28_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where under this section a person is authorized to search premises for stolen goods, he may enter and search the premises accordingly, and may seize any goods he believes to be stolen goods.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556302_013" name="4" temporalId="s28_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><ref>Section 102</ref> of the Criminal Procedure Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap221">Cap. 221</ref>) (which makes provision for the disposal of property connected with offences) shall apply to property which has come into the possession of the police under this section as it applies to property which has come into the possession of the police in the circumstances mentioned in that section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556302_021" name="5" temporalId="s28_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>This section is to be construed in accordance with <ref>section 26</ref> and in subsection (2) of this section the references to handling stolen goods shall include any corresponding offence committed before the commencement of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 26 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833534_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-24" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Evidence and procedure on charge of theft, handling stolen goods, and obtaining by deception</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556333_050" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any number of persons may be charged in one indictment, information or charge with reference to the same theft, with having at different times or at the same time handled all or any of the stolen goods, and the persons so charged may be tried together.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556349_005" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On the trial of 2 or more persons charged or indicted for jointly handling any stolen goods, the court or jury may find any one of the accused guilty if the court or jury is satisfied that he handled all or any of the stolen goods, whether or not he did so jointly with the other accused or any of them.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556349_013" name="3" temporalId="s29_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where a person is being proceeded against for handling stolen goods (but not for any offence other than handling stolen goods), then at any stage of the proceedings, if evidence has been given of his having or arranging to have in his possession the goods the subject of the charge, or of his undertaking or assisting in, or arranging to undertake or assist in, their retention, removal, disposal or realization, the following evidence shall be admissible for the purpose of proving that he knew or believed the goods to be stolen goods—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556349_021" name="a" temporalId="s29_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>evidence that he has had in his possession, or has undertaken or assisted in the retention, removal, disposal or realization of, stolen goods from any theft taking place not earlier than 12 months before the offence charged; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556364_006" name="b" temporalId="s29_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>(if 7
                    days’
                    notice in writing has been given to him of the intention to prove the
                    conviction) evidence that he has within the 5 years preceding the date of the
                    offence charged been convicted of theft or of handling stolen goods.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556364_013" name="4" temporalId="s29_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In any proceedings for the theft of anything in the course of transmission (whether by post or otherwise), or for handling stolen goods from such a theft, a statutory declaration made by any person that he despatched or received or failed to receive any goods or postal packet, or that any goods or postal packet, when despatched or received by him were in a particular state or condition, shall be admissible as evidence of the facts stated in the declaration, subject to the following conditions—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556364_021" name="a" temporalId="s29_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a statutory declaration shall only be admissible where and to the extent to which oral evidence to the like effect would have been admissible in the proceedings; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556364_029" name="b" temporalId="s29_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a statutory declaration shall only be admissible if at least 7 days before
                    the hearing or trial a copy of it has been given to the person charged, and he
                    has not, at least 3 days before the hearing or trial or within such further time
                    as the court may in special circumstances allow, given the prosecutor written
                    notice requiring the attendance at the hearing or trial of the person making the
                    declaration.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556380_005" name="5" temporalId="s29_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>This section is to be construed in accordance with <ref>section 26</ref>, and in subsection <ref>(3)(b)</ref> of this section the reference to handling stolen goods shall include any corresponding offence committed before the commencement of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556380_013" name="6" temporalId="s29_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>In any proceedings for an offence under <ref>section 17</ref>, <ref>18</ref>, <ref>18A</ref> or <ref>18B</ref>—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/45">45 of 1980 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556380_021" name="a" temporalId="s29_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of 1995 s. 53</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556380_029" name="b" temporalId="s29_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>where—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411556380_037" name="i" temporalId="s29_6_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any cheque or other bill of exchange bears any writing purporting to be written by or on behalf of the bank or other person on whom the cheque or bill of exchange was drawn and indicating that payment of the cheque or bill of exchange was refused upon presentation on or after becoming due; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411556395_007" name="ii" temporalId="s29_6_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any document purporting to be made by or on behalf of the bank or other person on whom any cheque or bill of exchange was drawn bears any writing indicating that payment of the cheque or bill of exchange was refused upon presentation on or after becoming due,</content></subparagraph><continued>then payment of the cheque or bill of exchange shall, until the contrary is proved, be deemed to have been so refused;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556395_020" name="c" temporalId="s29_6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the provisions of this subsection shall apply whether or not the bank or other person on whom the cheque or bill of exchange was drawn carries on business in Hong Kong and whether the writing was written on the cheque or bill of exchange or the document within or outside Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556395_028" name="d" temporalId="s29_6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any document purporting to be a document of the kind specified in paragraph (b) or purporting to be a copy or reproduction of any such document shall be admitted in evidence on its production by the prosecution without further proof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556411_006" name="e" temporalId="s29_6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>where any cheque or bill of exchange or any document of the kind specified in paragraph (b), or any copy or reproduction of such document, is to be adduced in evidence, a copy thereof shall be served on the defendant not less than 14 days before the commencement of the trial;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556411_014" name="f" temporalId="s29_6_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>if service is not effected in accordance with paragraph (e), the court may on application by the accused grant an adjournment for such period as it considers just.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 27 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833550_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Orders for restitution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556458_004" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where goods have been stolen, and a person is convicted of any offence with reference to the theft (whether or not the stealing is the gist of his offence), the court by or before which the offender is convicted may on the conviction exercise any of the following powers—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556458_012" name="a" temporalId="s30_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the court may order anyone having possession or control of the goods to restore them to any person entitled to recover them from him; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556458_020" name="b" temporalId="s30_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on the application of a person entitled to recover from the person convicted any other goods directly or indirectly representing the first-mentioned goods (as being the proceeds of any disposal or realization of the whole or part of them or of goods so representing them), the court may order those other goods to be delivered or transferred to the applicant; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556473_006" name="c" temporalId="s30_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on the application of a person who, if the first-mentioned goods were in the possession of the person convicted, would be entitled to recover them from him, the court may order that a sum not exceeding the value of those goods shall be paid to the applicant out of any money of the person convicted which was taken out of his possession on his apprehension.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556473_013" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where under subsection (1) the court has power on a person’s conviction to make an order against him both under paragraph (b) and under paragraph (c) with reference to the stealing of the same goods, the court may make orders under both paragraphs provided that the applicant for the orders does not thereby recover more than the value of those goods.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556489_005" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where under subsection (1) the court on a person’s conviction makes an order under paragraph (a) for the restoration of any goods, and it appears to the court that the person convicted has sold the goods to a person acting in good faith, or has borrowed money on the security of them from a person so acting, then on the application of the purchaser or lender the court may order that there shall be paid to the applicant, out of any money of the person convicted which was taken out of his possession on his apprehension, a sum not exceeding the amount paid for the purchase by the applicant or, as the case may be, the amount owed to the applicant in respect of the loan.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556505_005" name="4" temporalId="s30_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="TheAvailableDocuments">The court shall not exercise the powers conferred by
                this section unless in the opinion of the court the relevant facts sufficiently
                appear from evidence given at the trial or the available documents, together with
                admissions made by or on behalf of any person in
                connexion
                with any proposed exercise of the powers; and for this purpose
                    <term>the
                    available
                documents</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">可用的文件</term>) means any written statements or
                admissions which were made for use, and would have been admissible, as evidence at
                the trial, the depositions taken at any committal proceedings and any written
                statements or admissions used as evidence in those proceedings.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556520_004" name="5" temporalId="s30_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any order under this section shall be treated as an order for the restitution of property within the meaning of <ref>section 83X</ref> of the Criminal Procedure Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap221">Cap. 221</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556520_012" name="6" temporalId="s30_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>References in this section to stealing are to be construed in accordance with <ref>section 26(1)</ref> and (4).</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 28 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">General and Consequential
                Provisions</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402833550_003" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Husband and wife</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556551_033" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance shall apply in relation to the parties to a marriage, and to property belonging to the wife or husband whether or not by reason of an interest derived from the marriage, as it would apply if they were not married and any such interest subsisted independently of the marriage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556567_005" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsection (4), a person shall have the same right to bring proceedings against that person’s wife or husband for any offence (whether under this Ordinance or otherwise) as if they were not married.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2003/23">23 of 2003 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556567_013" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2003/23">23 of 2003 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556567_021" name="4" temporalId="s31_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><leadIn>Proceedings shall not be instituted against a person for any offence of stealing or doing unlawful damage to property which at the time of the offence belongs to that person’s wife or husband, or for any attempt, incitement or conspiracy to commit such an offence, unless the proceedings are instituted by or with the consent of the Secretary for Justice:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s31_4_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556567_036" name="a" temporalId="s31_4_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>this subsection shall not apply to proceedings against a person for an offence—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411556567_044" name="i" temporalId="s31_4_proviso_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if that person is charged with committing the offence jointly with the wife or husband; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411556567_052" name="ii" temporalId="s31_4_proviso_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if by virtue of any judicial decree or order (wherever made) that person and the wife or husband are at the time of the offence under no obligation to cohabit; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556567_059" name="b" temporalId="s31_4_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>this subsection shall not prevent the arrest, or the issue of a warrant for the arrest, of a person for an offence, or the remand in custody or admission to bail of a person charged with an offence, where the arrest (if without a warrant) is made, or the warrant of arrest issues on an information laid, by a person other than the wife or husband.</content></paragraph></proviso></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 30 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833565_002" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Verdict</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556598_064" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If on the trial of any information, charge or indictment for an offence specified in the first column of the <ref>Schedule</ref> it is proved that the accused is not guilty of that offence but guilty of one of the offences specified opposite thereto in the second column of that <ref>Schedule</ref> or of attempting or being a party to an offence so specified, the accused shall be acquitted of the offence originally charged and shall be convicted of such other offence or of attempting or being a party to such other offence and be liable to be punished accordingly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556629_004" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The references in the <ref>Schedule</ref> to numbered sections and subsections shall be construed to include every offence under the section or subsection so numbered in this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556629_012" name="3" temporalId="s32_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this section or in the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall exclude the application to any offence of any other law authorizing a person to be found guilty of an offence other than that with which he is charged.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833581_002" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Effect on civil proceedings and rights</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556645_020" name="1" temporalId="s33_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person shall not be excused, by reason that to do so may incriminate that person or the wife or husband of that person of an offence under this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556645_028" name="a" temporalId="s33_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>from answering any question put to that person in proceedings for the recovery or administration of any property, for the execution of any trust or for an account of any property or dealings with property; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556645_036" name="b" temporalId="s33_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>from complying with any order made in any such proceedings,</content></paragraph><continued>but no statement or admission made by a person in answering a question put or complying with an order made as aforesaid shall, in proceedings for an offence under this Ordinance, be admissible in evidence against that person or (unless they married after the making of the statement or admission) against the wife or husband of that person.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556661_004" name="2" temporalId="s33_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding any enactment to the contrary, where property has been stolen or obtained by fraud or other wrongful means, the title to that or any other property shall not be affected by reason only of the conviction of the offender.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 31 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833581_004" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Effect on existing law and construction of references to offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556692_004" name="1" temporalId="s34_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The following offences at common law are hereby abolished for all purposes not relating to offences committed before the commencement of this Ordinance, that is to say, any offence at common law of larceny, robbery, burglary, receiving stolen property, obtaining property by threats, extortion by colour of office or franchise, false accounting by public officers, concealment of treasure trove and, except as regards offences relating to the public revenue, cheating.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556707_005" name="2" temporalId="s34_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Except as regards offences committed before the commencement of this Ordinance, and except as the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411556707_013" name="a" temporalId="s34_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="Receive,Receiver">references in any enactment passed before this
                    Ordinance to an offence abolished or contained in any provision repealed by this
                    Ordinance shall, subject to any express amendment or repeal made by this
                    Ordinance, have effect as references to the corresponding offence under this
                    Ordinance, and in any such enactment
                        <term>receive</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">收受</term>) (when the expression relates to an
                    offence of receiving) shall mean handle, and
                        <term>receiver</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">收受贓物者</term>) shall be construed accordingly;
                    and</def></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411556723_005" name="b" temporalId="s34_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>without prejudice to paragraph (a), references in any enactment, whenever passed, to theft or stealing (including references to stolen goods), and references to robbery, burglary, aggravated burglary or handling stolen goods, shall be construed in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance, including those of <ref>section 26</ref>.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 32 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402833596_002" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Transitional provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411556739_033" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><ref>Sections 29</ref> and <ref>30</ref> shall apply in relation to proceedings for an offence committed before the commencement of this Ordinance as they would apply in relation to proceedings for a corresponding offence under this Ordinance and shall so apply in place of any corresponding enactment repealed by this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411556754_005" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsection (1), no repeal or amendment by this Ordinance of any enactment relating to procedure or evidence, or to the jurisdiction or powers of any court, or to the effect of a conviction, shall affect the operation of the enactment in relation to offences committed before the commencement of this Ordinance or to proceedings for any such offence.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1968 c. 60 s. 35(2) &amp; (3) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><schedule id="ID_1438402833612_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap210/s32">s.
                32</ref>]</note><heading>Alternative
            Verdicts</heading><content>
            
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="repeat_header">
                
                <col width="6%"></col>
                
                <col width="23%"></col>
                
                <col width="13%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="49%"></col>
                
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="valign_bottom">
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Offences</center>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="valign_bottom">
                            
                            <p class="align_center">Other offences of which the defendant
                                may be found guilty</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="9" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>1.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="9">
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Theft (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(i) </p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Taking
                            conveyance without authority (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            14</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining property by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            17</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining pecuniary advantage by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining services by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18A</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Evasion of liability by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18B</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(vi)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Making off without payment (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18C</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(vii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">False accounting (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            19</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(viii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Handling stolen goods (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            24</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(ix)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Going equipped for stealing (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            27</ref>).</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="5" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>2.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="5">
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Robbery (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            10</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Assault with intent to rob (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            10</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Blackmail (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            23(1)</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Handling stolen goods (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            24</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6">
                        <p class="align_right">(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Common assault.</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="4" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>3.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="4">
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Assault with
                            intent to rob (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 10</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p class="align_right">(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p class="align_right">(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Robbery (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            10</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p class="align_right">(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Blackmail (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            23(1)</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p class="align_right">(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Common assault.</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="4" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>4.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="4">
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Burglary (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            11</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Handling stolen goods (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            24</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Going equipped for stealing (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            27</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Inflicting grievous bodily harm.</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="8" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>5.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="8">
                        
                        <p class="align_left">Aggravated burglary</p>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">(<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            12</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Burglary (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            11</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Handling stolen goods (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            24</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Going equipped for stealing (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            27</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Inflicting grievous bodily harm.</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(vi)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Possession of arms.</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(vii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Possession of imitation firearm.</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(viii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Possession of explosive.</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>6.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_left">Taking conveyance without authority (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            14(1)</ref>).</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right"></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Going equipped for stealing (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            27</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="8" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>7.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="8">
                        
                        <p class="align_left">Obtaining property by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            17</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining pecuniary advantage by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining services by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18A</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Evasion of liability by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18B</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Making off without payment (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18C</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(vi)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Blackmail (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section<inline class="width_3"> </inline>23(1)</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(vii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified ">Handling stolen goods (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            24</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(viii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Going equipped for stealing (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            27</ref>).</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="5" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>8.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="5">
                        
                        <p class="align_left">Obtaining pecuniary advantage by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining property by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            17</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Evasion of liability by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18B</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Blackmail (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section<inline class="width_3"> </inline>23(1)</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Handling stolen goods (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            24</ref>).</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="6" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>9.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="6">
                        
                        <p class="align_left">Evasion of liability by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18B</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining property by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            17</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining pecuniary advantage by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining services by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18A</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Making off without payment (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18C</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(vi)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Blackmail (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            23(1)</ref>).</p>
                        
                        
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="5" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>10.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="5">
                        
                        <p class="align_left">Making off without payment (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18C</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Theft
                                (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            9</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining property by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            17</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining services by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18A</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Evasion of liability by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18B</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Blackmail (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            23(1)</ref>).</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    
                    <td rowspan="7" class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        
                        <p>11.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td rowspan="7">
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Blackmail (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            23(1)</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(i)</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining
                            property by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            17</ref>).</p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(ii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining pecuniary advantage by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Obtaining services by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18A</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(iv)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Evasion of liability by deception (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18B</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(v)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Making off without payment (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            18C</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(vi)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Possession of blackmailing letter (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            23(4)</ref>).</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_6 align_right">
                        <p>(vii)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified">Common assault.</p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
            </table>
        </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1980/45">45 of 1980 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of<inline class="width_3"> </inline>1995 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 102</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>