<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 81</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>81</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap81!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-12-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403566264_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-01">
            <content>To provide for control of the use of water-front areas by persons, vehicles and
                vessels and generally for control of the handling of cargo in such
                areas.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[26 July 1974]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1974/ln154">L.N. 154 of 1974</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403566264_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Port Control (Cargo Working Areas) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403566280_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Berth"><term>berth</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">停泊</term>) means to
                                    berth, moor, anchor or secure any vessel;</def><def name="Cargo"><term>cargo</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">貨物</term>) means any
                                    freight carried, or intended to be carried, in or on any vessel
                                    or vehicle and means also ships’ stores;</def><def name="CargoContainer"><term>cargo
                                                container</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">貨櫃</term>) includes an
                                    empty container of any kind used, or intended to be used, for
                                    the carriage of cargo and includes also any packing material
                                    used, or intended to be used, for or in
                                    connexion
                                    with the carriage of cargo;</def><def name="Director"><term>Director</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">處長</term>) means the
                                    Director of Marine;</def><def name="ExcludedWaterfront"><term>excluded
                                                water-front</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">例外的海旁</term>) means an
                                    area declared under <ref>section 3</ref> to be an excluded
                                    water-front;</def><def name="Owner"><leadIn><term>owner</term>
                                                  (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414059690_054" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to any cargo or cargo container, means any person being or holding himself out to be the owner, importer, exporter, consignee, agent or person in possession of, or beneficially interested in, or having any control of, or power of disposition over, the cargo or cargo container;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414059706_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to a vehicle, includes the person in whose name the vehicle is registered and the person by whom the vehicle is kept and used and, in relation to a vehicle which is the subject of a hiring agreement or hire purchase agreement, means the person in possession of the vehicle under that agreement;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414059706_014" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in relation to a vessel, includes the registered or licensed owner of the vessel and, in relation to a vessel which is the subject of a hiring agreement, means the person in possession of the vessel under that agreement;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def><def name="PublicCargoWorkingArea"><term>public
                                                cargo working
                                    area</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公眾貨物裝卸區</term>) means
                                    an area declared under <ref>section 3</ref> to be a public cargo
                                    working area;</def><def name="PublicWaterfront"><term>public
                                                water-front</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公眾海旁</term>) means an
                                    area declared under <ref>section 3</ref> to be a public
                                    water-front;</def><def name="Vehicle"><term>vehicle</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車輛</term>) means any
                                    vehicle intended or adapted for use on roads;</def><def name="Vessel"><term>vessel</term>
                                                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船隻</term>) includes any
                                    ship, boat, junk or lorcha and any other description of vessel
                                    used in navigation and includes also any floating wharf, ramp,
                                    pontoon or landing place.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403566295_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Declaration of areas to be public cargo working areas, public water-fronts and
            excluded water-fronts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414059784_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The
                Secretary
                for Transport and Logistics may, by order published in the
                Gazette, declare any area of unleased Government land (including any road), and any
                area of water adjoining any such area, to be—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/4">4 of 1995 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998
                        s. 105</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414059784_019" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a public cargo working area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414059784_027" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a public water-front; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414059784_035" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an excluded water-front.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059784_042" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In any order made under subsection (1) an area may be defined by reference to a
                plan deposited in the Land Registry, and a copy of any such plan purporting to be
                certified by the Director as a true copy thereof may be admitted as evidence of the
                plan without further proof in any criminal or civil proceedings before any court or
                    magistrate.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8
                        of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059799_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any order made and any plan prepared and deposited under the provisions of this
                section in force immediately before the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of the Port Control (Cargo
                Working Areas) (Amendment) Ordinance 1982 (<ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982</ref>)
                shall be deemed for all purposes to have been made, or prepared and deposited, as
                the case may be, under this section as amended by that Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of
                        1982 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1656995217362_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>
                Commencement
                date:
                10 January
                1983.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403566295_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Public cargo working areas, etc. deemed to be public places</heading><content>Every public cargo working area, public
            water-front or
            excluded
            water-front
            shall be a public place for the purposes of the Summary Offences Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap228">Cap. 228</ref>).</content></section><section id="ID_1438403566311_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Director’s powers in respect of abandoned cargo, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414059862_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Without prejudice to any other provisions of this Ordinance relating to the
                deposit of any cargo or cargo container in a public cargo working area or a public
                water-front, if the Director is satisfied that any cargo or cargo container has been
                left or abandoned in a public cargo working area or public water-front, he may, by
                affixing to such cargo or cargo container in a prominent position a notice in a form
                specified by him, seize such cargo or cargo container.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059877_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director shall cause a copy of a notice affixed under subsection (1) to be
                displayed in a conspicuous place within the public cargo working area or public
                water-front, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059877_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director may cause any cargo or cargo container seized under subsection (1)
                to be removed to a place of storage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059893_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The owner of any cargo or cargo container seized under subsection (1) may,
                within 14 days after the date of seizure, claim the same by notice in writing to the
                Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059893_013" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>The Director shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414059893_021" name="a" temporalId="s5_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on receipt of a claim in accordance with subsection (4); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414059893_029" name="b" temporalId="s5_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on payment to him of the prescribed fees and the costs, if any, of removal
                    and storage within the period referred to in that subsection,</content></paragraph><continued>release the cargo or cargo container to the claimant.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059893_042" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Where in respect of any cargo or cargo container seized under subsection
                (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414059893_050" name="a" temporalId="s5_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>no claim is made in accordance with subsection (4); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414059893_058" name="b" temporalId="s5_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the prescribed fees and the costs, if any, of removal and storage are not
                    paid within the period referred to in that subsection,</content></paragraph><continued>the Director may cause such cargo or cargo container to be sold or otherwise
                disposed of in such manner as he thinks fit and the proceeds, if any, of such sale
                or disposal, after deduction of the prescribed fees and the costs, if any, of
                removal and storage, and of the sale or disposal, shall be paid into the general
                revenue of Hong Kong at the expiry of 3 months from the date of such sale or
                disposal if not previously claimed by the owner of the cargo or cargo
                container.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059909_011" name="7" temporalId="s5_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>No action in respect of any damage to property shall lie against the Director
                or any other officer performing or exercising any function, duty or power under this
                section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059909_019" name="8" temporalId="s5_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Any person who interferes with or removes any cargo or cargo container seized
                under subsection (1), unless authorized or directed to do so by the Director,
                commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 4 and to imprisonment for 1 year.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403566326_001" name="s5A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5A"><num value="5A">5A.</num><heading>Obligation to give certain information in respect of offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414059971_004" name="1" temporalId="s5A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the person in charge of a vessel or the driver of a vehicle is suspected of having committed an offence under this Ordinance, any person (including the owner of the vessel or vehicle, and the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle, as the case may be, at the time of the alleged offence) shall, on demand made by the Director or a supervisor within 3 months after the date of the alleged offence, give to the Director or a supervisor in the manner prescribed in this section the name and address of the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle, as the case may be, at the time of the alleged offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059987_005" name="2" temporalId="s5A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A demand under subsection (1) may be made orally or by means of a notice served personally or by post on the person to whom it is made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414059987_013" name="3" temporalId="s5A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where a demand under subsection (1) is made orally to any person he shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414059987_021" name="a" temporalId="s5A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if he was the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle at the time of the alleged offence, give immediately his name and address; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060002_006" name="b" temporalId="s5A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if he was not the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle at the time of the alleged offence, give the information required under subsection (1) to the Director or to a specified supervisor either orally or in writing within 21 days after the date of the demand.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414060002_013" name="4" temporalId="s5A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A notice served under subsection (2) shall require the person to whom it is addressed—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414060002_021" name="a" temporalId="s5A_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to furnish to the Director, within 21 days after the date of the notice, a written statement, in such form as may be specified in the notice, giving the name and address of the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle, as the case may be, at the time of the alleged offence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060018_006" name="b" temporalId="s5A_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to sign the statement.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414060018_013" name="5" temporalId="s5A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Subject to subsection (6), any person who contravenes subsection (1) commits an
                offence and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 2 and to imprisonment for 3 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414060018_021" name="6" temporalId="s5A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In proceedings for an offence under subsection (5), it shall be a defence to show that the accused person did not know, and could not with reasonable diligence have ascertained, the name or address of the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle, as the case may be, at the time of the alleged offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414060018_029" name="7" temporalId="s5A_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="AllegedOffence"><term>alleged
                    offence</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指控罪行</term>) means the suspected offence referred
                to in subsection (1);</def><def name="Supervisor"><term>supervisor</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主管</term>) means a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>person appointed under regulations made under this Ordinance to be a
                supervisor at a public cargo working area or public water-front.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403566326_003" name="s5B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5B"><num value="5B">5B.</num><heading>Proof in summary proceedings of identity of driver</heading><leadIn>If, in any summary proceedings for an offence under this Ordinance, there is produced to the magistrate a statement which—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414060080_012" name="a" temporalId="s5B_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>purports to have been signed by the accused person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060080_020" name="b" temporalId="s5B_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>was furnished in accordance with a notice served on him under <ref>section 5A(2)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060080_028" name="c" temporalId="s5B_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>states that the accused person was the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle, as the case may be, at the time of the offence,</content></paragraph><continued>the magistrate shall admit the statement as prima facie evidence that the accused person was the person in charge of the vessel or driver of the vehicle at the time of the offence.</continued><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403566342_001" name="s5C" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5C"><num value="5C">5C.</num><heading>Copies of notices admissible as evidence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414060111_004" name="1" temporalId="s5C_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where under this Ordinance a notice is required to be affixed to any cargo or cargo container or displayed in any place, a document purporting to be a copy of such notice, signed and certified as a true copy by the Director or by any person authorized by him, in writing, in that behalf, shall be admissible in any criminal or civil proceedings before any court or magistrate on its production without further proof as evidence of the original notice and, until the contrary is proved, the court or magistrate shall presume that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414060127_005" name="a" temporalId="s5C_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the signature and certification to the document is that of the Director or a person authorized by him, in writing, in that behalf; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060127_013" name="b" temporalId="s5C_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the document is a true copy of the original notice.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414060127_020" name="2" temporalId="s5C_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall prejudice the admissibility of any evidence which would be admissible apart from the provisions of this section.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403566342_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414060174_018" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations for all or any of the
                following purposes—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/64">64 of 1999 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414060174_026" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>providing for any matter or thing which is to be or may be prescribed under
                    this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060189_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>regulating entry to and the use of any public cargo working area, public
                    water-front or excluded water-front;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060189_014" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>controlling or providing for the control of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414060189_022" name="i" temporalId="s6_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the handling, inspection or weighing of cargo or cargo containers in
                        any public cargo working area, public water-front or excluded
                        water-front;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414060189_030" name="ii" temporalId="s6_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>vessels and vehicles in any public cargo working area, public
                        water-front or excluded water-front;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060189_037" name="ca" temporalId="s6_1_ca"><num value="ca">(ca)</num><content>empowering the Director to set aside areas in a public cargo working area,
                    public water-front or excluded
                    water-front
                    for purposes specified in the regulations;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s.
                        5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060189_045" name="cb" temporalId="s6_1_cb"><num value="cb">(cb)</num><content>empowering the Director to specify the type of cargo handling machinery and
                    equipment to be used in a public cargo working area, public water-front or
                    excluded water-front for any purpose specified by him and to specify conditions
                    subject to which such cargo handling machinery and equipment may be so
                        used;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060205_006" name="d" temporalId="s6_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>empowering the Director—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414060205_014" name="i" temporalId="s6_1_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to give directions in relation to such matters as may be
                        specified;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414060205_022" name="ii" temporalId="s6_1_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to take such action as may be necessary to give effect to any such
                        direction which is not complied with;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414060205_030" name="iii" temporalId="s6_1_d_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>to recover the cost of any such action taken by the Director;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060205_037" name="e" temporalId="s6_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>empowering the Director or any person authorized by him to require any
                    person using any public cargo working area, public water-front or excluded
                    water-front to provide his name and address;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s.
                            5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060221_006" name="f" temporalId="s6_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>empowering the Director to require persons using any public cargo working
                    area, public water-front or excluded water-front, and the owner of any cargo or
                    cargo container handled therein, to give any specified information in respect of
                    the use of such area or water-front or in respect of any such cargo or cargo
                    containers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060221_014" name="g" temporalId="s6_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>prescribing fees and charges;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s.
                            5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060221_022" name="h" temporalId="s6_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>empowering the Director to waive the payment of any fee or charge or to
                    remit any fee or charge so paid; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of 1982 s.
                            5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414060236_006" name="i" temporalId="s6_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>generally for the better carrying out of the purposes of this
                    Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414060236_013" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Regulations made under this section may provide that a contravention thereof
                shall be an offence and prescribe a penalty on conviction of any such offence not
                exceeding a fine
                at
                level 4 and imprisonment for a term not exceeding
                    <ref>1 year</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/56">56 of
                        1982 s.
                    5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></main></ordinance>