<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 107 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>107C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap107C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-07-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402557460_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-07-08">Use
                                                of
                                                Electric Power
                                                on
                                                the
                                                Tramway
                                                Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap107/s31">Cap. 107, sections
        31</ref>
      and <ref href="/hk/cap107/s34">34</ref>)
      <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[14 May 1902]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of
                                                  2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402557460_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>These rules may be cited as the Use of Electric Power on the Tramway Rules.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557476_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><leadIn>In the following rules, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Current"><term>current</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電流</term>) means an electric current exceeding
            one-thousandth part of one ampere; </def><def name="Energy"><term>energy</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">能量</term>) means electrical energy; </def><def name="Generator"><term>generator</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">發電機</term>) means the dynamo or dynamos or other
            electrical apparatus used for the generation of energy; </def><def name="Motor"><term>motor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">發動機</term>) means any electric motor carried on a car
            and used for the conversion of energy; </def><def name="Pipe"><term>pipe</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">喉管</term>) means any gas or water pipe, or other
            metallic pipe, structure or substance; </def><def name="Wire"><term>wire</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電線</term>) means any wire or apparatus used for
            telegraphic, telephonic, electrical signalling or other similar purposes.</def></section><section id="ID_1438402557492_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>Any dynamo used as a generator shall be of such pattern and construction as to be capable of producing a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>continuous current without appreciable pulsation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557492_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>One of the two conductors used for transmitting energy from the generator to the
            motors shall be in every case insulated from earth, and is hereinafter referred to as
            the
                    <b><i>line</i></b>;
            the other may be insulated throughout or may be uninsulated in such parts and to such
            extent as is provided in the following rules, and is hereinafter referred to as the
                    <b><i>return</i></b>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557507_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>Where any rails on which cars run, or any conductors laid between or within 1 m of such rails, form any part of a return such part may be uninsulated. All other returns or parts of a return shall be insulated, unless of such sectional area as will reduce the difference of potential between the ends of the uninsulated portion of the return below the limit laid down in <ref>rule 9</ref>. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of 1977</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557507_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>When any uninsulated conductor laid between or within 1 m of the rails forms any
            part of a return, it shall be electrically connected to the rails at distances apart not
            exceeding 30 m by means of copper strips having a sectional area of at least 40
            mm²,
            or by other means of equal conductivity. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of 1977</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557523_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><leadIn>When any part of a return is uninsulated it shall be connected with the negative
            terminal of the generator, and in such case the negative terminal of the generator shall
            also be directly connected, through the current indicator hereinafter mentioned, to two
            separate earth
            connexions
            which shall be placed not less than 20 m apart: </leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_proviso">Provided that in place of such two earth
            connexions
            the company may make one
            connexion
            to a main for water supply of not less than 75 mm internal diameter, with the consent of
            the owner thereof and of the person supplying the water, and provided that where, from
            the nature of the soil or for other reasons, the company can show to the satisfaction of
            an inspecting officer of the Government that the earth
            connexions
            herein specified cannot be constructed and maintained without undue expense, the
            provisions of this rule shall not apply. The earth
            connexions
            referred to in this rule shall be constructed, laid and maintained so as to secure
            electrical contact with the general mass of earth, and so that an electro-motive force
            not exceeding four volts shall suffice to produce a current of at least two amperes from
            one earth
            connexion
            to the other through the earth, and a test shall be made at least once in every month to
            ascertain whether this requirement is complied with. No portion of either earth
            connexion
            shall be placed within 2 m of any pipe except a main for water supply of not less than
            75
            mm internal diameter metallically connected to the earth
            connexions
            with the consents hereinbefore specified.</proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of 1977</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557538_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><leadIn>When the return is partly or entirely uninsulated the company shall in the construction and maintenance of the tramway—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438410848887_026" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>so separate the uninsulated return from the general mass of earth and from any pipe in the vicinity; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410848887_034" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>so connect together the several lengths of the rails; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410848887_042" name="c" temporalId="s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>adopt such means for reducing the difference produced by the current between the potential of the uninsulated return at any other point; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410848903_006" name="d" temporalId="s8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>so maintain the efficiency of the earth
                connexions
                specified in the preceding rules, </content></paragraph><continued>as to fulfil the following conditions—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438410848903_020" name="i" temporalId="s8_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>that the current passing from the earth
                connexions
                through the indicator to the generator shall not at any time exceed either
                1.2 A/km
                of single tramway line, or five per cent of the total current output of the
                    station;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of 1977</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438410848903_028" name="ii" temporalId="s8_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that if at any time and at any place a test be made by connecting a
                galvanometer or other current-indicator to the uninsulated return to any pipe in the
                vicinity, it shall always be possible to reverse the direction of any current
                indicated by interposing a battery of three
                Leclanché
                cells connected in series if the direction of the current is from the return to the
                pipe, or by interposing one
                Leclanché
                cell if the direction of the current is from the pipe to the return. </content></paragraph><continued>In order to provide a continuous indication that condition (i) is complied with, the company shall place in a conspicuous position a suitable properly connected and correctly marked current-indicator and shall keep it connected during the whole time that the line is charged. <br></br>The owner of any such pipe may require the company to permit him at reasonable times and intervals to ascertain by test that the conditions specified in (ii) are complied with as regards his pipe.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438402557554_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><content>When the return is partly or entirely uninsulated a continuous record shall be kept by the company of the difference of potential during the working of the tramway between the points of the uninsulated return farthest from and nearest to the generating station. If at any time such difference of potential exceeds the limit of seven volts, the company shall take immediate steps to reduce it below that limit.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557554_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><content>Every electrical
            connexion
            with any pipe shall be so arranged as to admit of easy examination, and shall be tested
            by the company at least once in every three months.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557585_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><content>Every line and every insulated return or part of a return except any feeder shall be constructed in sections not exceeding 0.8 km in length, and means shall be provided for insulating each such section for purposes of testing. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of 1977</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557585_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><leadIn>The insulation of the line and of the return when insulated, and of all feeders and
            other conductors, shall be so maintained that the leakage current shall not exceed 6
            mA/km of tramway. The leakage current shall be ascertained daily before or after the
            hours of running when the line is fully charged. If at any time it should be found that
            the leakage current exceeds 0.3 A/km of tramway, the leak shall be localized and removed
            as soon as practicable and the running of the cars shall be stopped unless the leak is
            localized and removed within twenty-four hours:
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of
            1977</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s12_proviso">Provided that where both line and return
            are placed within a conduit this regulation shall not apply. </proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402557601_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><content>The insulation resistance of all continuously insulated cables used for lines, for
            insulated returns, for feeders, or for other purposes, and laid below the surface of the
            ground, shall not be permitted to fall below the equivalent of 6
            MΩ/km.
            A test of the insulation resistance of all such cables shall be made at least once in
            each month. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of 1977</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557616_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><content>Where in any case in any part of the tramway the line is erected overhead and the
            return is laid on or under the ground, and where any wires have been erected or laid
            before the construction of the tramway in the same or nearly the same direction as such
            part of the tramway, the company shall, if required so to do by the owners of such wires
            or any of them, permit such owners to insert and maintain in the company’s line one or
            more induction-coils or other apparatus approved by the company for the purpose of
            preventing disturbance by electric induction. In any case in which the company withholds
            its approval of any such apparatus the owners may appeal to the Chief Executive in
            Council, who may, if he thinks fit, dispense with such approval. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/62">62 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557616_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><content>Any insulated return shall be placed parallel to and at a distance not exceeding 1 m from the line when the line and return are both erected overhead, or 0.5 m when they are both laid underground. </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1977/ln156">L.N. 156 of 1977</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402557632_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><content>In the disposition,
            connexions
            and working of feeders the company shall take all reasonable precautions to avoid
            injurious interference with any existing wires.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557648_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><content>The company shall so construct and maintain its system as to secure good contact between the motors and the line and return respectively.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557648_004" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><content>The company shall adopt the best means available to prevent the occurrence of undue sparking at the rubbing or rolling contacts in any place and in the construction and use of its generator and motors.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557663_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><content>In working the cars the current shall be varied as required by means of a rheostat containing at least twenty sections or by some other equally efficient method of gradually varying resistance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402557679_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><leadIn>The company shall, so far as may be applicable to its system of working, keep
            records as specified below. These records shall, if and when required, be forwarded for
            the information of the Chief Executive in
            Council.</leadIn><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/62">62 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)</sourceNote><text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Daily records</inline></crossHeading>Number of
            cars running. <br></br>Maximum working current. <br></br>Maximum working pressure. <br></br>Maximum
            current from the earth
            connexions
            (see <ref>rule 8(i)</ref>). <br></br>Leakage current (see <ref>rule 12</ref>). <br></br>Fall of
            potential in return (see <ref>rule 9</ref>).<crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Monthly records</inline></crossHeading>Condition of earth
            connexions
            (see <ref>rule 7</ref>). <br></br>Insulation resistance of insulated cables (see <ref>rule
                13</ref>).<crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Quarterly
                record</inline></crossHeading>Conductance of joints to pipes (see <ref>rule
                    10</ref>).<crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Occasional
                records</inline></crossHeading>Any test made under the provisions of <ref>rule
                8(ii)</ref>. <br></br>Localization and removal of leakage, stating time occupied.
            <br></br>Particulars of any abnormal occurrence affecting the electric
            <br></br>working
            of the
            tramway.</text></section><section id="ID_1438402557694_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2021-07-08" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><content>Any person who acts in contravention of <ref>rules 3 to 13</ref> and <ref>15 to
                20</ref> shall be liable to a fine
            at level
            1,
            and also in the case of a continuing offence to a further fine of
            $10
            for every day after the first during which such offence continues.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1951/gna75">G.N.A. 75 of
            1951</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>