<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 112 sub. leg. R</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>112R</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap112R!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-05-14</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402598925_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-05-14">Specification
                                    of Arrangements (Government of the United Kingdom of Great
                                    Britain and Northern Ireland Concerning Air Services) (Double
                                    Taxation) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap112/s49">Cap.
                                                112, section
                                    49</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[24 October 1997]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402598941_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-05-14" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Declaration under <ref>section 49</ref></heading><content>For the purposes of <ref>section 49</ref> of the Ordinance it is declared that the arrangements referred to in <ref>section 2</ref> have been made with the Government of a territory outside Hong Kong with a view to affording relief from double taxation in relation to income tax and any tax of a similar character imposed by the laws of that territory, and that it is expedient that those arrangements should have effect.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402598941_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-05-14" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Arrangements specified</heading><content>The arrangements mentioned in <ref>section 1</ref> are in Article 14 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland concerning Air Services done in duplicate at Hong Kong on 25 July 1997 in the English and Chinese languages as specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> and having effect according to the tenor of that Agreement.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402598956_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-05-14" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap112R/s2">s. 2</ref>]<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><heading>Article 14 of the Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special
            Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the United
            Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland Concerning Air
            Services<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text>Done, in duplicate, at Hong Kong on the 25th day of July 1997 in the English and
            Chinese languages.</text><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text class="align_center">“<ins>ARTICLE 14</ins><inline class="not_bold"></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><ins><b>Relief from
                    Double
            Taxation</b></ins><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019944_001" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The existing taxes to which this Article shall apply are in particular:</leadIn></subsection><subsection id="ID_1586838019944_002" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph name="a" id="ID_1586838019960_003" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, the profits tax
                    (hereinafter referred to as “Hong Kong tax”);</content></paragraph><paragraph name="b" id="ID_1586838019960_004" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the case of the United Kingdom:</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019960_005" name="i" temporalId="sch0_0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the income tax; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019960_006" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the corporation tax;</content></subparagraph><continued>(hereinafter referred to as “United Kingdom tax”).</continued></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019960_007" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>This Article shall also apply to any identical or substantially similar taxes
                which are imposed by either Contracting Party after the signature of this Agreement
                in addition to, or in place of, the existing taxes. The competent authorities shall
                notify each other of any substantial changes which have been made in their
                respective taxation laws.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019960_008" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>Income or profits derived from the operation of aircraft in international
                traffic by an airline of one Contracting Party, including any income or profits
                attributable to its participation in a pool, joint business or international
                operating agency, and proportionate to its share in the pool or joint operation,
                which are subject to tax in the area of that Contracting Party, shall be exempt from
                tax imposed in the area of the other Contracting Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019960_009" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>For the purpose of this Article:</leadIn></subsection><subsection id="ID_1586838019960_010" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph name="a" id="ID_1586838019960_011" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>interest on funds directly connected with the operation of aircraft in
                    international traffic shall be regarded as profits from the operation of such
                    aircraft;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="b" id="ID_1586838019960_012" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="OperationOfAircraft">the term “<term class="old_format">operation of
                        aircraft</term>” shall include:</def><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019960_013" name="i" temporalId="sch0_0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the carriage by air of persons, baggage, livestock, goods, mail or
                        merchandise;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019960_014" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the sale of tickets or similar documentation connected with such
                        carriage, either for the airline or for any other airline;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019960_015" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(iii)</num><content>the incidental rental or lease of aircraft on a charter basis;
                    </content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph name="c" id="ID_1586838019960_016" temporalId="sch0_0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><def name="InternationalTraffic">the term “<term class="old_format">international
                        traffic</term>” means any carriage by an aircraft except where such carriage
                    is solely between places in the area of the other Contracting
                    Party;<marker role="section-break"></marker></def></paragraph><paragraph name="d" id="ID_1586838019960_017" temporalId="sch0_0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><def name="AirlineOfOneContractingParty">the term “<term class="old_format">airline
                        of one Contracting Party</term>” means, in the case of the Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region, an airline incorporated and having its principal place of
                    business in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region and in the case of the
                    United Kingdom, an airline which is resident in the United Kingdom for the
                    purposes of United Kingdom tax: and an airline of one Contracting Party shall
                    not be at the same time an airline of the other Contracting Party;</def></paragraph><paragraph name="e" id="ID_1586838019975_018" temporalId="sch0_0_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><def name="ContractingParty">the term “<term class="old_format">Contracting
                        Party</term>” means the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region or the
                    United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, as the context
                    requires;</def></paragraph><paragraph name="f" id="ID_1586838019975_019" temporalId="sch0_0_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><def name="CompetentAuthority">the term “<term class="old_format">competent
                        authority</term>” means, in the case of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region, the Commissioner of Inland Revenue or his authorised representative, or
                    any person or body authorised to perform any functions at present exercisable by
                    the Commissioner or similar functions, and, in the case of the United Kingdom,
                    the Commissioners of Inland Revenue or their authorised representative;</def></paragraph><paragraph name="g" id="ID_1586838019975_020" temporalId="sch0_0_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><def name="Area">the term “<term class="old_format">area</term>” in respect of the
                    Hong Kong Special Administrative Region includes Hong Kong Island, Kowloon and
                    the New Territories and in respect of the United Kingdom means Great Britain and
                    Northern Ireland including any area outside the territorial sea of the United
                    Kingdom which in accordance with international law has been or may hereafter be
                    designated, under the laws of the United Kingdom concerning the Continental
                    Shelf, as an area within which the rights of the United Kingdom with respect to
                    the sea bed and sub-soil and their natural resources may be exercised;</def></paragraph><paragraph name="h" id="ID_1586838019975_021" temporalId="sch0_0_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><def name="Tax">the term “<term class="old_format">tax</term>” means Hong Kong tax
                    or United Kingdom tax as the context requires.</def></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019975_022" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">(5)</num><content>The competent authorities of the Contracting Parties shall, through
                consultation, endeavour to resolve by mutual agreement any disputes regarding the
                interpretation or application of this Article. Article 16 (Settlement of Disputes)
                shall not apply to any such dispute.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019975_023" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding Article 20 (Entry into Force) each Contracting Party shall
                notify to the other the completion of the procedures required by its law for the
                bringing into force of this Article and this Article shall thereupon have
                effect:</leadIn></subsection><subsection id="ID_1586838019975_024" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph name="a" id="ID_1586838019975_025" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, for any year of assessment
                    beginning on or after 1st April in the calendar year next following that in
                    which this Agreement is signed;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="b" id="ID_1586838019975_026" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the United Kingdom:</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019975_027" name="i" temporalId="sch0_0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in respect of income tax, for any year of assessment beginning on or
                        after 6th April in the calendar year next following that in which this
                        Agreement is signed;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019975_028" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in respect of corporation tax, for any financial year beginning on or
                        after 1st April in the calendar year next following that in which this
                        Agreement is signed.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019975_029" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">(7)</num><content>Either Contracting Party may terminate this Article without terminating the
                remainder of this Agreement by giving notice to the other Contracting Party at least
                six months before the end of any calendar
                year.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019975_030" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num class="align_left" value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>Where notice of termination of this Agreement is given under Article 18, or
                notice of termination of this Article is given under paragraph (7), then,
                notwithstanding anything in Article 18 to the contrary, this Article shall cease to
                have effect:</leadIn></subsection><subsection id="ID_1586838019975_031" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph name="a" id="ID_1586838019975_032" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, for any year of assessment
                    beginning on or after 1st April in the calendar year next following that in
                    which notice is given;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="b" id="ID_1586838019975_033" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the United Kingdom:</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019991_034" name="i" temporalId="sch0_0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in respect of income tax, for any year of assessment beginning on or
                        after 6th April in the calendar year next following that in which notice is
                        given;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1586838019991_035" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in respect of corporation tax, for any financial year beginning on or
                        after 1st April in the calendar year next following that in which notice is
                        given.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_18 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1586838019991_036" name="9" temporalId="sch0_9"><num class="align_left" value="9">(9)</num><content>This Article shall not have effect so long as an Agreement for the avoidance of
                double taxation with respect to taxes on income or income and capital gains
                providing for similar exemptions has effect between the Contracting
                Parties.”.</content></subsection></schedule></main></subLeg>