<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 105</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>105</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap105!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-06-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402541611_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-04-11">
            <content>To provide for the public lighting of Hong Kong and for the protection of the
                appliances used in connexion therewith.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/57">57 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[8 May 1914]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402541626_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Public Lighting Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402541642_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Director of Highways to have power to erect lamp posts and affix lamps
            thereon</heading><content>It shall be lawful for the Director of Highways to cause a sufficient number of
            posts, standards and brackets for the lighting of the public or private streets, roads,
            ways and thoroughfares in Hong Kong or for the control of pedestrian and vehicular
            traffic therein to be provided and to be set up, fixed or erected in all suitable
            situations for such lighting or control, whether in any of the said streets, roads, ways
            and thoroughfares or in any place adjacent thereto or upon or against the wall of any
            house or building or the side of any wall or fence, or elsewhere, as he may think
            proper; and it shall also be lawful for him to cause to be provided and put and affixed
            upon the said posts, standards and brackets such a number of lamps and of such sizes and
            sorts respectively as may be found requisite for the lighting or control of the said
            streets, roads, ways and thoroughfares respectively. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1939/33">33 of 1939
                Schedule</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1940/28">28 of 1940 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1982/ln76">L.N. 76 of
                1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1986</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/57">57 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541642_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Property in lamp posts and lamps to be vested in Director of Highways</heading><content>The laws relating to the removing, taking, carrying away or stealing of fixtures and chattels respectively shall be interpreted to apply to the removing, taking, carrying away or stealing of any of the posts, standards, brackets or lamps provided under this Ordinance; and the property of and in all or any of such posts, standards, brackets or lamps shall be deemed to be vested in the Director of Highways for all the purposes of any proceedings, civil or criminal, in relation thereto.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/ln76">L.N. 76 of 1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/ln127">L.N. 127 of 1986</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541657_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-06-24" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Extinguishing light of lamps</heading><content>Every person who wilfully extinguishes, obscures or interferes in any way with the
            light of any lamp provided under this Ordinance shall be liable on summary conviction to
            a fine
            at
            level 1 in addition to the full amount of the damage and all
            incidental costs and expenses. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924
                Schedule</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1950/22">22 of 1950
                Schedule</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1972/48">48 of 1972 s.
            4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2021/er3">E.R. 3 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541673_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Apprehension without warrant of offender</heading><content>It shall be lawful for any person witnessing the commission of an offence against
                <ref>section 4</ref> to seize the said offender and to deliver him to any constable
            or to a magistrate, and no warrant shall be in any case necessary to justify the
            apprehension of any such offender. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924
                Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541673_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Compensation to be paid for damage other than wilful</heading><content>When any damage or injury has been occasioned to any of the posts, standards,
            brackets or lamps provided under this Ordinance by any person otherwise than wilfully,
            and such person has not made satisfaction for the same, the District Court shall, where
            proceedings are commenced in respect of such damage or injury, order the said person to
            make full satisfaction for the amount of such damage or injury, together with all
            incidental costs and expenses. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924
                Schedule</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1969/35">35 of 1969
                Schedule</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402541798_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance contained shall be deemed to affect any liability imposed
            by <ref>section 29</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap.
                123</ref>), upon the owners of the land fronting, adjoining or abutting on any
            street on land held under lease from the Government on which buildings front, adjoin or
            abut. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1935/18">18 of 1935 s. 172</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1939/33">33 of 1939
                Schedule</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>) </sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>