<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 23</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>23</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap23!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402861942_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2009-04-02">
            <content>To consolidate Ordinances relating to interests in land, assignments, contract, tort, breach of promise and foreign corporations; and to amend the law relating to the defence of tender before action.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2008/3">3 of 2008 s. 7</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 July 1901]</commencementNote><section id="ID_1438402861942_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Law Amendment and Reform
                                (Consolidation) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of
                        2017</ref>)</sourceNote></section><part id="ID_1438402861988_001" name="P1" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part I</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/62">62 of 1984 s. 66</ref>)</sourceNote></part><part id="ID_1438402862004_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Assignments</heading><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402862004_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Assignment of debt or chose in action</heading><leadIn>Any absolute assignment, by writing under the hand of the assignor (not purporting to be by way of charge only), of any debt or other legal chose in action, of which express notice in writing has been given to the debtor, trustee or other person from whom the assignor would have been entitled to receive or claim such debt or chose in action, shall be and be deemed to have been effectual in law (subject to all equities which would have been entitled to priority over the right of the assignee if this section, <ref>section 11</ref> of this Ordinance and <ref>sections 25</ref> and <ref>49</ref> of the Conveyancing and Property Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap219">Cap. 219</ref>) had not been enacted) to pass and transfer the legal right to such debt or chose in action from the date of such notice, and all legal and other remedies for the same, and the power to give a good discharge for the same, without the concurrence of the assignor:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_proviso">Provided that if the debtor, trustee or other person liable in respect of such debt or chose in action has had notice that such assignment is disputed by the assignor or any one claiming under him or of any other opposing or conflicting claims to such debt or chose in action, he shall be entitled to call upon the several person making claim thereto to interplead concerning the same, or he may pay the same into the court under and in conformity with the provisions of any Ordinance relating to trustees.</proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1901/4">4 of 1901 s. 8</ref> incorporated. Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1912/1">1 of 1912 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1988/31">31 of 1988 s. 30</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1873 c. 66 s. 25(6) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862020_001" name="s10" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/62">62 of 1984 s. 66</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402862020_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Contract</heading><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402862035_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Stipulations not of the essence of contracts</heading><content>Stipulations in contracts, as to time or otherwise, which would not, before 13 October 1873, have been deemed to be or to have become of the essence of such contracts in the court in its equitable jurisdiction shall receive in the court the same construction and effect as they would formerly have received in equity.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1901/4">4 of 1901 s. 9</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1873 c. 66 s. 25(7) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862035_004" name="s12" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1972/72">72 of 1972 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862051_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Action not maintainable on representations of character etc. unless in writing</heading><content>No action shall be brought whereby to charge any person upon or by reason of any representation or assurance made or given concerning or relating to the character, conduct, credit, ability, trade or dealings of any person, to the intent or purpose that such other person may obtain credit, money or goods thereupon, unless such representation or assurance is made in writing, signed by the party to be charged therewith.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/53">53 of 1971 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1828 c. 14 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862051_004" name="s13A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s13A"><num value="13A">13A.</num><heading>Part performance and damages</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632102_025" name="1" temporalId="s13A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A court may award damages for breach of a contract of which there has been part performance notwithstanding that an order for specific performance could not, in the circumstances of the case, be made by the court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632102_033" name="2" temporalId="s13A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section shall not apply to any contract made before 31 December 1972.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1972/72">72 of 1972 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862066_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Consideration for guarantee need not appear by writing</heading><content>No special promise made by any person to answer for the debt, default or miscarriage of another person, being in writing, and signed by the party charged therewith or some other person by him thereunto lawfully authorized, shall be deemed invalid to support an action, suit or other proceeding to charge the person by whom such promise has been made, by reason only that the consideration for such promise does not appear in writing or by necessary inference from a written document.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1864/13">13 of 1864 s. 4</ref> incorporated. Amended <ref href="/hk/1911/50">50 of 1911</ref>. Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/53">53 of 1971 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1856 c. 97 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862082_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Right of surety who discharges liability to assignment of all securities held by creditor</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632180_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every person who, being surety for the debt or duty of another or being liable with another for any debt or duty, pays such debt or performs such duty, shall be entitled to have assigned to him, or to a trustee for him, every judgment, specialty, or other security which is held by the creditor in respect of such debt or duty, whether such judgment, specialty, or other security is or is not deemed at law to have been satisfied by the payment of the debt or performance of the duty.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632180_012" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Such person shall be entitled to stand in the place of the creditor, to use all the remedies, and, if need be and upon a proper indemnity, to use the name of the creditor, in any action or other proceeding at law or in equity, in order to obtain from the principal debtor or any co-surety, co-contractor or co-debtor, as the case may be, indemnification for the advances made and loss sustained by the person who has so paid such debt or performed such duty, and such payment or performance so made by such surety shall not be a bar to any such action or other proceeding by him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632196_005" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No co-surety, co-contractor, or co-debtor, shall be entitled to recover from any other co-surety, co-contractor, or co-debtor, by the means aforesaid, more than the just proportion to which, as between those parties themselves, such last mentioned person is justly liable.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1864/13">13 of 1864 s. 6</ref> incorporated. Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/53">53 of 1971 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1856 c. 97 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862082_003" name="s15A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s15A"><num value="15A">15A.</num><heading>Charges and mortgages over choses in action</heading><content>For the avoidance of doubt, it is hereby declared that a person
                    (<b><i>the
                    first
            person</i></b>)
            is able to create, and always has been able to create, in favour of another person
                    (<b><i>the
                    second
            person</i></b>)
            a legal or equitable charge or mortgage over all or any of the first person’s interest
            in a chose in action enforceable by the first person against the second person, and any
            charge or mortgage so created shall operate neither to merge the interest thereby
            created with, nor to extinguish or release, that chose in action.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1991/60">60 of 1991 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862098_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Adjustment of rights and liabilities of parties to frustrated contracts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632258_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a contract governed by law applicable to the Colony has become impossible of performance or been otherwise frustrated, and the parties thereto have for that reason been discharged from the further performance of the contract, the following provisions of this section shall, subject to the provisions of <ref>section 17</ref>, have effect in relation thereto.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632274_005" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>All sums paid or payable to any party in pursuance of the contract before the time when the parties were so discharged (in this section and <ref>section 17</ref> referred to as the time of discharge) shall, in the case of sums so paid, be recoverable from him as money received by him for the use of the party by whom the sums were paid, and, in the case of sums so payable, cease to be so payable:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s16_2_proviso">Provided that, if the party to whom the sums were so paid or payable incurred expenses before the time of discharge in, or for the purpose of, the performance of the contract, the court may, if it considers it just to do so having regard to all the circumstances of the case, allow him to retain or, as the case may be, recover the whole or any part of the sums so paid or payable, not being an amount in excess of the expenses so incurred.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632274_019" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where any party to the contract has, by reason of anything done by any other party thereto in, or for the purpose of, the performance of the contract, obtained a valuable benefit (other than a payment of money to which subsection (2) applies) before the time of discharge, there shall be recoverable from him by the said other party such sum (if any), not exceeding the value of the said benefit to the party obtaining it, as the court considers just, having regard to all the circumstances of the case and, in particular—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632289_005" name="a" temporalId="s16_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the amount of any expenses incurred before the time of discharge by the benefited party in, or for the purpose of, the performance of the contract, including any sums paid or payable by him to any other party in pursuance of the contract and retained or recoverable by that party under subsection (2); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632289_013" name="b" temporalId="s16_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the effect, in relation to the said benefit, of the circumstances giving rise to the frustration of the contract.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632289_020" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In estimating, for the purposes of subsections (1), (2) and (3), the amount of any expenses incurred by any party to the contract, the court may, without prejudice to the generality of the said subsections, include such sum as appears to be reasonable in respect of overhead expenses and in respect of any work or services performed personally by the said party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632305_005" name="5" temporalId="s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In considering whether any sum ought to be recovered or retained under subsections (1), (2), (3) and (4) by any party to the contract, the court shall not take into account any sums which have, by reason of the circumstances giving rise to the frustration of the contract, become payable to that party under any contract of insurance unless there was an obligation to insure imposed by an express term of the frustrated contract or by or under any enactment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632305_013" name="6" temporalId="s16_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where any person has assumed obligations under the contract in consideration of the conferring of a benefit by any other party to the contract upon any other person, whether a party to the contract or not, the court may, if in all the circumstances of the case it considers it just to do so, treat for the purposes of subsection (3) any benefit so conferred as a benefit obtained by the person who has assumed the obligations as aforesaid.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1948/26">26 of 1948 s. 3</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1943 c. 40 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862113_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Provision as to the application of <ref>sections 16</ref>, <ref>17</ref> and <ref>18</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632352_018" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section and <ref>sections 16</ref> and <ref>18</ref> shall save as is hereinafter provided apply to contracts whether made before or after 18 June 1948, as respects which the time of discharge is on or after 8 December 1941, but not to contracts as respects which the time of discharge is before the latter date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632367_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section and <ref>sections 16</ref> and <ref>18</ref> shall apply to contracts to which the Crown is a party in like manner as to contracts between subjects.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632367_013" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where any contract to which this section and <ref>sections 16</ref> and <ref>18</ref> apply contains any provision which, upon the true construction of the contract, is intended to have effect in the event of circumstances arising which operate, or would but for the said provision operate, to frustrate the contract, or is intended to have effect whether such circumstances arise or not, the court shall give effect to the said provision and shall only give effect to <ref>section 16</ref> to such extent, if any, as appears to the court to be consistent with the said provision.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632383_005" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where it appears to the court that apart of any contract to which this section and <ref>sections 16</ref> and <ref>18</ref> apply can properly be severed from the remainder of the contract, being a part wholly performed before the time of discharge, or so performed except for the payment in respect of that part of the contract of sums which are or can be ascertained under the contract, the court shall treat that part of the contract as if it were a separate contract and had not been frustrated and shall treat <ref>section 16</ref> as only applicable to the remainder of that contract.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632399_005" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>This section and <ref>sections 16</ref> and <ref>18</ref> shall not apply—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632399_013" name="a" temporalId="s17_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to any charterparty, except a time charterparty or a charterparty by way of demise, or to any contract (other than a charterparty) for the carriage of goods by sea; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632399_021" name="b" temporalId="s17_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to any contract of insurance, save as is provided by <ref>section 16(5)</ref>; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632399_029" name="c" temporalId="s17_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to any contract to which <ref>section 9</ref> of the Sale of Goods Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap26">Cap. 26</ref>), (which avoids contracts for the sale of specific goods which perish before the risk has passed to the buyer) applies, or to any other contract for the sale, or for the sale and delivery, of specific goods, where the contract is frustrated by reason of the fact that the goods have perished.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632414_005" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><def name="Court">In this section and <ref>section 16</ref>,
                    <term>court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院</term>) includes any arbitrator by or before
                whom the matter falls to be determined.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1948/26">26 of 1948 ss. 2</ref> &amp; 4 incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1943 c. 40 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862113_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Saving for settlement or contrary agreement</heading><content>Nothing in <ref>sections 16</ref> and <ref>17</ref> shall affect any settlement or agreement between the parties subsequent to date of discharge whereby the rights and liabilities of the contracting parties fell to be determined otherwise than in accordance with the said sections.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1948/26">26 of 1948 s. 5</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402862129_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Tort</heading><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402862129_004" name="s19" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/77">77 of 1984 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862144_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Effect of death on certain causes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632492_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of this section, on the death of any person after 26 October 1951, all causes of action subsisting against or vested in him shall survive against, or, as the case may be, for the benefit of, his estate:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s20_1_proviso">Provided that this subsection shall not apply to causes of action for defamation or seduction or for inducing one spouse to leave or remain apart from the other or to claims for damages on the ground of adultery.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632492_018" name="1A" temporalId="s20_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>The right of a person to claim under <ref>section 4</ref> of the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>) (for bereavement) or under <ref>section 20C(1)</ref> of this Ordinance (for loss of society) shall not survive for the benefit of his estate on his death.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/40">40 of 1986 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632492_026" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where a cause of action survives as aforesaid for the benefit of the estate of a deceased person, the damages recoverable for the benefit of the estate of that person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632492_034" name="a" temporalId="s20_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall not include any exemplary damages;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632492_042" name="b" temporalId="s20_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>shall, where the death of that person has been caused by the act or omission which gives rise to the cause of action—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632492_050" name="i" temporalId="s20_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>be calculated without reference to any loss or gain to his estate consequent on his death, except that a sum in respect of funeral expenses may be included;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632508_007" name="ii" temporalId="s20_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>not include any damages in respect of loss of ability to render services after his death;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632508_015" name="iii" temporalId="s20_2_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content><leadIn>not include any damages for loss of property, whether income or otherwise, in respect of any period after his death, except in so far as the court is satisfied that, but for the act or omission that gave rise to the cause of action, the deceased would have achieved an accumulation of wealth by the time that he would otherwise have died, in which case damages may be awarded in respect of the loss of that wealth:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s20_2_b_iii_proviso">Provided that damages awarded under this sub-paragraph shall be subject to such deduction as the court considers it just to make in the circumstances of any particular case on account of the accelerated receipt of that wealth and in order to avoid over-compensation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1986/40">40 of 1986 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632508_027" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1987/52">52 of 1987 s. 45</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632508_035" name="4" temporalId="s20_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where damage has been suffered by reason of any act or omission in respect of which a cause of action would have subsisted against any person if that person had not died before or at the same time as the damage was suffered, there shall be deemed, for the purposes of this section and <ref>sections 21</ref> and <ref>22</ref>, to have been subsisting against him before his death such cause of action in respect of that act or omission as would have subsisted if he had died after the damage was suffered.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632523_005" name="5" temporalId="s20_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The rights conferred by this section and <ref>sections 21</ref> and <ref>22</ref> for the benefit of the estates of deceased persons shall be in addition to and not in derogation of any rights conferred on the dependants of deceased persons by the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>) and so much of this section and <ref>sections 21</ref> and <ref>22</ref> as relates to causes of action against the estates of deceased persons shall apply in relation to causes of action under the said Ordinance as it applies in relation to other causes of action not expressly excepted from the operation of subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632539_005" name="6" temporalId="s20_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In the event of the insolvency of an estate against which proceedings are maintainable by virtue of this section, any liability in respect of the cause of action in respect of which the proceedings are maintainable shall be deemed to be a debt provable in the administration of the estate, notwithstanding that it is a demand in the nature of unliquidated damages arising otherwise than by a contract, promise or breach of trust.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1951/36">36 of 1951 s. 2</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1934 c. 41 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862160_002" name="s20A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s20A"><num value="20A">20A.</num><heading>Abolition of rights to damages for loss of expectation of life</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632586_018" name="1" temporalId="s20A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In an action for damages for personal injuries—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632586_026" name="a" temporalId="s20A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>no damages shall be recoverable in respect of any loss of expectation of life caused to the injured person by the injuries; but</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632586_034" name="b" temporalId="s20A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the injured person’s expectation of life has been reduced by the injuries, the court, in assessing damages in respect of pain and suffering caused by the injuries, shall take account of any suffering caused or likely to be caused to him by awareness that his expectation of life has been so reduced.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632601_005" name="2" temporalId="s20A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The reference in subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> to damages in respect of loss of expectation of life does not include damages in respect of loss of income.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/40">40 of 1986 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 53 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862176_001" name="s20B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s20B"><num value="20B">20B.</num><heading>Abolition of common law actions for loss of society or service</heading><leadIn>Except as provided in <ref>section 20C</ref>, no person shall be liable in tort—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632617_019" name="a" temporalId="s20B_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to a husband on the ground only of having deprived him of the services or society of his wife;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632617_027" name="b" temporalId="s20B_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to a parent (or person standing in the place of a parent) on the ground only of having deprived him of the services of a child; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632617_035" name="c" temporalId="s20B_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>on the ground only—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632617_043" name="i" temporalId="s20B_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>of having deprived another of the services of his menial servant;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632617_051" name="ii" temporalId="s20B_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>of having deprived another of the services of his female servant by raping or seducing her; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632617_059" name="iii" temporalId="s20B_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>of enticement of a servant or harbouring a servant.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/40">40 of 1986 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 53 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862176_003" name="s20C" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s20C"><num value="20C">20C.</num><heading>Actions for loss of society or services</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632648_004" name="1" temporalId="s20C_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where injury is caused to any person by any wrongful act, neglect or default which entitles him to maintain an action and recover damages, and which causes any person referred to in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f) or (g) to be deprived of his society, the person who is liable to such an action shall, subject to subsection (3), also be liable in damages for the loss of the injured person’s society suffered by such of the following persons as survive 30 days after the date on which the cause of action accrued—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632648_012" name="a" temporalId="s20C_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the husband or wife of the injured person, unless they had been living apart for a continuous period of at least 2 years immediately before the date on which the cause of action accrued; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632648_020" name="b" temporalId="s20C_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where there is no spouse entitled to recover damages under paragraph (a), any children of the injured person; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632648_028" name="c" temporalId="s20C_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a) or (b), any concubine taken by the injured person before 7 October 1971; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632664_006" name="d" temporalId="s20C_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a), (b) or (c), any person who—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632664_014" name="i" temporalId="s20C_1_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>was living with the injured person in the same household immediately before the date on which the cause of action accrued; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632664_022" name="ii" temporalId="s20C_1_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>had been living with the injured person in the same household for at least 2 years before that date,</content></subparagraph><continued>as the husband or wife of the injured person; or</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632664_035" name="e" temporalId="s20C_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph (a), (b), (c) or (d), the parents of the injured person or (if the injured person was illegitimate) his mother; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632664_043" name="f" temporalId="s20C_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>where there is no person by or for whom a claim can be made under paragraph
                    (a), (b), (c), (d) or (e), but the injured person was at the date on which the
                    cause of action accrued a minor, any person who during any marriage to which
                    that person was a party treated the injured person as a son or daughter of the
                    family in relation to that marriage; or
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2014/18">L.N. 307 of
                        1998</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632679_006" name="g" temporalId="s20C_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>where there is no other person by or for whom a claim can be made under
                    this subsection, any brother or sister of the injured person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2014/18">18 of 2014 s. 153</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632679_013" name="2" temporalId="s20C_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The total sum awarded as damages under subsection (1) in respect of any injured person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632679_021" name="a" temporalId="s20C_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall not exceed the sum specified in <ref>section 4(3)</ref> of the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632695_006" name="b" temporalId="s20C_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall, where there are 2 or more claimants, be divided equally between them.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632711_005" name="3" temporalId="s20C_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Damages shall not be payable by virtue of subsection (1) if the injured person dies as a result of the act, neglect or default referred to in that subsection and his death gives rise to a right to claim damages for bereavement under <ref>section 4</ref> of the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632711_013" name="4" temporalId="s20C_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where injury is caused to any person by any wrongful act, neglect or default which entitles him to maintain an action and recover damages in respect thereof and which causes any dependant of the injured person to be deprived of his gratuitous services, the action may include a claim for damages by the injured person for impairment of his ability to render such services.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632726_005" name="5" temporalId="s20C_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="Child"><leadIn><term>child</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">子女</term>) of an injured person
                    includes—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632726_020" name="a" temporalId="s20C_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a child adopted by him in pursuance either of an adoption order made under the Adoption Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap290">Cap. 290</ref>) or of any other adoption recognized as valid by the law of Hong Kong; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632726_028" name="b" temporalId="s20C_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a person who, during any marriage to which the injured person was at any time a party, was treated by him as a son or daughter of the family in relation to that marriage;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Dependant"><leadIn><term>dependant</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受養人</term>), in relation to an injured person,
                    means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632726_042" name="a" temporalId="s20C_5_a-1"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the wife, husband, former wife or former husband of the injured person and any person whose marriage to the injured person has been annulled or declared void;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632726_050" name="b" temporalId="s20C_5_b-1"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a concubine lawfully taken by the injured person before 7 October 1971;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2014/18">18 of 2014 s. 153</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632726_058" name="c" temporalId="s20C_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>any person who—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632726_066" name="i" temporalId="s20C_5_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>was living with the injured person in the same household immediately before the date of his injury; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411632726_074" name="ii" temporalId="s20C_5_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>had been living with the injured person in the same household for at least 2 years before that date,</content></subparagraph><continued>as the husband or wife of the injured person;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632742_012" name="d" temporalId="s20C_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any parent or other ascendant of the injured person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632742_020" name="e" temporalId="s20C_5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>any person (not being a parent of the injured person) who, during any marriage to which that person was a party, treated the injured person as a son or daughter of the family in relation to that marriage; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632742_028" name="f" temporalId="s20C_5_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>any child or other descendant of the injured person; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632742_036" name="g" temporalId="s20C_5_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>any person (not being a child of the injured person) who, during any marriage to which the injured person was at any time a party, was treated by the injured person as a son or daughter of the family in relation to that marriage;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632742_044" name="h" temporalId="s20C_5_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>any person who is, or is the issue of, a brother, sister, uncle or aunt of the injured person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632742_052" name="i" temporalId="s20C_5_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any person who is, or is the issue of, a brother or sister of a grandparent of the injured person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632742_060" name="j" temporalId="s20C_5_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>any godchild or godparent of the injured person according to Chinese custom;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Injury"><term>injury</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">傷害</term>) includes any disease and any impairment
                of a person’s physical or mental condition;</def><def name="Parent"><term>parent</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">父母</term>) includes any person who, during any
                marriage to which that person was a party, treated the injured person as a son or
                daughter of the family in relation to that marriage;</def><def name="Wife"><term>wife</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">妻子</term>) has the same meaning as in the Fatal
                Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap.
                    22</ref>),<continued class="left_indent_35">and in deducing any relationship for the purposes of this
                    section, <ref>section 2(2)</ref> of the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>) shall apply as it applies for the purposes
                    of that Ordinance.</continued></def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/40">40 of 1986 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862222_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Apportionment of liability in case of contributory negligence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632835_018" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Where any person suffers damage as the result partly of his own fault and partly of the fault of any other person or persons, a claim in respect of that damage shall not be defeated by reason of the fault of the person suffering the damage, but the damages recoverable in respect thereof shall be reduced to such extent as the court thinks just and equitable having regard to the claimant’s share in the responsibility for the damage:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1989/ln337">L.N. 337 of 1989</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s21_1_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411632851_012" name="a" temporalId="s21_1_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>this subsection shall not operate to defeat any defence arising under a contract; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411632851_020" name="b" temporalId="s21_1_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where any contract or enactment providing for the limitation of liability is applicable to the claim, the amount of damages recoverable by the claimant by virtue of this subsection shall not exceed the maximum limit so applicable.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632851_027" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where damages are recoverable by any person by virtue of subsection (1) subject to such reduction as is therein mentioned, the court shall find and record the total damages which would have been recoverable if the claimant had not been at fault.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632851_035" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Civil Liability (Contribution) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap377">Cap. 377</ref>) shall apply in any case where 2 or more persons are liable or would, if they had all been sued, be liable by virtue of subsection (1) in respect of the damage suffered by any person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/77">77 of 1984 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632867_005" name="4" temporalId="s21_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where any person dies as the result partly of his own fault and partly of the fault of any other person or persons, and accordingly if an action were brought for the benefit of the estate under <ref>section 20</ref> the damages recoverable would be reduced under subsection (1), any damages recoverable in an action under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>) shall be reduced to a proportionate extent.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1986/40">40 of 1986 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632867_013" name="4A" temporalId="s21_4A"><num value="4A">(4A)</num><content>Where an action is brought under <ref>section 20C</ref> for the loss of the society of another in circumstances where any damages recoverable by that other in proceedings brought by him would be reduced under subsection (1) of this section, any damages awarded for such loss shall be reduced to a proportionate extent.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1986/40">40 of 1986 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632882_005" name="5" temporalId="s21_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where, in any case to which subsection (1) applies, one of the persons at fault avoids liability to any other such person or his personal representative by pleading any enactment limiting the time within which proceedings may be taken, he shall not be entitled to recover any damages from that other person or representative by virtue of the said subsection.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/77">77 of 1984 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632882_013" name="6" temporalId="s21_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where any case to which subsection (1) applies is tried with a jury, the jury shall determine the total damages which would have been recoverable if the claimant had not been at fault and the extent to which those damages are to be reduced.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632882_021" name="7" temporalId="s21_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Article 21 of the Convention contained in the <ref>First Schedule</ref> to the Carriage by Air Act 1932 (1932 c. 36 U.K.) (which empowers a court to exonerate wholly or partly a carrier who proves that the damage was caused by or contributed to by the negligence of the injured person) shall in its application to the Colony have effect subject to the provisions of this section. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632898_005" name="8" temporalId="s21_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>This section shall not apply to any claim to which <ref>section 1</ref> of the Maritime Conventions Act 1911 (1911 c. 57 U.K.), applies and that Act shall have effect as if this section and <ref>sections 20</ref> and <ref>22</ref> had not been enacted.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1945 c. 28 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632898_013" name="9" temporalId="s21_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>This section shall not apply to any case where the acts or omissions giving rise to the claim occurred before 26 October 1951.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1945 c. 28 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632898_021" name="10" temporalId="s21_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="Court"><term>court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院</term>) means, in relation to any claim, the
                court or arbitrator by or before whom the claim falls to be determined;</def><def name="Damage"><term>damage</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">損害</term>) includes loss of life and personal
                injury;</def><def name="Dependant"><term>dependant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受養人</term>) means any person for whose benefit an
                action could be brought under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>);</def><def name="Fault"><term>fault</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">過失</term>) means negligence, breach of statutory
                duty or other act or omission which gives rise to a liability in tort or would,
                apart from this section, give rise to the defence of contributory negligence.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1945 c. 28 s. 4
                    U.K.]</referenceNote></def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1951/36">36 of 1951 s. 4</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1945 c. 28 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862222_003" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Abolition of the defence of common employment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411632960_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It shall not be a defence to an employer who is sued in respect of personal injuries caused by the negligence of a person employed by him, that that person was at the time the injuries were caused in common employment with the person injured.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1948 c. 41 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632960_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any provision contained in a contract of service or apprenticeship, or in an agreement collateral thereto, (including a contract or agreement entered into before 26 October 1951) shall be void in so far as it would have the effect of excluding or limiting any liability of the employer in respect of personal injuries caused to the person employed or apprenticed by the negligence of persons in common employment with him.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1948 c. 41 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411632976_005" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="PersonalInjury,Injured">In this section,
                    <term>personal
                    injury</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">人身傷害</term>) includes any disease and any
                impairment of a person’s physical or mental condition and
                    <term>injured</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">傷害</term>) shall be construed accordingly.
                    <referenceNote>[cf. 1948 c. 41 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1951/36">36 of 1951 s. 5</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402862238_002" name="P4A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P4A"><num value="4A">Part
            IVA</num><heading>Congenital
            Disabilities—Civil
            Liability</heading><sourceNote>(Part IVA added <ref href="/hk/1978/20">20 of 1978 s.
            2</ref>. Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402862254_001" name="s22A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22A"><num value="22A">22A.</num><heading>Interpretation and other supplementary provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633007_018" name="1" temporalId="s22A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="LiableInTort">Without prejudice to subsection (2), this Part applies in
                respect of births after (but not before) the
                    commencement<sup>#</sup>
                of this Part, and in respect of any such birth it replaces any law in force before
                such commencement whereby a person could be liable to a child in respect of
                disabilities with which it might be born; but in <ref>section 22B(3)</ref> the
                expression
                    <term>liable
                    in
                tort</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">承擔侵權責任</term>) does not include any reference to
                liability by virtue of this Part, or to liability by virtue of any such law.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1976 c. 28 s. 4(5)
                    U.K.]</referenceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633023_004" name="2" temporalId="s22A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Section 22B</ref> does not affect the operation of the Nuclear Material (Liability for Carriage) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap479">Cap. 479</ref>), as to liability for, and compensation in respect of, injury or damage caused by occurrences involving nuclear matter or the emission of ionising radiations.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/45">45 of 1995 s. 15</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633023_012" name="3" temporalId="s22A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="Born,Birth">In this Part,
                    <term>born</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">出生</term>) means born alive (the moment of a
                child’s birth being when it first has a life separate from its mother), and
                    <term>birth</term>
                (出生) has a corresponding meaning.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633023_019" name="4" temporalId="s22A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>References in this Part to a child being born disabled or with disabilities are to its being born with any deformity, disease or abnormality, including predisposition (whether or not susceptible of immediate prognosis) to physical or mental defect in the future.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1470382172279_001"><content>Editorial Note:</content><content><sup>#</sup>
                Commencement date:
                14.4.1978</content></editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862254_003" name="s22B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22B"><num value="22B">22B.</num><heading>Civil liability to child born disabled</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633054_047" name="1" temporalId="s22B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a child is born disabled as the result of such an occurrence before its birth as is mentioned in subsection (2) and a person (other than the child’s own mother) is under this section answerable to the child in respect of the occurrence, the child’s disabilities are to be regarded as damage resulting from the wrongful act of that person and actionable accordingly at the suit of the child.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633069_005" name="2" temporalId="s22B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An occurrence to which this section applies is one which—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633069_013" name="a" temporalId="s22B_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>affected either parent of the child in his or her ability to have a normal, healthy child; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633069_021" name="b" temporalId="s22B_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>affected the mother during her pregnancy, or affected her or the child in the course of its birth, so that the child is born with disabilities which would not otherwise have been present.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633069_028" name="3" temporalId="s22B_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subsections (4) to (7), a person (here referred to as
                    <term>the
                    defendant</term>)
                is answerable to the child if he was liable in tort to the parent or would, if sued
                in due time, have been so; and it is no answer that there could not have been such
                liability because the parent suffered no actionable injury, if there was a breach of
                legal duty which, accompanied by injury, would have given rise to
                liability.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633085_005" name="4" temporalId="s22B_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In the case of an occurrence preceding the time of conception, the defendant is not answerable to the child if at that time either or both of the parents knew the risk of their child being born disabled (that is to say, the particular risk created by the occurrence); but should it be the child’s father who is the defendant, this subsection does not apply if he knew of the risk and the mother did not.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633085_013" name="5" temporalId="s22B_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The defendant is not answerable to the child, for anything he did or omitted to do when responsible in a professional capacity for treating or advising the parent, if he took reasonable care having due regard to then received professional opinion applicable to the particular class of case; but this does not mean that he is answerable only because he departed from received opinion.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633101_005" name="6" temporalId="s22B_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Liability to the child under this section may be treated as having been excluded or limited by contract made with the parent affected, to the same extent and subject to the same restrictions as liability in the parent’s own case; and a contract term which could have been set up by the defendant in an action by the parent, so as to exclude or limit his liability to him or her, operates in the defendant’s favour to the same, but no greater, extent in an action under this section by the child.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633116_005" name="7" temporalId="s22B_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>If in the child’s action under this section it is shown that the parent affected shared the responsibility for the child being born disabled, the damages are to be reduced to such extent as the court thinks just and equitable having regard to the extent of the parent’s responsibility.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1976 c. 28 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402862269_002" name="s22C" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22C"><num value="22C">22C.</num><heading>Liability to be regarded as liability for personal injuries sustained by child immediately after its birth</heading><leadIn>Liability to a child under <ref>section 22B</ref> is to be regarded—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633147_026" name="a" temporalId="s22C_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>as respects all its incidents and any matters arising or to arise out of it; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633147_034" name="b" temporalId="s22C_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>subject to any contrary context or intention, for the purpose of construing references in enactments and documents to personal or bodily injuries and cognate matters, </content></paragraph><continued>as liability for personal injuries sustained by the child immediately after its birth. </continued><referenceNote>[cf. 1976 c. 28 s. 4(3) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862285_001" name="s22D" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22D"><num value="22D">22D.</num><heading>No damages for loss of expectation of life unless child lives for at least 48 hours</heading><content>No damages shall be recoverable under <ref>section 22B</ref> in respect of any loss of expectation of life unless the child lives for at least 48 hours.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1976 c. 28 s. 4(4) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862285_003" name="s22E" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22E"><num value="22E">22E.</num><heading>Application to Crown</heading><content>This Part binds the Crown.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438402862300_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part V</num><heading>Breach of Promise</heading><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402862300_004" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Engagements to marry not enforceable at law</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633210_060" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An agreement between 2 persons to marry one another shall not have effect as a contract giving rise to legal rights and no action shall lie for breach of such an agreement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633225_005" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section shall have effect in relation to agreements entered into before 7 October 1971, except that it shall not affect any action begun before that date.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/35">35 of 1971 s. 4</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1970 c. 33 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862316_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Property of engaged couples</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633241_004" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an agreement to marry is terminated, any rule of law relating to the rights of husbands and wives in relation to property in which either or both has or have a beneficial interest shall apply, in relation to any property in which either or both of the parties to the agreement had a beneficial interest while the agreement was in force, as it applies in relation to property in which a husband or wife has a beneficial interest.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633241_012" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an agreement to marry is terminated, <ref>sections 6</ref> and <ref>7</ref> of the Married Persons Status Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap182">Cap. 182</ref>) (which sections confer power on a judge to settle disputes between husband and wife about property) shall apply, as if the parties were married, to any dispute between, or claim by, one of them in relation to property in which either or both had a beneficial interest while the agreement was in force; but an application made by virtue of this section to the judge under the said sections shall be made within 3 years of the termination of the agreement.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/35">35 of 1971 s. 4</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1970 c. 33 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862332_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Gifts between engaged couples</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633288_033" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A party to an agreement to marry who makes a gift of property to the other party to the agreement on the condition (express or implied) that it shall be returned if the agreement is terminated shall not be prevented from recovering the property by reason only of his having terminated the agreement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633303_005" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The gift of an engagement ring shall be presumed to be an absolute gift; this presumption may be rebutted by proving that the ring was given on the condition, express or implied, that it should be returned if the marriage did not take place for any reason.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/35">35 of 1971 s. 4</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1970 c. 33 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402862347_002" name="P5A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P5A"><num value="5A">Part
            VA</num><heading>Forfeiture</heading><sourceNote>(Part VA added <ref href="/hk/1996/16">16 of 1996 s.
            2</ref>. Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402862363_002" name="s25A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s25A"><num value="25A">25A.</num><heading>Definition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633335_018" name="1" temporalId="s25A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="TheForfeitureRule">In this Part <term>the forfeiture rule</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">喪失權利規則</term>) means the rule of law relating to public
                policy which in certain circumstances precludes a person who has unlawfully killed
                another from acquiring a benefit in consequence of the killing.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633350_004" name="2" temporalId="s25A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>References in this Part to a person who has unlawfully killed another includes a reference to a person who has unlawfully aided, abetted, counselled or procured the death of that other and references in this Part to unlawful killing shall be construed accordingly.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 34 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402862363_004" name="s25B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s25B"><num value="25B">25B.</num><heading>Power to modify the rule</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633366_004" name="1" temporalId="s25B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a court determines that the forfeiture rule has precluded a person (in
                this section referred to as
                        <b><i>the
                        offender</i></b>)
                who has unlawfully killed another from acquiring any interest in property mentioned
                in subsection (4), subject to <ref>section 25D</ref>, the court may make an order
                modifying the effect of that rule.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633366_012" name="2" temporalId="s25B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The court shall not make an order under subsection (1) unless it is satisfied that, having regard to the conduct of the offender and of the deceased concerned and to such other circumstances (if any) as appear to the court to be material, the justice of the particular case requires the effect of the rule to be modified in that case.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633381_005" name="3" temporalId="s25B_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In any case where a person stands convicted of an offence of which unlawful killing is an element, the court shall not make an order under subsection (1) modifying the effect of the forfeiture rule in that case unless proceedings for the purpose are brought before the expiry of the period of 90 days beginning on—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633397_005" name="a" temporalId="s25B_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in case an appeal is taken as regards the conviction, the day on which the appeal is determined or withdrawn; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633413_006" name="b" temporalId="s25B_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in any other case, the day on which the period during which such an appeal may be taken expires.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633413_013" name="4" temporalId="s25B_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The interests in property referred to in subsection (1) are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633413_021" name="a" temporalId="s25B_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>any beneficial interest in property which (apart from the forfeiture rule) the offender would have acquired—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411633413_029" name="i" temporalId="s25B_4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>under the relevant deceased’s will or the law relating to intestacy;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411633413_037" name="ii" temporalId="s25B_4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>on the nomination of that deceased or on the failure of that deceased to make a nomination;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411633413_045" name="iii" temporalId="s25B_4_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>as a donatio mortis causa made by that deceased; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633413_052" name="b" temporalId="s25B_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any beneficial interest in property which (apart from the forfeiture rule) the offender would have acquired in consequence of the death of such deceased, being property which, before the death, was held on trust for any person.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633413_059" name="5" temporalId="s25B_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>An order under subsection (1) may modify the effect of the forfeiture rule in respect of any interest in property to which the order relates and may do so in either or both of the following ways, that is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633413_067" name="a" temporalId="s25B_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where there is more than one such interest, by excluding the application of the rule in respect of any (but not all) of those interests; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633428_006" name="b" temporalId="s25B_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of any such interest in property, by excluding the application of the rule in respect of part of the property.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633428_013" name="6" temporalId="s25B_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>On the making of an order under subsection (1), the forfeiture rule shall have effect for all purposes (including purposes relating to anything done before the order was made) subject to the modifications made by the order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633428_021" name="7" temporalId="s25B_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A court shall not make an order under subsection (1) modifying the effect of the forfeiture rule in respect of any interest in property which, in consequence of the rule, has been acquired before the coming into force of this section by a person other than the offender or a person claiming through him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633428_029" name="8" temporalId="s25B_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="Property"><term>property</term>
                                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">財產</term>) includes any chose
                                in action or incorporeal movable property;</def><def name="Will"><term>will</term>
                                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">遺囑</term>) includes a
                                codicil.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 34 s.
                                2
                                U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402862378_002" name="s25C" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s25C"><num value="25C">25C.</num><heading>Application for financial provision not affected by the rule</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633475_004" name="1" temporalId="s25C_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The forfeiture rule shall not be taken to preclude any person from making any application under a provision mentioned in subsection (2) or the making of any order on any such application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633475_012" name="2" temporalId="s25C_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The provisions referred to in subsection (1) are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633475_020" name="a" temporalId="s25C_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any provision of the Inheritance (Provision for Family and Dependants) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap481">Cap. 481</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633475_028" name="b" temporalId="s25C_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><ref>sections 11</ref> and <ref>16</ref> of the Matrimonial Proceedings and
                    Property Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap192">Cap. 192</ref>).</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 34 s.
                    3
                    U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402862394_001" name="s25D" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s25D"><num value="25D">25D.</num><heading>Exclusion of murderers</heading><content>Nothing in this Part or in any order made under <ref>section 25B(1)</ref> or
            referred to in <ref>section 25C(1)</ref> shall affect the application of the forfeiture
            rule in the case of a person who stands convicted of murder.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1982 c. 34 s.
            5
            U.K.]</referenceNote><sourceNote></sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438402862394_003" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            VI</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402862410_002" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Validity of instruments under seal executed by persons not appointed under seal</heading><editorialNote id="ID_1470383324835_001"><content></content></editorialNote><subsection id="ID_1438411633522_011" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The fact that a power of attorney or document of authorization given by a foreign corporation to or in favour of any person is not under seal shall not, if such power of attorney or document of authorization is valid as a power of attorney or document of authorization in accordance with the laws of the place under which such corporation is incorporated, affect, for any purpose intended to be effected within Hong Kong, the validity or effect of any instrument under seal executed on behalf of such corporation by such person, which shall for all such purposes be as valid as if such authority had been under seal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633537_005" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="ForeignCorporation">In this section,
                    <term>foreign
                    corporation</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">外地法團</term>) means any corporate body duly
                incorporated in accordance with the laws of any place outside Hong Kong.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1920/1">1 of 1920 ss. 2</ref> &amp; 3 incorporated. Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/53">53 of 1971 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/23">23 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862425_001" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Payment of emoluments, etc., when the payee is certified to be incapable</heading><content>When any sum in respect of emoluments, pension, gratuity or other allowance is payable out of the revenues of the Colony to any public servant, or to the widow or child of any public servant, and the person to whom the sum is payable is certified by 2 persons who are either Government Medical Officers or medical practitioners to be unable by reason of mental disability to manage his or her affairs, the Governor in Council may direct the payment of so much of the said sum as he may think fit to the institution or person having the care of the disabled person, and may direct the payment of the surplus, if any, or so much thereof as he may think fit, for or towards the maintenance and benefit of the wife or husband and relatives of the disabled person, and payment under such direction shall be a sufficient discharge from all liability in respect of any sums so paid.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1935/27">27 of 1935 s. 2</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1890 c. 5 s. 335 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862425_003" name="s28" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1984/62">62 of 1984 s. 66</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862441_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Imposition of penalty not to bar civil action</heading><content>The imposition of a penalty or fine by or under any Ordinance shall not relieve any person from liability to answer in damages to a person injured.</content><editorialNote type="footnote"><content>Editorial Note:</content><content>This provision previously appeared in s. 85 of <ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>. By virtue of <ref href="/hk/1993/89">89 of 1993 s. 27</ref>, it was re-enacted as s. 29 of this Ordinance.</content></editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402862441_003" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Defence of tender before action</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411633600_032" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding any rule of law to the contrary, in proceedings for a monetary claim, whether liquidated or unliquidated, it is a defence for the defendant to prove that before the claimant commenced the proceedings, the defendant had unconditionally offered to the claimant—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633600_040" name="a" temporalId="s30_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the amount due where the claim is liquidated; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633600_048" name="b" temporalId="s30_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an amount sufficient to satisfy the claim where the claim is unliquidated.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633615_005" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The defendant is not entitled to rely on the defence under subsection (1) unless, before serving his defence on the claimant, he has—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411633615_013" name="a" temporalId="s30_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>made a payment into court of the amount offered; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411633615_021" name="b" temporalId="s30_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>notified the claimant of the payment into court.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411633615_028" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>This section does not apply in relation to proceedings commenced before the
                    commencement<sup>#</sup>
                of this section.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2008/3">3 of 2008 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1477453612347_001"><content>Editorial Note:</content><content><sup>#</sup>
                Commencement date: 2 April 2009.</content></editorialNote></section></part></main></ordinance>