<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 99 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>99A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap99A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-11-14</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403578198_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2024-11-07">Pension Benefits Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap99/s35">Cap.
                                                99, section
                                    35</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 July 1987]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
                                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403578198_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403578214_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the <shortTitle>Pension Benefits Regulations</shortTitle>. </content></section><section id="ID_1438403578214_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="CategoryAOfficer"><term>Category A officer</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">甲類人員</term>) means an officer who is appointed to an established office and who is
            confirmed in an established office at the time of his retirement or resignation from the
            service; </def><def name="CategoryBOfficer"><leadIn><term>Category B officer</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">乙類人員</term>) means an officer
                who is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118045_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>holding a non-established office at the time of his retirement or resignation from the service; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118045_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>holding an established office at the time of his retirement or resignation
                    from the service and who is not confirmed in an established office;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Month"><term>month</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">月</term>) means a complete month,
            and any incomplete month shall be taken to be that fraction of a complete month whereof
            the denominator is 30 and the numerator the number of days of service in that incomplete
            month, irrespective of the actual number of days in that month. </def></section></part><part id="ID_1438403578229_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part II</num><heading>Officers other than Transferred Officers</heading><section id="ID_1438403578229_004" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application of Part II</heading><text>Save when the Chief Executive in any special case otherwise directs, this Part shall not apply in the case of any officer who is transferred to or from the service under the Government from or to other public service except for the purpose of determining whether such officer would have been eligible for pension benefits, and the amount of the pension benefits for which he would have been eligible, if his service had been wholly under the Government. </text><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403578245_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Pension factor</heading><leadIn>Subject to <ref>section 21</ref> of the Ordinance, the factor for the computation of pension on retirement in the circumstances specified in <ref>sections 11</ref>, <ref>12</ref> and <ref>14</ref> of the Ordinance shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118139_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the case of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118139_020" name="i" temporalId="s4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a Category A officer or Category B officer who is appointed or re-appointed to service under the Government on or after 1 July 1987; or </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118139_028" name="ii" temporalId="s4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a Category A officer who is appointed or re-appointed to service under the Government before 1 July 1987, and who is an officer who has opted, or who is deemed to have opted, under <ref>section 9</ref> of the Ordinance,</content></subparagraph><continued>1/675 of his highest pensionable emoluments for each month of his pensionable service; and </continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118155_012" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the case of a Category B officer who is appointed or re-appointed to service under the Government before 1 July 1987, and who is an officer who has opted, or who is deemed to have opted, under <ref>section 9</ref> of the Ordinance—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118155_020" name="i" temporalId="s4_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>1/800 of his highest pensionable emoluments for each month of his pensionable service before 1 April 1987; and </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118155_028" name="ii" temporalId="s4_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>1/675 of his highest pensionable emoluments for each month of his pensionable service after 31 March 1987. </content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403578260_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Rate of short service gratuity</heading><content>The rate of short service gratuity granted to an officer under <ref>section 32</ref> of the Ordinance shall be an amount not exceeding 7 times the annual amount of the pension which, if there had been no requirement for a period of qualifying service, would have been granted to him at the factor prescribed in <ref>regulation 4</ref>. </content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403578260_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part III</num><heading>Transferred Officers</heading><section id="ID_1438403578276_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Application of Part III</heading><content>This Part shall apply only in the case of an officer who is transferred to or from service under the Government from or to other public service. </content></section><section id="ID_1438403578276_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414118264_011" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Part and Part IV—</leadIn><def name="ScheduledGovernment"><term><ref>Schedule</ref>d Government</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK"><ref>附表</ref>政府</term>) means the Government of any
                country or territory, or any authority, mentioned in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln374">L.N. 374 of
                        1992</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </def><def name="ServiceInTheGroup"><term>service in the Group</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">任職於組內的政府</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">任職於組內政府的服務</term>) means service
                under the Government and under a <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government or
                    <ref>Schedule</ref>d Governments. </def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118279_011" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purpose of this Part and Part IV—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118279_019" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any officer in public service under the Government of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland immediately before 1 January 1964 who was, immediately before that date, employed on secondment to service under the Government of Southern Rhodesia, the Government of Northern Rhodesia or the Government of Nyasaland, or was as from that date so employed, shall be deemed to continue in public service under the Government of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland until his employment on secondment was terminated; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118295_006" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any pension awarded on or after 1 January 1964 in respect of service under the Government of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland shall be deemed to have been granted by that Government notwithstanding the provisions of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland (Dissolution) Order 1963. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118295_013" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where an officer, to whom this Part applies, is, on his retirement from the public service, not granted a pension or gratuity in respect of his employment in the service in which he is last employed, solely by reason of the fact that he has not held office therein for a specified period he shall nevertheless be deemed for the purpose of this Part to have retired in circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in which he is last employed to retire on pension or gratuity. </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578292_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Pension for service wholly within the Group</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414118357_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the other public service of an officer to whom this Part applies has been wholly under one or more <ref>Schedule</ref>d Governments, and his aggregate service would have qualified him had it been wholly under the Government for a pension under the Ordinance, he may, on his retirement from the public service in circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in which he is last employed to retire on pension or gratuity, be granted in respect of his service under the Government a pension of such an amount as shall bear the same proportion to the amount of pension for which he would have been eligible had his service been wholly under the Government, as the aggregate amounts of his pensionable emoluments during his service under the Government shall bear to the aggregate amounts of his pensionable emoluments throughout his service in the Group. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118404_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In determining for the purposes of this regulation the pension for which an officer would have been eligible if his service had been wholly under the Government—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118404_013" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the application of <ref>regulation 16</ref>—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118404_021" name="i" temporalId="s8_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>where the officer is not serving under a <ref>Schedule</ref>d
                        Government at the date of his retirement from the public service, subject to
                        sub-subparagraph (ii), the highest pensionable emoluments enjoyed by him in
                        the service of a <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government shall be taken; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118404_029" name="ii" temporalId="s8_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if, by reason of any order made in any disciplinary proceedings against
                        the officer, the amount to be taken in accordance with sub-subparagraph (i)
                        exceeds the pensionable emoluments enjoyed or drawn by him in the service
                        under the Government, or the pensionable emoluments enjoyed by him in the
                        service under a <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government, as the case may be, at the
                        date of his retirement or transfer, there shall be taken such pensionable
                        emoluments;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118420_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>no regard shall be had to any additional pension granted under <ref>section 15</ref> or <ref>16</ref> of the Ordinance; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118420_014" name="c" temporalId="s8_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>regard shall be had to the provision in <ref>section 21</ref>(1) of the
                    Ordinance that pension shall not exceed two-thirds of his highest pensionable
                    emoluments; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118435_006" name="d" temporalId="s8_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>no period of other public service under a<inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref>Schedule</ref>d Government in respect of which no pension or gratuity is grantable to him shall be taken into account. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118435_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>For the purposes of this regulation, the aggregate amount of an officer’s pensionable emoluments shall be taken as the total amount of pensionable emoluments which he would have received or enjoyed had he been on duty on full pay in his substantive office or offices throughout his period of service in the Group:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s. 40</ref>)</sourceNote> </leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s8_3_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118435_028" name="a" temporalId="s8_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in calculating the aggregate amount of his pensionable emoluments, no account shall be taken of any service under the Government or under a <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government in respect of which no pension or gratuity is granted to him by the Government or such <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government, as the case may be; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118451_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where any service in a civil capacity otherwise than in a pensionable or established office is taken into account as pensionable service, the officer’s aggregate pensionable emoluments during that service shall be taken into account to the same extent as that service is taken into account as pensionable service. </content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578292_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Pension where other service not within the Group</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414118513_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the other public service of an officer to whom this Part applies has not
                included service under any <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government, and his aggregate
                service would have qualified him, had it been wholly under the Government, for a
                pension under the Ordinance he may, on his retirement from the public service in the
                circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in
                which he is last employed to retire on a pension or gratuity, be granted in respect
                of his service under the Government a pension at the rate of 1/675 of his highest
                pensionable emoluments for each month of his pensionable service under the
                Government. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118529_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the officer is not in the service under the Government at the time of
                such retirement, his pensionable emoluments for the purposes of paragraph (1) shall
                be those which would have been taken for the purpose of computing his pension if he
                had retired from the public service and had been granted a pension at the date of
                his last transfer from service under the Government.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578307_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Pension when other service both within and not within the Group</heading><content>Where a part only of the other public service of an officer to whom this Part applies has been under one or more <ref>Schedule</ref>d Governments, the provisions of <ref>regulation 8</ref> shall apply; but in calculating the amount of pension regard shall be had only to service in the Group. </content></section><section id="ID_1438403578307_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Rate of short service gratuity</heading><content>The rate of short service gratuity granted to an officer under <ref>section 32</ref> of the Ordinance to whom this Part applies and who retires from the public service in circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in which he is last employed to retire on pension or gratuity shall be an amount not exceeding 7 times the annual amount of the pension which, if there had been no requirement for a period of qualifying service, would have been granted to him under <ref>regulation 8</ref>, <ref>9</ref> or <ref>10</ref>, as the case may be. </content></section><section id="ID_1438403578323_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Computation of deferred pension for service within the Group</heading><content>A deferred pension granted to an officer in respect of service within the Group shall be computed in accordance with <ref>regulation 8</ref>, <ref>9</ref> or <ref>10</ref>, as the case may be. </content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403578338_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part IV</num><heading>General</heading><section id="ID_1438403578338_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>General rules as to qualifying service and pensionable service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414118669_011" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to these regulations, qualifying service shall be the inclusive period between the date on which an officer begins to draw salary in respect of public service and the date of his leaving public service, without deduction of any period during which he has been absent on leave. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118669_019" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Only service under the Government shall be taken into account as qualifying service in respect of an officer, other than an officer who is transferred to or from service under the Government from or to other public service. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118685_005" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No period which is not qualifying service shall be taken into account as pensionable service. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118685_013" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>No period during which an officer was not in the public service shall be taken into account as qualifying service and pensionable service. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118685_021" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any period during which an officer, who is in the public service, is seconded to service which is not public service may, with the approval of the Chief Executive, be counted as qualifying service and pensionable service.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote> </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578354_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Continuity of service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414118732_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Except as otherwise provided in these regulations, only continuous service shall be taken into account as qualifying service or as pensionable service. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118732_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an officer has more than one period of pensionable service, every such period shall be taken into account separately for the purposes of computing pension benefits. </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578370_001" name="s15" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-02-17" status="repealed" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403578370_003" name="s15A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s15A"><num value="15A">15A.</num><heading>Additional pension in respect of war service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414118825_011" name="1" temporalId="s15A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>This regulation applies to any officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118825_019" name="a" temporalId="s15A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>who has at any time (whether before or after the commencement<sup>#</sup>
                    of the Pension Benefits (Amendment) <ref>Regulation 1992</ref>
                    (<ref href="/hk/1992/ln374">L.N. 374 of
                    1992</ref>))
                    been granted, or who is eligible for, a pension under the Ordinance; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118841_006" name="b" temporalId="s15A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>who performed war service or compulsory national service; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118841_014" name="c" temporalId="s15A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>who is not entitled to an additional pension under the Colonial Service
                    Officers Pensions Addition for War Service (United Kingdom) Scheme 1989.
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118841_021" name="2" temporalId="s15A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An officer to whom this regulation applies shall be granted an additional
                pension in respect of his war service if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118841_029" name="a" temporalId="s15A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>his war service was not preceded by a period of pensionable service, and his
                    relevant Government service—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118841_037" name="i" temporalId="s15A_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>began before 1 July 1950; or </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118841_045" name="ii" temporalId="s15A_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>began on or after 1 July 1950 on the completion of a course of
                        training, or probationership which was regarded as training, after his
                        provisional selection to service under the Government or under the
                        Government of the United Kingdom, provided that such training or
                        probationership began before 1 July 1950 and was, in the opinion of the
                        Secretary for the Civil Service, necessary before he could be appointed to
                        that service; or </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414118857_007" name="iii" temporalId="s15A_2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>began on or after 1 July 1950 following his selection before 1 July
                        1950, provided that he was available to take up the appointment before 1
                        July 1950 and took the first opportunity to travel to take up the
                        appointment after selection; or </content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118857_014" name="b" temporalId="s15A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>his relevant Government service was interrupted by his war service because
                    he was required to perform compulsory national service on or after 1 July 1947.
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118872_005" name="3" temporalId="s15A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Subject to paragraphs (4), (5) and (6), the additional pension payable under
                this regulation shall be calculated as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118872_013" name="a" temporalId="s15A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of an officer to whom paragraph <ref>(2)(a)</ref> applies, an
                    annual amount equal to 1/675 of his pensionable emoluments for each complete
                    period of 2 months of war service; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118872_021" name="b" temporalId="s15A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of an officer to whom paragraph <ref>(2)(b)</ref> applies, an
                    annual amount equal to 1/675 of his pensionable emoluments for each complete
                    month of war service, </content></paragraph><continued>and in calculating any period of war service, service before the officer
                attained the age of 18 years shall be disregarded.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118872_034" name="4" temporalId="s15A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If there was a break other than a break caused by war service in an officer’s
                relevant Government service that has not been condoned by the Government concerned,
                the reference in paragraph (3) to pensionable emoluments shall be treated as a
                reference to the officer’s pensionable emoluments during the period of service
                before that break.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118888_005" name="5" temporalId="s15A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Any amount of pension in respect of war service payable to an officer at the
                date of his retirement—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118888_013" name="a" temporalId="s15A_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by the Government, otherwise than under this regulation; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118888_021" name="b" temporalId="s15A_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by a <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government, </content></paragraph><continued>shall be deducted from the additional pension payable under this regulation.
            </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118888_034" name="6" temporalId="s15A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Any period of war service in respect of which an officer received non-effective
                pay or excess remuneration shall not count as war service for the purposes of
                paragraph (3).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118888_042" name="7" temporalId="s15A_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>An additional pension granted under this regulation shall be granted as
                from—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414118903_005" name="a" temporalId="s15A_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the commencement of the Pension Benefits (Amendment) <ref>Regulation
                        1992</ref>
                    (<ref href="/hk/1992/ln374">L.N. 374 of
                    1992</ref>);
                    or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414118903_013" name="b" temporalId="s15A_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the retirement of the officer, </content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the later, and shall be calculated and granted in Hong Kong
                dollars. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118903_026" name="8" temporalId="s15A_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>An officer to whom an additional pension is granted under this regulation shall
                not have an option under
                    <ref>section
                    24</ref> of the Ordinance to be paid, in lieu of that additional pension, a
                gratuity and a reduced pension. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414118903_034" name="9" temporalId="s15A_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>In this regulation—</leadIn><def name="ExcessRemuneration"><term>excess remuneration</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附加報酬</term>) means, in relation to a retired officer of
                the Armed Forces of the United Kingdom who is re-employed in those forces, any
                service pension drawn in respect of such period of re-employment or any addition to
                the normal pay attaching to the post in which the officer was re-employed which is
                granted by reason of the officer’s former employment in those forces;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="NoneffectivePay"><term>non-effective pay</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">不再服務薪津</term>) includes naval, military or air force pensions, retired pay or
                gratuities (other than war gratuities to which <ref>section 23</ref> of the Finance
                (No. 2) Act 1945 (1945 c. 13 U.K.) applied); </def><def name="RelevantGovernmentService"><term>relevant Government service</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關的政府服務期</term>) means service under the Government or
                under the Government of the United Kingdom that may be taken into account in
                determining whether an officer is eligible by length of service for a pension; </def><def name="WarService">
                <leadIn><term>war service</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">戰時服務</term>) means
                    service at any time between 3 September 1939 and 30 June 1950 in—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438414118919_026" name="a" temporalId="s15A_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Armed Forces of the United Kingdom;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438414118919_034" name="b" temporalId="s15A_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the merchant navy or mercantile marine; </content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438414118919_042" name="c" temporalId="s15A_9_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any of the women’s services listed in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>. </content></paragraph>
            </def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln374">L.N. 374 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1728267312155_001">
        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
        <content>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="font_size_9">
                <col width="3%"></col>
                <col width="1%"></col>
                <col width="97%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td><sup xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">#</sup></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">Commencement date: 10 November 1992.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </content>
    </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438403578385_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Emoluments to be taken for computing pension benefits</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414119013_011" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Subject to this regulation, for computing the amount of the pension benefits of an officer, the highest pensionable emoluments enjoyed or drawn by him in the course of his public service shall be taken into account: </leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s16_1_proviso">Provided that if, by reason of any order made in any disciplinary proceedings against an officer, the amount to be taken in accordance with the provisions of this regulation exceeds the pensionable emoluments enjoyed or drawn by him at the date of his retirement or resignation, as the case may be, there shall be taken such pensionable emoluments. </proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119028_004" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an officer has more than one period of continuous service the highest pensionable emoluments enjoyed or drawn by him in the course of any particular period of continuous service only shall be taken into account for computing the amount of the pension benefits for that period. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119028_012" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where an officer is serving on trial or on probation in an office immediately following public service other than on trial or probation, the highest pensionable emoluments which the officer would have enjoyed or drawn in his substantive office shall be taken into account for computing the amount of the pension benefits in respect of such service. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119044_005" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), any increase in the pensionable emoluments of any
                office held by an officer due to a revision of salaries with effect from a date
                subsequent to the commencement of a period of his absence from duty on leave without
                salary shall be disregarded for the purposes of paragraph (1), unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119044_013" name="a" temporalId="s16_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the officer has, since the expiration of that period of absence and in
                    respect of that period of absence (taking the earliest period first if there is
                    more than one), completed an equal period of service on duty or leave with
                    salary (other than leave immediately preceding retirement); </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119044_021" name="b" temporalId="s16_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the officer retires in one of the cases referred to in <ref>section
                        11(1)(d)</ref>, (g) or (h) of the Ordinance; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119044_029" name="c" temporalId="s16_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Chief Executive in any case otherwise directs.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119059_005" name="5" temporalId="s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>In the case of a serving officer who has further opted under <ref>section
                    8(3)</ref> of the Ordinance that 100 per cent of his substantive salary, special
                allowance and expatriation pay shall be taken
                as
                pensionable emoluments under the Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119059_013" name="a" temporalId="s16_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the highest pensionable emoluments specified in <ref>section
                        22(1)(b)(i)</ref> of the Ordinance shall be taken into account for computing
                    the pension benefits for the period of his service prior to the material date;
                        and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s.
                            41</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119059_021" name="b" temporalId="s16_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the highest pensionable emoluments specified in <ref>section
                        22(1)(b)(ii)</ref> of the Ordinance shall be taken into account for
                    computing the pension benefits for the period of his service from the material
                        date.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/4">4
                            of 1993 s. 41</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119059_028" name="6" temporalId="s16_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><def name="MaterialDate">For the purposes of paragraph (5), <term>material date</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">關鍵日期</term>) means a date to be determined in
                accordance with the terms of a Circular issued by the Secretary for the Civil
                Service under this regulation.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578385_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Service which may be taken as pensionable service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414119137_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to any option exercised under <ref>section 8(1)</ref> of the Ordinance and to these regulations, only service in an office the terms of appointment of which attracts pension benefits shall be taken into account as pensionable service. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119137_012" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a Category A officer has a period of service in a non-established office prior to 1 April 1987 and such service is immediately followed by service in an established office and the officer is subsequently confirmed in an established office, only 675/800 of such service in the non-established office shall be taken into account as pensionable service of a Category A officer; but where all the service of an officer is in a non-established office after 31 March 1987 the whole of such service shall be taken into account as pensionable service. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119153_005" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where an officer has been transferred from an established office in which he has been confirmed to a non-established office and subsequently retires or resigns, or is retired, as specified in <ref>section 11(1)</ref> of the Ordinance, the whole service of such officer may be counted—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119169_005" name="a" temporalId="s17_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>as pensionable service of a Category B officer; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119169_013" name="b" temporalId="s17_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>as pensionable service of a Category A officer but at his pensionable emoluments at the date of his transfer, </content></paragraph><continued>whichever yields the greater pension or short service gratuity. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119169_026" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where a female officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119169_034" name="a" temporalId="s17_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has, prior to 27 May 1966, retired from the service by reason of her marriage; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119169_042" name="b" temporalId="s17_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has, upon retirement, received a marriage gratuity under the Pensions
                    Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap89A">Cap. 89 sub. leg. A</ref>),
                            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>the period of service prior to such retirement shall not be taken into account as pensionable service. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119169_055" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a female officer, other than a divorced or widowed female officer confirmed in an established office prior to 17 November 1972, has, after marriage, served in an established office prior to 27 May 1966, her service as a married officer for the period up to that date shall be deemed to be service in an established office and such period may be taken into account as pensionable service of a Category A officer.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote> </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119184_005" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Where a female officer who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119184_013" name="a" temporalId="s17_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has retired by reason of her marriage between 27 May 1966 and 17 November 1972; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119184_021" name="b" temporalId="s17_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has received a gratuity under <ref>regulation 6</ref> or <ref>13</ref> of
                    the Pensions Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap89A">Cap. 89 sub. leg. A</ref>),
                            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>is subsequently re-appointed to service under the Government, the period of service under the Government in respect of which the gratuity was granted shall not be taken into account as pensionable service unless—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414119200_005" name="i" temporalId="s17_6_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>an application to the contrary has been made within 6 months of 17 November 1972; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119200_013" name="ii" temporalId="s17_6_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>there has been no break of service; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119200_021" name="iii" temporalId="s17_6_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the gratuity received has been refunded together with interest at a rate to be determined by the Financial Secretary. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119200_028" name="7" temporalId="s17_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>Where a female officer who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119200_036" name="a" temporalId="s17_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has, prior to 17 November 1972, retired from the service by reason of her marriage; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119200_044" name="b" temporalId="s17_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has not, upon retirement, received a marriage gratuity under the Pensions
                    Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap89A">Cap. 89 sub. leg. A</ref>),
                            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>is without break in service subsequently re-appointed to service under the Government, the period of service prior to such retirement shall be taken into account as pensionable service. </continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578401_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Deemed increase in service where retirement is on medical grounds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414119262_011" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to paragraph (2), in the case of an officer who retires from the public
                service under <ref>section 11(1)(h)</ref> of the Ordinance and whose period of
                qualifying service under the Government is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119278_005" name="a" temporalId="s18_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>not less than 5 nor more than 22 1/2 years; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119278_013" name="b" temporalId="s18_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>more than 22 1/2 years but whose pensionable service is less than 22 1/2
                    years, </content></paragraph><continued>his pensionable service shall be deemed to be—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414119278_027" name="i" temporalId="s18_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>twice the actual period of his pensionable service, subject to a maximum of
                    22 1/2 years; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119278_035" name="ii" temporalId="s18_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the period of pensionable service that he would have completed if he had
                    served until attaining the age of 60, </content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the lesser. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119278_048" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Paragraph (1) shall apply in the case of an officer who is re-appointed to
                service under the Government irrespective of the length of qualifying service
                completed during such re-appointment, but the deemed increase of pensionable service
                under that paragraph shall be limited as provided in <ref>section 20(8)</ref> and
                (9) of the Ordinance.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578416_001" name="s18A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s18A"><num value="18A">18A.</num><heading>Deemed increase in service where retirement is necessitated by duty-related injury</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414119325_004" name="1" temporalId="s18A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to paragraph (2), where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119325_012" name="a" temporalId="s18A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an officer retires from the public service on the ground that he is
                    incapable by reason of infirmity of mind or body of discharging the duty of his
                    office; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119325_020" name="b" temporalId="s18A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>his retirement is necessitated or materially accelerated by permanent
                    injury sustained in the circumstances described in <ref>section 14(1)</ref> of
                    the Ordinance, </content></paragraph><continued>his pensionable service shall be deemed to be twice the actual period of his
                pensionable service, subject to a minimum of 2 years and a maximum of—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414119340_006" name="i" temporalId="s18A_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>22 1/2 years; or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119340_014" name="ii" temporalId="s18A_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the period of pensionable service that he would have completed if he had
                    served until attaining the age of 60, </content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the lesser. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119340_027" name="2" temporalId="s18A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Paragraph (1) shall apply in the case of an officer who is reappointed to
                service under the Government irrespective of the length of qualifying service
                completed during such reappointment, but the deemed increase of pensionable service
                under that paragraph shall be limited as provided in <ref>section 20(8)</ref> and
                (9) of the Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 52</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578416_003" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Deemed increase in service where <ref>Schedule</ref>d officers retire after the age
            of 55</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438414119387_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraphs (2), (3) and (4), in the case of a <ref>Schedule</ref>d
                officer who retires in accordance with an order made under <ref>section 10(3)</ref>
                of the Ordinance on attaining, or after attaining, the age of 55 years his
                pensionable service shall be deemed to increase at the following
                    rate—<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                    <col width="50%"></col>
                    <col width="50%"></col>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> <br></br>Age at date
                                of retirement</center>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Deemed increase
                                in service in <br></br>months for every full year <br></br>of completed
                                service </center>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">55 and less than
                                56<br></br>56 and less than 57<br></br>57 and less than 58<br></br>58 and less
                                than 59<br></br>59 and less than 60</center>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">1.25 <br></br>1.00
                                <br></br>0.75 <br></br>0.50 <br></br>0.25 </center>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </table><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119387_011" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The deemed increase in paragraph (1) shall apply to a <ref>Schedule</ref>d
                officer, who has further opted under <ref>section 8(3)</ref> of the Ordinance, on a
                pro rata basis in accordance with a Circular issued by the Secretary for the Civil
                Service.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119403_001" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The total length of the pensionable service of a <ref>Schedule</ref>d officer,
                after the addition of the deemed increase in his service in accordance with
                paragraph (1) or (2), shall not exceed—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119403_009" name="a" temporalId="s19_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the period of pensionable service required for attaining maximum pension;
                    or </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119403_017" name="b" temporalId="s19_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the period of pensionable service that the <ref>Schedule</ref>d officer
                    would have completed if he had served until attaining the age of 60 years,
                </content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the lesser. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119403_030" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>This regulation shall not apply to a <ref>Schedule</ref>d officer who retires
                under <ref>section 11(1)(i)</ref> of the Ordinance. </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578432_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Acting service</heading><leadIn>Where an officer has performed acting service in an office under the Government the period of the acting service may be taken into account as pensionable service (subject to <ref>regulation 17</ref> if the acting service is in a non-established office) if the period of the acting service—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119449_012" name="a" temporalId="s20_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is not taken into account as part of the officer’s pensionable service in other public service; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119449_020" name="b" temporalId="s20_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is immediately preceded or followed by service as the substantive holder of an established office under the Government. </content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403578432_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Service not counting as pensionable service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414119481_011" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Save as otherwise provided in these regulations, there shall not be taken into account as pensionable service any period of service while an officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119481_019" name="a" temporalId="s21_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s. 42</ref>) </sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119481_027" name="b" temporalId="s21_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>was on agreement expressly providing for the payment of a gratuity dependent upon the length of his service, unless he has refunded the gratuity (if any) received in respect of that period together with interest at a rate to be determined by the Financial Secretary; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119496_006" name="c" temporalId="s21_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>was on agreement on monthly terms not providing for payment of a gratuity, unless without break of service he is confirmed in an established office; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119496_014" name="d" temporalId="s21_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>was serving in an office the terms of appointment of which do not attract pension benefits; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119496_022" name="e" temporalId="s21_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>was absent from duty without salary, unless such absence shall have been approved on grounds of public policy by the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote> </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119496_029" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s. 42</ref>) </sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578448_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Rates of additional pension on retirement on abolition of office or compulsory
            retirement</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414119527_019" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the rate of additional pension granted under
                    <ref>section 16</ref> of the Ordinance shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119543_001" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a Category A officer, 10/675 of his highest pensionable
                    emoluments for each complete 3-year period of his pensionable service;
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119543_009" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the case of a Category B officer—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414119543_017" name="i" temporalId="s22_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in respect of service before 1 April 1987, 1/80 of his highest
                        pensionable emoluments for each complete 3-year period of his pensionable
                        service; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414119543_025" name="ii" temporalId="s22_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in respect of an incomplete 3-year period of his pensionable service,
                        service before 1 April 1987 which is followed by pensionable service after
                        that date sufficient to complete a 3-year period, 10/675 of his highest
                        pensionable emoluments; and </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414119543_033" name="iii" temporalId="s22_1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>in respect of service after 1 April 1987, other than where
                        sub-subparagraph (ii) applies, 10/675 of his highest pensionable emoluments
                        for each complete 3-year period of his pensionable service.
                                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
                            2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119559_005" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (3), an additional pension granted to an officer in
                accordance with paragraph (1), shall not exceed 100/675 of the officer’s highest
                pensionable emoluments. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119559_013" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An additional pension granted to an officer in accordance with paragraph (1)
                together with any pension granted to him at the factor prescribed in <ref>regulation
                    4</ref> shall not exceed the amount of pension which an officer would have been
                granted if he had continued to serve until the date on which he would have reached
                his retirement age, having received all increments for which he would have been
                eligible by that date. </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578448_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Rates of additional pension on account of injuries</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414119621_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (5), the annual rate of additional pension
                granted under <ref>section 15(1)</ref> of the Ordinance to an officer who is injured
                on or after 1 February 1993 in the circumstances described in <ref>section 14</ref>
                of the Ordinance shall be the same percentage of his actual pensionable emoluments
                as at the date of his injury as the percentage of permanent incapacity resulting
                from such injury.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 53</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552
                        of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119621_012" name="1A" temporalId="s23_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>The percentage of permanent incapacity referred to in paragraph (1) shall be
                assessed in such manner as the Secretary for the Civil Service may specify by
                general notice published in the Gazette.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
                    53</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119637_005" name="1B" temporalId="s23_1B"><num value="1B">(1B)</num><content>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (6), the annual rate of additional pension
                granted under <ref>section 15(1)</ref> of the Ordinance to an officer who is injured
                before 1 February 1993 in the circumstances described in <ref>section 14</ref> of
                the Ordinance shall be the proportion of his actual pensionable emoluments at the
                date of his injury appropriate to his case as shown in the table in this paragraph,
                whether his capacity to contribute to his own support because of the injury is
                impaired before or after his retirement.
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content><content>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="left_indent_30">
                    <col width="7%"></col>
                    <col width="73%"></col>
                    <col width="20%"></col>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td colspan="3" class="align_center">Table<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td colspan="3" class="align_left">When the officer’s capacity to
                                contribute to his own support is—</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>(a)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_.">slightly impaired </td>
                            <td class="align_right">50/675</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>(b)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_.">impaired </td>
                            <td class="align_right">100/675</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>(c)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_.">materially impaired </td>
                            <td class="align_right">150/675</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>(d)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_.">totally destroyed </td>
                            <td class="align_right">200/675</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552 of 1994</ref>) </sourceNote></td>
                            <td class="align_right"></td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119668_011" name="1C" temporalId="s23_1C"><num value="1C">(1C)</num><leadIn>A medical board appointed by the Hospital Authority shall determine for the
                purpose of paragraph (1B)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119668_019" name="a" temporalId="s23_1C_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>whether or not an officer’s capacity to contribute to his own support
                    because of the injury is impaired; and </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119668_027" name="b" temporalId="s23_1C_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the degree of impairment in accordance with the table in paragraph
                        (1B).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119668_034" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The rate of additional pension under paragraph (1) or (1B) may be reduced to
                such an extent as the Chief Executive thinks reasonable where the injury is not the
                cause or the sole cause of retirement.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119668_042" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 53</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119668_050" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>An additional pension in accordance with this regulation shall be
                payable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414119668_058" name="a" temporalId="s23_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of an officer who suffers incapacity before his retirement or
                    whose capacity to contribute to his own support is impaired before his
                    retirement, with effect from the date of his retirement;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 53</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552 of
                        1994</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414119683_006" name="b" temporalId="s23_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of an officer who suffers incapacity after his retirement or
                    whose capacity to contribute to his own support is impaired after his
                    retirement, with effect from the date on which such incapacity is determined in
                    accordance with paragraph (1A) or the date on which his degree of impairment is
                    determined, as the case may be.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 53</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote>
                </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119683_013" name="5" temporalId="s23_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If there is any variation in the degree of permanent incapacity of an officer
                subsequent to the grant of an additional pension at a rate in accordance with this
                regulation, the rate at which the additional pension has been granted may be
                reassessed in such manner as the Secretary for the Civil Service may specify by
                general notice published in the Gazette and at such time as the Secretary for the
                Civil Service may think fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 53</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414119699_005" name="6" temporalId="s23_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If there is any variation in the degree of the impairment of an officer’s
                capacity to contribute to his own support subsequent to the grant of an additional
                pension at a rate in accordance with paragraph (1B), the rate at which the
                additional pension has been granted may be reassessed in accordance with the table
                in paragraph (1B) by a medical board appointed by the Hospital Authority at such
                time or times as the board may think fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln552">L.N. 552 of
                    1994</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403578463_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-11-07" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Amendment of <ref>Schedule</ref></heading><content>The Secretary for the Civil Service may by order published in the Gazette amend the <ref>Schedule</ref>. </content></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403578463_004" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule 1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap99A/s7">reg.
                7</ref>]<sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln374">L.N. 374 of
                1992</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote></note><text>Aden</text><text>Antigua</text><text>Bahamas</text><text>Barbados</text><text>Basutoland</text><text>Bechuanaland
            Protectorate</text><text>Bermuda</text><text>British
            Antarctic
            Territory</text><text>British
            Guiana</text><text>British
            Honduras</text><text>British
            Solomon Islands
            Protectorate</text><text>Brunei</text><text>Cayman
            Islands</text><text>Ceylon,
            in respect of any officer appointed to service under the Government of Ceylon before 4
            February
            1948</text><text>Crown
            Agents for Oversea Governments and
            Administrations</text><text>Cyprus</text><text>Cyprus,
            in respect of any officer appointed to service under the Government of Cyprus before 16
            August
            1960</text><text>Dominica</text><text>East
            Africa High
            Commission</text><text>East
            African Common Services
            Organization</text><text>East
            African Common Services Organization or, with effect from 1 December 1967, the East
            African Community, in respect of any person deemed to have been appointed or appointed
            to service as President, Vice-President, Justice of Appeal, Registrar, officer or
            servant of the Court of Appeal for Eastern Africa or, with effect from 1 December 1967,
            of the Court of Appeal for East Africa or successor
            corporation</text><text>East
            African
            Community</text><text>East
            African Harbours
            Corporation</text><text>East
            African Posts and Telecommunications
            Corporation</text><text>East
            African Railways and Harbours
            Administration</text><text>East
            African Railways
            Corporation</text><text>Eastern
            Region of
            Nigeria</text><text>Employing
            Authorities under the Oversea Superannuation
            Scheme</text><text>Employing
            Authorities under the Overseas Service Act
            1958</text><text>Falkland
            Islands</text><text>Federal
            Republic of
            Nigeria</text><text>Federated
            Malay States
            </text><text>Federation
            of
            Malaya</text><text>Federation
            of
            Nigeria</text><text>Federation
            of Rhodesia and
            Nyasaland</text><text>Fiji
            </text><text>Gambia
            </text><text>Ghana</text><text>Gibraltar</text><text>Gilbert
            and Ellice Islands
            Colony</text><text>Gold
            Coast</text><text>Grenada</text><text>Guyana</text><text>Jamaica</text><text>Kenya</text><text>Kenya
            and Uganda Railways and Harbours
            Administration</text><text>Kingdom
            of
            Lesotho</text><text>Leeward
            Islands (before 1 July
            1956)</text><text>Malawi</text><text>Malayan
            Establishment</text><text>Malayan
            Union</text><text>Malaysia</text><text>Malta</text><text>Mauritius</text><text>Mid
            West
            Nigeria</text><text>Montserrat</text><text>Nigeria</text><text>North
            Borneo</text><text>Northern
            Region of
            Nigeria</text><text>Northern
            Rhodesia</text><text>Nyasaland</text><text>Overseas
            Audit Department (Home
            Establishment)</text><text>Palestine,
            in respect of any officer appointed to service under the Government of Palestine before
            15 May
            1948</text><text>Peoples’
            Democratic Republic of
            Yemen</text><text>Post
            Office, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern
            Ireland</text><text>Republic
            of
            Botswana</text><text>Republic
            of
            Zambia</text><text>Sabah</text><text>Sarawak</text><text>Seychelles</text><text>Sierra
            Leone</text><text>Singapore</text><text>Somali
            Republic, in respect of any officer appointed to service under the former Government of
            the Somaliland Protectorate before 26 June
            1960</text><text>Somaliland
            Protectorate
            </text><text>St.
            Christopher Nevis and Anguilla </text><text>St. Helena</text><text>St.
            Lucia</text><text>St.
            Vincent</text><text>Straits
            Settlements</text><text>Swaziland</text><text>Tanganyika</text><text>The
            West Indies
            (Federation)</text><text>Trinidad</text><text>Turks
            and Caicos
            Islands</text><text>Uganda</text><text>United
            Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern
            Ireland</text><text>United
            Republic of
            Tanzania<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>Virgin
            Islands</text><text>Western
            Region of
            Nigeria</text><text>Zanzibar</text><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
        2024</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403578479_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-11-14" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
                                    2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap99A/s15A">reg. 15A</ref>]</note><heading><inline>Women’s
                                                Services</inline></heading><section id="ID_1438414119964_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Member of Queen Alexandra’s Royal Naval Nursing Service
                                                or any reserve
                                                thereof</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119964_021" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>Member of the Women’s Royal Naval
                                                Service</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119964_030" name="s3" temporalId="sch2_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>Woman medical or dental practitioner serving in the
                                                Royal Navy or any naval
                                                reserve</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119964_039" name="s4" temporalId="sch2_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><content>Member of Queen Alexandra’s Imperial Military Nursing
                                                Service or any reserve thereof or of Queen
                                                Alexandra’s Royal Army Nursing Corps or any reserve
                                                thereof</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119964_048" name="s5" temporalId="sch2_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><content>Member of the Territorial Army Nursing Service or any
                                                reserve
                                                thereof</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119964_057" name="s6" temporalId="sch2_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><content>Member of the Auxiliary Territorial Service or the
                                                Women’s Royal Army
                                                Corps</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119980_005" name="s7" temporalId="sch2_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><content>Woman employed with the Royal Army Medical Corps or the
                                                Army Dental Corps with relative rank as an
                                                officer</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119980_014" name="s8" temporalId="sch2_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><content>Member of Princess Mary’s Royal Air Force Nursing
                                                Service or any reserve
                                                thereof<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1438414119980_023" name="s9" temporalId="sch2_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><content>Member of the Women’s Auxiliary Air Force or the
                                                Women’s Royal Air
                                                Force</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119980_032" name="s10" temporalId="sch2_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><content>Woman employed with the Medical Branch or the Dental
                                                Branch of the Royal Air Force with relative rank as
                                                an
                                                officer</content></section><section id="ID_1438414119980_041" name="s11" temporalId="sch2_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><content>Member of the Voluntary Aid Detachments employed under
                                                the Admiralty, Army Council or Air
                                                Council</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln374">L.N. 374 of
                                                1992</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2024/er6">E.R. 6 of
                                                2024</ref>) </sourceNote></section></schedule></main></subLeg>