<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 33</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>33</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap33!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403015571_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-04-07">
            <content>To provide for the formation and to regulate the operation of co-operative
                societies.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[15 February 1951]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1951/gna31">G.N.A. 31 of 1951</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403015586_001" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403015586_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Co-operative Societies Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403015602_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Bonus"><term>bonus</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">紅利</term>) means a share of the profits of a registered
            society divided among its members in proportion to the volume of business done with the
            society by them from which the profits of the society were derived;</def><def name="Bylaws"><term>by-laws</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">章程</term>) means the registered by-laws made by a
            society in the exercise of any power conferred by this Ordinance, and includes a
            registered amendment of the by-laws;</def><def name="Committee"><term>committee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">理事會</term>) means the governing body of a registered
            society to whom the management of its affairs is entrusted;</def><def name="Dividend"><term>dividend</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">股息</term>) means a share of the profits of a registered
            society divided among its members in proportion to the share capital held by them;</def><def name="Member"><term>member</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">社員</term>) includes a person or registered society
            joining in the application for the registration of a society, and a person or registered
            society admitted to membership after registration in accordance with the by-laws;</def><def name="Officer"><term>officer</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">高級人員</term>) includes a chairman, secretary, treasurer,
            member of committee, or other person empowered under the rules or by-laws to give
            directions in regard to the business of a registered society;</def><def name="RegisteredSociety"><term>registered
                society</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">註冊合作社</term>) means a co-operative society registered
            under this Ordinance;</def><def name="Registrar"><term>Registrar</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">註冊官</term>) means the Registrar of Co-operative
            Societies appointed under <ref>section 3</ref> and includes any person when exercising
            such powers of the Registrar as may have been conferred upon him under that
            section;</def><def name="Rules"><term>rules</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">規則</term>) means rules made under this Ordinance.</def></section></part><part id="ID_1438403015602_003" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Registration</heading><section id="ID_1438403015618_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Appointment of Registrar and assistant registrars</heading><text>The Chief Executive may appoint a person to be Registrar of Co-operative Societies for
            Hong Kong and may appoint persons to assist such Registrar, and may, by general or
            special order published in the Gazette, confer on any such persons all or any of the
            powers of a Registrar under this Ordinance.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403015618_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Societies which may be registered</heading><leadIn>Subject to the provisions hereinafter contained, a society which has as its object the promotion of the economic interests of its members in accordance with co-operative principles, or a society established with the object of facilitating the operations of such a society, may be registered under this Ordinance with or without limited liability as the Registrar may decide:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_proviso">Provided that the liability of a society which includes at least one registered society among its members shall be limited.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438403015633_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Conditions of registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411959625_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No society, other than a society of which a member is a registered society, shall be registered under this Ordinance, which does not consist of at least ten persons each of whom is qualified under <ref>section 21</ref> for membership.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959625_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The word “co-operative” or “合作社” shall form part of the English name or the Chinese name respectively of every society registered under this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 106</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959625_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The word “limited” shall be the last word in, or “有限責任” shall form part of, the English name or the Chinese name respectively of every society with limited liability registered under this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/21">21 of 1976 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 106</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959625_028" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>When for the purposes of this section any question arises as to age, residence, or occupation of land constituting the qualification of any person, that question shall be decided by the Registrar whose decision shall be final.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015633_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Application for registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411959656_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>For the purposes of registration an application shall be made to the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959656_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The application shall be signed—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411959656_020" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a society of which no member is a registered society, by at least ten persons qualified in accordance with the requirements of subsection (1) of <ref>section 5</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411959656_028" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a society of which a member is a registered society, by a duly authorized person on behalf of every such registered society, and, where all the members of the society are not registered societies, by ten other members, or, when there are less than ten other members, by all of them.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959656_035" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The application shall be accompanied by copies of the proposed by-laws of the society, and the persons by whom or on whose behalf such application is made shall furnish such information in regard to the society as the Registrar may require.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015649_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Registration and appeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411959687_011" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If the Registrar is satisfied that a society has complied with the provisions
                of this Ordinance and the rules, and that its proposed by-laws are not contrary to
                this Ordinance or to the rules, he may, if he thinks fit, register the society and
                its by-laws. An appeal shall lie to the Chief Executive in Council against the
                refusal of the Registrar to register any society within one month from the date of
                such refusal.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959687_019" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On registration the society shall pay such fee as may be required by the
                rules.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015664_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Societies to be bodies corporate</heading><content>The registration of a society shall render it a body corporate by the name under which it is registered, with perpetual succession and with power to hold property, to enter into contracts, to institute and defend suits and other legal proceedings, and to do all things necessary for the purpose of its constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403015664_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Evidence of registration</heading><content>A certificate of registration signed by the Registrar shall be conclusive evidence that the society therein mentioned is duly registered, unless it is proved that the registration of the society has been cancelled.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403015680_001" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Duties
            and Privileges
            of
            Societies</heading><section id="ID_1438403015680_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Amendment of the by-laws of a registered society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411959750_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any registered society may, subject to this Ordinance and the rules, amend its
                by-laws, including the by-law which declares the name of the society.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959750_019" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No amendment of the by-laws of a registered society shall be valid until that
                amendment has been registered under this Ordinance, for which purpose copies of the
                amendment shall be forwarded to the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959750_027" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the Registrar is satisfied that any amendment of the by-laws is not contrary
                to this Ordinance or to the rules, he may, if he thinks fit, register the amendment.
                An appeal shall lie to the Chief Executive in Council against the refusal of the
                Registrar to register any amendment of any by-law within one month from the date of
                such refusal.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/21">21 of 1976 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959765_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An amendment which changes the name of a society shall not affect any right or
                obligation of the society or of any of its members or past members, and any legal
                proceedings pending may be continued by or against the society under its new
                name.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959765_013" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>When the Registrar registers an amendment of the by-laws of a registered
                society, he shall issue to the society a copy of the amendment certified by him,
                which shall be conclusive evidence of the fact that the amendment has been duly
                registered.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015852_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Address of society</heading><content>Every registered society shall have an address to which all notices and communications may be sent and shall send to the Registrar notice of that address and of every change of that address within 30 days of the registration of the society or the change of address as the case may be; and the Registrar may effect registration thereof.</content><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/21">21 of 1976 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403015867_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Copy of Ordinance, rules, by-laws, etc., to be open to inspection</heading><content>Every registered society shall keep a copy of this Ordinance and of the rules and of its by-laws and a list of its members open to inspection, free of charge, at all reasonable times at the registered address of the society.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403015898_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Disposal of produce to or through a registered society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411959843_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A registered society which has as one of its objects the disposal of any article produced or obtained by the work or industry of its members whether the produce of agriculture, animal husbandry, forestry, fisheries, handicrafts or otherwise may provide in its by-laws or may otherwise contract with its members—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411959859_005" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that every such member who produces any such article shall dispose of the whole or any specified amount, proportion or description thereof to or through the society; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411959859_013" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that any member who is proved or adjudged, in such manner as may be prescribed by the rules to be guilty of a breach of the by-laws or contract shall pay to the society as liquidated damages a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>sum ascertained or assessed in such manner as may be prescribed by the aforesaid rules.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959859_020" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No contract entered into under the provisions of this section shall be contested in any court on the ground only that it constitutes a contract in restraint of trade.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015898_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Creation of charges in favour of registered societies</heading><leadIn>Subject to any prior claim of the Government on the property of the debtor and to
            the lien or claim of a landlord in respect of rent or any money recoverable as rent and
            in the case of immovable property to any prior registered charge
                thereon—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411959874_049" name="a" temporalId="s14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>
                <leadIn>any debt or outstanding demand payable to a registered society by any member
                    or past member shall be a first charge on all crops or other agricultural
                    produce, felled timber or other forest produce, marine produce, fish
                    (fresh-water and salt-water), livestock, fodder, agricultural, industrial and
                    fishing implements, plant, machinery, boats, tackle and nets, raw materials,
                    stock in trade and generally all produce of labour and things used in connexion
                    with production raised, purchased or produced in whole or in part from any loan
                    whether in money or in goods given him by the society:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s14_a_proviso">Provided that nothing herein
                    contained shall affect the claim of any bona fide purchaser or transferee
                    without notice;</proviso>
                
            </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411959890_012" name="b" temporalId="s14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any outstanding demands or dues payable to a registered housing society by any
                member or past member in respect of rent, shares, loans or purchase money or any
                other rights or amounts payable to such society shall be a first charge upon his
                interest in the immovable property of the society.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403015914_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Charge and set off in respect of shares or interest of members</heading><content>A registered society shall have a charge upon the shares or interests in the capital and on the deposits of a member or past member or deceased member and upon any dividend, bonus, or profits payable to a member or past member or to the estate of a deceased member in respect of any debt due to the society from such member or past member or estate, and may set off any sum credited or payable to a member or past member or estate of a deceased member in or towards payment of any such debt.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403015914_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Shares or interest not liable to attachment or sale</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 15</ref>, the share or interest of a member in the capital of a registered society shall not be liable to attachment or sale under any decree or order of a court in respect of any debt or liability incurred by such member, and neither his assignee in insolvency nor a receiver duly appointed shall be entitled to, or have any claim on, such share or interest.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403015930_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Transfer of interest on death of member</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411959937_011" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>On the death of a member, a registered society may transfer the share or interest of the deceased member to the person nominated in accordance with the rules made in this behalf, or, if there is no person so nominated, to such persons as may appear to the committee to be the heir or legal representative of the deceased member, or may pay to such nominee, heir or legal representative, as the case may be, a sum representing the value of such member’s share or interest, as ascertained in accordance with the rules or by-laws:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s17_1_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411959937_026" name="a" temporalId="s17_1_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a society with unlimited liability such nominee, heir or legal representative, as the case may be, may require payment by the society of the value of the share or interest of the deceased member ascertained as aforesaid;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411959937_034" name="b" temporalId="s17_1_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a society with limited liability, the society may transfer the share or interest of the deceased member to such nominee, heir or legal representative, as the case may be, being qualified in accordance with the rules and by-laws for membership of the society, or on his application within six months of the death of the deceased member to any person specified in the application who is so qualified.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959952_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A registered society shall pay all other moneys due to the deceased member from the society to such nominee, heir or legal representative, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959952_013" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>All transfers and payments made by a registered society in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be valid and effectual against any demand made upon the society by any other person.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015930_004" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Deposits by or on behalf of minors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411959984_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered society may receive deposits from or for the benefit of minors and it shall be lawful for a registered society to pay such minors the interest which may become due on such deposits. Any deposits made by a minor may, together with the interest accrued thereon, be paid to that minor; and any deposit made on behalf of a minor may, together with the interest accrued thereon, be paid to the guardian of that minor for the use of the minor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411959984_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The receipt of any minor or guardian for money paid to him under this section shall be a sufficient discharge of the liability of the society in respect of that money.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403015945_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Register of members</heading><leadIn>Any register or list of members kept by any registered society shall be prima facie evidence of any of the following particulars entered therein—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960015_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the date at which the name of any person was entered in such register or list as a member;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960015_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the date at which any such person ceased to be a member.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403015961_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Proof of entries in books of society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960030_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A copy of any entry in a book of a registered society regularly kept in the course of business shall, if certified in such manner as may be prescribed by the rules, be received in any legal proceeding, civil or criminal, as prima facie evidence of the existence of such entry and shall be admitted as evidence of the matters, transactions and accounts therein recorded in every case where, and to the same extent as, the original entry itself is admissible.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960030_012" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No officer of any such society shall, in any legal proceedings to which the
                society is not a
                party,
                be compelled to produce any of the society’s books, the contents of which can be
                proved under subsection (1) or to appear as a witness to prove any matters,
                transactions or accounts therein recorded, unless the court for special reason so
                directs.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403015961_003" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Rights
            and Liabilities
            of
            Members</heading><section id="ID_1438403015976_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Qualification for membership</heading><leadIn>In order to be qualified for membership of a co-operative society a person, other than a registered society, must—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960062_012" name="a" temporalId="s21_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>have attained the age of 18 years;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960062_020" name="b" temporalId="s21_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be resident within or in occupation of land within the society’s area of operations as described by the by-laws.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403015992_002" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Members not to exercise rights till due payment made</heading><content>No member of a registered society shall exercise the rights of a member unless or until he has made such payment to the society in respect of membership or acquired such interest in the society, as may be prescribed by the rules or by-laws.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016008_001" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Restriction of membership in society</heading><content>Except with the sanction of the Registrar, no person shall be a member of more than one registered society whose primary object is to grant loans to its members.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016008_003" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Votes of members</heading><leadIn>No member of any registered society shall have more than one vote in the conduct of the affairs of the society:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s24_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960108_019" name="a" temporalId="s24_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of an equality of votes the chairman shall have a casting vote;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960108_027" name="b" temporalId="s24_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of societies of which a registered society is a member that society may have such voting powers as are provided in the rules.</content></paragraph></proviso></section><section id="ID_1438403016023_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Representation by proxy</heading><content>A registered society which is a member of any other registered society may appoint any one of its members as its proxy for the purpose of voting in the conduct of the affairs of such other registered society.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016023_003" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Contracts with society of members who are minors</heading><content>The minority or non-age of any person duly admitted as a member of any registered society shall not debar that person from executing any instrument or giving any acquittance necessary to be executed or given under this Ordinance or the rules made thereunder, and shall not be a ground for invalidating or avoiding any contract entered into by any such person with the society; and any such contract entered into by any such person with the society, whether as principal or as surety, shall be enforceable at law or against such person notwithstanding his minority or non-age.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016039_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Block holdings of shares limited</heading><content>No member, other than a registered society, shall hold more than one-fifth of the share capital of any co-operative society.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016054_001" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Restriction on transfer of share or interest</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960155_011" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The transfer or charge of the share or interest of a member or past member or deceased member in the capital of a registered society shall be subject to such conditions as to maximum holding as may be prescribed by this Ordinance or by the rules.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960155_019" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In the case of a society registered with unlimited liability, a member shall not transfer any share held by him or his interest in the capital of the society or any part thereof, unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960171_005" name="a" temporalId="s28_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he has held such share or interest for not less than one year; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960171_013" name="b" temporalId="s28_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the transfer or charge is made to the society, or to a member of the society, or to a person whose application for membership has been accepted by the committee.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016054_003" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Liability of past member and estate of deceased member for debts of society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960186_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The liability of a past member for the debts of a registered society as they existed on the date on which he ceased to be a member shall not continue for a period of more than two years reckoned from that date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960186_012" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The estate of a deceased member shall not be liable for the debts of the society as they existed on the date of his decease for a period of more than two years reckoned from the date of his decease.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403016070_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Property
            and Funds
            of
            Registered
            Societies</heading><section id="ID_1438403016070_004" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Loans made by a registered society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960218_004" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>A registered society shall not, except as provided in <ref>section 33</ref>,
                    make any loan to any person other than a member:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s30_1_proviso">Provided that, with the consent
                    of the Registrar, a registered society may make loans to another registered
                    society.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960218_018" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Except with the permission of the Registrar, a registered society shall not
                lend money on the security of any movable property other than produce or goods in
                which the society is authorized to deal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960218_026" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Chief Executive may, by general or special order, prohibit or restrict the
                lending of money on mortgage of any description of immovable property by any
                registered society.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016086_002" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Deposits and loans received by a registered society</heading><content>A registered society shall receive deposits and loans from persons who are not members only to such extent and under such conditions as may be prescribed by the rules or by-laws.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016101_001" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Restrictions on other transactions with non-members</heading><content>Save as provided in <ref>sections 30</ref> and <ref>31</ref>, the transactions of a registered society with persons other than members shall be subject to such prohibitions and restrictions as may be prescribed by the rules.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016101_003" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Investment of funds</heading><leadIn>A registered society may invest or deposit its funds—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960264_005" name="a" temporalId="s33_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in a post office savings bank, or with any bank or person carrying on the business of banking approved for this purpose by the Registrar; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960264_013" name="b" temporalId="s33_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in any securities issued or guaranteed by the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region or of any other place approved by the Registrar; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960264_021" name="c" temporalId="s33_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>with any other registered society approved for this purpose by the Registrar; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960264_029" name="d" temporalId="s33_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in any other mode approved by the Registrar.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403016117_001" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Disposal of profits</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960280_019" name="1" temporalId="s34_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>At least one-fourth of the net profits of every registered society, as
                    ascertained by the audit prescribed by <ref>section 35</ref>, shall be carried
                    to a fund to be called the reserve fund, which shall be employed as prescribed
                    by the rules. After deduction of any tax which may have been charged on such
                    society in accordance with the provisions of the Inland Revenue Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap112">Cap. 112</ref>), the remainder of such profits and any
                    profits of past years available for distribution may be divided among the
                    members by way of dividend or bonus, or allocated to any funds constituted by
                    the society, to such extent or under such conditions as may be prescribed by the
                    rules or by-laws:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s34_1_proviso">Provided that in the case of a
                    society with unlimited liability, no distribution of profits shall be made
                    without the general or special order of the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of
                            2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960280_033" name="2" temporalId="s34_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any registered society, may, with the sanction of the Registrar, after
                one-fourth of the net profits in any year has been carried to a reserve fund,
                contribute an amount not exceeding ten per cent of the remaining net profits to any
                charitable purpose or to a common-good fund.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403016117_003" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            VI</num><heading>Audit, Inspection
            and
            Inquiry</heading><section id="ID_1438403016132_001" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Audit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960311_004" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar shall audit or cause to be audited by some person authorized by him by general or special order in writing the accounts of every registered society once at least in every year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960311_012" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The audit under subsection (1) shall include an examination of overdue debts, if any, and a valuation of the assets and liabilities of the registered society.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960327_005" name="3" temporalId="s35_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Registrar and every other person appointed to audit the accounts of a society shall have power when necessary—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960327_013" name="a" temporalId="s35_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to summon at the time of his audit any officer, agent, servant or member of the society who he has reason to believe can give material information in regard to any transactions of the society or the management of its affairs; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960327_021" name="b" temporalId="s35_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to require the production of any book or document relating to the affairs of, or any cash or securities belonging to, the society by the officer, agent, servant or member in possession of such book, document, cash or securities.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016148_002" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Power of Registrar to inspect society’s books, etc.</heading><content>The Registrar, or any person authorized by general or special order in writing by the Registrar, shall at all times have access to all the books, accounts, papers and securities of a registered society, and shall be entitled to inspect the cash in hand; and every officer of the society shall furnish such information in regard to the transactions and working of the society as the person making such inspection may require.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016164_002" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Inquiry and inspection</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960358_011" name="1" temporalId="s37_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar may of his own motion, and shall on the application of a majority of the committee, or of not less than one-third of the members of a registered society, hold an inquiry or direct some person authorized by him by order in writing in this behalf to hold an inquiry into the constitution, working, and financial condition of a registered society; and all officers and members of the society shall furnish such information in regard to the affairs of the society and produce the cash in hand and such books, accounts, papers and securities of the society as the Registrar or the person authorized by him may require.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960374_005" name="2" temporalId="s37_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Registrar shall, on the application of a creditor of the registered society, inspect or direct some person authorized by him in writing in this behalf to inspect the books of the society, if the applicant—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960374_013" name="a" temporalId="s37_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>proves that an ascertained sum of money is then due to him and that he has demanded payment thereof and has not received satisfaction within a reasonable time; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960389_006" name="b" temporalId="s37_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>deposits with the Registrar such sum as security for the costs of the proposed inspection as the Registrar may require.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960389_013" name="3" temporalId="s37_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Registrar shall communicate the results of any such inspection to the
                creditor and to the society into whose affairs inquiry has been made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960389_021" name="4" temporalId="s37_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where an inquiry is held under subsection (1) or an inspection is made under subsection (2), the Registrar may apportion the costs or such part of the costs, as he may think right, between the registered society, the members demanding an inquiry, the officers or former officers of the society, and the creditor, if any, on whose application the inquiry was made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960389_029" name="5" temporalId="s37_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any sum awarded by way of costs against any society or person under this section may be recovered, on application to a magistrate having jurisdiction in the place where the registered office of the society is situate or the person resides or carries on business for the time being, in like manner as a fine imposed by such court.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403016179_001" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part
            VII</num><heading>Dissolution</heading><section id="ID_1438403016179_003" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Dissolution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960436_011" name="1" temporalId="s38_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If the Registrar, after holding an inquiry or making an inspection under
                    <ref>section 37</ref> or on receipt of an application made by three-fourths of
                the members of a registered society, is of opinion that the society ought to be
                dissolved, he may make an order for the cancellation of the registration of the
                society.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960436_019" name="2" temporalId="s38_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any member of a registered society may, within two months from the date of an
                order under subsection (1), appeal from such order to the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of
                        2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960436_027" name="3" temporalId="s38_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where no appeal is presented within two months from the making of an order
                cancelling the registration of a society, the order shall take effect on the expiry
                of that period. Where an appeal is presented within two months, the order shall not
                take effect until it is confirmed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960452_005" name="4" temporalId="s38_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the Registrar makes an order for the cancellation of the registration of
                a society under subsection (1) he may make such further order as he may think fit
                for the custody of the books and documents and the protection of the assets of the
                society until the order cancelling registration takes effect.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960452_013" name="5" temporalId="s38_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>No registered society shall be wound up save by an order of the
                Registrar.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016210_001" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Cancellation of registration for lack of membership</heading><content>The Registrar may, by order in writing, cancel the registration of any registered society other than a society which includes among its members one or more registered societies, if at any time it is proved to his satisfaction that the number of the members has been reduced to less than ten. Every such order shall take effect from the date thereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016210_003" name="s40" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s40"><num value="40">40.</num><heading>Effect of cancellation of registration</heading><leadIn>Where the registration of a society is cancelled by an order under <ref>section 38</ref> or <ref>39</ref> the society shall cease to exist as a corporate body from the date on which the order takes effect, hereinafter referred to as the date of dissolution:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s40_proviso">Provided that any privileges conferred on the society by or under <ref>sections 14</ref>, <ref>15</ref>, <ref>16</ref> and <ref>17</ref> shall be deemed to be vested in any liquidator appointed for that society by the Registrar.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438403016226_001" name="s41" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s41"><num value="41">41.</num><heading>Liquidation after cancellation of registration of society</heading><content>Where the registration of a society is cancelled under <ref>section 38</ref> or <ref>39</ref> the Registrar may appoint one or more persons to be, subject to his direction and control, the liquidator or liquidators of the society.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016226_003" name="s42" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s42"><num value="42">42.</num><heading>Liquidator’s power</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960514_011" name="1" temporalId="s42_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A liquidator appointed under <ref>section 41</ref> shall, subject to the guidance and control of the Registrar and to any limitations imposed by the Registrar by order under <ref>section 43</ref>, have power to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960514_019" name="a" temporalId="s42_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>determine from time to time the contribution to be made by members and past members or by the estates of deceased members of the society to its assets;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960514_027" name="b" temporalId="s42_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>appoint a day by notice before which creditors whose claims are not already recorded in the books of the society shall state their claims for admission or to be excluded from any distribution made before they have proved them;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960514_035" name="c" temporalId="s42_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>decide any question of priority which arises between creditors;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_006" name="d" temporalId="s42_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>refer disputes to arbitration and institute and defend suits and other legal proceedings on behalf of the society by his name or office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_014" name="e" temporalId="s42_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>decide by what persons and in what proportions the costs of liquidation are to be borne;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_022" name="f" temporalId="s42_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>give such directions in regard to the collection and distribution of assets as may be necessary in the course of winding up the society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_030" name="g" temporalId="s42_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>compromise any claim by or against the society provided the sanction of the Registrar has first been obtained;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_038" name="h" temporalId="s42_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>call such general meetings of members as may be necessary for the proper conduct of the liquidation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_046" name="i" temporalId="s42_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>take possession of the books, documents and assets of the society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_054" name="j" temporalId="s42_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>sell the property of the society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_062" name="k" temporalId="s42_1_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content><leadIn>carry on the business of the society so far as may be necessary for winding it up beneficially:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s42_1_k_proviso">Provided that nothing herein contained shall entitle the liquidator of a credit society to issue any loan; and</proviso></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960530_076" name="l" temporalId="s42_1_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>arrange for the distribution of the assets of the society in a convenient manner when a scheme of distribution has been approved by the Registrar.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960530_083" name="2" temporalId="s42_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to such rules as may be made in this behalf, any liquidator appointed under this Ordinance shall in so far as such powers are necessary for carrying out the purposes of this section, have power to summon and enforce the attendance of parties and witnesses and to compel the production of documents by the same means and (so far as may be) in the manner as is provided in the case of a magistrate.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016242_002" name="s43" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s43"><num value="43">43.</num><heading>Power of Registrar to control liquidation</heading><leadIn>A liquidator shall exercise his powers subject to the control and revision of the Registrar, who may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_012" name="a" temporalId="s43_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>rescind or vary any order made by a liquidator and make whatever new order is required;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_020" name="b" temporalId="s43_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>remove a liquidator from office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_028" name="c" temporalId="s43_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>call for all books, documents and assets of the society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_036" name="d" temporalId="s43_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>by order in writing limit the powers of a liquidator under <ref>section 42</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_044" name="e" temporalId="s43_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>require accounts to be rendered to him by the liquidator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_052" name="f" temporalId="s43_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>procure the auditing of the liquidator’s accounts and authorize the distribution of the assets of the society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_060" name="g" temporalId="s43_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>make an order for the remuneration of the liquidator; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960576_068" name="h" temporalId="s43_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>refer any subject of dispute between a liquidator and any third party to arbitration if that party shall have consented in writing to be bound by the decision of the arbitrator.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403016257_002" name="s44" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s44"><num value="44">44.</num><heading>Enforcement of order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960608_004" name="1" temporalId="s44_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The decision of an arbitrator on any matter referred to him under <ref>section 43</ref> shall be binding upon the parties, and shall be enforceable in like manner as an order made by the Registrar under that section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960608_012" name="2" temporalId="s44_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An order made by a liquidator or by the Registrar under <ref>section 42</ref> or <ref>43</ref> shall be enforced by any civil court having jurisdiction over the place where the registered office of the society is situate in like manner as a decree of that court.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016273_001" name="s45" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s45"><num value="45">45.</num><heading>Limitation of the jurisdiction of the civil court</heading><content>Save in so far as is hereinbefore expressly provided, no civil court shall have any jurisdiction in respect of any matter concerned with the dissolution of a registered society under this Ordinance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403016273_003" name="s46" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s46"><num value="46">46.</num><heading>Closure of liquidation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960639_011" name="1" temporalId="s46_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In the liquidation of a society whose registration has been cancelled, the funds, including the reserve fund, shall be applied first to the costs of liquidation, then to the discharge of the liabilities of the society, then to the payment of the share capital and then, provided the by-laws of the society permit, to the payment of a dividend at a rate not exceeding ten per cent per annum for any period for which no disposal of profits was made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960654_005" name="2" temporalId="s46_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>When the liquidation of a society has been closed and any creditor of that society has not claimed or received what is due to him under the scheme of distribution, notice of the closing of the liquidation shall be published in the Gazette; and, all claims against the funds of the society liquidated shall be proscribed when two years have elapsed from the date of the publication of the Gazette notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960654_013" name="3" temporalId="s46_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any surplus remaining after the application of the funds to the purposes specified in subsection (1) and the payment of any claims for which an action is instituted under subsection (2) shall be available for use by the Registrar for any co-operative purpose at his discretion.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403016288_001" name="P8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part
            VIII</num><heading>Surcharge
            and
            Attachment</heading><section id="ID_1438403016288_003" name="s47" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s47"><num value="47">47.</num><heading>Power of Registrar to surcharge officers, etc., of a registered society</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960686_004" name="1" temporalId="s47_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where, in the course of the winding up of a registered society it appears that any person who has taken part in the organization or management of such society or any past or present officer of the society has misapplied or retained or become liable or accountable for any money or property of such society or has been guilty of misfeasance or breach of trust in relation to such society, the Registrar may, on the application of the liquidator or of any creditor or contributory, examine into the conduct of such person and make an order requiring him to repay or restore the money or property or any part thereof with interest at such rate as the Registrar thinks just or to contribute such sum to the assets of such society by way of compensation in regard to the misapplication, retainer, dishonesty or breach of trust as the Registrar thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960717_005" name="2" temporalId="s47_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section shall apply notwithstanding that the act is one for which the offender may be criminally responsible.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016304_001" name="s48" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s48"><num value="48">48.</num><heading>Appeal to Chief Executive</heading><text>Any person aggrieved by any order of the Registrar made under <ref>section 47</ref>
            may appeal to the Chief Executive within twenty-one days from the date of such order and
            the decision of the Chief Executive shall be final and conclusive.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403016304_003" name="P9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P9"><num value="9">Part
            IX</num><heading>Disputes</heading><section id="ID_1438403016320_002" name="s49" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s49"><num value="49">49.</num><heading>Settlement of disputes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960873_004" name="1" temporalId="s49_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If any dispute touching the business of a registered society arises—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960873_012" name="a" temporalId="s49_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>among members, past members and persons claiming through members, past members and deceased members; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960888_006" name="b" temporalId="s49_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>between a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>member, past member, or person claiming through a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>member, past member or deceased member, and the society, its committee, or any officer of the society; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960888_014" name="c" temporalId="s49_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>between the society or its committee and any officer of the society; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960888_022" name="d" temporalId="s49_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>between the society and any other registered
                    society,
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>such dispute shall be referred to the Registrar for decision. A claim by a registered society for any debt or demand due to it from a member, past member or the nominee, heir or legal representative of a deceased member, shall be deemed to be a dispute touching the business of the society within the meaning of this subsection.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960888_035" name="2" temporalId="s49_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Registrar may, on receipt of a reference under subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411960888_043" name="a" temporalId="s49_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>decide the dispute himself; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411960888_051" name="b" temporalId="s49_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>refer it for disposal to an arbitrator or arbitrators.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960888_058" name="3" temporalId="s49_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any party aggrieved by the award of the arbitrator or arbitrators may appeal therefrom to the Registrar within one month after the award is given by lodging notice in writing with the Registrar.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/21">21 of 1976 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960904_005" name="4" temporalId="s49_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A decision of the Registrar under subsection (2) or in appeal under subsection (3) shall be final and shall not be called in question in any civil court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411960904_013" name="5" temporalId="s49_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The award of the arbitrator or arbitrators under subsection (2) shall, if no appeal is preferred to the Registrar under subsection (3), or if any such appeal is abandoned or withdrawn, be final and shall not be called in question in any civil court and shall be enforced in the same manner as if the award had been a judgment of a civil court.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016320_004" name="s50" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s50"><num value="50">50.</num><heading>Case stated on question of law</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411960998_011" name="1" temporalId="s50_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Notwithstanding anything contained in <ref>section 49</ref>, the Registrar at
                any time when proceeding to a decision under this Ordinance, or the Chief Executive
                at any time when an appeal has been preferred to him against any decision of the
                Registrar under this Ordinance, may refer any question of law arising out of such
                decision for the ruling of the court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411961013_005" name="2" temporalId="s50_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Such judge or judges as the Chief Judge of the High Court may direct, may
                consider and determine any question of law so referred and the ruling given on such
                question shall be final and conclusive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/79">79 of 1995 s. 50</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403016335_002" name="P10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P10"><num value="10">Part
            X</num><heading>Rules</heading><section id="ID_1438403016351_001" name="s51" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s51"><num value="51">51.</num><heading>Rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411961076_011" name="1" temporalId="s51_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may make all such rules as may be necessary for
                the purpose of carrying out or giving effect to the principles and provisions of
                this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411961076_019" name="2" temporalId="s51_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In particular, and without prejudice to the generality of the power conferred by
                subsection (1), such rules may provide for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411961076_027" name="a" temporalId="s51_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>forms to be used and the conditions to be complied with in applying for the
                    registration of a society and the procedure in the matter of such
                    applications;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961076_035" name="b" temporalId="s51_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>conditions to be complied with by persons applying for admission or
                    admitted as members, election and admission of members from time to time, and
                    the payment to be made and interest to be acquired before exercising rights of
                    membership;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961091_006" name="c" temporalId="s51_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>subject to the provisions of <ref>section 27</ref>, the maximum number of
                    shares or portion of the capital of a registered society which may be held by a
                    member;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961091_014" name="d" temporalId="s51_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the extent to which a registered society may limit the number of its
                    members;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961091_022" name="e" temporalId="s51_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>withdrawal and expulsion of members and payments to be made to members who
                    withdraw or are expelled, and the liabilities of past members;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961091_030" name="f" temporalId="s51_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>general meetings of the members and for the procedure at such meetings and
                    the powers to be exercised by such meetings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961091_038" name="g" temporalId="s51_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>appointment, suspension and removal of the members of the committee and
                    other officers, and the procedure at meetings of the committee, and the powers
                    to be exercised and the duties to be performed by the committee and other
                    officers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961091_046" name="h" temporalId="s51_2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>matters in respect of which a society may or shall make by-laws and the
                    procedure to be followed in making, altering and rescinding by-laws, and the
                    conditions to be satisfied prior to such making, alteration or
                    rescission;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961107_006" name="i" temporalId="s51_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the manner in which funds may be raised by means of shares or debentures or
                    otherwise;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961107_014" name="j" temporalId="s51_2_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>conditions to be observed by a registered society applying for financial
                    assistance from government;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961107_022" name="k" temporalId="s51_2_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>the payments to be made, the conditions to be complied with and the forms
                    of the bonds, instruments or other documents to be executed by members applying
                    for loans or cash credits, the period for which loans may be made or credits
                    granted, and the maximum amount which may be lent and the maximum credit which
                    may be allowed to individual members with or without the consent of the
                    Registrar;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961122_006" name="1" temporalId="s51_2_1"><num value="1">(l)</num><content>the mode in which the value of a deceased member’s interest shall be
                    ascertained, and for the nomination of a person to whom such interest may be
                    paid or
                    transferred;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1540881144531_001" name="m" temporalId="s51_2_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>the mode in which the value of the interest of a member who has become of
                    unsound mind and incapable of managing himself or his affairs shall be
                    ascertained and the nomination of any person to whom such interest may be paid
                    or transferred;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961122_014" name="n" temporalId="s51_2_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content>formation and maintenance of reserve funds, and the objects to which such
                    funds may be applied, and investment of any funds under the control of any
                    registered society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961122_022" name="o" temporalId="s51_2_o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content>conditions under which profits may be distributed to the members of a
                    society with unlimited liability and the maximum rate of dividend which may be
                    paid by societies;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961138_006" name="p" temporalId="s51_2_p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content>accounts and books to be kept by a registered society, and for the
                    periodical publication of a balance sheet showing the assets and liabilities of
                    a registered society;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961138_014" name="q" temporalId="s51_2_q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content>audit of the accounts of registered societies and for the charges, if any,
                    to be made for such audit and the levy of contributions from all or any
                    registered societies to a fund to be used for the audit and supervision of
                    existing societies and co-operative propaganda and the administration of such a
                    fund;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961138_022" name="r" temporalId="s51_2_r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content>returns to be submitted by registered societies to the Registrar, and the
                    persons by whom and the form in which the same are to be made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961138_030" name="s" temporalId="s51_2_s"><num value="s">(s)</num><content>the persons by whom, and the form in which, copies of entries in books of
                    registered societies may be certified;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961138_038" name="t" temporalId="s51_2_t"><num value="t">(t)</num><content>formation and maintenance of a register of members, and, where the
                    liability of members is limited by shares, of a register of shares;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961138_046" name="u" temporalId="s51_2_u"><num value="u">(u)</num><content>inspection of documents and registers at the Registrar’s office and the
                    fees to be paid therefor and the issue of copies of such documents or
                    registers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961154_006" name="v" temporalId="s51_2_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the manner in which any question as to the breach of any by-law or contract
                    relating to the disposal of produce to or through a society may be determined,
                    and the manner in which the liquidated damages for any such breach may be
                    ascertained or assessed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961154_014" name="w" temporalId="s51_2_w"><num value="w">(w)</num><content>the mode of appointing an arbitrator or arbitrators and the procedure to be
                    followed in proceedings before the Registrar or such arbitrator or
                    arbitrators;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961154_022" name="x" temporalId="s51_2_x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content>the procedure to be followed by a liquidator appointed under <ref>section
                        41</ref> and the cases in which appeals shall lie from the orders of such
                    liquidator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961154_030" name="y" temporalId="s51_2_y"><num value="y">(y)</num><content>forms and fees and the procedure to be observed and all other matters
                    connected with or incidental to the presentation, hearing and disposal of
                    appeals under this Ordinance or the rules.</content></paragraph></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403016351_003" name="P11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="P11"><num value="11">Part
            XI</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403016366_002" name="s52" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s52"><num value="52">52.</num><heading>Recovery of sums due to Government</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411961216_004" name="1" temporalId="s52_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All sums due from a registered society or from an officer or member or past member of a registered society as such to the Government may be recovered in the manner provided for the recovery of debts due to the Government under the law for the time being in force.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411961216_012" name="2" temporalId="s52_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Sums due from a registered society to the Government and recoverable under subsection (1) may be recovered first, from the property of the society; secondly, in the case of a society of which the liability of members is limited, from members, subject to the limit of their liability; and thirdly, in the case of other societies, from the members.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403016366_004" name="s53" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s53"><num value="53">53.</num><heading>Special power of Chief Executive to exempt any society from requirements as to
            registration</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><text>Notwithstanding anything contained in this Ordinance the Chief Executive may by
            special order in each case and subject to such conditions as he may impose, exempt any
            society from any of the requirements of this Ordinance as to registration.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403016382_002" name="s54" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s54"><num value="54">54.</num><heading>Special power of Chief Executive to exempt societies from provisions of
            Ordinance</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><text>The Chief Executive may by general or special order exempt any registered society or
            class of societies from any of the provisions of this Ordinance, or may direct that such
            provisions shall apply to any society or class of societies with effect from such date
            or with such modifications as may be specified in the order.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403016398_001" name="s55" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s55"><num value="55">55.</num><heading>Power to remit registration fees</heading><text>The Chief Executive by notification in the Gazette may, in the case of any registered
            society or class of registered societies, remit any fee payable under the law of
            registration for the time being in force, and any such notification in respect of any
            registered society may provide for the revocation thereof in respect of such registered
            society.</text><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1981/31">31 of 1981 s. 65</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403016398_003" name="s56" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s56"><num value="56">56.</num><heading>Prohibition of the use of the word “co-operative”</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411961294_011" name="1" temporalId="s56_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>No person other than a registered society shall trade or carry on business
                    under any name or title of which the word “co-operative” or “合作社” is part
                    without the sanction of the Chief Executive:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s.
                            107</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/61">61 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s56_1_proviso">Provided that nothing in this
                    section shall apply to the use by any person or his successor in interest of any
                    name or title under which he traded or carried on business at the
                    commencement*
                    of this Ordinance.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411961310_004" name="2" temporalId="s56_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes the provisions of this section shall be guilty of an
                offence and shall be liable to a fine
                at
                level 1 and in the case of a continuing offence to a further fine
                of
                $20
                for each day during which the offence continues.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1638503701771_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 15 February
                1951.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403016413_002" name="s57" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s57"><num value="57">57.</num><heading>Certain legislation not to apply to registered societies</heading><content>The provisions of the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>)
            and the Companies (Winding Up and Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>), and of any law relating to trade unions, shall not
            apply to societies registered under this Ordinance.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                912 &amp;
                920</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403016429_001" name="s58" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s58"><num value="58">58.</num><heading>Penalty for non-compliance with Ordinance</heading><paragraph id="ID_1438411961341_004" name="a" temporalId="s58_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Any registered society or an officer or a member thereof, wilfully neglecting
                or refusing to do any act or to furnish any information required for the purposes of
                this Ordinance by the Registrar or other persons duly authorized by him in this
                behalf; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411961341_012" name="b" temporalId="s58_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any person wilfully or without any reasonable excuse disobeying any summons,
                requisition or lawful written order issued under the provisions of this Ordinance,
                or failing to furnish any information lawfully required from him by a person
                authorized to do so under the provisions of this Ordinance,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable to a fine
            at
            level
            1.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403016429_003" name="s59" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-07" status="operational" temporalId="s59"><num value="59">59.</num><heading>Punishment of fraud or misappropriation</heading><content>If any person obtains possession by false representation or imposition of any property of a
                                    society, or having it in his possession withholds or misapplies
                                    it, or wilfully applies any part thereof to purposes other than
                                    those expressed or directed in the by-laws of the society, and
                                    authorized by this Ordinance, he shall, on the complaint of the
                                    society, or of any member authorized by the society, or the
                                    committee thereof, or of the Registrar, be liable to a fine of
                                    two thousand dollars, and to be ordered to deliver up all such
                                    property or to repay all monies applied improperly, and, in
                                    default of such delivery or repayment, or of the payment of such
                                    fine to be imprisoned for twelve months.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1956/53">53 of 1956 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/21">21 of 1976 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1893 c. 39 s. 64 U.K.]</referenceNote></section></part></main></ordinance>