<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 89 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>89A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap89A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-03-21</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403568744_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2024-03-21">Pensions
            Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap89/s3">Cap. 89, section
            3</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[9 December 1949]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2024/er2">E.R. 2 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="add-toc">Regulations for
            Granting of Pensions, Gratuities and Other
            Allowances</crossHeading><part id="ID_1438403568744_005" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403568760_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the <shortTitle>Pensions
            Regulations</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403568760_004" name="s2" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403568776_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Officers
            other than Transferred
            Officers</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403568776_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application of Part II</heading><text>Save when the Chief Executive in any special case otherwise directs, this Part shall
            not apply in the case of any officer transferred to or from the service under the
            Government from or to other public service except for the purpose of determining whether
            such officer would have been eligible for pension or gratuity and the amount of pension
            or gratuity, for which the officer would have been eligible, if the service of the
            officer had been wholly under the Government.</text><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36
                of 1987 s. 49</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568791_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Pensions to whom and at what rates to be granted</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414073418_025" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of the Ordinance and of these regulations, every officer holding an established office under the Government, who has been in the service under the Government in a civil capacity for 10 years or more, shall be granted on retirement a pension at the annual rate of one six-hundredth of his pensionable emoluments for each complete month of his pensionable service under the Government, and any incomplete month of pensionable service shall be taken to be that fraction of a complete month whereof the denominator is 30 and the numerator the number of days of pensionable service in that incomplete month, irrespective of the actual number of days in that month.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s. 36</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414073449_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding the limit in the service specified in paragraph (1), a pension shall be granted in accordance with that paragraph to an officer who is retired under <ref>section 6(1)(i)</ref> or (j) irrespective of the length of his qualifying service.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568791_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Gratuities where length of service does not qualify for pension</heading><content>Every officer, otherwise qualified for a pension, who has not been in the service under the Government in a civil capacity for 10 years, shall be granted on retirement a gratuity not exceeding 7 times the annual amount of the pension which, if there had been no qualifying period, might have been granted to him under <ref>regulation 4</ref>.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568791_005" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Marriage gratuity when payable</heading><leadIn>Where a female officer who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414073512_019" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has been appointed to an established office before 17 November 1972;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073512_027" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has been in the public service under the Government for not less than 5
                years;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073512_035" name="c" temporalId="s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>has been confirmed in an established office; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073512_043" name="d" temporalId="s6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>is not eligible for the grant of a pension or otherwise eligible for a gratuity
                under this Part,</content></paragraph><continued>retires from the public service for the reason that she has married or is about
            to marry she may be granted, on production within 6 months after her retirement, or
            within such longer period as the Chief Executive may in any particular case allow, of
            satisfactory evidence of her marriage, a gratuity of an amount not
                    exceeding—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414073512_057" name="i" temporalId="s6_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the highest annual rate of pensionable emoluments with effect from 9 December
                1949; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of
                        1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073527_006" name="ii" temporalId="s6_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>four and one-sixth times the annual amount of the pension which might have been
                granted to her under <ref>regulation 4</ref> had there been no qualifying period and
                had <ref>regulation 4</ref> been applicable to her,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the less.</continued><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1972/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1972</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36
                of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403568807_002" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Transferred
            Officers</heading><section id="ID_1438403568807_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Application of Part III</heading><content>This Part shall apply only in the case of an officer transferred to or from the service under the Government from or to other public service.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568822_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414073590_018" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Part and Part IV—</leadIn><def name="ScheduledGovernment"><leadIn><term>Scheduled
                        Government</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK"><ref>附表</ref>政府</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414073605_012" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Government of any territory, or any authority, mentioned in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln373">L.N. 373 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073605_020" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Government of Ceylon, in respect of any officer appointed to service under that Government before 4 February 1948;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073605_028" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Government of Palestine, in respect of any officer appointed to service under that Government before 15 May 1948;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073605_036" name="d" temporalId="s8_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the Government of the Somali Republic, in respect of any officer appointed to service under the former Government of the Somaliland Protectorate before 26 June 1960;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073605_044" name="e" temporalId="s8_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the Government of Cyprus, in respect of any officer appointed to service under that Government before 16 August 1960; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073605_052" name="f" temporalId="s8_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the East African Common Services Organization or, with effect from 1 December 1967, the East African Community, in respect of any person deemed to have been appointed or appointed to service as President, Vice-President, Justice of Appeal, Registrar, officer or servant of the Court of Appeal for Eastern Africa or, with effect from 1 December 1967, of the Court of Appeal for East Africa;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1962/gna34">G.N.A. 34 of 1962</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1970/ln44">L.N. 44 of 1970</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def><def name="ServiceInTheGroup"><term>service
                    in the
                Group</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">任職於組內的政府</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">任職於組內政府的服務</term>)
                means service under the Government and under a
                Scheduled
                Government or <ref>Schedule</ref>d Governments.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
                    49</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414073621_011" name="1A" temporalId="s8_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><leadIn>For the purpose of this Part and Part IV—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414073621_019" name="a" temporalId="s8_1A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any officer in public service under the Government of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland immediately before 1 January 1964 who was, immediately before that date, employed on secondment to service under the Government of Southern Rhodesia, the Government of Northern Rhodesia or the Government of Nyasaland, or was as from that date so employed, shall be deemed to continue in public service under the Government of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland until his employment on secondment is terminated;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073637_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_1A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any pension awarded on or after 1 January 1964 in respect of service under the Government of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland shall be deemed to have been granted by that Government notwithstanding the provisions of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland (Dissolution) Order in Council 1963.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln15">L.N. 15 of 1967</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414073652_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an officer, to whom this Part applies, is, on his retirement from the public service, not granted a pension or gratuity in respect of his employment in the service in which he is last employed, solely by reason of the fact that he has not held office therein for a specified period he shall nevertheless be deemed for the purpose of this Part to have retired in circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in which he is last employed to retire on pension or gratuity.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568822_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Pension for service wholly within the Group</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414073715_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the other public service of an officer to whom this Part applies has been wholly under one or more <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government, and his aggregate service would have qualified him had it been wholly under the Government for a pension under the Ordinance, he may, on his retirement from the public service in circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in which he is last employed to retire on pension or gratuity be granted in respect of his service under the Government a pension of such an amount as shall bear the same proportion to the amount of pension for which he would have been eligible had his service been wholly under the Government, as the aggregate amounts of his pensionable emoluments during his service under the Government shall bear to the aggregate amounts of his pensionable emoluments throughout his service in the Group.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414073761_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In determining for the purposes of this regulation the pension for which an officer would have been eligible if his service had been wholly under the Government—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414073761_013" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the application of <ref>regulation 18</ref>—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414073761_021" name="i" temporalId="s9_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>where the officer is not serving under a <ref>Schedule</ref>d
                        Government at the date of his retirement from the public service, subject to
                        sub-subparagraph
                        (ii) the highest pensionable emoluments enjoyed by him in the service of a
                            <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government shall be taken;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414073761_029" name="ii" temporalId="s9_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if, by reason of any order made in any disciplinary proceedings against
                        the officer, the amount to be taken in accordance with the provisions of
                        sub-subparagraph
                        (i) exceeds the pensionable emoluments enjoyed by him at the date of his
                        retirement or transfer, as the case may be, there shall be taken such
                        pensionable emoluments;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
                            6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073777_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>no regard shall be had to an additional pension under <ref>regulation 22</ref> or <ref>31</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073777_014" name="c" temporalId="s9_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>regard shall be had to the condition that pension may not exceed two-thirds of his highest pensionable emoluments;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073777_022" name="d" temporalId="s9_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>no period of other public service under a<inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref>Schedule</ref>d Government in respect of which no pension or gratuity is grantable to him shall be taken into account.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414073777_029" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><leadIn>For the purposes of this regulation, the aggregate amount of an officer’s pensionable emoluments shall be taken as the total amount of pensionable emoluments which he would have received or enjoyed had he been on duty on full pay in his substantive office or offices throughout his period of service in the Group:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s. 37</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_3_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414073793_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in calculating the aggregate amount of his pensionable emoluments, no account shall be taken of any service under the Government or under a<inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref>Schedule</ref>d Government in respect of which no pension or gratuity is granted to him by the Government or such <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government, as the case may be;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln15">L.N. 15 of 1967</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073793_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where any service in a civil capacity otherwise than in a pensionable or established office is taken into account as pensionable service, the officer’s aggregate pensionable emoluments during that service shall be taken into account to the same extent as that service is taken into account as pensionable service;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln15">L.N. 15 of 1967</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414073808_006" name="c" temporalId="s9_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where an officer entered the public service prior to 1 January 1930, his pension in respect of his service under the Government may be calculated as though any <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government under which he has served had not been included in these regulations should this be to his advantage.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568838_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Pension where other service not within the Group</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414073871_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the other public service of an officer to whom this Part applies has not included service under any of the <ref>Schedule</ref>d Governments, and his aggregate service would have qualified him, had it been wholly under the Government, for a pension under these regulations he may, on his retirement from the public service in circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in which he is last employed to retire on a pension or gratuity, be granted in respect of his service under the Government a pension at the annual rate of one six-hundredth of his pensionable emoluments for each complete month of his pensionable service under the Government, and any incomplete month of pensionable service shall be taken to be that fraction of a complete month whereof the denominator is 30 and the numerator the number of days of pensionable service in that incomplete month, irrespective of the actual number of days in that month.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414073917_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the officer is not in the service under the Government at the time of such retirement, his pensionable emoluments for the purposes of paragraph (1) shall be those which would have been taken for the purpose of computing his pension if he had retired from the public service and been granted a pension at the date of his last transfer from the service under the Government.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568838_004" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Pension when other service both within and not within the Group</heading><content>Where a part only of the other public service of an officer to whom this Part applies has been under one or more of the <ref>Schedule</ref>d Governments, the provisions of <ref>regulation 9</ref> shall apply; but in calculating the amount of pension regard shall be had only to service in the Group.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403568854_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Gratuities where length of service does not qualify for pension</heading><content>Where an officer to whom this Part applies retires from the public service in circumstances in which he is permitted by the law or regulations of the service in which he is last employed to retire on pension or gratuity, but has not been in the public service in a civil capacity for 10 years, he may be granted in respect of his service under the Government a gratuity not exceeding 7 times the annual amount of the pension which, if there had been no qualifying period, might have been granted to him under <ref>regulation 9</ref>, <ref>10</ref> or <ref>11</ref>, as the case may be.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568854_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Marriage gratuities</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414073995_018" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to paragraph (2), where a female officer to whom this Part applies retires or is required to retire from the public service for the reason that she is about to marry or has married, and—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074011_005" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>would have been eligible for a gratuity under <ref>regulation 6</ref>
                    disregarding
                    subparagraph
                    (a) thereof if her public service had been wholly under the Government;
                        and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1983/ln388">L.N. 388 of 1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074011_013" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is not eligible for the grant of any pension or otherwise eligible for a gratuity under this Part,</content></paragraph><continued>she may be granted in respect of her public service under the Government a gratuity of an amount not exceeding four and one-sixth times the annual amount of the pension for which she would have been eligible under <ref>regulation 9</ref>, <ref>10</ref> or <ref>11</ref> had there been no qualifying period and had <ref>regulation 9</ref>, <ref>10</ref> or <ref>11</ref>, as the case may be, been applicable to her:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s13_1_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that, for the purpose of computing the amount of such a gratuity—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074011_034" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_b_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to a pension under <ref>regulation 9</ref> or <ref>11</ref>, <ref>regulation 9(2)(c)</ref> shall have effect as if the reference therein to two-thirds of her highest pensionable emoluments were a reference to six twenty-fifths of her annual pensionable emoluments; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074027_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to a pension under <ref>regulation 9</ref>, <ref>10</ref> or <ref>11</ref>, the annual amount of that pension shall not exceed six twenty-fifths of her annual pensionable emoluments.</content></paragraph></proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074027_013" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In the case of a female officer transferring to the service under the Government from other public service and retiring whilst in the service under the Government, paragraph (1) only applies if the last such transfer preceding the retirement occurred before 17 November 1972.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1972/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1972</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln15">L.N. 15 of 1967</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1972/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1972</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403568869_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>General</heading><section id="ID_1438403568869_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>General rules as to qualifying service and pensionable service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414074089_011" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of these regulations, qualifying service shall be the
                inclusive period between the date on which an officer begins to draw salary in
                respect of public service and the date of his leaving the public service, without
                deduction of any period during which he has been absent on leave.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074089_019" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No period which is not qualifying service by virtue of paragraph (1) shall be
                taken into account as pensionable service or as service for the purpose of
                calculating an allowance under Part V.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074105_005" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                <leadIn>No period during which the officer was not in public service shall be taken
                    into account as qualifying service or as pensionable service or service for the
                    purpose of calculating an allowance under Part V:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s14_3_proviso">Provided that any period during
                    which an officer shall have been seconded for non-public service with the
                    approval of the Chief Executive may be taken into account as qualifying service
                    and as pensionable service or service for the purpose of calculating an
                    allowance under Part V.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568885_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Continuity of service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414074136_011" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                                                  <leadIn>Except as otherwise provided in these
                                                  regulations, only continuous service shall be
                                                  taken into account as qualifying service or as
                                                  pensionable service:</leadIn>
                                                  <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s15_1_proviso">Provided that any break in service caused by
                                                  temporary suspension of employment not arising
                                                  from misconduct or voluntary resignation shall be
                                                  disregarded for the purposes of this
                                                  paragraph.</proviso>
                                                </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074136_025" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074136_033" name="a" temporalId="s15_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>whose pension has been suspended under
                                                  <ref>section 11</ref> of the Ordinance or under a
                                                  corresponding provision in any law or regulation
                                                  relating to the grant of pensions in respect of
                                                  public service; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074151_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>who has retired from the public service
                                                  without pension on account of ill-health,
                                                  abolition of office, or re-organization designed
                                                  to effect greater efficiency or economy, and has
                                                  subsequently been re-employed in the public
                                                  service; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074151_014" name="c" temporalId="s15_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>who has left pensionable service under
                                                  the Teachers (Superannuation) Act 1925 (1925 c. 59
                                                  U.K.), with a view to entering public service not
                                                  being service pensionable under the said Act and
                                                  has, not later than 3 months after leaving such
                                                  first mentioned service, received any salary in
                                                  respect of employment in public service not so
                                                  pensionable; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074151_022" name="d" temporalId="s15_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>who, between 27 May 1966 and 17 November
                                                  1972, has retired from the public service by
                                                  reason of her marriage and who, not later than 3
                                                  months after leaving such service, resumes
                                                  employment in the public service,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1972/ln238">L.N. 238 of
                                                  1972</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>may, if the Chief Executive thinks fit,
                                                  be granted the pension or gratuity for which he
                                                  would have been eligible if any break in his
                                                  public service immediately prior to such
                                                  suspension, re-employment or employment had not
                                                  occurred, such pension to be in lieu
                                                  of—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414074167_012" name="i" temporalId="s15_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any pension previously granted to him
                                                  from the general revenue; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
                                                  49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074167_020" name="ii" temporalId="s15_2_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any gratuity so granted which is required
                                                  to be refunded as a condition of the application
                                                  to the officer of this regulation,</content></paragraph><continued>but additional to any gratuity so granted
                                                  which is not required to be refunded as
                                                  aforesaid.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074167_033" name="2A" temporalId="s15_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><leadIn>Where an officer has more than one
                                                  qualifying service or pensionable
                                                  service—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074167_041" name="a" temporalId="s15_2A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all such service may be aggregated in
                                                  accordance with paragraph (2); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074183_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_2A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>each such service may be treated
                                                  separately,</content></paragraph><continued>for the purposes of the grant of pension
                                                  or gratuity in respect of such service, whichever
                                                  is to his advantage in the circumstances.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
                                                  49</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074183_019" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438414074183_023" name="a" temporalId="s15_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>
                                                  <leadIn>A break in the service of an officer
                                                  occurring wholly between 12 July 1946 and 23 July
                                                  1946, or between 16 August 1947 and 23 September
                                                  1947, as a result of the voluntary absence from
                                                  the place of employment of such officer shall be
                                                  disregarded for the purpose of computing the
                                                  length of service qualifying for pension, annual
                                                  allowance or gratuity:</leadIn>
                                                  <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s15_3_a_proviso">Provided that any
                                                  such break in service shall not be disregarded in
                                                  computing the length of service for the purpose of
                                                  determining the amount of such pension, annual
                                                  allowance or gratuity.</proviso>
                                                  </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074183_035" name="b" temporalId="s15_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>This paragraph shall be deemed to have
                                                  had effect from 1 January 1947, in relation to
                                                  officers to whom Part V does not apply and from 9
                                                  December 1949, in relation to officers to whom
                                                  Part V applies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1950/gna229">G.N.A. 229 of
                                                  1950</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568900_002" name="s16" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="2012-02-17" status="repealed" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568900_004" name="s17" reason="repealed" role="regulation" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568916_001" name="s17A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s17A"><num value="17A">17A.</num><heading>Additional pension in respect of war service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414074292_004" name="1" temporalId="s17A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>This regulation applies to any officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074292_012" name="a" temporalId="s17A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>who has at any time (whether before or after the
                        commencement<sup>#</sup>
                    of the Pensions (Amendment) <ref>Regulation 1992</ref>
                    (<ref href="/hk/1992/ln373">L.N. 373 of
                    1992</ref>))
                    been granted, or who is eligible for, a pension under the Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074292_020" name="b" temporalId="s17A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>who performed war service or compulsory national service; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074292_028" name="c" temporalId="s17A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>who is not entitled to an additional pension under the Colonial Service
                    Officers Pensions Addition for War Service (United Kingdom) Scheme
                    1989.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074292_035" name="2" temporalId="s17A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An officer to whom this regulation applies shall be granted an additional
                pension in respect of his war service if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074292_043" name="a" temporalId="s17A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>his war service was not preceded by a period of pensionable service, and his
                    relevant Government service—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414074292_051" name="i" temporalId="s17A_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>began before 1 July 1950; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414074292_059" name="ii" temporalId="s17A_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>began on or after 1 July 1950 on the completion of a course of
                        training, or probationership which was regarded as training, after his
                        provisional selection to service under the Government or under the
                        Government of the United Kingdom, provided that such training or
                        probationership began before 1 July 1950 and was, in the opinion of the
                        Secretary, necessary before he could be appointed to that service; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/10">10 of
                                2005 s. 195</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414074307_007" name="iii" temporalId="s17A_2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>began on or after 1 July 1950 following his selection before 1 July
                        1950, provided that he was available to take up the appointment before 1
                        July 1950 and took the first opportunity to travel to take up the
                        appointment after selection; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074307_014" name="b" temporalId="s17A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>his relevant Government service was interrupted by his war service because
                    he was required to perform compulsory national service on or after 1 July
                    1947.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074323_005" name="3" temporalId="s17A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Subject to paragraphs (4), (5) and (6), the additional pension payable under
                this regulation shall be calculated as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074323_013" name="a" temporalId="s17A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of an officer to whom paragraph <ref>(2)(a)</ref> applies, an
                    annual amount equal to one six-hundredth of his pensionable emoluments for each
                    complete period of 2 months of war service;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074323_021" name="b" temporalId="s17A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of an officer to whom paragraph <ref>(2)(b)</ref> applies, an
                    annual amount equal to one six-hundredth of his pensionable emoluments for each
                    complete month of war service,</content></paragraph><continued>and in calculating any period of war service, service before the officer
                attained the age of 18 years shall be disregarded.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074323_034" name="4" temporalId="s17A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If there was a break other than a break caused by war service in an officer’s
                relevant Government service that has not been condoned by the Government concerned,
                the reference in paragraph (3) to pensionable emoluments shall be treated as a
                reference to the officer’s pensionable emoluments during the period of service
                before that break.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074339_005" name="5" temporalId="s17A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Any amount of pension in respect of war service payable to an officer at the
                date of his retirement—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074339_013" name="a" temporalId="s17A_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by the Government, otherwise than under this regulation; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074339_021" name="b" temporalId="s17A_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by a <ref>Schedule</ref>d Government,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be deducted from the additional pension payable under this
                regulation.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074339_034" name="6" temporalId="s17A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Any period of war service in respect of which an officer received non-effective
                pay or excess remuneration shall not count as war service for the purposes of
                paragraph (3).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074354_005" name="7" temporalId="s17A_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>An additional pension granted under this regulation shall be granted as
                from—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074354_013" name="a" temporalId="s17A_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the commencement of the Pensions (Amendment) <ref>Regulation 1992</ref>
                    (<ref href="/hk/1992/ln373">L.N. 373 of
                    1992</ref>);
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074354_021" name="b" temporalId="s17A_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the retirement of the officer,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the later, and shall be calculated and granted in Hong Kong
                dollars.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074354_034" name="8" temporalId="s17A_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>An officer to whom an additional pension is granted under this regulation shall
                not have an option under <ref>regulation 23</ref> to be paid, in lieu of that
                additional pension, a gratuity and a reduced pension.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074354_042" name="9" temporalId="s17A_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>In this regulation—</leadIn><def name="ExcessRemuneration"><term>excess
                    remuneration</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附加報酬</term>) means, in relation to a retired
                officer of the Armed Forces of the United Kingdom who is re-employed in those
                forces, any service pension drawn in respect of such period of re-employment or any
                addition to the normal pay attaching to the post in which the officer was
                re-employed which is granted by reason of the officer’s former employment in those
                    forces;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/2">2
                        of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="NoneffectivePay"><term>non-effective
                    pay</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">不再服務薪津</term>) includes naval, military or air
                force pensions, retired pay or gratuities (other than war gratuities to which
                    <ref>section 23</ref> of the Finance (No. 2) Act 1945 (1945 c. 13 U.K.)
                applied);</def><def name="RelevantGovernmentService"><term>relevant
                    Government
                service</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關的政府服務期</term>) means service under the Government
                or under the Government of the United Kingdom that may be taken into account in
                determining whether an officer is eligible by length of service for a pension;</def><def name="WarService">
                <leadIn><term>war
                        service</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">戰時服務</term>) means service at any time between
                    3 September 1939 and 30 June 1950 in—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438414074370_026" name="a" temporalId="s17A_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Armed Forces of the United Kingdom;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438414074370_034" name="b" temporalId="s17A_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the merchant navy or mercantile marine;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438414074370_042" name="c" temporalId="s17A_9_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any of the women’s services listed in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>.</content></paragraph>
            </def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln373">L.N. 373 of 1992</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" orientation="portrait" id="ID_1683186717461_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><sup>#</sup> Commencement date: 20 November 1992.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568947_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Emoluments to be taken for computing pension or gratuity</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414074463_011" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Subject to this regulation, for the purpose of computing the amount of the
                    pension or gratuity of an officer, the highest pensionable emoluments enjoyed or
                    drawn by him during his service in an established office shall be taken:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
                            6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
                    49</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s18_1_proviso">Provided that if, by reason of
                    any order made in any disciplinary proceedings against any officer, the amount
                    to be taken in accordance with the provisions of this regulation exceeds the
                    pensionable emoluments enjoyed by him at the date of his retirement, there shall
                    be taken such pensionable emoluments.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of
                            1980</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074479_004" name="1A" temporalId="s18_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>Where an officer has more than one period of continuous service the highest
                pensionable emoluments enjoyed or drawn by him in the course of any particular
                period of continuous service only shall be taken in to account for computing the
                amount of the pension or gratuity for that period.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
                    49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074479_012" name="1B" temporalId="s18_1B"><num value="1B">(1B)</num><content>Where an officer is serving on trial or probation in an office immediately
                following service other than on trial or probation, the highest pensionable
                emoluments which the officer would have enjoyed or drawn in his substantive rank at
                the date of his retirement or death shall be taken for the purpose of computing the
                amount of the pension or gratuity of the officer.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
                    49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074495_005" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) any increase in the pensionable emoluments of any
                office held by an officer due to a revision of salaries with effect from a date
                subsequent to the commencement of a period of his absence from duty on leave without
                salary shall be disregarded for the purposes of paragraph (1), unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074495_013" name="i" temporalId="s18_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the officer has since the expiration of that period of absence and in
                    respect of that period of absence, (taking the earliest period first if there is
                    more than one) completed an equal period of service on duty or leave with salary
                    (other than leave immediately preceding retirement); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074510_006" name="ii" temporalId="s18_2_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the officer retires in one of the cases referred to in <ref>section
                        6(1)(c)</ref>, (d) or (e) of the Ordinance; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s.
                        102</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074510_014" name="iii" temporalId="s18_2_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the Chief Executive in any case otherwise directs.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403568947_003" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Pensionable service, what is to be taken into account</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414074541_012" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraphs (2) to (9) hereof, only service in an established office shall be taken into account as pensionable service.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074557_005" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where a period of service in a civil capacity otherwise than in an established office is immediately followed by service in an established office and the officer is confirmed therein—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074557_013" name="a" temporalId="s19_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>three-quarters of such period may be so taken into account; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln551">L.N. 551 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074557_021" name="b" temporalId="s19_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if prior to 31 May 1937, the officer was in the service under the Government and such period of service might have been taken into account as pensionable service either as a whole or less a third for any part of such period paid for out of an open vote, such period may as a whole or less such third, continue to be so taken into account, if this shall be to such officer’s advantage.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074573_003" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any break in service which may be disregarded under the provisions of
                    <ref>regulation 15</ref> may likewise be disregarded in determining for the
                purposes of paragraph (2), <ref>(8)(d)</ref> or (9) whether one period of service
                immediately follows another period of
                service.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074573_011" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where an officer has been transferred from an established office in which he has been confirmed to a non-established office and subsequently retires either from an established office or a non-established office, his service in the non-established office may be taken into account as though it were service in the established office which he held immediately prior to such transfer and at the pensionable emoluments which were payable to him at the date of transfer; except—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln551">L.N. 551 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074573_019" name="a" temporalId="s19_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the officer so elects, his total service including service in the established office, may be reckoned as though it were service in a non-established office; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074588_006" name="b" temporalId="s19_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where a transfer from an established to a non-established office is made to provide continued employment for an officer who, on the ground of physical infirmity, has become incapable of retaining his established office, then the whole of his service shall be deemed to be service in a non-established office unless, by his subsequent retransfer to an established office, his case is brought within the provisions of paragraph (2).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074588_013" name="5" temporalId="s19_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a period of service in a non-established office is so taken into account under this regulation, the officer shall, during that period, be deemed for the purposes of <ref>regulations 6</ref>, <ref>22</ref> and <ref>31</ref> to be holding an established office, and where that period is taken into account under paragraph (4), to have been confirmed therein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074604_005" name="6" temporalId="s19_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Where a female officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074604_013" name="a" temporalId="s19_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has, prior to 27 May 1966, retired from the service by reason of her marriage; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074604_021" name="b" temporalId="s19_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has, upon retirement, received a marriage gratuity under these regulations,</content></paragraph><continued>the period of service prior to such retirement shall not be taken into account as pensionable service.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1972/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1972</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074604_034" name="7" temporalId="s19_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where a female officer, other than a divorced or widowed female officer
                confirmed in an established office prior to 17 November 1972, has, after marriage,
                served in an established office prior to 27 May 1966, her service as a married
                officer for the period up to that date shall be deemed to be service in an
                established office and such period may be taken into account as pensionable
                    service.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
                    6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln551">L.N. 551 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074619_005" name="8" temporalId="s19_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>Where a female officer who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074619_013" name="a" temporalId="s19_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has retired by reason of her marriage between 27 May 1966 and 17 November 1972; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074619_021" name="b" temporalId="s19_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has received a gratuity under <ref>regulation 6</ref> or <ref>13</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>is subsequently re-employed in the service under the Government, the period of service under the Government in respect of which the gratuity was granted shall not be taken into account as pensionable service unless—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414074635_005" name="c" temporalId="s19_8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an application to the contrary is made within 6 months of 17 November 1972;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074635_013" name="d" temporalId="s19_8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>there has been no break of service; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074635_021" name="e" temporalId="s19_8_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the gratuity received is refunded together with interest at a rate to be determined by the Financial Secretary.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074635_028" name="9" temporalId="s19_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>Where a female officer who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074635_036" name="a" temporalId="s19_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has, prior to 17 November 1972, retired from the service by reason of her marriage; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074635_044" name="b" temporalId="s19_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has not, upon retirement, received a marriage gratuity under these regulations,</content></paragraph><continued>is without break in service subsequently re-employed in the service under the Government,
                the period of service prior to such retirement shall be taken into account as
                pensionable service.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/30">30 of 1980 s.
                    5</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1972/ln238">L.N. 238 of 1972</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1980/30">30 of 1980 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568963_002" name="s19A" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s19A"><num value="19A">19A.</num><heading>Deemed increase in service</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414074729_004" name="1" temporalId="s19A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In the case of an officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074729_012" name="a" temporalId="s19A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>who retires from the public service under <ref>section 6(1)(e)</ref> of the
                    Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074729_020" name="b" temporalId="s19A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>whose retirement is necessitated or materially accelerated by permanent
                    injury sustained in the circumstances described in <ref>regulation
                        31(1)(a)</ref>, (b) and (c),</content></paragraph><continued>his pensionable service shall be deemed to be twice the actual period of his
                pensionable service, subject to—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414074729_034" name="i" temporalId="s19A_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a minimum of 2 years; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074729_042" name="ii" temporalId="s19A_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><leadIn>a maximum of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414074729_050" name="A" temporalId="s19A_1_ii_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>20 years; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414074729_058" name="B" temporalId="s19A_1_ii_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>the period of pensionable service that he would have completed if he
                        had served until attaining the age of 55 years,</content></subparagraph></paragraph><continued>whichever is the lesser.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
                31</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074744_003" name="2" temporalId="s19A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In the case of an officer who retires from the public service under <ref>section
                    6(1)(e)</ref> of the Ordinance otherwise than under the circumstances described
                in paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref> and whose period of qualifying service under the
                Government is—
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
                31</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074744_011" name="a" temporalId="s19A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>not less than 5 nor more than 20 years; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074744_019" name="b" temporalId="s19A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>more than 20 years but whose period of pensionable service is less than 20
                    years,</content></paragraph><continued>his pensionable service shall be deemed to be—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414074744_033" name="i" temporalId="s19A_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>twice the actual period of his pensionable service, subject to a maximum of
                    20 years; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074744_041" name="ii" temporalId="s19A_2_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the period of pensionable service that he would have completed if he had
                    served until attaining the age of 55 years,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the lesser.</continued></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
            6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568978_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Acting service</heading><leadIn>Where an officer has performed acting service in an office under the Government the period of such service may be taken into account as pensionable service (subject if the office is a non-established office to the provisions of <ref>regulation 19</ref>) if the period of such acting service—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074822_012" name="a" temporalId="s20_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is not taken into account as part of the officer’s own pensionable service in other public service;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074822_020" name="b" temporalId="s20_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is immediately preceded or followed by service as the substantive holder of an established office under the Government.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568978_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Service not counting for pension</heading><leadIn>Save as otherwise provided in these regulations, there shall not be taken into
            account as pensionable service—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074853_019" name="a" temporalId="s21_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s. 38</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074853_027" name="b" temporalId="s21_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any period of service while he was on agreement expressly providing for the
                payment of a gratuity dependent upon the length of his service or on agreement on
                monthly terms not providing for payment of a gratuity or while he was on probation,
                unless without break of service he is confirmed in an established office in the
                public service and, if on agreement providing for the payment of such a gratuity,
                has repaid the gratuity (if any) received in respect of that period together with
                interest at a rate to be determined by the Financial Secretary; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
                        6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1988/ln352">L.N. 352 of 1988</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074869_006" name="c" temporalId="s21_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any period during which an officer shall have been absent from duty without
                salary, unless such absence shall have been approved on grounds of public policy by
                the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln352">L.N. 352 of 1988</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of
                        1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074885_006" name="d" temporalId="s21_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s21_d_proviso">Provided that any break of service which
            may be disregarded under the provisions of <ref>regulation 15</ref> may likewise be
            disregarded in determining whether the officer is confirmed in an established office
            without break of service.</proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568994_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Abolition of office and reorganization</heading><leadIn>If an officer holding an established office and who has been confirmed therein retires from the public service in consequence of the abolition of his office or for the purpose of facilitating improvements in the organization of the department to which he belongs, by which greater efficiency or economy may be effected—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414074931_005" name="a" temporalId="s22_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he may, if he has been in the public service for less than 10 years, be granted in lieu of any gratuity under <ref>regulation 5</ref> or <ref>12</ref>, a pension under <ref>regulation 4</ref>, <ref>9</ref>, <ref>10</ref> or <ref>11</ref>, as the case may be, as if the words “for 10 years or more” were omitted from <ref>regulation 4</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414074931_013" name="b" temporalId="s22_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><leadIn>he may, if he retires from the service under the Government, be granted an additional pension at the annual rate of one-sixtieth of his pensionable emoluments for each complete period of 3 years’ pensionable service:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s22_b_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414074931_028" name="i" temporalId="s22_b_proviso_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the addition shall not exceed ten-sixtieths; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414074947_007" name="ii" temporalId="s22_b_proviso_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the addition together with the remainder of the officer’s pension shall not exceed the pension for which he would have been eligible if he had continued to hold the office held by him at the date of his retirement and retired on reaching the age at which he is normally required to retire under the provisions of <ref>section 8</ref> of the Ordinance, having received all increments for which he would have been eligible by that date.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1952/gna165">G.N.A. 165 of 1952</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></proviso></content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403568994_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Gratuity and reduced pension</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414074994_011" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (7), an officer to whom a pension is granted under the
                Ordinance shall, if he has exercised his option as hereinafter provided, but not
                otherwise, be paid in lieu of such pension a pension at the rate of 75, 80, 85, 90
                or 95 per cent of such pension, respectively, as he shall have exercised his option,
                together with a gratuity equal to 14 times the amount of the annual reduction so
                made in the pension.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1954/gna44">G.N.A. 44 of 1954</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1962/gna34">G.N.A. 34 of 1962</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1983/ln249">L.N. 249 of
                    1983</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414074994_019" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>The option referred to in paragraph (1) shall be exercisable, and if it has
                    been exercised may be revoked, not later than the day immediately preceding the
                    date of such officer’s retirement:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s23_2_proviso">Provided that the Chief Executive
                    may, if it appears to him equitable in all the circumstances so to do, allow him
                    to exercise the option or revoke an option previously exercised at any time
                    between that date and the actual date of award of pension under the
                        Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075009_011" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), if an officer has exercised the
                option his decision shall be irrevocable so far as concerns any pension to be
                granted to him under the Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1976/ln17">L.N. 17 of
                    1976</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075009_019" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If an officer who has not exercised the option dies after he has finally
                retired but before a pension has been awarded under the Ordinance, it shall be
                lawful for the Chief Executive to grant a gratuity and a reduced pension as provided
                in paragraph (1), as if the officer before his death had exercised his option to
                receive a gratuity and 75 per cent of the pension granted to him.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of
                        1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1962/gna34">G.N.A. 34 of 1962</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075025_005" name="5" temporalId="s23_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The date of the exercise of the option by an officer shall be deemed to be the
                date of the receipt of his written notification addressed to the Director of
                Accounting Services.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1976/ln226">L.N. 226 of 1976</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075025_013" name="6" temporalId="s23_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A re-employed officer or pensioner shall be deemed to have exercised, or not to
                have exercised, in respect of his service subsequent to re-employment, the said
                option, according as he exercised, or did not exercise, such option in respect of
                his previous service even if, in respect of such previous service, the option was
                not available to him.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1976/ln17">L.N. 17 of 1976</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075041_005" name="7" temporalId="s23_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where an officer retires or leaves the service in accordance with any
                compensation scheme, the reduced pension and the gratuity in lieu of the reduction
                in the pension shall be in accordance with the compensation scheme applicable to the
                officer.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403569010_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Non-pensionable
            Officers</heading><section id="ID_1438403569010_004" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Application of Part V</heading><content>This Part shall apply only to non-pensionable officers and shall have effect from the date of enactment hereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403569041_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Part—</leadIn><def name="NonpensionableOfficer">
            <leadIn><term>non-pensionable officer</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">非可享退休金人員</term>) includes—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438414075119_033" name="a" temporalId="s25_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a person paid at daily rates of pay, hereinafter referred to as a
                            <b><i>daily
                            paid
                    employee</i></b>;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438414075134_006" name="b" temporalId="s25_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an officer other than a daily paid employee who does not hold an
                    established office or who holding an established office is serving on probation,
                    but not including an officer who is serving under an agreement expressly
                    providing for the payment of a gratuity dependent upon the length of service of
                    such officer; such officers are hereinafter referred to as
                            <i><b>monthly
                            paid
                    officers</b></i>:
                </content></paragraph>
            <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s25_b_proviso">Provided that an officer holding an
                established office whilst on probation who is confirmed without break of service to
                an established office shall not be eligible for benefit under this Part in respect
                of service in an established office whilst on probation.</proviso>
            <continued>For the purpose of this provision any break of service which may be
                disregarded under the provisions of <ref>regulation 15</ref> may likewise be
                disregarded in determining whether an officer is confirmed in an established office
                without break of service; <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2024/er2">E.R. 2 of
                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote></continued>
        </def><def name="Salary">
            <leadIn><term>salary</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">薪金</term>) and
                    <term>pay</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">工資</term>) mean remuneration exclusive of cost of
                living allowance or other allowance or extra pay for work done in hours which are
                beyond the normal working period:</leadIn>
            <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s25_proviso">Provided that in the case of an officer
                who has elected
                    <term>salary</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">薪金</term>) means 90 per cent of such salary as
                hereinbefore
                    defined.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln15">L.N. 15 of
                        1967</ref>; <ref href="hk/2024/er2">E.R. 2 of
                2024</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
        </def><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
            49</ref>; <ref href="hk/2024/er2">E.R. 2 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403569103_001" name="s26" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Annual allowance and gratuity for monthly paid officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414075165_025" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every monthly paid non-pensionable officer serving under the Government in
                respect of whom the conditions set forth herein are fulfilled may on retirement be
                granted by the Chief Executive an annual allowance which, if his length of service
                does not exceed 25 years, shall be calculated at the rate of one eight-hundredth of
                his annual salary for every complete month of service under the Government and if
                his service exceeds 25 years, shall be calculated at three-hundred eight-hundredths
                of such annual salary with an addition thereto of one six-hundredth of such annual
                salary for every complete month of service under the Government in excess of 25
                years, and any incomplete month of service shall be taken to be that fraction of a
                complete month whereof the denominator is 30 and the numerator the number of days of
                service in that incomplete month, irrespective of the actual number of days in that
                    month.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075212_005" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Such annual salary shall be computed in accordance with the provisions of
                    <ref>regulation 18</ref>, subject to the following modifications—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075212_013" name="a" temporalId="s26_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for the word “pension” wherever it occurs, there shall be substituted the
                    words “annual allowance”;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075212_021" name="b" temporalId="s26_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for the words “service in an established office” in paragraph (1)<inline class="width_3"> </inline>there shall be substituted the words “public
                        service”;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
                        6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075228_006" name="c" temporalId="s26_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>for the words “pensionable emoluments” wherever they occur, there shall be
                    substituted the word “salary”; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of
                            1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of
                        1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075228_014" name="d" temporalId="s26_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>for the words “<ref>section 6(1)(c)</ref>, (d) or (e) of the Ordinance” in
                    paragraph <ref>(2)(ii)</ref> there shall be substituted the words
                        “<ref>regulation 26(4)(c)</ref>, (cc) or (d)”.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 102</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075228_021" name="3" temporalId="s26_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Annual salary in respect of an officer who, having held a non-established
                office is serving on probation in an established office, shall be the annual
                pensionable emoluments of the established office or the annual pay last received in
                respect of his service in a non-established office, whichever shall be
                greater.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075228_029" name="4" temporalId="s26_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The conditions upon which an annual allowance or gratuity may be granted under
                this regulation are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075243_005" name="a" temporalId="s26_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>subject to paragraphs (9), (10) and (11), such service must have been
                        continuous for a period of not less than 10 years:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1976/ln17">L.N. 17 of
                                1976</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s.
                            39</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                    <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s26_4_a_proviso">Provided that such
                        interruptions in service which may be disregarded under <ref>regulation
                            15</ref> for the purpose of qualifying for and computing a pension may
                        be disregarded for the purpose of qualifying for and computing an annual
                        allowance under this regulation; and either</proviso>
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075243_019" name="b" temporalId="s26_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the officer must have attained the age of 55; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075243_027" name="bb" temporalId="s26_4_bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content>where the officer’s retirement is with the approval of the Chief Executive,
                    the officer must have attained the age of 45; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of
                            1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075243_035" name="c" temporalId="s26_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Chief Executive must be satisfied on medical evidence that he is
                    incapable by reason of infirmity of mind or body of discharging the duties of
                    his office and that such infirmity is likely to be permanent; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075259_006" name="cc" temporalId="s26_4_cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content>the officer’s retirement must be necessitated by the abolition of his
                    office; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075259_014" name="d" temporalId="s26_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the officer’s retirement must be necessitated by the reorganization of the
                    department to which he belongs in order to effect greater economy or efficiency;
                        or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln352">L.N. 352 of 1988</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075259_022" name="e" temporalId="s26_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the officer’s retirement must be necessitated by the public interest;
                        or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln352">L.N. 352 of 1988</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075259_030" name="f" temporalId="s26_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the officer’s retirement must be compulsory and by reason of the exercise
                    by the Government of disciplinary powers of punishment.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln352">L.N. 352 of
                            1988</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075259_037" name="4A" temporalId="s26_4A"><num value="4A">(4A)</num><content>Unless otherwise directed by the Chief Executive, an annual allowance or
                gratuity granted to an officer to whom paragraph <ref>(4)(e)</ref> or (f) applies
                shall not be payable until the officer attains the age of 55 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s.
                        39</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075275_005" name="5" temporalId="s26_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>An officer to whom an annual allowance is granted under this regulation shall,
                if he has exercised his option as hereinafter provided, but not otherwise, be paid
                in lieu of such annual allowance an annual allowance at the rate of 75, 80, 85, 90
                or 95 per cent of such annual allowance, respectively, as he shall have exercised
                his option, together with a gratuity equal to 14 times the amount of the annual
                reduction so made in the annual allowance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1983/ln249">L.N. 249 of
                1983</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075275_013" name="5A" temporalId="s26_5A"><num value="5A">(5A)</num><content>
                <leadIn>The option referred to in paragraph (5) shall be exercisable, and if it has
                    been exercised may be revoked, not later than the day immediately preceding the
                    date of such officer’s retirement:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s26_5A_proviso">Provided that the Chief
                    Executive may, if it appears to him equitable in all the circumstances so to do,
                    allow him to exercise the option or revoke the option previously exercised at
                    any time between that date and the actual date of award of the annual allowance
                    under this regulation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of
                        1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075290_011" name="5B" temporalId="s26_5B"><num value="5B">(5B)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (5A), if an officer has exercised the option his decision
                shall be irrevocable so far as concerns any annual allowance to be granted to him
                under this regulation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075290_019" name="5C" temporalId="s26_5C"><num value="5C">(5C)</num><content>If an officer who has not exercised the option dies after he has finally
                retired but before an annual allowance has been granted to him under this
                regulation, it shall be lawful for the Chief Executive to grant a gratuity and
                reduced annual allowance as provided in paragraph (5), as if the officer before his
                death had exercised his option to receive a gratuity and 75 per cent of the annual
                    allowance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1992/ln63">L.N.
                        63 of 1992</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of
                        1999
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075306_005" name="5D" temporalId="s26_5D"><num value="5D">(5D)</num><content>The date of exercise of the option by an officer shall be deemed to be the date
                of the receipt of his written notification addressed to the Director of Accounting
                    Services.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075306_013" name="6" temporalId="s26_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>No annual allowance may be granted under this regulation to any officer in an
                established office in excess of the pension which might have been granted had that
                officer been a pensionable officer in the office held by him, with the same
                service.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075306_021" name="7" temporalId="s26_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438414075321_001" name="a" temporalId="s26_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Unless it shall have been approved on grounds of public policy by the Chief
                    Executive, any period during which a non-pensionable officer shall have been
                    absent from duty without salary shall not be taken into account for the purpose
                    of computing the period of service in respect of which an annual allowance or a
                    gratuity may be granted under these regulations.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075321_007" name="b" temporalId="s26_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>A period during which a non-pensionable officer is absent from duty without
                    salary shall not be regarded as constituting a break in service.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1988/ln352">L.N. 352
                            of 1988</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075321_014" name="8" temporalId="s26_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Every monthly paid non-pensionable officer serving under the Government who
                retires on any of the conditions stated in paragraph
                (4)(b),
                (bb), (c), (cc) and (d) and who on his retirement has not completed 10 years
                unbroken service may be granted by the Chief Executive a gratuity not exceeding 7
                times the annual allowance which if there has been no qualifying period might have
                been granted to him under this regulation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1955/gna72">G.N.A. 72 of 1955</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075337_005" name="8A" temporalId="s26_8A"><num value="8A">(8A)</num><leadIn>Where a non-pensionable female officer who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075337_013" name="a" temporalId="s26_8A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has, prior to 17 November 1972, retired from the service by reason of her
                    marriage; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075337_021" name="b" temporalId="s26_8A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has not, upon retirement, received a marriage gratuity under these
                    regulations,</content></paragraph><continued>is without break in service subsequently re-employed in the service under the
                Government, the period of service prior to such retirement shall be taken into
                account for the purpose of computing the period of service in respect of which an
                annual allowance or gratuity may be granted under these regulations.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/30">30 of 1980 s.
                        5</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075353_004" name="8AA" temporalId="s26_8AA"><num value="8AA">(8AA)</num><leadIn>In the case of an officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075353_012" name="a" temporalId="s26_8AA_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>who retires under paragraph <ref>(4)(c)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075353_020" name="b" temporalId="s26_8AA_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>whose retirement is necessitated or materially accelerated by permanent
                    injury sustained in the circumstances described in <ref>regulation
                        31(1)(a)</ref>, (b) and (c),</content></paragraph><continued>for the purposes of paragraph (1) or (8) his period of service to be taken
                into account in computing an award of an annual allowance or gratuity shall be
                deemed to be twice the actual period of his service, subject to a minimum of 2 years
                and a maximum of—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414075353_034" name="i" temporalId="s26_8AA_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>20 years; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075353_042" name="ii" temporalId="s26_8AA_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the period of pensionable service that he would have completed if he had
                    served until attaining the age of 55 years,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the lesser.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 32</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075368_004" name="9" temporalId="s26_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>In the case of an officer who retires under paragraph <ref>(4)(c)</ref>
                otherwise than under the circumstances described in paragraph <ref>(8AA)(b)</ref>
                and whose period of service under the Government is—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 32</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075368_012" name="a" temporalId="s26_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>not less than 5 nor more than 20 years; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075368_020" name="b" temporalId="s26_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>more than 20 years but whose period of service to be taken into account in
                    computing an award under paragraph (1) is less than 20 years,</content></paragraph><continued>for the purposes of paragraph (1) or paragraph (8) his period of service to
                be taken into account in computing an award under paragraph (1) shall be deemed to
                be—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414075368_034" name="i" temporalId="s26_9_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>twice his actual period of service to be taken into account in computing an
                    award under paragraph (1) (subject to a maximum of 20 years); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075368_042" name="ii" temporalId="s26_9_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the period of service to be taken into account in computing an award under
                    paragraph (1) that he would have completed if he had served until attaining the
                    age of 55 years,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the lesser.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
                    6</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075384_011" name="10" temporalId="s26_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><leadIn>Where an officer’s retirement is necessitated by the abolition of his office or
                by the reorganization of the department to which he belongs in order to effect
                greater economy or efficiency—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075384_019" name="a" temporalId="s26_10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he may, if he has been in the service of the Government for less than 10
                    years, be granted in lieu of any gratuity under paragraph (8), an annual
                    allowance under paragraph (1), as if the words “for a period of not less than 10
                    years” were omitted from paragraph <ref>(4)(a)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075384_027" name="b" temporalId="s26_10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>he may be granted an additional annual allowance in respect of his unbroken
                    service calculated in the following manner—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075384_035" name="i" temporalId="s26_10_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>for each complete period of 3 years service under the Government up to
                        24 years, one-eightieth of his annual salary;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075399_007" name="ii" temporalId="s26_10_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>for the complete period of 3 years service under the Government after
                        24 years, eleven-seven hundred and twentieths of his annual salary;
                            <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2024/er2">E.R. 2 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075399_015" name="iii" temporalId="s26_10_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>
                        <leadIn>for each complete period of 3 years service under the Government
                            after 27 years, one-sixtieth of his annual salary:</leadIn>
                        <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s26_10_b_iii_proviso">
                            <content>Provided that—</content>
                        </proviso>
                    </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075399_029" name="i" temporalId="s26_10_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any such additional annual allowance shall not exceed ten-eightieths of
                        his annual salary; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075399_037" name="ii" temporalId="s26_10_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any such additional annual allowance together with the remainder of the
                        officer’s annual allowance shall not exceed the annual allowance for which
                        he would have been eligible if he had continued to hold the office held by
                        him at the date of his retirement and retired on reaching the age of 55
                        having received all increments for which he would have been eligible by that
                            date.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075415_005" name="11" temporalId="s26_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>An officer referred to in paragraph <ref>(4)(e)</ref> or (f) may, if he has
                been in the service of the Government for less than 10 years, be granted an annual
                allowance under paragraph (1), as if the words “for a period of not less than 10
                years” were omitted from paragraph <ref>(4)(a)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s.
                    39</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075431_004" name="12" temporalId="s26_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>An annual allowance under this regulation shall be paid in monthly instalments,
                or less frequently if so requested by the recipient.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/4">4 of 1993 s.
                    39</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403569244_001" name="s27" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Gratuity for daily paid employees</heading><leadIn>Every daily paid employee serving under the Government may on his retirement on any
            of the conditions stated in <ref>regulation 26(4)(b)</ref>, (bb), (c), (cc) and (d)
            after completing not less than 5 years unbroken service be granted by the Chief
            Executive a gratuity calculated at the rate of 15 times the rate of pay per day of which
            he is in receipt at the time of his retirement for every completed period of 12 months’
                service:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>; <ref href="hk/2024/er2">E.R. 2 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s27_proviso">Provided that the Chief Executive may give
            directions in any particular case that service prior to a break which is not occasioned
            by dismissal for misconduct or by voluntary resignation and which does not extend for
            more than 3 years, shall be deemed to have preceded subsequent service without
                break.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1954/gna31">G.N.A. 31 of 1954</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of
                1960</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403569259_001" name="s28" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Service partly as monthly paid officer and partly as a daily paid
            employee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414075602_011" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a person’s service under the Government has been partly as a monthly paid
                officer and partly as a daily paid employee he may if he fulfils any of the
                conditions set out in <ref>regulation 26(4)(b)</ref>, (bb), (c), (cc) and (d) on his
                retirement be granted in respect of his service—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075602_019" name="a" temporalId="s28_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>an annual allowance or gratuity in respect of his aggregate service as a
                        monthly paid officer under <ref>regulation 26</ref>:</leadIn>
                    <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s28_1_a_proviso">Provided that
                            <ref>regulation 18</ref> shall be applied as though the words “date of
                        the final termination of his service as a monthly paid officer” were
                        substituted for the words “date of his retirement” wherever they appear in
                        the said regulation; and</proviso>
                </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075618_002" name="b" temporalId="s28_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if his total service under the Government is not less than 5 years a
                    gratuity in respect of his aggregate service as a daily paid employee under
                        <ref>regulation 27</ref> as though the words “time of the final termination
                    of his service as a daily paid employee” were substituted for the words “time of
                    his retirement” in the said regulation; or, if he so elects, in lieu of such
                    gratuity his continuous daily paid service prior to a transfer to monthly paid
                    service shall be deemed to be monthly paid service for the purpose of
                    calculating an annual allowance or gratuity under
                    subparagraph
                        (a).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
                        6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075633_005" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this regulation—</leadIn><def name="ContinuousDailyPaidService"><term>continuous
                    daily paid
                service</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">連續日薪服務期</term>) includes 2 or more periods of
                service only if they are separated by a period or periods of monthly paid
                service;</def><def name="DailyPaidService"><term>daily
                    paid
                service</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">日薪服務期</term>) includes any period of absence from
                duty in such circumstances as may be approved by the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N. 123 of 1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36
                of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403569290_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Gratuity payable where a non-pensionable officer dies in the service under the
      Government</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414075680_011" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where no gratuity can be granted under <ref>section 17</ref> of the Ordinance in
        respect of a non-pensionable officer who dies while in the service under the Government or
        whose death was caused in the discharge of his duty or as a direct result of injuries
        received whilst on duty or by illness specifically attributable to the nature of his duties,
        a gratuity may be granted under this regulation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075680_019" name="a" temporalId="s29_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the officer had not made a nomination under paragraph (1AA), to his legal
          personal representative;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075680_027" name="b" temporalId="s29_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the officer had made a nomination under paragraph (1AA), to his spouse;
          or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075696_006" name="c" temporalId="s29_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where such gratuity does not exceed such amount as may be determined by the Chief
          Executive, to such person as the Chief Executive shall name as the recipient.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 33</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075696_013" name="1AA" temporalId="s29_1AA"><num value="1AA">(1AA)</num><content>A non-pensionable officer may by a notice in writing to the Secretary nominate his
        spouse to be the recipient of the gratuity payable under this regulation in respect of his
          death.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
            33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075696_021" name="1AB" temporalId="s29_1AB"><num value="1AB">(1AB)</num><content>An officer who makes a nomination under paragraph (1AA) may at any time revoke the
        nomination by a notice in writing to the Secretary.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
        33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075696_029" name="1A" temporalId="s29_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>In respect of an officer who has more than one period of continuous service, a
        gratuity shall be granted under paragraph (1) in respect of each period of continuous
        service; but the total sum of the gratuities granted in respect of more than one period of
        continuous service shall not exceed the sum of the gratuity that would have been granted had
        the officer’s period of service been continuous and had his highest salary or notional
        highest salary in respect of his previous period of service, whichever is the greater, been
        taken for the calculation of the gratuity, less any pension, gratuity or allowance already
        paid or payable to him but excluding any additional pension granted under <ref>regulation
          31</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987
            s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075727_005" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A gratuity granted under paragraph (1) shall be of an amount to be determined by the
        Chief Executive but shall not exceed—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
            6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075727_013" name="a" temporalId="s29_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>where the officer has completed not less than 2 years’ service under the Government
          and where—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075727_021" name="i" temporalId="s29_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><leadIn>he was paid monthly—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075743_003" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s29_2_a_i_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>9 months’ salary; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075743_011" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s29_2_a_i_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>the commuted annual allowance gratuity, if any, or where appropriate the
              commuted annual allowance gratuity supplemented in accordance with paragraph
              (2A),</content></subparagraph><continued>whichever is the greater; and</continued></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075743_025" name="ii" temporalId="s29_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>he was paid daily, 180 days’
              pay;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
              33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075743_032" name="b" temporalId="s29_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>where the officer has completed not less than 1 year’s but less than 2 years’
          service under the Government and where—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/ln551">L.N. 551
              of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075743_040" name="i" temporalId="s29_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>he was paid monthly, 6 months’ salary; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075743_048" name="ii" temporalId="s29_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>he was paid daily, 120 days’
              pay;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
              33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075743_055" name="c" temporalId="s29_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>where the officer has completed less than 1 year’s service under the Government and
          where—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075743_063" name="i" temporalId="s29_2_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>he was paid monthly, 3 months’ salary; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414075743_071" name="ii" temporalId="s29_2_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>he was paid daily, 60 days’ pay.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
            33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075743_077" name="2A" temporalId="s29_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><leadIn>In the case of an officer whose period of service under the Government is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075758_005" name="a" temporalId="s29_2A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>not less than 5 nor more than 20 years; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075758_013" name="b" temporalId="s29_2A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>more than 20 years but whose period of service to be taken into account in
          computing an award under <ref>regulation 26(1)</ref> is less than 20 years,</content></paragraph><continued>the commuted annual allowance gratuity, if any, may be supplemented by deeming his
        period of service to be taken into account in computing an award under <ref>regulation
          26(1)</ref> to be twice his actual period of service to be taken into account in computing
        such award (subject to a maximum of 20 years) or the period of such service he would have
        completed if he had served until attaining the age of 55 years, whichever is the lesser, but
        an officer who has been granted a deemed increase of service under this paragraph in respect
        of his previous period of service shall only be eligible for a further deemed increase of
        service for any subsequent period of service to the extent that the total deemed increase of
        service does not exceed the maximum deemed increase of service specified in this
        paragraph:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s29_2A_proviso">Provided that this paragraph shall not
        apply in the case of a computation of a gratuity where the officer’s service to be so taken
        into account has already been deemed under <ref>regulation 26(9)</ref> to be twice his
        actual period of such service or the period of such service he would have completed if he
        had served until attaining the age of 55 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
          6</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075774_001" name="2AA" temporalId="s29_2AA"><num value="2AA">(2AA)</num><leadIn>In computing a deceased officer’s commuted annual allowance gratuity for the purposes
        of paragraph (2)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414075774_009" name="a" temporalId="s29_2AA_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the officer’s service shall be deemed to include any period of untaken vacation
          leave for which an ex gratia payment corresponding to the salary for that period has been
          made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414075774_017" name="b" temporalId="s29_2AA_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>notwithstanding
          subparagraph
          (a), for the purpose of determining an officer’s annual salary, his service shall be
          deemed to have ended on the date of his
          death.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075774_024" name="2B" temporalId="s29_2B"><num value="2B">(2B)</num><content>For the purpose of supplementing under paragraph (2), (2A) or (6) the commuted annual
        allowance gratuity of an officer to whom such paragraph applies, where appropriate his
        continuous daily paid service prior to transfer to monthly paid service shall be deemed to
        be monthly paid service as if he had so elected under <ref>regulation 28(1)(b)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s.
          6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075789_005" name="3" temporalId="s29_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A gratuity granted under paragraph (1) to the legal personal representative shall
        form part of the estate of the officer for the purposes of distribution but, nevertheless,
        no estate duty shall be payable in respect thereof, and this addition to the principal value
        of the estate shall not be taken into account for the purpose of increasing the rate at
        which estate duty on the remainder of the estate may be payable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075805_005" name="4" temporalId="s29_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="CommutedAnnualAllowanceGratuity">In this regulation
          <term>commuted
          annual allowance
        gratuity</term>
          (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經折算的年積金酬金</term>) means the maximum gratuity, if any, which
        might have been granted to the officer under <ref>regulation 26(5)</ref> if he had retired
        at the date of his death in the circumstances described in paragraph <ref>(4)(a)</ref> and
        (c) of that regulation and had elected to receive a gratuity and a reduced annual
          allowance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1962/gna34">G.N.A.
            34 of 1962</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075805_012" name="5" temporalId="s29_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>For the purposes of computing 3 months’, 6 months’ or 9 months’ salary of an officer
        under paragraph (2), the highest monthly salary enjoyed or drawn by him in the course of any
        particular period of continuous service only shall be taken into account for computing the
        amount for that period; but, where an officer is serving on trial or probation
        in
        an office immediately following service other than on trial or probation, the highest
        monthly salary which the officer would have enjoyed or drawn in his substantive rank at the
        date of his retirement or death shall be taken into account.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414075821_005" name="6" temporalId="s29_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where an officer dies after retirement from service under the Government having been
        granted, or having become eligible for, an annual allowance under <ref>regulation 26</ref>
        and that sums paid or payable at the date of his death on account of such annual allowance,
        including any sum awarded by way of gratuity under <ref>regulation 26</ref> but excluding
        any additional pension awarded in accordance with the provisions of <ref>regulation
          31(2)</ref> are in total, less than the amount of 9 months’ salary, or his commuted annual
        allowance gratuity, if any, or where appropriate the commuted annual allowance gratuity
        supplemented in accordance with paragraph (2A), whichever is the greater, the Chief
        Executive may grant a gratuity equal to the deficiency to the officer’s legal personal
        representative or, where that gratuity does not exceed such amount as may be determined by
        the Chief Executive, to such person as the Chief Executive shall name as the
          recipient.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of
            1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1980/ln123">L.N.
        123 of 1980</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403569306_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Application of <ref>section 9</ref> of the Ordinance</heading><content>The provisions of <ref>section 9</ref> of the Ordinance shall apply to annual allowances under this Part as though the words “annual allowance” were substituted for the word “pension” except where the word “pension” relates to an additional pension and as though the word “salary” was substituted for “pensionable emoluments” wherever such word or words may appear, and as though the words “<ref>regulation 26(4)(c)</ref>, (cc) or (d)” were substituted for the words “<ref>section 6(1)(c)</ref>, (d) or (e)”.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/26">26 of 1982 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 102</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403569306_003" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            VI</num><heading>Supplementary</heading><section id="ID_1438403569322_001" name="s31" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Officers retiring on account of injuries</heading><subsection id="ID_1438414076023_004" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If an officer holding an established office in which he has been confirmed is
                permanently injured—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438414076039_005" name="a" temporalId="s31_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the actual discharge of his duty; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414076039_013" name="b" temporalId="s31_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not due to his own serious and wilful misconduct; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline>
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
                        34</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414076039_021" name="c" temporalId="s31_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on account of circumstances specifically attributable to the nature of his
                    duty,</content></paragraph><continued>he may—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438414076039_035" name="i" temporalId="s31_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if his retirement is thereby necessitated or materially accelerated and he
                    has been in the public service for less than 10 years, be granted, in lieu of
                    any gratuity under <ref>regulation 5</ref> or <ref>12</ref>, a pension under
                        <ref>regulation 4</ref>, <ref>9</ref>, <ref>10</ref> or <ref>11</ref>, as
                    the case may be, as if the words “for 10 years or more” were omitted from the
                    said <ref>regulation 4</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414076055_006" name="ii" temporalId="s31_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><leadIn>if he is so injured on or after 1 February 1993 while in the service under
                    the Government and as a result of such injury his capacity to contribute to his
                    own support thereby becomes impaired at or after his retirement, be granted an
                    additional pension at the annual rate of the proportion of his actual
                    pensionable emoluments at the date of his injury in direct proportion to the
                    percentage of permanent incapacity suffered by him, and such additional pension
                    shall be payable—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438414076055_014" name="A" temporalId="s31_1_ii_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>where he suffers incapacity before his retirement, with effect from the
                        date of his retirement;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438414076055_022" name="B" temporalId="s31_1_ii_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>where he suffers incapacity after his retirement, with effect from the
                        date on which such incapacity is determined in accordance with paragraph
                            (1A);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/98">98 of
                                1994 s. 14</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414076070_006" name="iii" temporalId="s31_1_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>if he is so injured before 1 February 1993 while in the service under the
                    Government, be granted on retirement an additional pension at the annual rate of
                    the proportion of his actual pensionable emoluments at the date of his injury
                    appropriate to his case as shown in the table in this
                        paragraph;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/98">98 of 1994 s.
                            14</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438414076070_014" name="iv" temporalId="s31_1_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>if he is so injured before 1 February 1993 while in the service under the
                    Government and his capacity to contribute to his own support thereby becomes
                    impaired after his retirement, be granted from the time such impairment is
                    established an additional pension at the annual rate of the proportion of his
                    actual pensionable emoluments at the date of his injury appropriate to his case
                    as shown in the table in this
                        paragraph.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/98">98 of 1994 s.
                            14</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><continued><center>Table</center><marker role="blank-line"></marker>When
                the officer’s capacity to contribute to his own support
                    is—<table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="100%">
                    <col width="10%"></col>
                    <col width="70%"></col>
                    <col width="20%"></col>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>(a)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_.">slightly impaired </td>
                            <td class="cellpadding_left_10" align="right">50/600</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="cellpadding_top_5">(b)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_. cellpadding_top_5">impaired</td>
                            <td class="cellpadding_top_5 cellpadding_left_10" align="right">100/600</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="cellpadding_top_5">(c)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_. cellpadding_top_5">materially impaired </td>
                            <td class="cellpadding_top_5 cellpadding_left_10" align="right">150/600</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="cellpadding_top_5">(d)</td>
                            <td class="leaders_. cellpadding_top_5">totally destroyed </td>
                            <td class="cellpadding_top_5 cellpadding_left_10" align="right">200/600</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table></continued><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/98">98 of 1994 s. 14</ref>)</sourceNote><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s31_proviso">Provided that the amount of the
                additional pension may be reduced to such an extent as the Chief Executive shall
                think reasonable where the injury is not the cause or the sole cause of retirement.
                    <sourceNote>(G.N.A. <ref href="/hk/1960/90">90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076086_032" name="1A" temporalId="s31_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>The percentage of permanent incapacity referred to in paragraph
                    <ref>(1)(ii)</ref> shall be assessed in such manner as the Secretary may specify
                by general notice published in the Gazette.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
                    34</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076101_005" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any officer so injured while in the service under the Government not holding an
                established office, or holding an established office in which he has not been
                confirmed, may be granted on retirement a pension of the same amount as the
                additional pension which might be granted to him under paragraph (1) if his office
                were an established office and he had been confirmed therein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076101_013" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076101_021" name="4" temporalId="s31_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An officer who is permanently injured while travelling by any means in
                pursuance of official instructions or in the course of his duties shall be deemed to
                have been injured in the circumstances detailed in paragraph <ref>(1)(a)</ref> and (c).
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s.
                    34</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076117_005" name="4A" temporalId="s31_4A"><num value="4A">(4A)</num><content>Where an additional pension is granted under this regulation in respect of an
                injury which was caused in circumstances creating a legal liability in some person
                other than the Government, the Government may take proceedings against such person
                to recover an amount not exceeding the amount of the additional pension multiplied
                by
                14.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076117_013" name="5" temporalId="s31_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The provisions of <ref>regulation 23</ref> shall not apply to a pension granted
                under this regulation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076117_021" name="6" temporalId="s31_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Paragraphs <ref>(1)(ii)</ref>, (iii) and (iv) and (2) shall not apply in the
                case of an officer who, in consequence of his injury, is entitled to and has
                received compensation under the Employees’ Compensation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap282">Cap. 282</ref>), the Pneumoconiosis and Mesothelioma
                (Compensation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap360">Cap. 360</ref>) or the Occupational
                Deafness (Compensation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap469">Cap. 469</ref>).
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1962/gna34">G.N.A. 34 of 1962</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1980/51">51 of 1980 s. 48</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of
                        1993 s. 34</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/98">98 of 1994 s. 14</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/21">21 of 1995 s. 46</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2008/6">6 of 2008
                        s. 39</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076133_005" name="7" temporalId="s31_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>If there is any variation in the degree of incapacity of an officer subsequent
                to the grant of a pension or additional pension granted to him under this
                regulation, the rate at which such pension has been granted may be reassessed in
                such manner as the Secretary may specify by general notice published in the Gazette
                and at such time as the Secretary may think fit.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/3">3 of 1993 s. 34</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438414076148_005" name="8" temporalId="s31_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>A pension or additional pension granted to an officer under paragraph
                    <ref>(1)(iii)</ref> or (iv) may be reassessed in accordance with the table in
                paragraph (1) at such time or times as a medical board appointed by the Hospital
                Authority may determine, if there is any variation in the extent of the impairment
                of that officer’s capacity to contribute to his own support.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1994/98">98 of 1994 s.
                    14</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403569353_001" name="s32" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Commutation</heading><leadIn>In lieu of the grant of a pension or annual allowance there may, with the approval
            of the Chief Executive, be granted to an officer if he intends to reside in India or in
            China (excluding Hong Kong), a capital sum equal to the amount of 5 annual payments, but
            no such capital sum shall ordinarily be paid in any case of retirement on the ground of
            ill-health:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s32_proviso">Provided that for the purposes of this
            regulation such annual payments shall be the remaining portions after deduction of the
            annual contribution, if any, due in respect of widows and orphans pension.</proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403569353_003" name="s33" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Allowance in certain cases to hospital matrons and nursing-sisters, with other
            services</heading><leadIn>Where a European matron or a European nursing-sister has been employed in other
            public service as a qualified
            nursing-sister
            or matron, which employment was obtained by or through the Overseas Nursing Association,
            and has held an established office under the Government on or at any time after 1
            January 1926, as a matron or nursing-sister in a Government hospital for a period, which
            need not be continuous, of not less than 3 years, and she is not eligible in respect of
            such period or any part thereof for pension, gratuity or other retiring allowance under
            the regulations contained in Parts II and IV, but her aggregate service under the
            Government and in other public service as aforesaid make up a period, which need not be
            continuous, of not less than 15 years, or 10 years if she is compelled by reason of
            ill-health, not caused by her own misconduct, to relinquish her overseas nursing career,
            she may, subject as hereinafter provided, on her ultimate retirement from the public
            service be granted an allowance calculated at the rate of 8 shillings and 4 pence per
            annum, if retiring before 1 April 1951, and at the rate of one pound per annum if
            retiring on or after that date, for each complete month of her pensionable service under
            the Government in respect of which she is not otherwise eligible for pension, gratuity
            or other allowance under Parts II and IV, as aforesaid:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1953/gna93">G.N.A. 93 of 1953</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1955/gna107">G.N.A. 107 of 1955</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s33_proviso">Provided that, except in the case of
            retirement, which in the opinion of the Chief Executive is ultimate retirement on
            account of infirmity of mind or body, or which is from a British colony in which the age
            of voluntary retirement is less than 50 years, no such allowance shall be payable until
            the matron or nursing-sister attains the age of 50 years; and provided further that the
            grant of every allowance under this regulation shall be dependent on the production to
            the satisfaction of the Chief Executive of certificates of satisfactory service in
            respect of each term of service making up the minimum period of 15 years or 10 years, as
            the case may be, and that the total allowance drawn by a matron or nursing-sister from
            all sources in respect of her nursing career shall not exceed two-thirds of the highest
            pensionable emoluments drawn by her at any time in the course of her service under the
            Government or in other public service.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1960/gna90">G.N.A. 90 of 1960</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/63">63 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s. 49</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403569368_002" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule 1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap89A/s8">reg.
          8</ref>]<sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/1992/ln373">L.N. 373 of
      1992</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><content>Aden</content><content>Antigua</content><content>Bahamas</content><content>Barbados</content><content>Basutoland</content><content>Bechuanaland
      Protectorate</content><content>Bermuda</content><content>British Antarctic
      Territory</content><content>British Guiana</content><content>British
      Honduras</content><content>British Solomon Islands
      Protectorate</content><content>Brunei</content><content>Cayman Islands</content><content>Crown
      Agents for Oversea Governments and
      Administrations</content><content>Cyprus</content><content>Dominica</content><content>East
      Africa High Commission</content><content>East African Common Services
      Organization</content><content>East African Community</content><content>East African Harbours
      Corporation</content><content>East African Posts and Telecommunications
      Corporation</content><content>East African Railways and Harbours
      Administration</content><content>East African Railways Corporation</content><content>Eastern
      Region of Nigeria</content><content>Employing Authorities under the Oversea Superannuation
      Scheme</content><content>Employing Authorities under the Overseas Service Act
      1958</content><content>Falkland Islands</content><content>Federal Republic of
      Nigeria</content><content>Federated Malay States</content><content>Federation of
      Malaya</content><content>Federation of Nigeria</content><content>Federation of Rhodesia and
      Nyasaland</content><content>Fiji</content><content>Gambia</content><content>Ghana</content><content>Gibraltar</content><content>Gilbert
      and Ellice Islands Colony</content><content>Gold
      Coast</content><content>Grenada</content><content>Guyana</content><content>Jamaica</content><content>Kenya</content><content>Kenya
      and Uganda Railways and Harbours Administration</content><content>Kingdom of
      Lesotho</content><content>Leeward Islands (before 1 July
      1956)</content><content>Malawi</content><content>Malayan
      Establishment</content><content>Malayan
      Union</content><content>Malaysia</content><content>Malta</content><content>Mauritius</content><content>Mid
      West Nigeria</content><content>Montserrat</content><content>Nigeria</content><content>North
      Borneo</content><content>Northern Region of Nigeria</content><content>Northern
      Rhodesia</content><content>Nyasaland</content><content>Overseas Audit Department (Home
      Establishment)</content><content>Peoples’ Democratic Republic of Yemen</content><content>Post
      Office, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</content><content>Republic of
      Botswana</content><content>Republic of Zambia</content><content>Sabah</content><content>St.
      Christopher Nevis and Anguilla</content><content>St. Helena</content><content>St.
      Lucia</content><content>St.
      Vincent</content><content>Sarawak</content><content>Seychelles</content><content>Sierra
      Leone</content><content>Singapore</content><content>Somaliland
      Protectorate</content><content>Straits
      Settlements</content><content>Swaziland</content><content>Tanganyika</content><content>The
      West Indies (Federation)</content><content>Trinidad</content><content>Turks and Caicos
      Islands</content><content>Uganda</content><content>United Kingdom of Great Britain and
      Northern Ireland</content><content>United Republic of Tanzania</content><content>Virgin
      Islands</content><content>Western Region of Nigeria</content><content class="first_line_indent_0">Zanzibar</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1962/gna34">G.N.A. 34 of 1962</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1967/ln15">L.N. 15 of
        1967</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1970/ln44">L.N. 44 of 1970</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1972/ln238">L.N.
        238 of 1972</ref>;<ref href="/hk/1987/36">36 of 1987 s.
      49</ref>) </sourceNote></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403569400_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-21" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
                                    2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap89A/s17A">reg. 17A</ref>]</note><heading>Women’s
                                    Services</heading><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076476_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_s1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Member of Queen Alexandra’s Royal Naval Nursing Service
                                                or any reserve thereof</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076476_021" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_s2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>Member of the Women’s Royal Naval Service</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076476_030" name="s3" temporalId="sch2_s3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>Woman medical or dental practitioner serving in the
                                                Royal Navy or any naval reserve</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076476_039" name="s4" temporalId="sch2_s4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>Member of Queen Alexandra’s Imperial Military Nursing
                                                Service or any reserve thereof or of Queen
                                                Alexandra’s Royal Army Nursing Corps or any reserve
                                                thereof</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076491_005" name="s5" temporalId="sch2_s5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>Member of the Territorial Army Nursing Service or any
                                                reserve thereof</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076491_014" name="s6" temporalId="sch2_s6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>Member of the Auxiliary Territorial Service or the
                                                Women’s Royal Army Corps</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076491_023" name="s7" temporalId="sch2_s7"><num value="7">7.</num><content>Woman employed with the Royal Army Medical Corps or the
                                                Army Dental Corps with relative rank as an
                                                officer</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076491_032" name="s8" temporalId="sch2_s8"><num value="8">8.</num><content>Member of Princess Mary’s Royal Air Force Nursing
                                                Service or any reserve thereof</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076491_041" name="s9" temporalId="sch2_s9"><num value="9">9.</num><content>Member of the Women’s Auxiliary Air Force or the
                                                Women’s Royal Air Force</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076491_050" name="s10" temporalId="sch2_s10"><num value="10">10.</num><content>Woman employed with the Medical Branch or the Dental
                                                Branch of the Royal Air Force with relative rank as
                                                an officer</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1438414076491_059" name="s11" temporalId="sch2_s11"><num value="11">11.</num><content>Member of the Voluntary Aid Detachments employed under
                                                the Admiralty, Army Council or Air Council</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/ln373">L.N. 373 of 1992</ref>; <ref href="hk/2024/er2">E.R. 2 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></section></schedule></main></subLeg>