<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 138 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>138C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap138C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-07-30</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402708328_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-07-30">Course
                                    of Training, Study and Examination for Applicants for
                                    Registration as Pharmacists
                                    Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap138/s4">Cap.
                                                138, section
                                    4</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 January 1938]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="add-toc">Requirements for Registration as an Apprentice or
        Student</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402708344_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1"><b>1.</b></num><leadIn>Every applicant for registration as an apprentice or student must have entered into
            Articles of Pupilage with a registered pharmacist or with a body corporate entitled to
            become an authorized seller of poisons, or with a pharmacist jointly with either the
            committee of a hospital or similar institution or the owner of a pharmaceutical
            manufacturing laboratory:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s1_proviso">Provided that where a person is engaged on a
            full time agreement in a Government hospital or other Government institution under the
            direction of a qualified pharmacist, such agreement shall be accepted in the place of
            Articles of Pupilage.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402708359_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2"><b>2.</b></num><leadIn>At the time of making an application for registration as an apprentice or student
            the applicant shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276312_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>lodge with the registrar a certificate of having passed the Matriculation
                Examination of the University of Hong Kong or such other equivalent examination as
                the registrar shall approve;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1952/gna187">G.N.A. 187 of 1952</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276312_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>pay the prescribed fee for registration;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276312_028" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>lodge with the registrar a copy of his Articles of Pupilage.</content></paragraph></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Qualifying Examination—General</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402708375_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3"><b>3.</b></num><content>The Qualifying Examination shall be styled “The Chemist and Druggist Qualifying
            Examination”.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402708406_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4"><b>4.</b></num><content>The Qualifying Examination shall be in two parts, the first part the Intermediate
            Examination and the second part the Final Examination.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Training and
        Requirements for Admission to the Qualifying
        Examination</crossHeading><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline class="not_bold">Requirements for entry to the
            Intermediate Examination</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402708406_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5"><b>5.</b></num><leadIn>The Intermediate Examination shall be held twice a year in June and December. When
            applying to enter for the first time, the candidate shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276359_026" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>have been registered as an apprentice or student;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276359_034" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>pay the prescribed fee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276359_042" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>lodge with the registrar a certificate on the official form obtainable from the
                registrar signed by the applicant’s principal or his authorized deputy that,
                subsequent to registration as an apprentice or student, he has attended a course of
                approved instruction at a recognized educational institution over a period of one
                year full time study or two years’ attendance at evening classes.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402708437_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6"><b>6.</b></num><content>The subjects of the Intermediate Examination shall be Chemistry, Physics and
            Biology and the examination shall be conducted in accordance with the syllabus as
            approved from time to time by the Chief Executive in Council. The registrar shall
            supply, without fee, a copy of the syllabus to any person on application.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/60">60 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402708437_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7"><b>7.</b></num><content>A person who has been registered as an apprentice or student and who satisfies the
            registrar that he has passed one of the examinations set out in Appendix 1 shall be
            deemed to have passed the Intermediate Examination provided that the subjects include
            Chemistry, Physics and Biology. If the subjects include two only of those prescribed in
            these regulations he shall be deemed to have passed the examination in such two
            subjects.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402708453_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8"><b>8.</b></num><content>A candidate shall present himself for examination in all of the subjects of the
            examination except that a candidate who shall be deemed to have passed the examination
            in two of the subjects only may present himself for examination in the one remaining
            subject.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402708469_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9"><b>9.</b></num><content>A candidate who has failed to satisfy the Examiners in one subject only may,
            subject to the permission of the Examiners, present himself for examination in that one
            subject only. Before be applies to enter again for the examination a candidate who has
            failed to satisfy the Examiners shall produce satisfactory evidence to the Examiners
            that he has complied with any conditions made by them concerning his presenting himself
            for examination in the subject in which he failed to satisfy the Examiners.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402708469_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10"><b>10.</b></num><leadIn>Except in the following circumstances no fee or portion of a fee shall be
            returned—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276437_019" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a candidate who withdraws before the last date of entry for the examination
                shall receive back the fee paid;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276437_027" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a candidate who has entered for the examination but fails to present himself
                and submits proof satisfactory to the registrar that his absence was due to illness
                or other unavoidable cause shall receive back the fee paid.</content></paragraph></section><crossHeading class="add-toc"><inline class="not_bold">Requirements for Entry to the Final
            Examination</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402708484_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11"><b>11.</b></num><leadIn>The Examination shall be held twice a year in March and October. When applying to
            enter the Examination for the first time a candidate shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276468_012" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>have passed or be deemed to have passed the Intermediate Examination;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276468_020" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>pay the prescribed fee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276468_028" name="c" temporalId="s11_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>produce to the registrar—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411276468_036" name="I" temporalId="s11_c_I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content>a certificate of registration of birth;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411276468_044" name="II" temporalId="s11_c_II"><num value="II">(II)</num><leadIn>a declaration, signed by the candidate on the official form obtainable from
                    the registrar, that he has been trained under the supervision of a registered
                    pharmacist in the dispensing and compounding of medicines for a period of not
                    less than four thousand hours, spread over not less than two years, in one of
                    the following places—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411276468_051" name="i" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s11_c_II_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a set of premises registered under <ref>section 13</ref> of the
                            Ordinance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411276484_007" name="ii" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s11_c_II_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a manufacturing pharmaceutical laboratory;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411276484_015" name="iii" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s11_c_II_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a dispensary of a hospital or<inline class="width_3"> </inline>similar
                        institution.</content></subparagraph><continued>The declaration shall state the address of the place or places at which
                    the course has been undergone with the dates and periods of such training and
                    shall be signed by the pharmacist who supervised the training. The declaration
                    shall only be valid if the course was undergone by the candidate subsequent to
                    registration as an apprentice or student and while serving under Articles of
                    Pupilage in accordance with regulations, and only if the course was subsequent
                    to such Articles of Pupilage having been endorsed by the registrar and a copy
                    lodged with him;</continued></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411276484_028" name="III" temporalId="s11_c_III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content>a certificate on the official form obtainable from the registrar signed by
                    the candidate’s principal or his deputy that, subsequent to having passed or
                    being deemed to have passed the Intermediate Examination, the candidate has
                    attended at a recognized educational institution an approved systematic course
                    of instruction in the subjects of the Final Examination and has completed the
                    work to the satisfaction of the principal. The course of instruction shall be
                    spread over a period of not less than 250 hours in Pharmaceutics, 250 hours in
                    Pharmaceutical Chemistry and 250 hours in Physiology, Pharmacognosy and Forensic
                    Pharmacy.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402708515_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12"><b>12.</b></num><content>The subjects of the Examination shall be Pharmaceutics, Pharmaceutical Chemistry,
            Pharmacognosy, Physiology and Forensic Pharmacy, and shall be in accordance with the
            syllabus as approved from time to time by the Chief Executive in Council. The registrar
            shall supply, without fee, a copy of the syllabus to any person on
            application.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/60">60 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402708531_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13"><b>13.</b></num><leadIn>A candidate shall present himself for examination in all subjects of the Examination
            except that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276546_033" name="a" temporalId="s13_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a candidate who has failed to satisfy the Examiners in one subject only, may,
                subject to the permission of the Examiners, present himself for examination in that
                one subject only. Before he applies to enter again for the Examination a candidate
                who has failed to satisfy the Examiners shall produce satisfactory evidence to the
                Examiners that he has complied with any conditions made by them concerning his
                presenting himself again for examination in the subject in which he failed to
                satisfy the Examiners;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276562_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>
                <leadIn>a candidate who satisfies the Examiners in the subject or subjects in which
                    he presents himself for examination in accordance with these regulations shall
                    be granted a certificate by the Examiners to that effect and entitling him to be
                    registered as a chemist and druggist in accordance with the provisions of the
                    Ordinance:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s13_b_proviso">Provided that no such certificate
                    shall be issued until such time as the candidate has attained the age of
                    twenty-one years.</proviso>
            </content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402708562_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14"><b>14.</b></num><content>The Articles of Pupilage shall contain the provisions of the draft Articles set out
            in Appendix 2 or provisions to like effect or the provisions of any Articles under which
            the candidate may have been serving on 18th March, 1949, provided that such Articles had
            been endorsed by the registrar.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402708578_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15"><b>15.</b></num><leadIn>Except in the following circumstances no fee or portion of a fee shall be
            returned—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276609_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a candidate who withdraws before the last date of entry for the examination
                shall receive back the fee paid;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276609_020" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a candidate who has entered for the examination but fails to present himself
                and submits to the registrar proof satisfactory to the registrar that his absence
                was due to illness or other unavoidable cause shall receive back the fee
                paid.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402708578_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16"><b>16.</b></num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the provisions of the foregoing regulations it shall be permissible
            for the registrar to exempt from compliance with any requirement contained in such of
            the regulations as apply to examinations for registration as an apprentice or student to
            courses of theoretical and practical study, any person who produces evidence to the
            satisfaction of the registrar that either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276624_027" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he has complied with a corresponding requirement under previous regulations at
                the time such regulations were in force; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276624_035" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he has received a sufficient preliminary practical training in a course of
                study for the subjects of the examination.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438402708609_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17"><b>17.</b></num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of the foregoing regulations the registrar may,
            subject to such conditions as he may prescribe, accept a practical course of study
            undergone in a place other than Hong Kong provided the person is registered as an
            apprentice or student.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402708609_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18"><b>18.</b></num><leadIn>A candidate who has received training in a place other than Hong Kong may, at the
            discretion of the registrar, be admitted to the Final Examination of the Chemist and
            Druggist Qualifying Examination provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276671_012" name="a" temporalId="s18_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he produces evidence satisfactory to the registrar of having undergone a course
                of training and study which, in the opinion of the registrar, is equivalent to that
                required under <ref>regulation 11</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276671_020" name="b" temporalId="s18_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he produces evidence satisfactory to the registrar of having passed an
                examination which in the opinion of the registrar is equivalent to the Intermediate
                Examination of the Chemist and Druggist Qualifying Examination;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276671_028" name="c" temporalId="s18_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>he pays the prescribed fee for entry to the Final Examination.</content></paragraph></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Citation</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402708640_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19"><b>19.</b></num><content>These regulations may be cited as the Course of Training, Study and Examination for
            Applicants for Registration as Pharmacists Regulations.</content></section><appendix id="ID_1438402708656_002" name="app1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="app1">
    <num value="1">Appendix
      1</num>
    
    <note role="crossReferences" type="inline" class="font_size_11">[<ref href="/hk/cap138C/s7">reg.
        7</ref>]</note>
    <heading>Examination
      Accepted in Place of the First Part or Intermediate Examination for the Chemist and Druggist
      Qualifying Examination
      <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading>
    
    
    <section class="no_header" id="ID_1588668418618_001" name="s0" temporalId="app1_s0"><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0">A candidate shall be deemed to have passed
        the Intermediate Examination of the Chemist and Druggist Qualifying Examination if he
        produces evidence to the registrar as having passed one of the following examinations
        provided that the subjects include Chemistry, Physics and Biology—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438411276718_014" name="a" temporalId="app1_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Final or Intermediate Examination for a degree in Arts or Science of the
          University of Hong Kong or of any other British or Colonial or Dominion
          University;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411276718_023" name="b" temporalId="app1_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Higher School Examination;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411276718_032" name="c" temporalId="app1_s0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the First or any subsequent examination for any degree or diploma recognized by the
          General Medical Council;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411276718_041" name="d" temporalId="app1_s0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the Preliminary Scientific Examination for Chemist and Druggist of the Pharmacy and
          Poisons Ordinance if taken prior to the 18th of March, 1949.</content></subsection></section>
  </appendix><appendix id="ID_1438402708671_001" name="app2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-30" status="operational" temporalId="app2">
        <num value="2">Appendix
            2</num>
        
        <note class="font_size_11" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap138C/s14">reg. 14</ref>]</note>
        <heading>Draft
            Articles of
            Pupilage<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading>
        <leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">It is agreed between <fillIn class=" width_72">.</fillIn> of <fillIn class=" width_72">.</fillIn> (hereinafter
            called the Employer) of the first part <fillIn class=" width_108">.</fillIn> of <fillIn class=" width_111">.</fillIn> (hereinafter called the Pupil), son or ward of <fillIn class=" width_95">.</fillIn> (hereinafter called the Parent or Guardian) of the
            third part, as follows:—<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></leadIn>
        <paragraph id="ID_1438411276734_055" name="1" temporalId="app2_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The Pupil for himself and the Parent or Guardian as surety for him jointly and
                severally bind themselves that the Pupil shall honestly faithfully and diligently
                serve the Employer in his business of Dispensing Chemist for a period of <fillIn class=" width_57">.</fillIn> years from the <fillIn class=" width_52">.</fillIn>
                day of <fillIn class=" width_97">.</fillIn> Nineteen hundred and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><fillIn class=" width_75">.</fillIn> which day is
                declared to be the commencement of the Pupilage of the Pupil; that the Pupil shall
                always keep the Employer’s secrets and shall obey his lawful commands, and shall not
                without authority make copies of any papers or books belonging to the Employer; that
                the Pupil shall not absent himself from the Employer’s service without leave, shall
                behave himself civilly and respectfully to the Employer and his customers, shall
                observe the rules appended to these Articles and shall both during and outside of
                business hours abstain from all illegal
                practices.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID_1438411276780_004" name="2" temporalId="app2_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>And the Employer (in consideration of the Premium of H.K.$ <fillIn class=" width_93">.</fillIn> now paid by the Parent or Guardian the receipt of
                which the Employer hereby acknowledges)* binds himself to instruct the Pupil in his
                business of Dispensing Chemist; to afford the Pupil such reasonable opportunities
                and work as may be required to enable him to learn the same; to observe the rules
                appended to these Articles; to grant the Pupil such facilities to attend such
                classes as may be necessary; on their due completion to discharge these Articles in
                the form provided and if in his opinion correct, to verify the facts set out in the
                declaration regarding<inline class="width_3"> </inline>the practical study required
                by the regulations to be made by the Pupil when entering for the Qualifying
                Examination.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID_1438411276812_004" name="3" temporalId="app2_3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>And the Employer further binds his executors and administrators to repay to the
                Parent or Guardian a proportionate part of the premium afore-mentioned in the event
                of the death of the Employer before the expiration of these Articles, or
                alternatively to make provision for the completion by the Pupil of the remainder of
                the Pupilage under conditions acceptable under the afore-mentioned regulations
                without cost to the Parent or
                Guardian.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID_1438411276827_004" name="4" temporalId="app2_4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>In Witness Whereof the parties to these Articles have set their hands and seals
                this <fillIn class=" width_88">.</fillIn> day of <fillIn class=" width_54">.</fillIn> Nineteen hundred and <fillIn class=" width_75">.</fillIn><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph>
        
        <continued>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="446">
                <colgroup>
                    <col width="50%"></col>
                    <col width="18%"></col>
                    <col width="32%"></col>
                </colgroup>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Signed, Sealed and Delivered by the said Employer said Employer in the
                            presence
                            of<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center"><fillIn xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class=" width_110">.</fillIn><br></br>(Employer)</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center">
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_center">(Witness)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Occupation </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Address </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Signed, Sealed and Delivered by the said Pupil in the presence
                            of<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center">
                            <fillIn xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class=" width_110">.</fillIn>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_center">(Witness)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Occupation </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Address </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Signed, Sealed and Delivered by the said Parent or Guardian in the
                            presence of</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center"><fillIn xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class=" width_110">.</fillIn><br></br>(Parent or Guardian)</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_center">(Witness)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Occupation </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Address </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_12">In the foregoing Articles words
                importing the singular number shall include the plural and vice versa, words
                importing the masculine gender shall include the feminine, the words importing
                persons shall include Firms and Corporations, unless there be anything in the
                context repugnant to such construction.</text>
        </continued>
        
        
        <crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">DISCHARGE</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading>
        <text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">I, <fillIn class=" width_63">.</fillIn> in
            respect that <fillIn class=" width_90">.</fillIn> has served me in terms of the
            foregoing Articles during the whole period herein stipulated do hereby discharge him and
            also <fillIn class=" width_183">.</fillIn> of all obligations under the said
            Articles.</text>
        <text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">In Witness Whereof I have set my hand this
                <fillIn class=" width_129">.</fillIn> day of Nineteen hundred and <fillIn class=" width_88">.</fillIn><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text>
        <text class="align_right">
            <fillIn class=" width_129">.</fillIn>
        </text>
        <text class="first_line_indent_0">
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="446">
                <colgroup>
                    <col width="5%"></col>
                    <col width="95%"></col>
                </colgroup>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>*</td>
                        <td>No receipt stamp necessary,</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>delete if not applicable.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text>
        <crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold"><i>APPENDIX</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker>Rules
                for Practical Course of Study During
                Apprenticeship<marker role="blank-line"></marker></inline></crossHeading>
        <subsection id="ID_1438411276843_108" name="1" temporalId="app2_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The employer shall from time to time if so requested, furnish such information
                as may be required by the registrar about the staff, accommodation, equipment and
                work of the shop, hospital, dispensary or manufacturing laboratory where the
                apprenticeship is being carried out, and shall permit a representative of the
                registrar to inspect the premises at any reasonable time during working
                hours.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection>
        <subsection id="ID_1438411276874_004" name="2" temporalId="app2_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>If the employer is not a registered pharmacist or does not undertake personally
                the practical course of study of the pupil he shall appoint some registered
                pharmacist member of his staff who shall be responsible to the employer therefor.
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection>
        <subsection id="ID_1438411276874_012" name="3" temporalId="app2_3"><num value="3">3.</num><leadIn>The practical course of study shall include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411276874_022" name="a" temporalId="app2_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the manipulation of pharmaceutical apparatus in common use;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276874_031" name="b" temporalId="app2_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the preparation of the more commonly used galenicals;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276874_040" name="c" temporalId="app2_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the reading, translation and copying of prescriptions including the
                    checking of doses;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276874_049" name="d" temporalId="app2_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the dispensing of prescriptions;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411276874_058" name="e" temporalId="app2_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>experience in the keeping of the records required by the different parts of
                    the Pharmacy and Poisons Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap138">Cap. 138</ref>) and
                    Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>), as affecting
                    pharmaceutical
                    practice.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph></subsection>
        <subsection id="ID_1438411276890_004" name="4" temporalId="app2_4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>The apprentice or pupil shall keep a record of his
                work.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection>
        <subsection id="ID_1438411276890_012" name="5" temporalId="app2_5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>The employer shall provide such apparatus, books of reference, materials and
                the opportunity to enable the pupil to undergo the practical course of study
                outlined in <ref>paragraph
                3</ref>.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection>
        <subsection id="ID_1438411276890_020" name="6" temporalId="app2_6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>The number of pupils that may be employed in any shop, hospital dispensary or
                manufacturing pharmaceutical laboratory, shall not exceed two for each registered
                pharmacist engaged in the work in which the pupil is undergoing the course mentioned
                and referred to above.</content></subsection>
    </appendix></main></subLeg>