<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 190 sub. leg. K</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>190K</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap190K!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-08-26</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438402815485_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-08-26">The
            World
            Health
            Organization</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap190/s2">Cap. 190, section
                2</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[19 May 1950]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><text class="first_line_indent_0">
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><sourceNote class="align_left">(Words repealed <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s.
            3</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">A.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>The
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815500_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The World
            Health
            Organization
            is an organization to which the Diplomatic Privileges Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap190">Cap. 190</ref>) shall apply.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815516_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><content><shortTitle>The World Health Organization</shortTitle> shall have the legal capacities of a body corporate and, except in so far as in any particular case it has expressly waived its immunity, immunity from suit and legal process. No waiver of immunity shall be deemed to extend to any measure of execution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815532_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The World Health Organization shall have the like inviolability of official archives and premises occupied as offices as is accorded in respect of official archives and premises of an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402815532_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>The World Health Organization shall have the like exemption or relief from taxes and rates, other than taxes on the importation of goods, as is accorded to a foreign sovereign power.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815547_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><content>The World Health Organization shall have exemption from taxes on the importation of goods directly imported by the Organization for its official use in Hong Kong or for exportation, or on the importation of any publications of the Organization directly imported by it, such exemption to be subject to compliance with such conditions as the Commissioner of Customs and Excise may prescribe for the protection of the revenue.
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1985/40">40 of 1985 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438402815563_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><content>The World Health Organization shall have exemption from prohibitions and restrictions on importation or exportation in the case of goods directly imported or exported by the Organization for its official use and in the case of any publications of the Organization directly imported or exported by it.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402815563_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><content>The World Health Organization shall have the right to avail itself, for telegraphic communications sent by it and containing only matter intended for publication by the press or for broadcasting (including communications addressed to or dispatched from places outside Hong Kong) of any reduced rates applicable for the corresponding service in the case of press telegrams.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">B.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>Representatives
            of Members
            and
            of
            the<br></br>Executive Board
            of
            the
            World
            Health
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815578_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><subsection id="ID_1438411513433_029" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived,
                in the case of representatives of member Governments, by the member Governments whom
                they represent, representatives of the Governments of Associate Members of the
                Organization and in the case of persons designated to serve on the Executive Board
                of <shortTitle>the World Health Organization</shortTitle> and their alternates and
                advisers, by the Executive Board, representatives of member Governments and persons
                designated to serve on the Executive Board of the Organization and their alternates
                and advisers shall
                        enjoy— <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1956/gna17">G.N.A. 17 of 1956</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411513433_038" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>while exercising their functions as such, and during their journey to and
                    from the place of meeting, immunity from personal arrest or detention and from
                    seizure of their personal baggage and inviolability of all papers and
                    documents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411513448_007" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or
                    written and all acts done by them in their capacity as
                    representatives;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411513448_016" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>while exercising their functions and during their journey to and from the
                    place of meeting, the like exemption or relief from taxes as is accorded to an
                    envoy of a foreign power accredited to the Government of the People’s Republic
                    of China, save that the relief allowed shall not include relief from customs and
                    excise duties except in respect of goods imported as part of their personal
                    baggage. They shall not, where the incidence of any form of taxation depends
                    upon residence, be deemed to be resident in Hong Kong during any period when
                    they are present in Hong Kong whilst exercising their functions or during their
                    journey to and from the place of meeting. The provisions of this paragraph shall
                    not apply to Chinese nationals whose usual place of abode is in Hong Kong.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/80">80 of 1982 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411513480_006" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="RepresentativesOfMemberGovernments,RepresentativesOfTheGovernmentsOfAssociateMembersOfTheOrganization">For the purposes of the application of this Order, the expressions
                    <term>representatives
                    of member
                governments</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">成員政府代表</term>) and
                    <term>representatives
                    of the Governments of Associate Members of the
                Organization</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">該組織附屬成員的政府代表</term>) shall be deemed to include
                their official staffs, accompanying them as such representatives, as delegates,
                deputy delegates, advisers, technical experts or secretaries of delegations.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1956/gna17">G.N.A. 17 of
                    1956</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411513480_014" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The provisions of the preceding paragraphs of this Article shall not confer any
                immunity or privilege upon any person as the representative of the Central People’s
                Government in Hong Kong or as a member of the staff of such a representative or any
                person who is a Chinese national.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1982/80">80 of 1982 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">C.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>High
            Officials</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815594_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><content>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the World Health
            Organization,
            officers of the Organization holding the offices of Director-General or Deputy
            Director-General shall be accorded in respect of themselves, their spouses and children
            under the age of twenty-one, the like immunity from suit and legal process, the like
            inviolability of residence and the like exemption or relief from taxes as is accorded to
            an envoy of a foreign sovereign power accredited to the Government of the People’s
            Republic of China, his spouse and children, and they shall also enjoy exemption from
            income tax in respect of emoluments received by them as officers of
            the World Health
            Organization.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/81">81 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">D.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>Persons Serving
            on Committees
            of
            or Employed
            on<br></br>Missions
            on
            behalf
            of
            the
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815594_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the World Health
            Organization,
            persons (other than officials of the Organization) serving on committees of, or employed
            on missions on behalf of the Organization shall enjoy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411513604_029" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>while exercising their functions as such, and during their journey to and from
                the place of meeting, immunity from personal arrest or detention and from seizure of
                their personal baggage and inviolability of all papers and documents relating to the
                work of the Organization;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411513604_038" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or written
                and all acts done by them in the exercise of their functions. Such immunity shall
                continue notwithstanding that the person concerned is no longer employed on missions
                on behalf of the Organization.</content></paragraph></section><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">E.<inline class="width_6"> </inline>Other Officials
            of
            the
            Organization</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438402815610_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="others" startPeriod="2021-08-26" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><leadIn>Except in so far as in any particular case any privilege or immunity is waived by
            the Organization, all officials of
            the World Health
            Organization,
            (other than those referred to in Article 9 above or officials engaged locally and
            remunerated by payment calculated on the number of hours worked) shall enjoy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411513636_021" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>immunity from suit and legal process in respect of words spoken or written and
                all acts done by them in the course of the performance of their official
                duties;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411513636_030" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>exemption from income tax in respect of emoluments received by them as officers
                and servants of
                the World
                Health
                Organization.</content></paragraph></section></main></subLeg>