<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 16</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>16</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap16!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-06-20</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402758077_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-06-20">
            <content>To make better provision in Hong Kong for the granting by the District Court of
                separation and maintenance orders.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1969/35">35 of 1969 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
            2</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[6 December 1935]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402758092_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Separation and Maintenance Orders Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402758092_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Education"><term>education</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">敎育</term>)
            includes training;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="HabitualDrunkard,DrugAddict"><term>habitual
                drunkard</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">慣性酗酒者</term>) and
                <term>drug
                addict</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">吸毒者</term>) mean a person who is, by reason of habitual
            intemperate drinking of intoxicating liquor, or habitual taking or using, except upon
            and in accordance with medical advice, of opium, or any dangerous drug within the
            meaning of the Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>), at
            times dangerous to himself or herself or to others, or incapable of managing himself or
            herself, and his or her affairs;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf.
                1879 c. 19 s. 3 U.K.; 1925 c. 51 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></def><def name="Husband"><term>husband</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">丈夫</term>) means the husband or partner of a wife or
            married woman;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/28">28 of 1971 s. 19</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="MaintenanceOrder"><leadIn><term>maintenance
                    order</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">贍養令</term>) means an order made—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423124_005" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>under <ref>section 5(1)(c)</ref> or (d) or 9(1) for periodical payments; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423124_013" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>under <ref>section 5(1)(c)</ref> or (d) for payment of a lump sum;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2003/18">18 of 2003 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def><def name="MarriedPerson"><term>married
                person</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已婚人士</term>) means a husband or a wife;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s.
                    9</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="OtherPartyToTheMarriage"><term>other
                party to the
            marriage</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">婚姻的另一方</term>) means, in relation to a husband or a
            wife, the wife or husband of that person;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s.
                9</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Wife,MarriedWoman"><leadIn><term>wife</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">妻子</term>) and
                    <term>married
                    woman</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已婚女子</term>) mean the wife or partner of a man
                by—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423124_041" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a marriage celebrated or contracted in accordance with the provisions of the Marriage Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap181">Cap. 181</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423124_049" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a modern marriage validated by the Marriage Reform Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap178">Cap. 178</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423124_057" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a customary marriage declared to be valid by the Marriage Reform Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap178">Cap. 178</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423124_065" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a union of concubinage as defined by <ref>section 14</ref> of the Legitimacy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap184">Cap. 184</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423124_073" name="e" temporalId="s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a kim tiu marriage entered in accordance with Chinese law and custom applicable thereto in Hong Kong before the appointed day under the Marriage Reform Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap178">Cap. 178</ref>); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423140_006" name="f" temporalId="s2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>a marriage celebrated or contracted outside Hong Kong in accordance with the law in force at the time and in the place where the marriage was performed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/28">28 of 1971 s. 19</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def></section><section id="ID_1438402758108_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Grounds on which an application for a
            section
            5 order may be made</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423171_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a married person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423171_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has been convicted summarily of an assault upon the other party to the
                    marriage which in the opinion of the convicting magistrate is of an aggravated
                    character;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423171_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has been convicted whether on indictment or summarily of an assault upon
                    the other party to the marriage, and sentenced to pay a fine of more than $500
                    or to a term of imprisonment exceeding 2 months;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423171_028" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>has deserted the other party to the marriage;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423171_036" name="d" temporalId="s3_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>has been guilty of persistent cruelty to the other party to the marriage or
                    that party’s children;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423171_044" name="e" temporalId="s3_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>has failed to provide reasonable maintenance for the other party to the
                    marriage or reasonable maintenance and education for that party’s children whom
                    the married person is legally liable to maintain;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423187_006" name="f" temporalId="s3_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>has, while suffering from a venereal disease, and knowing that he or she
                    was so suffering, insisted on having sexual intercourse with the other party to
                    the marriage;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423187_014" name="g" temporalId="s3_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>has compelled the other party to the marriage to submit to
                    prostitution;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423187_022" name="h" temporalId="s3_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>is a habitual drunkard, or a drug addict,</content></paragraph><continued>that other party may apply to the District Court for an order under this
                Ordinance.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423187_035" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purpose of subsection <ref>(1)(g)</ref>, where a married person has, in
                the opinion of the District Court, been guilty of such conduct as was likely to
                result and has resulted in the other party to the marriage submitting to
                prostitution, that person shall be deemed to have compelled the other party to the
                marriage so to submit.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758123_002" name="s4" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-07-04" status="repealed" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758139_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Powers of District Court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423233_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>On any application under <ref>section 3</ref>, the District Court may make an order containing all or any of the following provisions—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423249_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the applicant be no longer bound to cohabit with the other party to the marriage (which provision while in force shall have the effect of a decree of judicial separation on the ground of cruelty);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423249_013" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the legal custody of any children of the marriage be committed to the husband, or to the wife, until such children attain the age of 18 years;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423249_021" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that the husband or wife shall pay to the other party to the marriage, or to the Registrar of the District Court or any third person on such other party’s behalf, such lump sum (whether in one amount or by instalments) or periodical payments or both as the court, having regard to the means of both of the parties to the marriage, considers reasonable, and an order under this paragraph for the payment of a lump sum may be made for the purpose of enabling any liabilities or expenses reasonably incurred in maintaining such other party before the making of the order to be met;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423265_006" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that the husband or wife shall pay to the other party to the marriage, or to the said Registrar or any third person on such other party’s behalf, such lump sum (whether in one amount or by instalments) or periodical payments or both as the court considers reasonable, having regard to the means of both of the parties to the marriage, for the maintenance and education of each child of the marriage committed to such other party’s custody under paragraph (b);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423280_006" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a provision for payment by the husband or the wife, or both of them, of such reasonable costs of the parties or either of them as the court may think fit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423280_013" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An order under subsection <ref>(1)(d)</ref> directing a lump sum payment for the maintenance and education of a child of the marriage shall only be made for the purpose of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423280_021" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>providing for the immediate and non-recurring needs of the child; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423280_029" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enabling any liabilities or expenses reasonably incurred in maintaining or educating the child before the making of the order to be met,</content></paragraph><continued>or for both such purposes.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423280_042" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In making an order under subsection (1), the court shall have regard primarily to the best interests of the children.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758155_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Limitation of powers of District Court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423327_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>No order shall be made under this Ordinance if it is proved that the applicant has committed an act of adultery:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_1_proviso">Provided that the husband or, as the case may be, the wife, of the applicant has not condoned, or connived at, or by his or her wilful neglect or misconduct conduced to such act of adultery.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423327_018" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No order made under this Ordinance shall be enforceable and no liability shall accrue under any such order whilst the married woman, and her husband, with respect to whom the order was made, reside together, and any such order shall cease to have effect if for a period of 3 months after it is made the married woman and her husband continue to reside together.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1895 c. 39 s. 6 U.K.; 1925 c. 51 s. 1(4) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402758155_003" name="s6A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6A"><num value="6A">6A.</num><heading>Condonation</heading><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, adultery and cruelty shall not be deemed to have been condoned by reason only of a continuation or resumption of cohabitation between the parties for one period not exceeding 3 months, or of any thing done during such cohabitation, if it is proved that cohabitation has continued or resumed, as the case may be, with a view to effecting a reconciliation.</content><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1972/33">33 of 1972 s. 25</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1965 c. 72 s. 42(2) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758170_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>District Court may vary or discharge order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423374_025" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The District Court may on the application of the husband or the wife, and upon cause being shown on fresh evidence, at any time alter, vary, discharge, suspend or revive after being so suspended any order (other than an order for a lump sum payment in one amount or for a lump sum to be paid in instalments where all such instalments have been paid) made under this Ordinance, and may from time to time increase or diminish the amount of any unpaid instalment of a lump sum payment or periodical payments or both ordered to be paid under <ref>section 5</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423389_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The jurisdiction conferred by subsection (1) shall be exercisable notwithstanding that the proceedings for the revocation, variation, discharge or suspension of the order or the revival of an order which has been suspended are brought by or against a person residing outside Hong Kong.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423405_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subsection (4), if any married person who has applied for an order and with respect to whom an order has been made under this Ordinance voluntarily resumes cohabitation with the other party to the marriage, or commits an act of adultery, such order shall upon proof of such matter be discharged.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423405_013" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The District Court may, if it thinks fit—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423405_021" name="a" temporalId="s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>refuse to discharge an order under this Ordinance as provided in subsection
                    (3) if in its opinion the act of adultery was conduced to by the failure of the
                    other party to the marriage to make such payments as in the opinion of the court
                    he or she was able to make under the order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423405_029" name="b" temporalId="s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the event of an order being discharged as provided in subsection (3),
                    make a new order ordering that the legal custody of the children of the marriage
                    shall continue to be committed to the married person mentioned in subsection (3)
                    until such children attain the age of 18 years, and that the other party to the
                    marriage shall pay to that married person, or to the Registrar of the District
                    Court or any third person on the married person’s behalf, either or both of the
                    following—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423421_006" name="i" temporalId="s7_4_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><leadIn>such lump sum (whether in one amount or by instalments) for—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423421_013" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s7_4_b_i_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>the immediate and non-recurring needs of the child; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423421_021" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s7_4_b_i_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>the purpose of enabling any liabilities or expenses reasonably
                            incurred in maintaining and educating the child before the making of the
                            order to be met,</content></subparagraph><continued>or for both, as the court considers reasonable, having regard to the
                        means of both the husband and the wife and to any payment previously made
                        under any order for a lump sum payment;</continued></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423421_034" name="ii" temporalId="s7_4_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>such periodical payments as the court considers reasonable having
                        regard to the means of both the husband and the wife for the maintenance and
                        education of the child until that child attains the age of 18
                        years.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423421_041" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In making an order under subsection <ref>(4)(b)</ref> the court shall have regard primarily to the best interests of the children.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 12</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758186_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>District Court may refuse an order in
            cases
            more fit for the Court of First Instance</heading><leadIn>If in the opinion of the District Court the matters in question between the parties
            or any of them would be more conveniently dealt with by the Court of First Instance, the
            District Court may refuse to make an order under this Ordinance, and in such case,
            without prejudice to the general right of appeal conferred by <ref>Part 4</ref> of the
            District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>), no appeal shall lie
            from the decision of the District Court:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s8_proviso">Provided that the Court of First Instance
            shall have power by order in any proceeding in the Court of First Instance relating to
            or comprising the same subject matter as the application so refused as aforesaid, or any
            part thereof, to direct the District Court to rehear and determine the same.</proviso><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1969/35">35 of 1969 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2013</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1895 c. 39 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758201_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Power to order interim payments where application for maintenance is adjourned</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423483_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), where, on the hearing of an application for an order under this Ordinance for maintenance or for maintenance and education, the application is adjourned for a period exceeding 1 week, the District Court may order the respondent to pay to the applicant or to the Registrar of the District Court or any third person on the applicant’s behalf such periodical payments as the court considers reasonable for the maintenance of the applicant and the maintenance and education of any child or children in the applicant’s custody until the final determination of the application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423499_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An order under this section shall operate for not more than 3 months from the date on which it is made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423499_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An order under this section shall be enforceable in like manner as if it were a final order of the District Court.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 13</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758217_001" name="s9A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9A"><num value="9A">9A.</num><heading>Attachment of income to satisfy order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423514_034" name="1AA" temporalId="s9A_1AA"><num value="1AA">(1AA)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="AmendmentOrdinance"><term>Amendment
                                        Ordinance</term>
                                        (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">修訂條例</term>》) means the
                                Attachment of Income Order (Application to Government and
                                Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 2007 (<ref href="/hk/2007/20">20
                                        of 2007</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20 of
                                                2007 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="AttachmentOrder"><term>attachment
                                        order</term>
                                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">扣押令</term>) means an order made
                                under subsection (1);</def><def name="DesignatedPayee"><term>designated
                                        payee</term>
                                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指定受款人</term>) means, in
                                relation to a maintenance order, the person named in that order as
                                the person to whom the maintenance payments are to be made;</def><def name="IncomeSource"><term>income
                                        source</term>
                                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">入息來源</term>) means a person by
                                whom the income of the maintenance payer is payable and includes the
                                        Government;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20 of
                                                2007 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="MaintenancePayer"><term>maintenance
                                        payer</term>
                                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">贍養費支付人</term>) means, in
                                relation to a maintenance order, the person against whom that order
                                is made;</def><def name="SpecifiedPayee"><term>specified
                                        payee</term>
                                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明受款人</term>) means, in
                                relation to an attachment order, the person named in that order as
                                the person to whom an amount attached by that order is to be
                                paid.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2001/20">20 of 2001 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2003/18">18 of 2003 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438411423530_046" name="1" temporalId="s9A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a maintenance order has been made against a maintenance payer
                                and—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423530_054" name="a" temporalId="s9A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423530_057" name="i" temporalId="s9A_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a court is satisfied that the payer has without
                                                reasonable excuse failed to make any payment which
                                                he is required to make by the maintenance order;
                                                or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423530_064" name="ii" temporalId="s9A_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a court is satisfied that there are reasonable
                                                grounds to believe that the payer will not make full
                                                and punctual payment in compliance with the
                                                maintenance order; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423530_072" name="iii" temporalId="s9A_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the payer and designated payee agree to the making
                                                of an order under this section; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423530_079" name="b" temporalId="s9A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>there is any income capable of being attached payable to
                                        the payer,</content></paragraph><continued>the court may, in accordance with rules made under subsection
                                (6), order the income to be attached as to the whole or part of the
                                amount payable under the maintenance order and the amount attached
                                to be paid to the specified payee.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2001/20">20
                                                of 2001 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423545_011" name="1A" temporalId="s9A_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><leadIn>For the purpose of subsection <ref>(1)(a)(ii)</ref>, in deciding
                                whether there are reasonable grounds to believe that the maintenance
                                payer will not make full and punctual payment in compliance with the
                                maintenance order, the court shall take into account all the
                                circumstances of the case, including (but not limited to)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423545_019" name="a" temporalId="s9A_1A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the payer’s past record and conduct in discharging his
                                        reasonable financial obligation towards the designated payee
                                        before any maintenance order is made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423545_027" name="b" temporalId="s9A_1A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the payer’s past record and conduct in connection with the
                                        making of maintenance payments to the payee pursuant to the
                                        maintenance order or an undertaking in any proceedings;
                                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423545_035" name="c" temporalId="s9A_1A_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the risk of the payer dissipating his property.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2001/20">20 of 2001 s.
                                                3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423545_042" name="2" temporalId="s9A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2001/20">20 of 2001 s.
                                3</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423545_050" name="2A" temporalId="s9A_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><content>The court may, at any time after a maintenance order has been made,
                                including in the same hearing in which the maintenance order is made
                                or varied, make an attachment order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2001/20">20 of
                                                2001 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423561_005" name="2B" temporalId="s9A_2B"><num value="2B">(2B)</num><content>An attachment order may be made by the court on its own motion or
                                on the application by the maintenance payer or the designated payee
                                or both.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2001/20">20 of 2001 s.
                                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423561_013" name="3" temporalId="s9A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An attachment order is an authority to an income source to make the
                                payment in accordance with the order, and the receipt of the
                                specified payee is a good discharge to that income source.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20 of 2007 s.
                                        5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423561_021" name="3A" temporalId="s9A_3A"><num value="3A">(3A)</num><content>Without limiting the generality of subsection (1), that subsection
                                applies to income that is wages or salary payable to a maintenance
                                payer by the Government, and accordingly paragraph (a) of the
                                proviso to <ref>section 23(1)</ref> of the Crown Proceedings
                                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap300">Cap. 300</ref>) is not to be
                                construed as precluding the court from making an attachment order in
                                respect of such wages or salary.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20 of
                                                2007 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423577_005" name="4" temporalId="s9A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Without limiting the generality of subsection (1), that subsection
                                applies to income that is wages payable to a maintenance payer by a
                                person other than the Government, and accordingly <ref>section
                                        66</ref> of the Employment Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap57">Cap. 57</ref>) is not to be construed as precluding the
                                court from making an attachment order in respect of such
                                        wages.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20
                                                of 2007 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423577_013" name="5" temporalId="s9A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423577_021" name="a" temporalId="s9A_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>pursuant to an attachment order, an employer is required to
                                        make a deduction from the wages of his employee in any wage
                                        period; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423577_029" name="b" temporalId="s9A_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that deduction, together with any deduction authorized to
                                        be made under <ref>section 32</ref> of the Employment
                                        Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap57">Cap. 57</ref>) by the
                                        employer from the employee’s wages in the same wage period
                                        would in total exceed the whole of the wages payable to the
                                        employee in respect of that wage period,</content></paragraph><continued>then the amount liable to be deducted by the employer pursuant to
                                the attachment order shall be treated as being reduced by such an
                                amount that the total of all deductions made by the employer does
                                not exceed the whole of the wages payable to the employee in respect
                                of the wage period.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423592_011" name="6" temporalId="s9A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>The Chief Justice may make such rules of court as he considers
                                necessary or expedient for the purpose of giving effect to
                                subsection (1), and rules made under this subsection may in
                                particular provide for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423592_019" name="a" temporalId="s9A_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the matters to be contained in any application for an
                                        attachment order, and the manner of filing and service of
                                        such an application;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423592_027" name="b" temporalId="s9A_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>compliance with an attachment order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423592_035" name="c" temporalId="s9A_6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the obligations on the part of the income source;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20 of 2007 s.
                                                5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423592_043" name="d" temporalId="s9A_6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the obligations of the maintenance payer when an attachment
                                        order is in force or in the event of an attachment order
                                        ceasing to have effect for any reason;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423608_006" name="e" temporalId="s9A_6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the recovery
                                        from
                                        the maintenance payer of the clerical and administrative
                                        costs incurred in complying with an attachment
                                        order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423608_014" name="f" temporalId="s9A_6_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the variation or discharge of an attachment
                                        order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423608_022" name="g" temporalId="s9A_6_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the enforcement of an attachment order.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423608_029" name="6A" temporalId="s9A_6A"><num value="6A">(6A)</num><content>Rules made under subsection (6) may empower the court to dispense
                                with or relax any procedure or abridge any time limit specified in
                                the rules if the court is satisfied that it is fair and reasonable
                                to do so in the circumstances of the case.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2001/20">20 of
                                                2001 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423608_037" name="7" temporalId="s9A_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Rules made under subsection (6) may provide that the contravention
                                of any rule shall constitute an offence punishable by a fine at
                                level 2 and by imprisonment for 1 month.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423608_045" name="8" temporalId="s9A_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Chief Justice may specify the form of any document which is to
                                be or may be filed in proceedings under subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423608_053" name="9" temporalId="s9A_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>Any attachment order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423608_061" name="a" temporalId="s9A_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>made by the court before the commencement date* of the
                                        Amendment Ordinance in respect of the wages or salary
                                        payable to a maintenance payer by the Government;
                                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423623_006" name="b" temporalId="s9A_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>which has not been discharged or declared invalid by the
                                        court as at that commencement date,</content></paragraph><continued>has effect from that commencement date as if it were made under
                                subsection (1) as read with subsection (3A).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20 of
                                                2007 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423623_019" name="10" temporalId="s9A_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><leadIn>An application—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423623_027" name="a" temporalId="s9A_10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for an attachment order in respect of the wages or salary
                                        payable to a maintenance payer by the Government;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423623_035" name="b" temporalId="s9A_10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that is pending immediately before the commencement date*
                                        of the Amendment Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423623_043" name="c" temporalId="s9A_10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in which an attachment order has not been made as at that
                                        commencement date,</content></paragraph><continued>is to be determined in accordance with this section as amended by
                                the Amendment Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2007/20">20 of
                                                2007 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 14</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1556161713358_001">
                        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
                        <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>
                                Commencement date: 23 November 2007.</content>
                </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758248_001" name="s9B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9B"><num value="9B">9B.</num><heading>Interest on arrears of maintenance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423701_004" name="1" temporalId="s9B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this section and <ref>section 9C</ref>—</leadIn><def name="CommencementDate">*<term>commencement
                    date</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">生效日期</term>) means the date on which the Interest
                and Surcharge on Arrears of Maintenance Ordinance 2003 (<ref href="/hk/2003/18">18
                    of 2003</ref>) comes into operation;</def><def name="JudgmentCreditor"><term>judgment
                    creditor</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">判定債權人</term>) means a person entitled to enforce a
                maintenance order;</def><def name="JudgmentDebtor"><term>judgment
                    debtor</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">判定債務人</term>) means a person liable under a
                maintenance order.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423701_032" name="2" temporalId="s9B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a maintenance order has been made against a judgment debtor, and the judgment debtor fails to make full and punctual payment in compliance with the maintenance order, the judgment creditor is entitled to interest in respect of arrears of maintenance which accrue on or after the commencement date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423717_005" name="3" temporalId="s9B_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (2)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423717_013" name="a" temporalId="s9B_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the arrears in respect of each periodical payment or payment of a lump sum, as the case may be, under a maintenance order shall be treated as a judgment debt for the purposes of <ref>section 50</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423717_021" name="b" temporalId="s9B_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the interest under subsection (2) shall be calculated in accordance with that <ref>section 50</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423717_029" name="c" temporalId="s9B_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>for the purposes of that <ref>section 50</ref>, the date on which payment is due as specified by the maintenance order shall be treated as the date of the judgment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423717_036" name="4" temporalId="s9B_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The judgment debtor is liable to pay the interest under subsection (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423717_044" name="5" temporalId="s9B_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>If any payment under a maintenance order is not paid and interest in respect of the arrears has accrued under subsection (2), and subsequently the judgment debtor makes payment, the payment is deemed to be made in the following order in or towards the discharge of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423733_005" name="a" temporalId="s9B_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>interest accrued under subsection (2);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423733_013" name="b" temporalId="s9B_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>surcharge payable under <ref>section 9C</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423733_021" name="c" temporalId="s9B_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if there are any proceedings instituted for enforcing the maintenance order, the costs ordered by the court to be paid under those proceedings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423733_029" name="d" temporalId="s9B_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any sums from time to time falling due under the maintenance order, with the sums discharged in the reversed chronological sequence of the dates on which payment is due (that is, the most recent arrears will be discharged first);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423733_037" name="e" temporalId="s9B_5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>if the court makes an order in any proceedings instituted for enforcing the maintenance order, the amount of the maintenance in arrears, whether in one amount or by instalments, payable by the judgment debtor under the order.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423733_044" name="6" temporalId="s9B_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A judgment debtor who considers that he has reasonable grounds not to pay the interest under subsection (2) may, within a reasonable time after having knowledge of the requirement to pay, apply by summons to the court not to pay the interest, and shall set out the grounds in the application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423748_005" name="7" temporalId="s9B_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>If an application is made under subsection (6), in deciding whether to require the judgment debtor to pay interest and, if so, the amount of interest, the court shall take into account all the circumstances of the case, including (but not limited to) the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423748_013" name="a" temporalId="s9B_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>whether the judgment debtor has a reasonable excuse for his failure to comply with the maintenance order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423748_021" name="b" temporalId="s9B_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>whether the judgment debtor has evaded service of court documents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423748_029" name="c" temporalId="s9B_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the judgment debtor’s past record and conduct in connection with the making of maintenance payments to the judgment creditor pursuant to the maintenance order or an undertaking in any proceedings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423748_037" name="d" temporalId="s9B_7_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>whether the judgment debtor has given the judgment creditor a reasonable explanation for his failure to comply with the maintenance order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423748_045" name="e" temporalId="s9B_7_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the judgment debtor’s ability to pay.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423748_052" name="8" temporalId="s9B_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>A judgment debtor who is aggrieved by a requirement under subsection (7) to pay interest may appeal to the Court of Appeal against the decision under <ref>section 63</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2003/18">18 of 2003 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1556165572402_001"><content>Editorial Note:</content><content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>
                                                  Commencement
                                                  date : 1 May
                                                  2005.</content></editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758264_002" name="s9C" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9C"><num value="9C">9C.</num><heading>Surcharge on arrears of maintenance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423811_004" name="1" temporalId="s9C_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a maintenance order has been made against a judgment debtor, and the judgment debtor, without reasonable excuse, repeatedly fails to make full and punctual payment in compliance with the maintenance order, the court may, on application made by the judgment creditor, make an order requiring the judgment debtor to pay to the judgment creditor a surcharge in respect of the total arrears of maintenance which accrue on or after the commencement date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423811_012" name="2" temporalId="s9C_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The application for a surcharge under subsection (1) may be made—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423811_020" name="a" temporalId="s9C_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in proceedings instituted for enforcing the maintenance order; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423811_028" name="b" temporalId="s9C_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in a manner described in subsections (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8) and (9).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423811_035" name="3" temporalId="s9C_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref>, the application for a surcharge shall be made by a summons supported by an affidavit of the judgment creditor stating—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423826_005" name="a" temporalId="s9C_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the name of the judgment creditor and the address for service of the documents relating to the application;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423826_013" name="b" temporalId="s9C_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the name and the address for service or last known address of the judgment debtor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423826_021" name="c" temporalId="s9C_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the particulars of the maintenance order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423826_029" name="d" temporalId="s9C_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the total arrears of maintenance due and unpaid and the date on which the arrears first accrued;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423826_037" name="e" temporalId="s9C_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a request for an order requiring the judgment debtor to pay surcharge at a rate to be decided by the court under subsection (11);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423826_045" name="f" temporalId="s9C_3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>a request for fixing a date, time and place for the hearing of the application;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423826_053" name="g" temporalId="s9C_3_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>a request for an order requiring the judgment debtor to pay to the judgment creditor the surcharge claimed if the judgment debtor does not appear at the hearing.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423826_060" name="4" temporalId="s9C_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>On receipt of the summons and affidavit, the court shall fix a date, time and place for the hearing of the application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423826_068" name="5" temporalId="s9C_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The judgment creditor shall serve a sealed copy of the summons and a copy of the affidavit, together with a notice of the hearing, on the judgment debtor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423842_005" name="6" temporalId="s9C_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to any enactment relating to the service of documents and save as is otherwise expressly provided, the summons, affidavit and notice may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423842_013" name="a" temporalId="s9C_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>be personally served on the judgment debtor; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423842_021" name="b" temporalId="s9C_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>be sent—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423842_029" name="i" temporalId="s9C_6_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the judgment debtor is represented, by post to the solicitor acting for that judgment debtor, or by leaving the same with the solicitor; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411423842_037" name="ii" temporalId="s9C_6_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the judgment debtor is unrepresented, by post to the address for service given by him or his last known address, or by leaving the same at the address for service or the last known address of that judgment debtor; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423842_044" name="c" temporalId="s9C_6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>be served in such other manner as the court directs.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423842_051" name="7" temporalId="s9C_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>If the judgment debtor fails to appear at the hearing of the application on the date fixed under subsection (4), then—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423842_059" name="a" temporalId="s9C_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the court is satisfied that the summons, affidavit and notice have been duly served on the judgment debtor, it may proceed to hear the application and may make an order requiring the judgment debtor to pay a surcharge to the judgment creditor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423857_006" name="b" temporalId="s9C_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the court is not satisfied that the summons, affidavit and notice have been duly served on the judgment debtor, it may adjourn the hearing to a date, time and place as it thinks fit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423857_013" name="8" temporalId="s9C_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The judgment creditor shall serve a notice of the adjourned hearing on the judgment debtor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423857_021" name="9" temporalId="s9C_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>If the judgment debtor fails to appear at the adjourned hearing on the date fixed under subsection <ref>(7)(b)</ref>, the court may proceed to hear the application and may make an order requiring the judgment debtor to pay a surcharge to the judgment creditor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423857_029" name="10" temporalId="s9C_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><leadIn>If the judgment debtor, within a reasonable time after having knowledge of the order made under subsection <ref>(7)(a)</ref> or (9), applies by summons to vary or set aside the order, the court may, if it is satisfied that there is reasonable excuse for the judgment debtor’s failure to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423857_037" name="a" temporalId="s9C_10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>appear at the hearing; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423857_045" name="b" temporalId="s9C_10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>make full and punctual payment in compliance with the maintenance order,</content></paragraph><continued>vary or set aside the order on such terms as it thinks fit.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423857_058" name="11" temporalId="s9C_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>The amount of surcharge payable by the judgment debtor under subsection (1) shall not exceed 100% of the total arrears of maintenance calculated from the date on which the arrears first accrued to the date of payment of the surcharge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423873_005" name="12" temporalId="s9C_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>If the court makes an order requiring the judgment debtor to pay a surcharge, it shall specify in the order the amount of surcharge payable by the judgment debtor and the date of payment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423873_013" name="13" temporalId="s9C_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>A surcharge payable under this section is recoverable as a civil debt due to the judgment creditor by the judgment debtor. An action under this subsection may be brought in the District Court even though the amount to be recovered otherwise exceeds the limit of jurisdiction of the District Court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423873_021" name="14" temporalId="s9C_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content>A judgment debtor who is aggrieved by an order to pay a surcharge may appeal to the Court of Appeal against the order under <ref>section 63</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2003/18">18 of 2003 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758279_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Notice of change of address</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423935_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person for the time being under an obligation to make payments, including costs, under an order under this Ordinance shall within 14 days of any change of his address give notice of his new address to any person whose name is specified in the order by sending it by registered post to the last known address of that person or to such address as may be notified to him by that person for the purposes of this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423951_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, contravenes subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 2.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 15</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758279_004" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Procedure</heading><content>Except as otherwise expressly provided in this Ordinance, all applications under this Ordinance shall be made and be dealt with and all orders be enforced in accordance with <ref>Part 4</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>).</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1969/35">35 of 1969 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758295_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Provisions as to powers of court to make orders in favour of children and duration of such orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411423982_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), the term for which by virtue of an order under <ref>section 5(1)(d)</ref> or <ref>9</ref> any payments are to be made for the benefit of a child may begin with the date of the making of an application for the order in question or any later date but shall not extend beyond the date when the child will attain the age of 18.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423982_012" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The court may include in an order referred to in subsection (1) in relation to a child who has not attained the age of 18 a provision extending beyond the date when the child will attain that age the term for which by virtue of the order any payments are to be made for the benefit of that child, if it appears to the court that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411423982_020" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that child is, or will be, or if such an order or provision were made would be, receiving instruction at an educational establishment or undergoing training for a trade, profession or vocation, whether or not he is also, or will also be, in gainful employment; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411423998_006" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>there are special circumstances which justify the making of the order or provisions.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411423998_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any order for periodical payments made by virtue of <ref>section 5(1)(d)</ref> or <ref>7(4)(b)(ii)</ref> shall, regardless of anything in the order, cease to have effect on the death of the person liable to make payments under the order, except in relation to any arrears due under the order on the date of such death.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 17</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402758311_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411424029_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The amendments to <ref>sections 2</ref>, <ref>3</ref>, <ref>4</ref>,
                    <ref>5</ref>, <ref>7</ref>, <ref>9</ref> and <ref>10</ref> of this Ordinance
                made by <ref>sections 9</ref>, <ref>10</ref>, <ref>11</ref>, <ref>12</ref>,
                    <ref>13</ref> and <ref>15</ref> of the Marriage and Children (Miscellaneous
                Amendments) Ordinance 1997 (<ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997</ref>)
                        (<b><i>the
                        amending
                Ordinance</i></b>)
                do not apply in relation to orders made before the commencement of the amending
                Ordinance, and the provisions of this Ordinance in force immediately before the
                commencement of the amending Ordinance continue to apply in relation to those orders
                as if the amending Ordinance had not been enacted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411424045_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The amendment adding <ref>section 9A</ref>, and the amendments to <ref>section 12</ref>, of this Ordinance made by <ref>sections 14</ref> and <ref>17</ref> of the amending Ordinance apply in relation to orders made before the commencement of the amending Ordinance as they apply in relation to orders made after that commencement, but where an order made before that commencement provides for payments to be made in respect of a child beyond the date when the child will attain the age of 18, nothing in this subsection shall be construed as affecting the term of such order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411424060_005" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Section 12(2)</ref> of this Ordinance (as substituted by <ref>section 17</ref> of the amending Ordinance) applies in relation to a child who at the commencement of the amending Ordinance has attained the age of 18 as if reference in that subsection to the age of 18 was a reference to the age of 21.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/69">69 of 1997 s. 18</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>