<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 48</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>48</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap48!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-04-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403244127_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-04-11">
            <content>To consolidate and amend the law relating to factors.</content>
        </longTitle><referenceNote>[cf. 1889 c. 45
            U.K.]</referenceNote><commencementNote>[1 July 1896]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="add-toc">Preliminary</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403244127_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Factors
            Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1924/5">5 of 1924 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403244142_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412653140_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="DocumentOfTitle"><term>document
                    of
                title</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">所有權文件</term>) includes any bill of lading, dock
                warrant, warehouse keeper’s certificate, and warrant or order for the delivery of
                goods, and any other document used in the ordinary course of business as proof of
                the possession or control of goods, or authorizing or purporting to authorize,
                either by indorsement or by delivery, the possessor of the document to transfer or
                receive goods thereby represented;</def><def name="Goods"><term>goods</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">貨品</term>) includes wares and merchandise;</def><def name="MercantileAgent"><term>mercantile
                    agent</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">商業代理人</term>) means a mercantile agent having, in
                the customary course of his business as such agent, authority either to sell goods,
                or to consign goods for the purpose of sale, or to buy goods, or to raise money on
                the security of goods;</def><def name="Person"><term>person</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">人</term>) includes any body of persons corporate or
                unincorporate;</def><def name="Pledge"><term>pledge</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">質押</term>) includes any contract pledging, or
                giving a lien or security on goods, whether in consideration of an original advance,
                or of any further or continuing advance, or of any pecuniary liability.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412653155_039" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, a person shall be deemed to be in possession of goods or of the documents of title to goods, where the goods or documents are in his actual custody or are held by any other person subject to his control, or for him, or on his behalf.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Dispositions by
        Mercantile
        Agents</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403244158_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Powers of mercantile agent with respect to disposition of goods</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412653186_018" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Where a mercantile agent is, with the consent of the owner, in possession of
                    goods or of the documents of title to goods, any sale, pledge, or other
                    disposition of the goods, made by him when acting in the ordinary course of
                    business of a mercantile agent, shall, subject to the provisions of this
                    Ordinance, be as valid as if he were expressly authorized by the owner of the
                    goods to make the same:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s3_1_proviso">Provided that the person taking
                    under the disposition acts in good faith, and has not, at the time of the
                    disposition,
                    noticed
                    that the person making the disposition has
                    no
                    authority to make the same.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412653186_032" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Where a mercantile agent has, with the consent of the owner, been in
                    possession of goods or of the documents of title to goods, any sale, pledge, or
                    other disposition, which would have been valid if the consent had continued,
                    shall be valid notwithstanding the determination of the consent:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s3_2_proviso">Provided that the person taking
                    under the disposition has not, at the time thereof,
                    noticed
                    that the consent has been determined.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412653202_011" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a mercantile agent has obtained possession of any documents of title to
                goods by reason of his being or having been, with the consent of the owner, in
                possession of the goods represented thereby, or of any other documents of title to
                the goods, his possession of the first-mentioned documents shall, for the purposes
                of this Ordinance, be deemed to be with the consent of the owner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412653202_019" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, the consent of the owner shall be presumed
                in the absence of evidence to the contrary.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403244174_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Pledge of documents of title</heading><content>A pledge of the documents of title to goods shall be deemed to be a pledge of the goods.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403244174_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Pledge for antecedent debt</heading><content>Where a mercantile agent pledges goods as security for a debt or liability due from the pledgor to the pledgee before the time of the pledge, the pledgee shall acquire no further right to the goods than could have been enforced by the pledgor at the time of the pledge.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403244189_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Rights acquired by exchange of goods or documents</heading><content>The consideration necessary for the validity of a sale, pledge, or other disposition of goods, in pursuance of this Ordinance, may be either a payment in cash, or the delivery or transfer of other goods, or of a document of title to goods, or of a negotiable security, or any other valuable consideration; but where goods are pledged by a mercantile agent in consideration of the delivery or transfer of other goods, or of a document of title to goods, or of a negotiable security, the pledgee shall acquire no right or interest in the goods so pledged in excess of the value of the goods, document, or security when so delivered or transferred in exchange.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403244189_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Agreement through clerk, etc.</heading><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, an agreement made with a mercantile agent through a clerk or other person authorized in the ordinary course of business to make contracts of sale or pledge on his behalf shall be deemed to be an agreement with the agent.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403244205_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Provisions as to consignor and consignee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412653280_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the owner of goods has given possession of the goods to another person for the purpose of consignment or sale, or has shipped the goods in the name of another person, and the consignee of the goods has not had notice that such person is not the owner of the goods, the consignee shall, in respect of advances made to or for the use of such person, have the same lien on the goods as if such person were the owner of the goods, and may transfer any such lien to another person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412653296_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall limit or affect the validity of any sale, pledge, or disposition by a mercantile agent.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Dispositions by
        Sellers and Buyers of
        Goods</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403244220_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Disposition by seller remaining in possession</heading><content>Where a person, having sold goods, continues, or is, in possession of the goods or
            of the documents of title to the goods, the delivery or transfer by that person, or by a
            mercantile agent acting for him, of the goods or documents of title under any sale,
            pledge, or other disposition thereof, or under any agreement for sale, pledge, or other
            disposition thereof, to any person receiving the same in good faith and without notice
            of the previous sale, shall have the same effect as if the person making the delivery or
            transfer were expressly authorized by the owner of the goods to make the same.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403244220_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Disposition by buyer obtaining possession</heading><content>Where a person, having bought or agreed to buy goods, obtains, with the consent of the seller, possession of the goods or the documents of title to the goods, the delivery or transfer, by that person or by a mercantile agent acting for him, of the goods or documents of title, under any sale, pledge, or other disposition thereof, or under any agreement for sale, pledge, or other disposition thereof, to any person receiving the same in good faith and without notice of any lien or other right of the original seller in respect of the goods, shall have the same effect as if the person making the delivery or transfer were a mercantile agent in possession of the goods or documents of title with the consent of the owner.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403244236_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Effect of transfer of document of title on vendor’s lien or right of stoppage in transitu</heading><content>Where a document of title to goods has been lawfully transferred to a person as a buyer or owner of the goods, and that person transfers the document to a person who takes the document in good faith and for valuable consideration, the last-mentioned transfer shall have the same effect for defeating any vendor’s lien or right of stoppage in transitu as the transfer of a bill of lading has for defeating the right of stoppage in transitu.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Supplementary</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403244236_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Mode of transferring document</heading><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, the transfer of a document may be by
            indorsement, or, where the document is by custom or by its express terms transferable by
            delivery or makes the goods deliverable to the bearer, then by delivery.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403244252_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Saving for rights of true owner</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412653389_018" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall authorize an agent to exceed or depart from his authority as between himself and his principal, or exempt him from any liability, civil or criminal, for so doing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412653389_026" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall prevent the owner of goods from recovering the goods from an agent or his trustee in bankruptcy at any time before the sale or pledge thereof, or shall prevent the owner of goods pledged by an agent from having the right to redeem the goods at any time before the sale thereof, on satisfying the claim for which the goods were pledged, and paying to the agent, if by him required, any money in respect of which the agent would by law be entitled to retain the goods, or the documents of title thereto, or any of them, by way of lien as against the owner, or from recovering from any person with whom the goods have been pledged any balance of money remaining in his hands as the produce of the sale of the goods after deducting the amount of his lien.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412653420_005" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall prevent the owner of goods sold by an agent from recovering from the buyer the price agreed to be paid for the same, or any part of that price, subject to any right of set-off on the part of the buyer against the agent.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403244267_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Saving of common law powers of agent</heading><content>The provisions of this Ordinance shall be construed in amplification and not in
            derogation of the powers exercisable by an agent independently of this
            Ordinance.</content></section></main></ordinance>