<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 63</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>63</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap63!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-09-09</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403553316_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-09-09">
            <content>To provide machinery for fixing minimum wages, determining normal working
                hours, and fixing overtime rates in trades where the wage standards are unreasonably
                low.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[21 June 1940]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403553316_005" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Trade Boards Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403553332_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Trade Boards and minimum wages</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413996697_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may, at any time he thinks fit, by Government
                notification published in the Gazette, fix minimum rates of wages for any trade in
                Hong Kong either generally or in any specified area or district in any case in which
                he is satisfied that the minimum rates of wages being paid to any persons employed
                in any such trade are unreasonably low. Every notification fixing minimum rates of
                wages may be varied from time to time or revoked.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996713_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purpose of instituting, making, and conducting any inquiry that may be
                deemed advisable in
                connexion
                with fixing any minimum rates of wages in any trade under this Ordinance, and for
                reporting thereon, the Chief Executive may at any time establish for any trade, or
                for any branch of work in a trade, a Trade Board, consisting of members representing
                employers and members representing workers, in this Ordinance referred to as
                        <b><i>representative
                        members</i></b>, in equal proportions, and of appointed members, provided
                that the number of appointed members shall be less than half the total number of
                representative members. Where a Trade Board has been established for any branch of
                work in a trade, any reference in this Ordinance to the trade for which the Board is
                established shall be construed as a reference to the branch of work in the trade for
                which the Board has been established.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 ss. 2(2), 11 &amp; 13
                    U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996760_005" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Women shall be eligible as members of Trade Boards as well as men.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996760_013" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Chairman of a Trade Board shall be the Commissioner for Labour or such
                other public officer as the Chief Executive may appoint.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/ln142">L.N. 142 of
                        1974</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996760_021" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>All members shall be appointed by the Chief Executive, but the employers and
                workers may nominate representatives for appointment, subject to the Chief
                Executive’s approval, as representative members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996760_029" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In order to constitute a meeting of a Trade Board, at least one-third of the
                whole number of the representative members and at least one appointed member must be
                    present.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s.
                    11(6) U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996775_005" name="7" temporalId="s2_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A Trade Board for any trade shall consider, as occasion requires, any matter
                referred to them by the Chief Executive with reference to the industrial conditions
                of the trade, and shall make a report upon the matter to the Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 3
                    U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/54">54 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403553332_004" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application of
            Cap.
            86</heading><content>The provisions of <ref>sections 3 to 10</ref> of the
            Commissioners
            Powers
            Ordinance*
            shall apply to any Board so
            appointed.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1621584140981_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>
                See 1968
                Extractions—Cap.
                86,
                1964 Revised
                Edition</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403553347_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Duties and powers of Trade Boards with respect to minimum rates of wages</heading><leadIn>Every Trade Board shall, subject to the provisions of this section, recommended a
            minimum rate of wages for time-work in their trade, in this Ordinance referred to as a
                    <b><i>general
                    minimum time-rate</i></b>, and may also recommend for their trade—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413996853_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a general minimum rate of wages for piece-work, in this Ordinance referred to
                as a
                        <b><i>general
                        minimum piece-rate</i></b>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413996853_027" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a minimum time-rate (which shall not be higher than the general minimum
                time-rate) to apply in the case of workers employed on piece-work for the purpose of
                securing to such workers a minimum rate of remuneration on a time-work basis, in
                this Ordinance referred to as a
                        <b><i>guaranteed
                        time-rate</i></b>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413996853_035" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a minimum rate (whether a time-rate or a piece-rate) to apply, in substitution
                for the minimum rate which would otherwise be applicable, in respect of hours worked
                by a worker in any week or on any day in excess of the number of hours considered by
                the Trade Board to be the normal number of hours of work per week or for that day in
                the trade, in this Ordinance referred to as an
                        <b><i>overtime
                        rate</i></b>.</content></paragraph><continued>Any of the minimum rates aforesaid may be fixed so as to apply universally to the
            trade or so as to apply to any special process in the work of the trade or to any
            special area, or to any class of workers in the trade, or to any class of workers in any
            special process or in any special area. If a Trade Board report to the Chief Executive
            that it is impracticable in any case to fix a general minimum time-rate in accordance
            with this section, the Chief Executive may so far as respects that case relieve the
            Trade Board of their duty.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/54">54 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403553347_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Penalty for not paying wages in accordance with minimum rate which has been made
            obligatory</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413996916_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any minimum rate of wages has been fixed by the Chief Executive in
                Council under this Ordinance, an employer shall, in cases to which the minimum rate
                is applicable, pay wages to the person employed at not less than the minimum rate
                clear of all deductions, and if he fails to do so shall be liable on summary
                conviction in respect of each offence to a fine 
                at
                level 1 and to a fine of
                $50
                for each day on which the offence is continued after conviction therefor.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1950/22">22 of
                        1950 </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/2000/54">54 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996931_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On the conviction of an employer under this section for failing to pay wages at
                not less than the minimum rate to a person employed, the court may by the conviction
                adjudge the employer convicted to pay, in addition to any fine, such sum as appears
                to the court to be due to the person employed on account of wages, the wages being
                calculated on the basis of the minimum rate, but the power to order the payment of
                wages under this provision shall not be in derogation of any right of the person
                employed to recover wages by any other proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996947_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where an employer has been convicted for failing to pay wages at not less than
                the minimum rate to any worker, then, if notice of intention so to do has been
                served with the summons, warrant, or complaint, evidence may be given of any failure
                on the part of the employer to pay wages at not less than the minimum rate to that
                worker at any time during the two years immediately preceding the date on which the
                information was laid or the complaint was served, and on proof of the failure the
                court may order the employer to pay such sum as in the opinion of the court
                represents the difference between the amount which, having regard to the provisions
                of this Ordinance, ought properly to have been paid to the worker by way of wages
                during those years and the amount actually so paid.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1918 c. 32 s. 9(1)
                U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996978_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>It shall be the duty of every employer in a trade to which a minimum rate is
                applicable, to keep such records of wages as are necessary to show that the
                provisions of this Ordinance are being complied with as respects persons in his
                employment, and if he fails to do so he shall be liable on summary conviction in
                respect of each offence to a fine
                at level
                1
                and also to a fine of
                $25
                for every day during which the default continues after conviction.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1950/22">22 of
                        1950
                    </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996994_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>On any prosecution of a person for failing to pay wages at not less than the
                minimum rate, it shall lie on that person to prove that he has not paid wages at
                less than the minimum rate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413996994_013" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Any agreement for the payment of wages in contravention of this provision shall
                be void.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403553363_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Liability of agents and other persons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413997040_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an offence for which an employer is by virtue of this Ordinance liable to a fine has in fact been committed by some agent of the employer or other person, that agent or other person shall be liable to be proceeded against for the offence in the same manner as if he were the employer, and either together with, or before or after the conviction of, the employer, and shall be liable on conviction to the same punishment as that to which the employer is liable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413997056_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an employer who is charged with an offence against this Ordinance proves
                to the satisfaction of the court that he has used due diligence to enforce the
                execution of the Ordinance, and that the offence was in fact committed by his agent
                or some other person without his knowledge, consent, or connivance, he shall, in the
                event of the conviction of that agent or other person for the offence, be exempt
                from any fine in respect of the offence, without prejudice, however, to the power of
                the court under section
                5(2)
                and
                (3)
                to adjudge him to pay any sum which appears to the court to be due to the person
                employed on account of
                    wages.<sourceNote> (Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413997072_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the immediate employer of any worker to whom a minimum rate of wages applies is himself in the employment of some other person and that worker is employed on the premises of that other person, that other person shall for the purposes of the provisions of this Ordinance relating to the penalty for not paying wages in accordance with the minimum rate be deemed to be the employer of the worker jointly with the immediate employer.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1918 c. 32 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403553363_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Provision for case of persons employed by piece-work where a minimum time-rate but
            no general minimum piece-rate has been fixed</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413997118_018" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An employer shall, in cases where persons are employed on piece-work and a
                general minimum time-rate but no general minimum piece-rate has been fixed, be
                deemed to pay wages at less than the minimum rate—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413997118_026" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in cases where a special minimum piece-rate has been fixed under the
                    provisions of this Ordinance for persons employed by that employer, if the rate
                    of wages paid is less than that special minimum piece-rate; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413997134_006" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in cases where a special minimum piece-rate has not been so fixed, unless
                    he shows that the piece-rate of wages paid would yield, in the circumstances of
                    the case, to an ordinary worker at least the same amount of money as the basis
                    rate.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413997134_013" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="BasisRate">For the purpose of this section the expression
                    <term>basis
                    rate</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">基本工資率</term>) means the general minimum time-rate
                or, where a rate, in this Ordinance referred to as a
                        <b><i>piece-work
                        basis time-rate</i></b>, has been fixed by the Chief Executive in Council
                for the purpose of being substituted for the general minimum time-rate as the basis
                rate, the rate so fixed.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413997134_020" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may fix a piece-work basis time-rate in any case
                in which, having regard to all the circumstances of the case, he is of opinion that
                the general minimum time-rate does not form a proper basis for the purposes of
                subsection
                (1)(b),
                and a piece-work basis time-rate may be higher or lower than the general minimum
                time-rate and may be fixed so as to apply universally to the trade or so as to apply
                to any special process in the work of the trade or to any special area, or to any
                class of workers in the trade or to any class of workers in any special process or
                in any special
                    area.<inline></inline><sourceNote> (Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/54">54 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403553378_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Prevention of evasion</heading><content>Any shopkeeper, dealer, or trader, who by way of trade makes any arrangement express or
            implied with any worker in pursuance of which the worker performs any work for which a
            minimum rate of wages has been fixed under this Ordinance, shall be deemed for the
            purposes of this Ordinance to be the employer of the worker, and the net remuneration
            obtainable by the worker in respect of the work after allowing for his necessary
            expenditure in
            connexion
            with the work shall be deemed to be wages.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403553394_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Employers not to receive premium where minimum rates in force</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413997228_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Where a worker in any trade, being a person to whom a minimum rate of wages
                    fixed by the Chief Executive in Council applies, is an apprentice or learner, it
                    shall not be lawful for his employer to receive directly or indirectly from him,
                    or on his behalf or on his account, any payment by way of premium:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/54">54 of
                            2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_1_proviso">Provided that nothing in the
                    foregoing provisions shall apply to any such payment duly made in pursuance of
                    any instrument of apprenticeship not later than four weeks after the
                    commencement of the employment. </proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413997228_025" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any employer acts in contravention of this provision, he shall be liable on
                summary conviction in respect of each offence to a fine
                at level
                1,
                and the court may by the conviction, in addition to imposing a fine, adjudge him to
                repay to the worker or other person by whom the payment was made the sum improperly
                received by way of premium.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1950/22">22 of 1950
                    </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote>
            </content><referenceNote>[cf. 1918 c. 32 s. 7 U.K.]
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403553394_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Powers of officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413997274_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any officer of any Government department for the time being assisting in carrying this Ordinance into effect shall have power for the performance of his duties—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413997274_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to require the production of wages sheets or other record of wages by an employer, and records of payments made to outworkers by persons giving out work, and to inspect and examine the same and copy any material part thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413997274_020" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to require any person giving out work and any outworker to give any information which it is in his power to give with respect to the names and addresses of the persons to whom the work is given out or from whom the work is received, as the case may be, and with respect to the payments to be made for the work;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413997290_006" name="c" temporalId="s10_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>at all reasonable times to enter any factory or workshop or any place used for giving out work to outworkers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413997290_014" name="d" temporalId="s10_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to inspect and copy any material part of any list of outworkers kept by an employer or person giving out work to outworkers; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413997290_022" name="e" temporalId="s10_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to examine, either alone or in the presence of any other person, as he thinks fit, with respect to any matters under this Ordinance any person whom he finds in any factory or workshop or any place used for giving out work to outworkers, or whom he has reasonable cause to believe to be or to have been a worker in any trade to which a minimum rate under this Ordinance is applicable, and to require every such person to be so examined, and to sign a declaration of the truth of the matters in respect of which he is so examined.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413997306_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any person fails to furnish the means required by an officer as necessary
                for any entry or inspection or the exercise of his powers under this section, or if
                any person hinders or molests any officer in the exercise of the powers given by
                this section, or refuses to produce any document or give any information which any
                officer requires him to produce or give under the powers given by this section, that
                person shall be liable on summary conviction in respect of each offence to a fine
                at
                level
                1;
                and, if any person makes, or causes to be made, or knowingly allows to be made any
                wages sheet, or record of wages, or record of payments, or any list of outworkers
                which is false in any material particular, or produces or causes to be produced, or
                knowingly allows to be produced any such sheet, record or list to any officer acting
                in the exercise of the powers given by this section, knowing the same to be false,
                or furnishes any information to any such officer knowing the same to be false, he
                shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1 or to imprisonment for
                3
                    months.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1950/22">22 of 1950
                    </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 15 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403553410_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Officers to produce certificates when required</heading><content>Every officer of any Government department for the time being assisting in carrying this Ordinance into effect, shall be furnished by the Commissioner for Labour with a certificate of his appointment, and when acting under any or exercising any power conferred upon him by this Ordinance shall, if so required, produce the said certificate to any person or persons affected. </content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/ln142">L.N. 142 of 1974</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 16 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403553410_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Power to conduct proceedings</heading><content>Any such officer may, although not a barrister or solicitor, prosecute or conduct before a court of summary jurisdiction any proceedings arising under this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 22 s. 17(2) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403553425_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-09" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Consent of Commissioner to prosecution</heading><content>No prosecution under this Ordinance shall be commenced without the consent of the Commissioner for Labour.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/ln142">L.N. 142 of 1974</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>