<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 556 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>556C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap556C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-12-22</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403439093_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-12-12">Mass
            Transit Railway (Transport Interchange) Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap556/s33">Cap. 556, section
                33</ref>)*</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[13 February 1998]</commencementNote><sourceNote class="align_right">(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1572246134398_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            
            <content class="left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> This Regulation was
                first
                made under <ref>section 24(3)</ref> of the repealed Mass Transit
                Railway Corporation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap270">Cap. 270</ref>).
                By
                virtue of
                <ref>section 64</ref>
                and
                    <ref>Schedule 3</ref> to the Mass Transit Railway Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap556">Cap.
                556</ref>),
                this Regulation is adopted and becomes a regulation made under <ref href="/hk/cap556">Cap.
                556</ref>.</content>
        </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438403439108_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AuthorizedPerson"><term>authorized
                person</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">獲授權人</term>) means a person authorized by the
            Corporation to act on behalf of the Corporation for the purposes of this
            Regulation;</def><def name="CarPark"><term>car
                park</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">停車場</term>) means a place designated as a car park
            under <ref>section 10</ref>;</def><def name="FranchisedBus"><term>franchised
                bus</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">專利巴士</term>) means a bus in respect of which a
            franchise is in force under the Public Bus Services Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap230">Cap. 230</ref>);</def><def name="LightSignal"><term>light
                signal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">管制燈號</term>) means an illuminated signal to control
            vehicular traffic or pedestrians, including the yellow globe prescribed in <ref>Schedule
                4</ref> to the Road Traffic (Traffic Control) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374G">Cap. 374 sub. leg.
            G</ref>);</def><def name="ParkingSpace"><term class="t">parking
            space</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">泊車位</term>) means a parking space designated under
                <ref>section 9</ref>;</def><def name="Pass"><term>pass</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">通行證</term>) means a pass issued by the Corporation or
            other persons authorized by the Corporation in that behalf for the purpose of
            authorizing access and parking of a vehicle at a parking space;</def><def name="Permit"><term>permit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">許可證</term>) means a permit or an authorization issued
            by the Corporation or other persons authorized by the Corporation in that behalf to
            enable a vehicle to pick up or set down passengers or to load or unload luggage or goods
            in a restricted zone or to be driven into or within a prohibited zone in a transport
            interchange;</def><def name="PrescribedLightSignal"><term>prescribed
                light
            signal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訂明管制燈號</term>) means a light signal of the design,
            size, colour and type prescribed in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Mass Transit Railway
            (Transport Interchange) Bylaw (<ref href="/hk/cap556D">Cap. 556 sub. leg. D</ref>) or
                <ref>Schedule 3</ref> to the Road Traffic (Traffic Control) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374G">Cap. 374 sub. leg. G</ref>), and includes the yellow globe
            prescribed in <ref>Schedule 4</ref> to those
            Regulations;</def><def name="PrescribedRoadMarking"><term>prescribed
                road
            marking</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訂明道路標記</term>) means a road marking of the design,
            size, colour and type prescribed in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Mass Transit Railway
            (Transport Interchange) Bylaw (<ref href="/hk/cap556D">Cap. 556 sub. leg. D</ref>) or
            under the Road Traffic (Traffic Control) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374G">Cap. 374
                sub. leg. G</ref>) or as described in <ref>Schedule
                4 or
                4A</ref> to the Road Traffic (Public Service Vehicles) Regulations
                (<ref href="/hk/cap374D">Cap. 374 sub. leg. D</ref>);
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/34">34 of 2023 s.
            40</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="PrescribedTrafficSign"><term>prescribed
                traffic
            sign</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訂明交通標誌</term>) means a traffic sign of the design,
            size, colour and type prescribed in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Mass Transit Railway
            (Transport Interchange) Bylaw (<ref href="/hk/cap556D">Cap. 556 sub. leg. D</ref>) or
            under the Road Traffic (Traffic Control) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374G">Cap. 374
                sub. leg. G</ref>) or as described in <ref>Schedule
                4 or
                4A</ref> to the Road Traffic (Public Service Vehicles) Regulations
                (<ref href="/hk/cap374D">Cap. 374 sub. leg. D</ref>);
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/34">34 of 2023 s.
            40</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ProhibitedZone"><term>prohibited
                zone</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">禁區</term>) means a prohibited zone designated under
                <ref>section 13(1)(a)</ref>;</def><def name="PublicLightBus"><term>public
                light
            bus</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公共小巴</term>) has the same meaning as in the Road
            Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap. 374</ref>);</def><def name="RestrictedZone"><term>restricted
                zone</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">限制區</term>) means a restricted zone designated under
                <ref>section 13(1)(b)</ref>;</def><def name="RoadMarking"><term>road
                marking</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">道路標記</term>) means a line, word, mark or device placed
            on, or set into, the surface of a road for conveying to persons using the road any
            warning, information, requirement, restriction, prohibition or direction, and includes a
            road hump;</def><def name="TrafficSign"><term>traffic
                sign</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">交通標誌</term>) means a sign, object or device for
            conveying to persons using a road any warning, information, direction, requirement,
            restriction or prohibition.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403439108_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Facilities for the use of transport interchanges</heading><content>The Corporation shall provide, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, adequate, efficient, safe and continuous roads and facilities for the use of transport interchanges by vehicles and members of the public, the operation of public transport services and the parking of vehicles.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403439124_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Directions of the Commissioner</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303297_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Commissioner may give directions to the Corporation by notice in writing in respect of the control and regulation of vehicular and pedestrian traffic and the operation of public transport services, car parks and parking spaces within a transport interchange.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303297_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Corporation shall comply with a direction given under subsection (1) within such period of time as may be specified in the direction.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439124_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Commissioner’s powers to do certain acts</heading><content>Where the Corporation fails to do an act which the Corporation is required or directed to do under this Regulation, the Commissioner may do or cause such act to be done and recover from the Corporation as a civil debt any costs incurred by or incidental to such act.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403439139_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Erection of prescribed traffic signs, etc.</heading><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303360_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>erect or display any prescribed traffic sign or prescribed light signal; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303360_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>place any prescribed road marking,</content></paragraph><continued>at any place within a transport interchange.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403439155_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Erection of other traffic signs, etc.</heading><leadIn>The Corporation may for the guidance of any person using a transport interchange—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303375_034" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>erect or display any traffic sign or light signal other than a prescribed traffic sign or prescribed light signal; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303391_006" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>place any road marking other than a prescribed road marking,</content></paragraph><continued>at any place within a transport interchange.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403439155_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Manner of erection of traffic signs, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303406_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A traffic sign, light signal or road marking, whether prescribed or not, shall be erected, displayed or placed (as the case may be) in such manner so that it is clearly visible to all road users to whom it is directed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303406_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a traffic sign, light signal or road marking purporting to be a prescribed traffic sign, prescribed light signal or prescribed road marking erected, displayed or placed (as the case may be) under <ref>section 5</ref> varies or differs in positioning, size, colour or type from the relevant prescribed traffic sign, prescribed light signal or prescribed road marking, if the variation or difference does not materially impair its appearance and meaning, the variation or difference shall not prevent such traffic sign, light signal or road marking (as the case may be) from being treated as a prescribed traffic sign, prescribed light signal or prescribed road marking.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439171_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Revocation of operation of traffic signs, etc.</heading><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303484_012" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revoke; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303484_020" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>vary or suspend temporarily,</content></paragraph><continued>the operation of any prescribed traffic sign, prescribed light signal or prescribed road marking erected, displayed or placed under <ref>section 5</ref>.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403439171_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Designation of parking space</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303516_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, designate any place within a transport interchange as a parking space for the parking of a vehicle by means of prescribed traffic signs or prescribed road markings, and may in such manner as it thinks fit with the prior approval of the Commissioner limit the use of any parking space to vehicles of any description, or of any particular type or class, or allocate any parking space for use by any person or persons, and revoke or amend any such limitation or allocation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303531_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, in such manner as it thinks fit limit the hours during which vehicles of any description or of any particular type or class may use a parking space, and revoke or amend any such limitation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303531_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Corporation may issue a pass for the parking of a vehicle at a parking space which may be subject to any conditions of issue as determined by the Corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303531_021" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303547_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revoke; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303547_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>suspend temporarily,</content></paragraph><continued>a designation made under subsection (1).</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439186_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Designation of car park</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303578_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, designate any place within a transport interchange as a car park by notice in the Gazette.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303578_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A designation made under subsection (1) shall become effective on the date of publication of the notice in the Gazette or such later date as may be specified in the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303578_020" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Corporation may in such manner as it thinks fit with the prior approval of the Commissioner limit the use of any part of a car park to vehicles of any description or of any particular type or class, or allocate any parking space in a car park for use by any person or persons, and revoke or amend such limitation or allocation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303594_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, in such manner as it thinks fit limit the hours during which vehicles of any description or of any particular type or class may use a car park, and revoke or amend any such limitation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303594_013" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Corporation may, having regard to the need to provide adequate parking facilities for users of the railway and to promote the use of the railway, determine the fees and the charging method for the use of a car park designated under subsection (1) and vary such fees or method as it thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303594_021" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303594_029" name="a" temporalId="s10_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revoke; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303594_037" name="b" temporalId="s10_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>suspend temporarily,</content></paragraph><continued>the designation of any place or any part thereof as a car park.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303609_011" name="7" temporalId="s10_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The Corporation shall cause a notice of any revocation made under subsection <ref>(6)(a)</ref> to be published in the Gazette, and any such revocation shall become effective on the date of publication of the notice in the Gazette or such later date as may be specified in the notice.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439202_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-12-22" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Designation of taxi
            rank and fleet
            taxi stopping place</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/34">34 of 2023 s. 41</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438413303640_026" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, designate any
                area of road within a transport interchange, by means of prescribed traffic signs,
                prescribed road markings or prescribed light signals, as— <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/34">34 of 2023 s. 41</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1702976419688_001" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a taxi rank within which a taxi may stand or ply for hire or set down
                    passengers; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1702976419689_002" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a fleet taxi stopping place within which a fleet taxi may stop for picking
                    up passengers who hire the taxi for a pre-arranged journey. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/34">34 of 2023 s. 41</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303656_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A taxi rank designated under subsection (1) may be restricted for the use of a
                particular class, type or description of taxis by means of prescribed traffic signs
                or prescribed road markings indicating such restriction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303656_013" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303656_021" name="a" temporalId="s11_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revoke; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303656_029" name="b" temporalId="s11_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>suspend temporarily,</content></paragraph><continued>the designation
                made under
                subsection (1), whether in respect of the whole area designated or a part of it.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/34">34 of 2023 s.
                41</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1702976419722_003" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="FleetTaxi"><term>fleet taxi</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車隊的士</term>)
                has the meaning given by <ref>regulation 2(1)</ref> of the Road Traffic (Public
                Service Vehicles) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374D">Cap. 374 sub. leg.
                D</ref>);</def><def name="PrearrangedJourney"><term>pre-arranged journey</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">預定行程</term>) has the meaning given by <ref>regulation
                    2(1)</ref> of the Road Traffic (Public Service Vehicles) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374D">Cap. 374 sub. leg. D</ref>). <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/34">34 of 2023 s. 41</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439202_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Designation of bus stop and public light bus stand</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303687_012" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, designate any area of road within a transport interchange as a bus stop or a public light bus stand for use by franchised buses or public light buses (as the case may be) by means of prescribed traffic signs or prescribed road markings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303703_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A bus stop or public light bus stand designated under subsection (1) may be restricted for use by one or more routes operated by one or more operators.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303703_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a place is designated as a bus stop or public light bus stand under subsection (1), the Corporation shall require the operator of such route or routes to erect and maintain a sign at the bus stop or public light bus stand (as the case may be) specifying the operator and the route or routes.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303703_021" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303703_029" name="a" temporalId="s12_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revoke; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303703_037" name="b" temporalId="s12_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>suspend temporarily,</content></paragraph><continued>a designation made under subsection (1).</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439217_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Designation of prohibited zones or restricted zones</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303734_034" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, by means of prescribed traffic signs or prescribed road markings, designate any place within a transport interchange as—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303750_005" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a prohibited zone; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303750_013" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a restricted zone.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303750_020" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A designation made under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> may, absolutely, on specified days, during specified hours of any day, or during specified hours of any specified days, prohibit the driving of any vehicle or any specified class, type or description of vehicle into or within the prohibited zone.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303750_028" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A designation made under subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> may, absolutely, on specified days, during specified hours of any day, or during specified hours of any specified days, prohibit the driver of any vehicle or any specified class, type or description of vehicle from—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303750_036" name="a" temporalId="s13_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>picking-up or setting-down passengers; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303765_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>loading or unloading luggage or goods, </content></paragraph><continued>on any road within the restricted zone.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303765_019" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Corporation shall cause a notice of any designation under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> or (b) to be published in the Gazette, and any such designation shall become effective on the date of publication of the notice or such later date as may be specified in the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303765_027" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Corporation may issue a permit for a vehicle to be driven into or within a prohibited zone free of charge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303765_035" name="6" temporalId="s13_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Corporation may issue a permit for a vehicle to pick up or set down passengers, luggage or goods in a restricted zone free of charge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303765_043" name="7" temporalId="s13_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303765_051" name="a" temporalId="s13_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revoke; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303781_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>suspend
                    temporarily,</content></paragraph><continued>a designation made under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> or (b).</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303781_019" name="8" temporalId="s13_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Corporation shall cause a notice of any revocation made under subsection <ref>(7)(a)</ref> to be published in the Gazette, and any such revocation shall become effective on the date of publication of the notice in the Gazette or such later date as may be specified in the notice.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439217_004" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Variation of speed limit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303828_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner, vary the speed limit imposed under <ref>section 40(1)</ref> of the Road Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap. 374</ref>) in respect of any section of a road within a transport interchange by means of prescribed traffic signs and revoke or amend such variation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303828_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Corporation shall cause a notice of any variation or revocation made under subsection (1) to be published in the Gazette.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303828_020" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A variation or revocation made under subsection (1) shall become effective on the date of publication of the notice in the Gazette or such later date as may be specified in the notice.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439233_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Closure and suspension of operation of a transport interchange</heading><leadIn>The Corporation may, with the prior approval of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303859_035" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>close; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303859_043" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>suspend temporarily the operation of,</content></paragraph><continued>a transport interchange or any part thereof, including any road or facility therein.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403439249_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Acts may be done without prior approval of the Commissioner</heading><content>Where the Corporation having regard to the particular circumstances of a transport interchange or any part thereof, is of the opinion that it is necessary to do any act referred to in <ref>sections 5</ref>, <ref>8(b)</ref>, <ref>9(1)</ref>, <ref>9(2)</ref>, <ref>9(4)(b)</ref>, <ref>10(3)</ref>, <ref>10(4)</ref>, <ref>10(6)(b)</ref>, <ref>11(1)</ref>, <ref>11(3)(b)</ref>, <ref>12(1)</ref>, <ref>12(4)(b)</ref>, <ref>13(1)</ref>, <ref>13(7)(b)</ref> and <ref>15(b)</ref> immediately and it is impractical to obtain the prior approval of the Commissioner, the Corporation may do any of such acts without the prior approval of the Commissioner, but the Corporation shall notify the Commissioner and the Commissioner of Police of any act done under this section as soon as practicable.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403439249_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Appointment and identification of authorized persons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413303937_011" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation may authorize any person as the Corporation thinks fit and proper to exercise any powers and perform any duties conferred or imposed upon the Corporation under this Regulation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413303937_019" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An authorized person on duty shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413303937_027" name="a" temporalId="s17_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>wear a uniform of a design approved by the Commissioner of Police;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303952_006" name="b" temporalId="s17_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>carry such means of identity as may be approved by the Commissioner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413303952_014" name="c" temporalId="s17_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>promptly produce his means of identity to any person who on reasonable grounds requests him to do so.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403439264_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>No compensation is payable to the Corporation</heading><content>No compensation is payable by the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region to the Corporation for anything done or required to be done under or by virtue of any provision of this Regulation or any other regulations made under <ref>section 33</ref> of the Ordinance which is for the benefit of the operation of the transport interchanges in serving the railway.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/13">13 of 2000 s. 64</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>