<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 464</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>464</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap464!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-02-10</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403221756_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-02-10">
                                                <content>An
                                                  Ordinance
                                                  to
                                                  regulate timber stores.</content>
                                                <content>
                                                  <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                                                  <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                                                </content>
                                </longTitle><commencementNote>[17 March 1995]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1995/ln97">L.N. 97 of
                                                  1995</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of
                                                  2021</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
                                                <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of
                                                  2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
                                </enactingFormula><part id="ID_1438403221756_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403221772_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438412578150_011" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Timber Stores
                    Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578150_019" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403221850_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Director"><term>Director</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">處長</term>) means the Director of Fire Services;</def><def name="Licence"><term>licence</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">牌</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">牌照</term>) means a
            licence granted under <ref>section 4</ref>, or renewed under <ref>section 7</ref> to
            operate a timber store;</def><def name="Licensee"><term>licensee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">持牌人</term>) means a person to whom a licence has been
            granted or transferred or whose licence has been renewed;</def><def name="Place"><term>place</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">地方</term>) includes any premises, yard or place on
            land;</def><def name="TimberStore"><leadIn><term>timber
                    store</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">木料倉</term>) means any place used for the storage of
                timber other than—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412578166_069" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a place used for the storage of timber in bulk with an average sectional area of not less than 0.05 m<sup>2</sup>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578182_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a place used for the storage of any timber in a quantity in the aggregate of less than 12 m<sup>3</sup>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578182_014" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a place used for the storage of any timber being a construction site within
                    the meaning of <ref>regulation 2</ref> of the Construction Sites (Safety)
                    Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap59I">Cap. 59 sub.
                        leg.
                        I</ref>).
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></def></section><section id="ID_1438403221865_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Prohibition on operating timber store without a licence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578213_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who on any occasion operates, keeps, manages or otherwise has control of a timber store in regard to the operation of which a licence is not in force commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578213_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an offence under subsection (1) is alleged to have been committed, proof that a defendant did any act in connection with the operation, keeping, management or other control of a timber store is, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, proof that the defendant operated, kept, managed or otherwise had control of a timber store.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578213_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>It shall not be a defence that a person charged with an offence under subsection (1) did not know that the operation of the timber store which is the subject of the offence was not licensed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578228_005" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person who commits an offence under subsection (1) shall be liable to a fine at level 5 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403221881_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Licences</heading><section id="ID_1438403221897_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Application for and grant of a licence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578244_018" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An application by a person for a licence shall be made to the Director in such form and manner as he may require.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578260_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsection (3), the Director may grant a licence, and may impose such conditions in relation to the operation, keeping, management or other control of a timber store as he thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578260_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Director shall not grant a licence unless he is satisfied, in relation to the proposed operation of a timber store, that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412578260_021" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the applicant will adequately and personally supervise the operation of the timber store;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578260_029" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the place of proposed operation is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412578260_037" name="i" temporalId="s4_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>suitable for the operation of a timber store; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412578260_045" name="ii" temporalId="s4_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>located in an area suitable for the operation of a timber store.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578260_051" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A licence granted under this section shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412578260_059" name="a" temporalId="s4_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>be in such form as the Director may require;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578260_067" name="b" temporalId="s4_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not take effect except on payment of the prescribed fee; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578260_075" name="c" temporalId="s4_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>authorize the licensee to operate a timber store for a period of 12 months, or such lesser period as may be indicated in the licence, from the date on which it is granted.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403221897_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Transfer of licence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578291_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Except as provided in this section a licence shall not be transferable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578291_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director may on application in writing to him by the licensee, showing cause to his satisfaction, and on payment of the prescribed fee, permit the transfer of an existing licence until its expiration to another person, and such transfer shall be endorsed on the licence.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403221912_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Grant or transfer of licence to bodies corporate or partnerships</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578306_026" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a body corporate or a partnership wishes to obtain a licence under <ref>section 4</ref> a person authorized by the body corporate or the partnership in that behalf shall apply as the representative of the body corporate or the partnership and, if a licence is granted by the Director, it shall be expressed to be granted to that person on behalf of the body corporate or the partnership, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578322_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a licence is transferred to a body corporate or a partnership under <ref>section 5(2)</ref>, it shall be expressed to be transferred to a person authorized by the body corporate or the partnership in that behalf as the representative of the body corporate or the partnership, as the case may be.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403221928_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Renewal of a licence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578338_026" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A licensee may, before the expiration of his licence, apply for his licence to be renewed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578338_034" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section does not apply to a licensee whose licence is revoked.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578338_042" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An application by a licensee for the renewal of a licence shall be made to the Director in such form and manner as he may require.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578338_050" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The renewal of a licence under this section shall not take effect except on payment of the prescribed fee and the Director may in respect of the renewed licence impose any condition in relation to the operation, keeping, management or other control of a timber store in addition to or instead of any condition previously imposed by him under <ref>section 4(2)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578353_005" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A renewal of a licence under this section before the expiration of the licence shall take effect on the day following the day of its expiration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578353_013" name="6" temporalId="s7_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Any licence in respect of which an application for renewal is made under this section and which expires prior to the determination of such application shall, unless such application is withdrawn, or the licence is revoked or suspended under <ref>section 8</ref>, remain in force until the determination by the Director of such application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578353_021" name="7" temporalId="s7_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A renewal of a licence granted under this section shall have effect from the day following the day upon which the licence being renewed would have expired but for subsection (6), for a period of 12 months or such lesser period as may be indicated by the Director at the time of renewal.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403221928_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Revocation, suspension, refusal to renew or transfer; amendment or variation of conditions of a licence</heading><leadIn>The Director may by notice in writing served on the licensee either personally or by registered post—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412578384_043" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>revoke a licence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578384_051" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>suspend a licence for such period of time as he may think fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578384_059" name="c" temporalId="s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>refuse to renew or transfer a licence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578384_067" name="d" temporalId="s8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>amend or vary the conditions of a licence,</content></paragraph><continued>if—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438412578384_081" name="i" temporalId="s8_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>he is satisfied that any false or misleading statement or information was made or furnished by an applicant in connection with the application to obtain, renew or transfer the licence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578400_006" name="ii" temporalId="s8_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the licensee has been convicted of an offence under this Ordinance or any regulations made under <ref>section 12</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578400_014" name="iii" temporalId="s8_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a condition of the licence is contravened, whether or not any person has been convicted of an offence under <ref>section 13</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578400_022" name="iv" temporalId="s8_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>he ceases to be satisfied of any matter in respect of which he is required to be satisfied under <ref>section 4(3)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578400_030" name="v" temporalId="s8_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>in his opinion the licensed timber store has on any occasion since the date on which the licence was granted been operated in a manner contrary to the public interest.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403221943_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Notice of refusal of licence or renewal and of revocation or suspension etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578431_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director shall, before refusing an application for a licence or serving notice under <ref>section 8</ref>, give to the applicant or the licensee, as the case may be, notice of his intention to do so, stating the grounds on which he intends to refuse the application or serve a notice under <ref>section 8</ref> and containing an intimation that such applicant or such licensee may make written representations to him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578447_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the Director decides to refuse an application for a licence or serve a notice under <ref>section 8</ref>, he shall make a written order, properly dated and signed, to that effect and shall send a copy thereof by registered post to the applicant or the licensee, at the address last known to the Director.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403221975_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Appeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578462_026" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person aggrieved by a decision of the Director made in respect of him under <ref>section 4</ref>, <ref>5</ref> or <ref>8</ref> may appeal to the Administrative Appeals Board within 28 days of receiving notice of the decision.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578478_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A decision under <ref>section 8</ref> that is appealed against under subsection (1) shall be suspended in its operation as from the day on which the appeal is made until such appeal is disposed of, withdrawn or abandoned unless such suspension would, in the opinion of the Director, be contrary to the public interest and the notice of the decision contains a statement to that effect.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403221975_004" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403221990_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Powers of entry</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578509_010" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), for the purpose of ascertaining whether the provisions of this Ordinance or of any regulations made under <ref>section 12</ref> are being complied with any police officer or the Director or any public officer authorized in writing by the Director in that behalf may on production of his authority, if required, enter and inspect any licensed timber store.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578509_018" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If it is made to appear to a magistrate by information upon oath that there is reason to believe that an offence against <ref>section 3(1)</ref> is being committed in any place, the magistrate may issue a warrant authorizing the Director or any police officer to enter and search such place.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403222021_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578540_011" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may by regulation—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/71">71 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412578540_019" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>prescribe anything required or permitted to be prescribed under this
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578540_027" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>provide for precautions to be taken against fire in any licensed timber
                    store;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578540_035" name="c" temporalId="s12_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>provide for the issue of a duplicate of a licence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578540_043" name="d" temporalId="s12_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>provide for the fees that may be charged for and in relation to the grant,
                    transfer, endorsement of transfer and the renewal of a licence, the amendment of
                    the conditions or the particulars of a licence where the amendment is at the
                    request of a licensee, and the issue of a duplicate of a licence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578540_051" name="e" temporalId="s12_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>generally, provide for the better carrying into effect of the provisions
                    and purposes of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578556_004" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any regulation made under this section may provide that a contravention thereof
                shall be an offence and may provide penalties for such offence not exceeding a fine
                at level 5.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403222037_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Offences in relation to a licence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578572_018" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who on any occasion operates, keeps, manages or otherwise has control of a licensed timber store in contravention of any condition of the licence commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578572_026" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an offence under subsection (1) is alleged to have been committed, proof that a defendant did any act in connection with the operation, keeping, management or other control of a timber store is, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, proof that the defendant operated, kept, managed or otherwise had control of a timber store.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578587_005" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where a condition of a licence is contravened the licensee commits an offence unless he proves that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412578587_013" name="a" temporalId="s13_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he did not know and had no reason to suspect the existence of the circumstances giving rise to the contravention; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412578587_021" name="b" temporalId="s13_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he could not, by the exercise of reasonable supervision and reasonable diligence, have prevented those circumstances arising.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578587_028" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person who makes any false or misleading statement or furnishes any false or misleading information in connection with any application for the grant, renewal or transfer of a licence commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578587_036" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person who commits an offence under this section is liable to a fine at level 5 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403222053_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Aids in proof</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578618_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A licence or a copy thereof purporting to be certified under the hand of the Director shall be evidence of the facts stated therein as at the date of such licence or such copy thereof and shall be received in evidence without further proof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578618_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A certificate purporting to be certified under the hand of the Director and stating that a timber store is licensed or is not licensed shall be evidence of the facts stated therein as at the date of such certificate and shall be received in evidence without further proof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403222053_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Existing licences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412578634_026" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A timber store licence granted under the Miscellaneous Licences Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap114">Cap. 114</ref>) and in force immediately before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance shall continue in force after such commencement and have effect
                according to its tenor as if it were a licence granted under <ref>section 4</ref> of
                this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412578650_005" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director may, in regard to any licence to which subsection (1) applies, by
                notice in writing served upon the licensee or sent by registered post to the address
                of the licensee appearing on the licence, impose such conditions in relation to the
                operation, keeping, management or other control of a timber store on the licence as
                he thinks fit.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1637823088239_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 17 March
                1995.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222068_002" name="s16" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222084_001" name="s17" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222084_003" name="s18" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222099_002" name="s19" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222115_001" name="s20" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222115_003" name="s21" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222131_002" name="s22" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403222146_001" name="s23" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-02-10" status="omitted" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></main></ordinance>