<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 334 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>334A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap334A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-04-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403023574_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-04-11">Government
            Lotteries Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap334/s9">Cap.
                334,
                section
            9</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[31 March 1962]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403023589_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These rules may be cited as the Government Lotteries Rules.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403023589_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Announcement of lotteries</heading><leadIn>Whenever the Committee considers it expedient to conduct a lottery, the Chairman shall cause to be published in the Gazette and, in his discretion, in such other manner as he may think fit, a notice declaring—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411976208_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the date and time when and the place at which the draw of the lottery shall take place;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976208_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the price at which the tickets shall be sold, and the places at which such tickets may be obtained;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976223_002" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the number and value of the prizes apportioned to the lottery expressed either in percentages of the total value of such tickets as may be sold or by way of fixed values in relation to a fixed number of tickets issued for sale, as the case may be;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976223_010" name="d" temporalId="s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the date and manner in which the numbers of the winning tickets shall be published after the draw of the lottery;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976223_018" name="e" temporalId="s2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the place where and hours during which payment of prizes may be claimed.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403023605_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Tickets to be numbered</heading><content>Every ticket issued for sale in respect of any lottery shall be numbered serially and no such number shall be repeated in respect of the same lottery.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403023620_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Particulars to be stated on tickets</heading><leadIn>The following particulars shall be specified on every ticket issued for sale in respect of any lottery—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411976270_005" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the date and number or other description of lottery for which the ticket is issued;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976270_013" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the serial number allocated to the ticket;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976270_021" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the number and value of the prizes apportioned to the lottery for which the ticket is issued, expressed either in percentages of the total value of the tickets which may be sold or by way of fixed values in relation to a fixed number of tickets issued for sale in respect of the lottery for which the ticket is issued, as the case may be;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976270_029" name="d" temporalId="s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the time and date when and the place at which the draw of the lottery will take place.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403023620_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Procedure at draw</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411976286_042" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Whenever a lottery is drawn there shall be present at the draw not less than
                3
                members of the Committee, and if, at the time appointed for the draw, there shall
                not be that number of members present the draw shall be postponed to such time,
                whether on the same or another day, as the Chairman or any person then present who
                has been authorized for that purpose by the Chairman may direct.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976301_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The members of the Committee present at the draw shall appoint one of their number to preside at the draw.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976301_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The public shall be admitted to the place at which the draw of a lottery is conducted so far as may reasonably be practicable having regard to the accommodation available for such purpose.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976301_021" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A ticket in a lottery shall be eligible for more than one prize.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln95">L.N. 95 of
                    1967</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403023636_001" name="s5A" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5A"><num value="5A">5A.</num><heading>Postponement of draw</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411976317_035" name="1" temporalId="s5A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chairman may postpone the drawing of any lottery if the draw is to take place within the duration of a gale warning.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976317_043" name="2" temporalId="s5A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of any postponement under paragraph (1) shall be published in the Gazette as soon as practicable, and shall specify the date and time when and the place at which the postponed draw shall take place.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1973/ln252">L.N. 252 of 1973</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403023636_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Publication of results of draw</heading><content>The Chairman shall cause the numbers of the winning tickets at any draw and the time and place at which and the manner in which prizes may be claimed to be published in the Gazette and in his discretion in such other manner as may appear to him to be advisable, so soon as may be after the draw is concluded.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403023652_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Payment of prizes</heading><leadIn>Prizes shall be paid in accordance with the following provisions—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411976348_019" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>payment shall be claimed by presenting and delivering up the ticket in respect
                of which the claim is made at the place and during the hours appointed therefor in
                the notice published pursuant to <ref>rule 6</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976348_027" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>payment shall be claimed within
                2
                years after the publication in the Gazette of the number of the ticket in respect of
                which the claim is made;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln95">L.N. 95 of
                    1967</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411976364_006" name="c" temporalId="s7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>
                <leadIn>payment shall be made to the person who presents the ticket for payment of
                    the prize won by the ticket:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_c_proviso">Provided that, if, when any ticket
                    is presented for payment of a prize any number, mark, figure or word which is
                    material for identifying the ticket is, in the opinion of the Committee,
                    illegible or not clearly legible or is incomplete or has been obliterated,
                    defaced or removed, payment shall not be made in respect thereof unless the
                    person claiming payment produces evidence, to the satisfaction of the Committee,
                    identifying such ticket as the ticket in respect of which the prize claimed is
                    payable.</proviso>
            </content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403023652_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Forfeiture of unclaimed prizes</heading><content>If the payment of any prize is not claimed in the manner and within the period prescribed in <ref>rule 7</ref>, and if the number of the ticket in respect of which the prize was payable has been duly published in the manner prescribed in <ref>rule 6</ref>, the proceeds of that prize shall upon expiry of such period be forfeited to the Lotteries Fund.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1967/ln95">L.N. 95 of 1967</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403023667_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Agents for sale of tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411976395_018" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Committee may appoint such number of agents for the sale of tickets to the public as the Committee may from time to time consider expedient and may fix their remuneration, and the duration of their appointments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976395_026" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any agent appointed for the sale of tickets to the public in accordance with this rule may appoint sub-agents.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976410_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The name and address of any sub-agent appointed under paragraph (2) shall be reported to the Committee before such sub-agent commences the sale of tickets to the public.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976410_013" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any appointment of any agent made under this rule may be terminated at any time
                by the Committee giving to such agent
                24
                hours notice in writing terminating the appointment.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411976410_021" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="Agent,Subagent">For the purposes of this rule, the expressions
                    <term>agent</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">代理商</term>) and
                    <term>sub-agent</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">分銷代理商</term>) do not include street vendors.</def></subsection></section></main></subLeg>