<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 384</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>384</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap384!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-01-31</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403137204_004" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-01-31">
            <content>To control, in the interests of safety, the preparation, packing, marking,
                labelling and offering of dangerous goods for carriage by air, and for matters
                connected therewith.</content>
            <content>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[9 September 1985]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1985/ln267">L.N. 267 of 1985</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403137220_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Dangerous Goods (Consignment by Air) (Safety) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403137235_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-01-31" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Annex"><term>Annex</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附件</term>) means Annex 18 to the Convention on
            International Civil Aviation which, on 7 December 1944, was opened for signature at the
            International Civil Aviation Conference held at Chicago;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="DangerousGoods"><term>dangerous
                goods</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">危險品</term>) means any article or substance which is
            listed in the Technical Instructions and any article or substance not so listed by name
            but having properties corresponding to those of one of the general classifications of
            articles and substances in the Technical Instructions;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/52">52 of 1985 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Director"><term>Director</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">處長</term>) means the Director-General of Civil
                Aviation;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/ln326">L.N. 326 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="DomesticPremises"><term>domestic
                premises</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">住宅處所</term>) means premises used solely or principally
            for the purposes of a dwelling;</def><def name="Package"><term>package</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">包裹</term>) means the packaging and the articles and
            substances contained therein including one or more packages placed or arranged within
            one container or enclosure for convenience in handling;</def><def name="Packaging"><term>packaging</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">包裝用品</term>) means any receptacle made for the purpose
            of complying with the minimum packing requirements of the Technical Instructions and any
            other component or material necessary for the receptacle to perform its containment
            function;</def><def name="Packing"><term>packing</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">包裝</term>) means the art and operation whereby articles
            and substances are wrapped up, enclosed in a receptacle or otherwise secured;</def><def name="TechnicalInstructions"><term>Technical
                Instructions</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">技術指令</term>) means the Technical Instructions for the
            Safe Transport of Dangerous Goods by Air approved and published by decision of the
            Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization pursuant to the Annex.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403137235_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-01-31" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Regulations concerning dangerous goods</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412346958_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412346958_019" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for giving effect to and carrying out the Annex and any edition of the
                    Technical Instructions specified in the regulations, in so far as they relate to
                    the duties and obligations of any person with respect to the preparation,
                    packing, marking, labelling and offering of dangerous goods for carriage by air
                    and the packaging and documentation for such goods;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412346958_027" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>empowering the Chief Executive to exempt any person, dangerous goods or
                    packaging or any class or category of persons, dangerous goods or packaging from
                    the regulations;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412346958_035" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>empowering the Director—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412346958_043" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to exempt any person, dangerous goods or packaging from the
                        regulations;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412346974_007" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to give directions in relation to such matters as may be specified in
                        the regulations; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412346974_015" name="iii" temporalId="s3_1_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>to amend any <ref>Schedule</ref> to the regulations; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412346974_022" name="d" temporalId="s3_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>generally for the better carrying into effect of the provisions and
                    purposes of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412346974_029" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Regulations made under this section may provide that a contravention of any
                specified provision thereof is an offence and may prescribe a penalty therefor not
                exceeding a fine of $500,000 and imprisonment for 2 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/52">52 of 1985 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403137251_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-01-31" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Powers of entry, inspection and seizure</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412347005_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The
                Director or any officer of the Civil Aviation Department authorized in writing by
                him in that behalf (hereinafter referred to as an
                        <b><i>authorized
                        officer</i></b>)
                may for the purposes of this Ordinance without a warrant but upon
                production of his authority (if requested to do so)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412347005_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enter, inspect and examine at any reasonable time any place or premises,
                    other than domestic premises, in which he has reason to believe that dangerous
                    goods intended for carriage by air are made, stored or used, or are prepared,
                    processed, packed or handled, or in which any other thing is done in
                    connexion
                    with the preparation or packing of dangerous goods for carriage by air or with
                    the packaging thereof, and may inspect any activity in any such place or
                    premises and make enquiries for the purposes of securing compliance with this
                    Ordinance, or any matter related thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347020_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>require the production of, inspect, examine or take copies of any record or
                    other document in any such place or premises relating to any matter referred to
                    in paragraph (a);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/52">52 of 1985 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347020_014" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>require the occupier of any place or premises which he is entitled under
                    this subsection to enter, or a person employed by the occupier therein, to give
                    him samples of any article or substance therein;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/52">52 of 1985 s.
                            2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347020_022" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>enter and search any place or premises, other than domestic premises, in
                    which he has reasonable grounds for suspecting that there may be anything which,
                    under paragraph (h), is liable to seizure;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347020_030" name="e" temporalId="s4_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>stop, board and search any vessel, vehicle or aircraft in which he has
                    reasonable grounds for suspecting that there may be anything which, under
                    paragraph (h), is liable to seizure;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347036_006" name="f" temporalId="s4_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>inspect, open and examine any consignment of dangerous goods, packaging or
                    package;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347036_014" name="g" temporalId="s4_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>require any person to give information as to the source from which any
                    dangerous goods were obtained, or as to the making, packing, marking or
                    labelling of such goods or of any packaging, or as to the use or destination of
                    such goods; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347036_022" name="h" temporalId="s4_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><leadIn>seize, remove and detain—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412347036_030" name="i" temporalId="s4_1_h_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>anything with respect to which he has reasonable grounds for suspecting
                        that any offence under this Ordinance has been committed; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412347036_038" name="ii" temporalId="s4_1_h_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any other thing which may appear to him likely to be, or to contain,
                        evidence of any such offence.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412347036_044" name="1A" temporalId="s4_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>Where a person is convicted of an offence under this Ordinance in relation to anything seized, removed or detained under subsection <ref>(1)(h)</ref>, he is liable to the Government for its reasonable expenses incurred in the seizure, removal and detention; and those expenses are recoverable as a civil debt.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1988/56">56 of 1988 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412347052_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director or an authorized officer may detain any vessel, vehicle or aircraft which he is empowered under subsection (1) to stop, board and search, and may prevent any person from approaching or boarding such vessel, vehicle or aircraft until the vessel, vehicle or aircraft has been searched.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412347052_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A magistrate may, if he is satisfied by information on oath that there may be found in any domestic premises any evidence of an offence under this Ordinance, issue a warrant authorizing the Director or an authorized officer to enter and search the domestic premises at any reasonable time and to exercise such of the powers under subsection (1) as are specified in the warrant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412347052_021" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412347052_029" name="a" temporalId="s4_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>obstructs or delays the Director or an authorized officer in the exercise of any of the powers conferred upon him by or under this section; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347067_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>when required to give information under subsection <ref>(1)(g)</ref>, wilfully or recklessly gives false information or withholds such information,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at level
                4
                and to imprisonment for 6 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er6">E.R. 6 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403137267_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Liability of directors, etc. where offence committed by company</heading><leadIn>Where a person by whom an offence under this Ordinance is committed is a company, every director and every officer concerned in the management of the company may be convicted of the like offence unless he proves to the satisfaction of the court or magistrate that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412347145_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the act or omission constituting the offence occurred without his knowledge or consent; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412347145_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he exercised all such reasonable supervision and reasonable diligence to prevent the commission of the offence as he ought to have exercised having regard to the nature of his functions in that capacity and to all the circumstances.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403137267_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Forfeiture</heading><content>A magistrate may order
            the
            forfeiture of any dangerous goods and any packaging for dangerous goods in respect of
            which an offence under this Ordinance has been committed, whether or not any person has
            been charged with the offence.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403137282_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Saving for other enactments</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412347176_009" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), the provisions of this Ordinance shall be in addition to and not in derogation of the provisions of any other enactment relating to dangerous goods.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412347176_017" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding anything in the Dangerous Goods Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap295">Cap. 295</ref>), where dangerous goods intended for carriage by air are properly packed, and the packaging thereof is properly marked and labelled, in accordance with this Ordinance, the goods and packaging shall be deemed to comply with the requirements of the Dangerous Goods Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap295">Cap. 295</ref>) with respect to the packing, marking and labelling of such goods for the purpose of conveyance by vehicle or vessel to or from any aerodrome.</content></subsection></section></main></ordinance>