<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 499</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>499</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap499!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-04-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403273923_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-04-08">An Ordinance to
            provide for assessing the impact on the environment of certain projects and proposals,
            for protecting the environment and for incidental
            matters.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></longTitle><commencementNote>[1 April 1998]<sourceNote> <ref href="/hk/1998/ln70">L.N. 70 of 1998</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2015/er3">E.R. 3 of
                        2015</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><part id="ID_1438403273938_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403273938_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438412743167_004" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the
                Environmental
                Impact Assessment
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743167_012" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2015/er3">E.R. 3 of 2015</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403273954_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><content>In this Ordinance the expressions defined in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> have the meanings set out there.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403273970_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743245_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance binds the Government.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743245_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Sections 26</ref> and <ref>27</ref> do not have effect to permit proceedings to be taken against, or to impose criminal liability on, the Government or on a person doing anything in the course of carrying out his duties as a public officer in the service of the Government.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743245_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the Director considers that a public officer, in carrying out his duties in the service of the Government, has done, or has omitted to do, something in contravention of this Ordinance, the Director shall, if the act or omission is not immediately terminated to his satisfaction, report the matter to the Chief Secretary for Administration.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743261_006" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>On receiving a report, the Chief Secretary for Administration shall inquire into the matter and, if his inquiry shows that a public officer is continuing to contravene this Ordinance or is likely to contravene the Ordinance again, the Chief Secretary for Administration shall ensure that the best practicable steps are taken to stop the contravention or avoid the recurrence and to remedy any environmental damage that may have occurred.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403273970_003" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Environmental
            Impact
            Assessment</heading><section id="ID_1438403273985_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Certain projects to be designated projects</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743292_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The projects listed in <ref>Schedules 2</ref> and <ref>3</ref> are designated projects.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743308_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Secretary may by order published in the Gazette amend the lists of designated projects in <ref>Schedules 2</ref> and <ref>3</ref> by adding projects to or removing projects from the lists.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743308_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The addition of a designated project to <ref>Schedule 2</ref> or <ref>3</ref> does not affect an existing project—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743308_021" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the existing project has been approved, permitted or authorized, or consented to, by the Government or a statutory authority under an Ordinance specified by the Secretary in the order amending the <ref>Schedule</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743308_029" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if construction of the project commences within 6 months of the addition of the project to the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743308_036" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Secretary may after consulting the Director specify in writing as a designated project, contiguous projects which, if taken individually, do not meet the specified levels in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> or <ref>3</ref> to qualify as a designated project, and which are proposed by the same person or associated persons, if he is satisfied that the purpose behind the separation of the projects is to avoid the purposes of this Ordinance. The Director must give the person or associated persons who propose or are carrying out the contiguous projects a copy of the specification of the projects as a designated project.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743323_005" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person or associated persons may apply to the Director for confirmation as to whether contiguous projects proposed by him or them are to be treated as designated projects. The Director must advise the person or associated persons within 14 days that the projects are to be treated as a designated project.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403273985_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Application for brief or permission to apply directly for environmental permit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743355_019" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person who is planning a designated project shall apply to the Director—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743355_027" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for an environmental impact assessment study brief to proceed with an environmental impact assessment study for the project; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743355_035" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the requirements of subsection (9), (10) or (11) are relevant, for approval to apply directly for an environmental permit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743370_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The applicant shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743370_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>submit the application in the form approved by the Director;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743370_021" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>submit a project profile that complies with the technical memorandum;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743370_029" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>advertise in the form the Director may require the availability of the project profile on the day following the lodging of the project profile with the Director in a Chinese language daily newspaper and an English language daily newspaper, each of which circulate generally in Hong Kong; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743370_037" name="d" temporalId="s5_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>pay the prescribed application fee.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743370_044" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director shall inform the Advisory Council on the Environment on the receipt of a project profile and forward a copy of the project profile to it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743370_052" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director may within 14 days of receiving the application request the applicant to give further information concerning the project profile or notify the applicant of any defects in the application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743386_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If the Director requires further information, the Director may also require the applicant to advertise the availability of the additional information or details relating to the information.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743386_013" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Advisory Council on the Environment and any person may comment on a project profile to the Director on environmental issues covered by the technical memorandum relevant to the designated project within 14 days of its being advertised. The Director is to consider any comments received in drawing up the study brief for the designated project.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743386_021" name="7" temporalId="s5_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>The Director shall within 45 days of receiving the application or further information under subsection (4)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743386_029" name="a" temporalId="s5_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>issue to the applicant an environmental impact assessment study brief; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743386_037" name="b" temporalId="s5_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>notify the Advisory Council on the Environment that he has issued the environmental impact assessment study brief; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743386_045" name="c" temporalId="s5_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by notice in writing permit the applicant to apply directly for an environmental permit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743386_052" name="8" temporalId="s5_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Director is taken to have given his consent for an applicant under subsection <ref>(7)(c)</ref> to apply directly for an environmental permit if the Director has not given notice in writing refusing permission within 45 days of receiving the application or further information under subsection (4).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743401_005" name="9" temporalId="s5_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>The Director may permit an applicant to apply directly for an environmental permit if he satisfies the Director, having regard to the project profile, that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743401_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the environmental impact of the project is adequately assessed in an environmental impact assessment report in the register; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743401_021" name="b" temporalId="s5_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the information and findings of the environmental impact assessment report in the register are still relevant.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743401_028" name="10" temporalId="s5_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>The Director may permit an applicant to apply directly for an environmental permit for a material change to an exempted project by notice in writing if the applicant satisfies the Director, having regard to the project profile, that the impact of the material change to the project and the mitigation measures described in the project profile meet the requirements of the technical memorandum.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743417_005" name="11" temporalId="s5_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>The Director may, with the consent of the Secretary, permit an applicant to apply directly for an environmental permit if he satisfies the Director, having regard to the project profile, that the environmental impact of the designated project is unlikely to be adverse and the mitigation measures described in the project profile meet the requirements of the technical memorandum.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743417_013" name="12" temporalId="s5_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>The Director may impose conditions on a permission to apply directly for an environmental permit that include, without limiting the power to impose any reasonable condition, requirements to be complied with for the issue and holding of an environmental permit for the designated project, but shall be guided by the relevant technical memorandum.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274001_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Environmental impact assessment report</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743495_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An applicant shall prepare an environmental impact assessment report in accordance with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743495_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the requirements of the environmental impact assessment study brief; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743495_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the technical memorandum applicable to the assessment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743495_027" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The applicant shall deliver an environmental impact assessment report to the Director for approval and pay the prescribed application fee. The Director may require the applicant to supply sufficient copies of the report so that the Director is able to circulate copies to relevant parties as defined in the technical memorandum.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743511_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Director shall, within 60 days of receiving the environmental impact assessment report, decide if the assessment—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743511_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>meets the requirements of the environmental impact assessment study brief and technical memorandum; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743511_021" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>does not meet the requirements of the environmental impact assessment study brief and technical memorandum.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743511_028" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If the Director decides that the environmental impact assessment report meets the requirements of the brief and the technical memorandum, he shall advise the applicant when the report must be exhibited for public inspection, whether the advertisement is to contain any specific material and whether a submission to the Advisory Council on the Environment or its subcommittee is required.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743511_036" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Director is taken to have decided that the environmental impact assessment report meets the requirements of the environmental impact assessment study brief and the technical memorandum if the Director has not given notice in writing that the report does not meet the requirements of the brief and the technical memorandum within 60 days of receiving the report. The applicant is required to submit the number of copies of the report as set out in the brief.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743526_005" name="6" temporalId="s6_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If the Director decides that the environmental impact assessment report does not meet the requirements of the brief and the technical memorandum, he shall advise the applicant of the reasons why the report is unacceptable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743526_013" name="7" temporalId="s6_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The applicant shall present his environmental impact assessment report to the Advisory Council on the Environment at the times and places advised by the Director if the applicant is required to submit the report to the Council.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274016_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Public inspection of reports</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743557_028" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The applicant shall as soon as reasonably practicable after he has been notified under <ref>section 6(3)(a)</ref> that an environmental impact assessment report meets the requirements of the environmental impact assessment study brief—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743557_036" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>make the report available in such numbers as the Director may reasonably require at locations approved by the Director for public inspection free of charge for a period of 30 days;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743573_006" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>advertise as the Director may require the availability of the report once every 10 days of the period in a Chinese language newspaper and an English language newspaper, each of which circulate generally in Hong Kong; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743573_014" name="c" temporalId="s7_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>provide free of charge sufficient quantities as the Director may require of the report to comply with paragraph (a).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743573_021" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The applicant shall set out in the advertisement—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743573_029" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the nature of the designated project and the site where the project is proposed to be carried out;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743573_037" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the period for which, the places at which and the hours during which the report is available for public inspection;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743573_045" name="c" temporalId="s7_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that a member of the public may give the Director written comments on the report before the period of public inspection expires;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743573_053" name="d" temporalId="s7_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the address to which the comments are to be sent; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743573_061" name="e" temporalId="s7_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>any other information that the Director may reasonably require relating to the project.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743589_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director shall require an applicant to readvertise or extend the period of public inspection for up to another 30 days if the applicant fails to comply with any requirement under this Part or a direction that the Director gives to an applicant under this section unless the Director is satisfied that the failure is not significant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743589_013" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director shall notify the Advisory Council on the Environment if an environmental impact assessment report is suitable for public inspection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743589_021" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Advisory Council on the Environment may give any comments it has on the report to the Director within 60 days of its receiving a copy of the report.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274032_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Approval of environmental impact assessment report</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743620_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may, within 14 days of the expiry of the public inspection period or the receipt of comments from the Advisory Council on the Environment, whichever is later, ask an applicant in writing to give him the information he requires to decide whether to approve an environmental impact assessment report. The Director shall supply the applicant with one set of written comments received from members of the public and the Advisory Council on the Environment free of charge where comments have been received.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743635_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director shall not make a request for further information where comments have not been submitted to him on the report as a result of the public consultation or from the Advisory Council on the Environment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743635_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Director shall, within 30 days of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743635_021" name="a" temporalId="s8_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the expiry of the public inspection period;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743635_029" name="b" temporalId="s8_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the receipt of comments from the Advisory Council on the Environment; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743635_037" name="c" temporalId="s8_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the receipt of information under subsection (1),</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the later, approve, approve with conditions or reject an environmental impact assessment report for the designated project.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743635_050" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director is taken to have approved without conditions an environmental impact assessment report if the Director has not given notice in writing rejecting the report or approving it with conditions within 30 days of the happening of the later of the events set out in subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref>, (b) or (c).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743651_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Director shall place an approved environmental impact assessment report on the register.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743651_013" name="6" temporalId="s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If the Director rejects an environmental impact assessment report, he shall give the applicant the reasons for the rejection.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403274032_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Environmental
            Permits</heading><section id="ID_1438403274048_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Prohibition against carrying out designated project unless environmental permit has
            been issued, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743682_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person shall not construct or operate a designated project listed in Part I of
                    <ref>Schedule 2</ref> or decommission a designated project listed in Part II of
                    <ref>Schedule 2</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743682_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>without an environmental permit for the project; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743682_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>contrary to the conditions, if any, set out in the permit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743682_027" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A project listed in Part I of <ref>Schedule 2</ref> that has—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743682_035" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>had planning permission granted by the Town Planning Board under
                        <ref>section 16</ref> of the Town Planning Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap131">Cap. 131</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743698_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>had consent granted to commence building works by the Building Authority
                    under the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743698_014" name="c" temporalId="s9_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>had reclamation authorized under the Foreshore and Sea-bed (Reclamations)
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap127">Cap. 127</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743698_022" name="d" temporalId="s9_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>had road works authorized under the Roads (Works, Use and Compensation)
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap370">Cap. 370</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743698_030" name="e" temporalId="s9_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>been approved as a new development under the Country Parks Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap208">Cap. 208</ref>) or the Marine Parks Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap476">Cap. 476</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743698_038" name="f" temporalId="s9_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>been authorized under the Water Pollution Control (Sewerage) Regulation
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap358AL">Cap. 358 sub. leg. AL</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743698_046" name="g" temporalId="s9_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>commenced construction, or been in operation,</content></paragraph><continued>before this Ordinance comes into
                operation*
                is exempt from the provisions of this Ordinance so far as the construction and
                operation of the project is concerned.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743698_059" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A project listed in Part II of <ref>Schedule 2</ref> and the demolition plan of
                which has been approved by the Building Authority under the Buildings Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>) before this Ordinance comes into
                operation, is exempt from the provisions of this Ordinance so far as the
                decommissioning of the project is concerned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743713_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A material change to an exempted project is subject to this Ordinance and
                requires an environmental permit unless subsequently exempted under this
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743713_013" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The inclusion of a class of projects in <ref>Schedule 3</ref> does not exempt
                the construction, operation or decommissioning of the whole or any part of the
                project from the need to have an environmental permit.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1611199421971_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Date of coming into operation: 1
                April 1998.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403274063_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Application for environmental permit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743745_020" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person who wishes to have constructed, construct or operate a designated project listed in Part I of <ref>Schedule 2</ref> or to decommission a designated project listed in Part II of <ref>Schedule 2</ref> shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743745_028" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>apply to the Director for an environmental permit in the form approved by the Director; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743745_036" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>refer to an environmental impact assessment report on the register in the application for an environmental permit; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_006" name="c" temporalId="s10_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>submit an environmental impact assessment report prepared under <ref>section 6</ref> with the application; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_014" name="d" temporalId="s10_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>refer to the permission under <ref>section 5(9)</ref>, (10) and (11) to apply directly for an environmental permit and the conditions under <ref>section 5(12)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_022" name="e" temporalId="s10_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>pay the prescribed application fee.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743760_029" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In granting or refusing an environmental permit, the Director shall have regard to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_037" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the approved environmental impact assessment report on the register;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_045" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the attainment and maintenance of an acceptable environmental quality;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_053" name="c" temporalId="s10_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>whether the environmental impact caused or experienced by the designated
                    project is or is likely to be prejudicial to the health or
                    well-being
                    of people, flora, fauna or ecosystems;
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_061" name="d" temporalId="s10_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any relevant technical memorandum;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_069" name="e" temporalId="s10_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>any environmental impact assessment report approved under this Ordinance or any conditions in an approval; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743760_077" name="f" temporalId="s10_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the comments, if any, submitted to him under <ref>section 7</ref> on the report.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743760_084" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Director shall advise the applicant and the Advisory Council on the Environment, where it has been consulted under <ref>section 6(7)</ref>, of the grant or refusal of the environmental permit within 30 days of the later of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743776_005" name="a" temporalId="s10_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the receipt of the application;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743776_013" name="b" temporalId="s10_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the expiry of the public inspection period of the environmental impact assessment report under <ref>section 7</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743776_021" name="c" temporalId="s10_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the receipt of comments from the Advisory Council on the Environment on the environmental impact assessment report; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743776_029" name="d" temporalId="s10_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the receipt of information under <ref>section 8(1)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743776_036" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director is taken to have granted without conditions an environmental permit if the Director has not given notice in writing rejecting the permit or approving it with conditions within 30 days of the happening of the later of the events set out in subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref>, (b), (c) or (d).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743776_044" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Director may issue an environmental permit subject to the conditions, if any, as the Director thinks fit and specifies in the permit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743776_052" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Without limiting the general nature of conditions which the Director may include in an environmental permit, he may include conditions relating to the matters set out in <ref>Schedule 4</ref> but shall be guided by the relevant technical memorandum.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743791_005" name="7" temporalId="s10_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A condition specified in an environmental permit may be subject to a qualification, restriction or requirement concerning the location, time or period of the condition’s application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743791_013" name="8" temporalId="s10_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>The Director shall not specify in an environmental permit conditions that might be included in approval of any nature under another pollution control Ordinance unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743791_021" name="a" temporalId="s10_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the conditions are necessary to meet the requirements of the technical memorandum or the environmental impact assessment study brief; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743791_029" name="b" temporalId="s10_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the environmental impact assessment report approved for the project or the conditions on which the applicant was allowed to apply directly for an environmental permit under <ref>section 5</ref> specified expressly that the environmental permit may include the conditions.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743807_005" name="9" temporalId="s10_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>If the environmental permit is refused, the Director shall advise the applicant and give the reasons why the permit is refused.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274063_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Surrender of permit</heading><content>A person who is issued with an environmental permit may surrender the whole or a part of the permit after ceasing to be responsible for implementing the whole or a part of the project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403274079_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Issue of further environmental permit for a project</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743869_011" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where responsibility for a designated project for which an environmental permit has been issued changes while the environmental permit is still in force, the person who assumes responsibility of the designated project shall before he assumes the responsibility apply for and obtain an environmental permit for the whole or a part of the project.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743885_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person applying for a further environmental permit under this section is not required to submit an environmental impact assessment report where he satisfies the Director that there has been no material change to the designated project since the previous environmental permit was issued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743885_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Director shall issue an environmental permit to an applicant under this section within 30 days of receipt of the application if he is satisfied that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743885_021" name="a" temporalId="s12_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>there has been no material change to the designated project since the previous environmental permit was issued; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743885_029" name="b" temporalId="s12_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the information and findings of the environmental impact assessment report, if any, are still relevant and adequate.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743885_036" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director is taken to have issued a further environmental permit on the same conditions as the previous environmental permit if the Director has not given notice in writing rejecting the application or approving it with conditions within 30 days of the receipt of the application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743901_005" name="5" temporalId="s12_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>An applicant under this section shall apply in the form approved by the Director and shall pay the prescribed application fee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743901_013" name="6" temporalId="s12_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>The Director may exempt a designated project from the requirement to be further subject to an environmental permit if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743901_021" name="a" temporalId="s12_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an environmental permit has been issued for the designated project and the terms of the environmental permit have been complied with; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743901_029" name="b" temporalId="s12_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the designated project is not subject to any conditions under the environmental permit that are of an on-going nature and require monitoring or other compliance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743901_036" name="7" temporalId="s12_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A material change to a designated project exempted under subsection (6) is subject to the provisions of this Ordinance and requires an environmental permit unless subsequently exempted under this Ordinance.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274079_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Application for variation of an environmental permit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743932_049" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The person holding an environmental permit or a person who assumes
                responsibility for a designated project the subject of an environmental permit may
                apply for a variation of the conditions of the environmental permit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743947_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director shall notify the applicant for a variation of an environmental
                permit within 30 days of the receipt of an application whether he requires the
                applicant to submit an environmental impact assessment report for the variations
                sought.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743947_013" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director is taken not to require an environmental impact assessment report
                for the variations sought if the Director does not notify the applicant within 30
                days of the receipt of the application.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743947_021" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If the Director requires an applicant to submit an environmental impact
                assessment report, <ref>sections 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref>, <ref>7</ref> and
                    <ref>8</ref> apply to the report and assessment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743947_029" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>The Director may amend the environmental permit without calling for an
                environmental impact assessment report if the applicant satisfies him that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743947_037" name="a" temporalId="s13_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>there is no material change to the environmental impact of the project with
                    the mitigation measures in place; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743947_045" name="b" temporalId="s13_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the project complies with the requirements described in the technical
                    memorandum.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection name="5A" temporalId="s13_5A" id="ID_1744613857327_001"><num value="5A">(5A)</num><content><ref>Schedule 5</ref> has effect in relation to the criterion for evaluating
                air quality impact under the technical memorandum for the purpose of an
                environmental impact assessment report required to be submitted under
                    <ref>subsection (4)</ref> or a requirement mentioned in <ref>subsection
                    (5)(b)</ref>. <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/5">5 of 2025 s.
                    23</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743963_005" name="6" temporalId="s13_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>An applicant under this section shall apply in the form approved by the
                Director and shall pay the prescribed application fee.</content></subsection><subsection name="7" temporalId="s13_7" id="ID_1744613857420_002"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The Secretary may, by notice published in the Gazette, amend <ref>Schedule
                    5</ref> to make any provisions or amendments, or repeal any provisions, that the
                Secretary considers appropriate on account of any amendment to the air quality
                objective by any enactment. <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/5">5 of 2025 s.
                        23</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274094_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Cancellation or variation of environmental permit by the Director</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412743979_033" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director may, with the consent of the Secretary, suspend, vary or cancel an
                environmental permit if he is satisfied that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412743979_041" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>on the application for the environmental permit the applicant gave—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412743979_049" name="i" temporalId="s14_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>misleading information;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412743979_057" name="ii" temporalId="s14_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>wrong information;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412743979_065" name="iii" temporalId="s14_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>incomplete information; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412743979_073" name="iv" temporalId="s14_1_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>false information; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412743979_080" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the applicant is no longer able to comply with the conditions of the
                    environmental permit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743994_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director shall give written notice of his decision to suspend, vary or
                cancel an environmental permit under this section together with the reasons for the
                suspension, variation or cancellation and the conditions on which the permit can be
                reinstated.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743994_013" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may suspend, vary or cancel an environmental
                permit if he is satisfied that the continuation of the designated project is, or is
                likely to be more prejudicial to the health and
                well-being
                of people, flora, fauna or ecosystems than expected at the time of issuing the
                environmental permit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/34">34 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743994_021" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council shall give the reasons for the suspension,
                variation or cancellation and the conditions on which the permit can be
                    reinstated.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/34">34 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412743994_029" name="5" temporalId="s14_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="Vary">In this section,
                    <term>vary</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">更改</term>) includes to delete, modify or add to the
                conditions of an environmental permit.</def></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403274110_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>The
            Register</heading><section id="ID_1438403274110_004" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>The register</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744041_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director shall keep a register in the form he determines containing details
                of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>project profiles he receives;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_020" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>environmental impact assessment study briefs he issues;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_028" name="c" temporalId="s15_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>his decisions on the applications for permission to apply directly for an
                    environmental permit under <ref>section 5(9)</ref>, (10) or (11);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_036" name="d" temporalId="s15_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>environmental impact assessment reports he receives;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_044" name="e" temporalId="s15_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>his decisions on the environmental impact assessment reports;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_052" name="f" temporalId="s15_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>environmental impact assessment reports he held prior to the
                    commencement*
                    of this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_060" name="g" temporalId="s15_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>applications for environmental permits;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_068" name="h" temporalId="s15_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>his decisions on the applications for environmental permits;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744041_076" name="i" temporalId="s15_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>matters required by regulations.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744041_083" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The register is open for inspection by the public (free of charge) during
                normal office hours at the places the Director determines.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1611042973531_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 April
                1998.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403274126_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Technical
            Memorandum</heading><section id="ID_1438403274141_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Technical memorandum</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744088_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Secretary may issue technical memorandums setting out principles, procedures, guidelines, requirements and criteria for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the technical content of a project profile;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the technical content of an environmental impact assessment study brief or environmental impact assessment report;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_028" name="c" temporalId="s16_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>deciding whether a designated project is environmentally acceptable;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_036" name="d" temporalId="s16_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>deciding whether an environmental impact assessment report meets the requirements of the environmental impact assessment study brief;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_044" name="e" temporalId="s16_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>deciding whether the Director will permit an applicant to apply directly for an environmental permit under <ref>section 5(9)</ref>, (10) or (11);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_052" name="f" temporalId="s16_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>resolving conflicts on the content of the environmental impact assessment study brief and the environmental impact assessment report;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_060" name="g" temporalId="s16_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>taking advice from other authorities;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_068" name="h" temporalId="s16_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>deciding what is a material change, addition or alteration to an environmental impact or to a designated project;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744088_076" name="i" temporalId="s16_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the issue of environmental permits;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744103_006" name="j" temporalId="s16_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>the imposition of environmental monitoring and audit requirements for designated projects as conditions in environmental permits.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744103_013" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A technical memorandum may require or authorize the Director to follow the advice of the Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744103_021" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In giving advice pursuant to a technical memorandum, the Secretary shall ensure that the effect of his advice is to protect the environment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744103_029" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director shall be guided by all applicable technical memorandums when deciding on matters under <ref>sections 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref>, <ref>8</ref>, <ref>10</ref>, <ref>12</ref>, <ref>13</ref> and <ref>14</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744103_037" name="5" temporalId="s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A technical memorandum is to be published in the Gazette and laid on the table of the Legislative Council at the next sitting after its publication.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744103_045" name="6" temporalId="s16_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Legislative Council may, by resolution passed at a sitting of the Legislative Council held before the expiration of a period of 28 days of the sitting at which a technical memorandum was laid on the table of the Legislative Council, repeal the technical memorandum.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744119_005" name="7" temporalId="s16_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>If the period for debate would but for this subsection expire—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744119_013" name="a" temporalId="s16_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>after the end of a session of the Legislative Council or a dissolution; but</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744119_021" name="b" temporalId="s16_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on or before the day of the second sitting of the Legislative Council in the next session,</content></paragraph><continued>the period extends to and expires on the day after that second sitting.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744119_034" name="8" temporalId="s16_8"><num value="8">*(8)</num><leadIn>Before the expiry of the period referred to in subsection (6) or that period as extended by virtue of subsection (7), the Legislative Council may by resolution in relation to a technical memorandum specified therein—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744119_042" name="a" temporalId="s16_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of the period referred to in subsection (6), extend that period
                    to the first sitting of the Legislative Council held not earlier than the
                    twenty-first day after the day of its expiry;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744119_050" name="b" temporalId="s16_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case where the period referred to in subsection (6) has been
                    extended by virtue of subsection (7), extend that period as so extended to the
                    first sitting of the Legislative Council held not earlier than the twenty-first
                    day after the day of the second sitting in that next session.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2002/8">8 of
                            2002 s. 22</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744135_005" name="9" temporalId="s16_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>A resolution passed by the Legislative Council in accordance with this section is to be published in the Gazette within 14 days of its passing or within the further period the Chief Executive may allow in a particular case.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/34">34 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744135_013" name="10" temporalId="s16_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>A technical memorandum issued under this section is to come into operation on the expiry of the period for debate of the technical memorandum in the Legislative Council.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744135_021" name="11" temporalId="s16_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><def name="Sitting">In this section,
                    <term>sitting</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會議</term>), when used to calculate time, means the
                day on which the sitting commences and only includes a sitting at which subsidiary
                legislation is included on the order paper.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744135_028" name="12" temporalId="s16_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>A technical memorandum is not subsidiary legislation.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1612488808657_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            
            <content class="left_indent_46 first_line_indent_-8"><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> For the transitional
                provision relating to this subsection as amended by <ref>section 22</ref> of the
                Extension of Vetting Period (Legislative Council) Ordinance 2002 (<ref href="/hk/2002/8">8 of 2002</ref>), see <ref>section 23</ref> of that
                Ordinance.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403274157_001" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            VI</num><heading>Appeals</heading><section id="ID_1438403274157_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Appeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744197_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An environmental permit holder or an applicant for—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744197_012" name="a" temporalId="s17_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an environmental impact assessment study brief;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744197_020" name="b" temporalId="s17_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>permission to apply directly for an environmental permit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744197_028" name="c" temporalId="s17_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>approval of an environmental impact assessment report; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744197_036" name="d" temporalId="s17_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>an environmental permit,</content></paragraph><continued>may appeal to the Appeal Board if he is aggrieved by a decision of the Director—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438412744197_050" name="i" temporalId="s17_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>as to the content of an environmental impact assessment study brief issued by the Director under <ref>section 5(7)(a)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744213_006" name="ii" temporalId="s17_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>not to issue an environmental permit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744213_014" name="iii" temporalId="s17_1_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>not to permit an applicant to apply directly for an environmental permit under <ref>section 5(9)</ref>, (10) or (11);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744213_022" name="iv" temporalId="s17_1_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>as to the conditions imposed under <ref>section 5(12)</ref> on an applicant’s applying directly for an environmental permit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744213_030" name="v" temporalId="s17_1_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>not to approve an environmental impact assessment report;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744213_038" name="vi" temporalId="s17_1_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>to impose conditions on the issue or variation of an environmental permit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744213_046" name="vii" temporalId="s17_1_vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content>to vary or to cancel an environmental permit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744213_054" name="viii" temporalId="s17_1_viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content>to claim costs incidental to remedying environmental damage under this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744213_061" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person whose project is specified as a designated project under <ref>section 4(4)</ref> may appeal to the Appeal Board against the decision to designate the project.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744213_069" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An applicant shall appeal by lodging notice of appeal in the prescribed manner within 30 days of receipt of the notice of the decision.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274172_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Appeal Board panel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744244_053" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Appeal Board shall determine an appeal under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744244_061" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive shall appoint as Chairman of the Appeal Board panel a
                person who is qualified for appointment as a District Judge under <ref>section
                    5</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap.
                336</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744259_005" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Chief Executive may appoint as Deputy Chairman of the Appeal Board panel a
                person who is qualified for appointment as a District Judge under <ref>section
                    5</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>)
                who may act as Chairman in his absence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744259_013" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Chairman, a Deputy Chairman and a person appointed to the Appeal Board
                panel are appointed for a term of 3 years but may be reappointed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744259_021" name="5" temporalId="s18_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Chief Executive shall appoint a panel of persons whom he considers suitable
                for appointment as members of the Appeal Board to hear any appeal under this
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744259_029" name="6" temporalId="s18_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>An appointment under subsection (2), (3) or (5) is to be notified in the
                Gazette.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744259_037" name="7" temporalId="s18_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The Chairman, a Deputy Chairman and a person appointed to the Appeal Board
                panel may at any time resign by notice in writing to the Chief Executive.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/34">34 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403274188_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Constitution of Appeal Board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744291_018" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chairman and the number of persons from the panel the Chairman appoints to
                be members to hear an appeal constitutes an Appeal Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744291_026" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Appeal Board may give directions to the Director as to the exercise of the
                Director’s functions relevant to the appeal. The Director shall comply with the
                directions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744291_034" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The opinion of the majority of the members hearing the appeal determines a
                question before the Appeal Board except a question of law which the Chairman
                determines. The Chairman has a casting vote where there is an equality of
                votes.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744306_005" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>At least 3 members, one of whom must be either the Chairman or Deputy Chairman,
                shall hear and determine the appeal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744306_013" name="5" temporalId="s19_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Appeal Board must not include public officers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744306_021" name="6" temporalId="s19_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The contents of any technical memorandum must not be called into question in an
                appeal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744306_029" name="7" temporalId="s19_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>In an appeal the Appeal Board may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744306_037" name="a" temporalId="s19_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>administer an oath and receive evidence on oath;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744306_045" name="b" temporalId="s19_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>admit or take into account a statement, document, information or matter
                    whether or not it would be admissible in a court of law;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744306_053" name="c" temporalId="s19_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by notice in writing summon a person to appear before it to produce a
                    document or to give evidence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744306_061" name="d" temporalId="s19_7_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>confirm, reverse or vary the decision or requirement appealed against;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744306_069" name="e" temporalId="s19_7_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>make an award of the costs of the appeal as is just and equitable in all
                    the circumstances of the case.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744306_076" name="8" temporalId="s19_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>In the exercise of its powers under subsection (7) the Appeal Board has the
                powers which the Court of First Instance may exercise.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744322_005" name="9" temporalId="s19_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>If a person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744322_013" name="a" temporalId="s19_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on being summoned as a witness before the Appeal Board fails to attend;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744322_021" name="b" temporalId="s19_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>being in attendance as a witness refuses to take an oath required by the
                    Appeal Board to be taken, or to produce a document under his power or control
                    required by the Appeal Board to be produced by him, or to answer a question to
                    which the Appeal Board may require an answer; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744322_029" name="c" temporalId="s19_9_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>does any other thing which would, if the Appeal Board had been a court of
                    law having power to commit for contempt, have been contempt of that
                    court,</content></paragraph><continued>the Chairman may certify in writing the contempt of the person to the Court
                of First Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744322_042" name="10" temporalId="s19_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><leadIn>The Court of First Instance may inquire into the alleged contempt and after
                    hearing—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744322_050" name="a" temporalId="s19_10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the witnesses who may be produced against or for the person charged with
                    the contempt; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744322_058" name="b" temporalId="s19_10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any statement that may be offered in defence,</content></paragraph><continued>punish or take steps for the punishment of that person in the same way if he
                had been guilty of contempt of the court.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744322_071" name="11" temporalId="s19_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>A witness before the Appeal Board has the same immunities and privileges as if
                he were a witness in civil proceedings before the Court of First Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of
                        1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744337_005" name="12" temporalId="s19_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>Costs awarded by the Appeal Board are enforceable as a civil debt and costs
                payable by the Director under an award are charged on the general revenue.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744337_013" name="13" temporalId="s19_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>The Chairman may determine a form or matter of practice or procedure of the
                Appeal Board for which a provision is not made in this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744337_021" name="14" temporalId="s19_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><def name="PublicOfficer">In this section
                    <term>public
                    officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公職人員</term>) does not include a judge who is
                appointed as the Chairman or a Deputy Chairman.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274188_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Supplementary provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744384_011" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If both the Chairman and Deputy Chairman are precluded by illness, absence from
                Hong Kong or any other cause from exercising his functions, the Chief Executive may
                appoint a person qualified for appointment as a District Judge under <ref>section
                    5</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>)
                to act as Chairman and as such to exercise and perform all the functions of the
                Chairman during the period of his appointment.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/34">34 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744384_019" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If a person appointed by the Chairman to hear an appeal under this Part is
                precluded by illness, absence from Hong Kong or any other cause from exercising his
                functions, the Chairman may appoint another person from the panel to act in his
                place.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274204_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Case may be stated for Court of Appeal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744415_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Appeal Board may, before an appeal under this Part is determined, refer a question of law arising in the appeal to the Court of Appeal for determination by way of case stated.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744415_012" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On the hearing of the case the Court of Appeal may amend the case or order it to be sent back to the Appeal Board for amendment having regard to the opinion of the Court of Appeal.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403274219_001" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part
            VII</num><heading>Enforcement</heading><section id="ID_1438403274219_003" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Authorized officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744447_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may in writing authorize a public officer to exercise the powers conferred on an authorized officer under this Part as the Director may specify in the authorization.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744447_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A public officer exercising a power under this Part—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744447_020" name="a" temporalId="s22_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may obtain the assistance of persons he reasonably requires for the purposes of the discharge of his functions;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744447_028" name="b" temporalId="s22_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall, if required, produce his identity card issued under the Registration of Persons Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap177">Cap. 177</ref>), together with his written authorization under this section.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274235_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Powers of entry and inspection, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744462_027" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An authorized officer may without warrant and on production, if required, of his written authorization under this Part—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744462_035" name="a" temporalId="s23_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>enter and search a place if he reasonably believes that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412744462_043" name="i" temporalId="s23_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>an offence against this Ordinance has been or is being committed in the place;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412744462_051" name="ii" temporalId="s23_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>there is in the place anything that is or is likely to constitute evidence that an offence against this Ordinance has been or is being committed;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744462_058" name="b" temporalId="s23_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enter a place to serve a notice under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744478_006" name="c" temporalId="s23_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>enter a place to measure, inspect, take samples and test as he reasonably believes is necessary to determine if an offence against this Ordinance has been or is being committed.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744478_013" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An authorized officer shall not, except with the consent of the occupier or person in charge of the premises, enter domestic premises without a warrant issued by a magistrate under subsection (3) or (4).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744478_021" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If a magistrate informed on oath is satisfied that there is reason to believe that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744478_029" name="a" temporalId="s23_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an offence against this Ordinance has been or is being committed on domestic premises; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744478_037" name="b" temporalId="s23_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>there is on domestic premises anything that is or is likely to constitute evidence that an offence against this Ordinance has been or is being committed,</content></paragraph><continued>the magistrate may issue a warrant authorizing an authorized officer to enter and search the premises.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744478_050" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If a magistrate informed on oath is satisfied that there is reason to believe that it is necessary for an authorized officer to enter domestic premises to serve a notice or to measure, inspect, take samples or test as the authorized officer reasonably believes is necessary to determine if an offence against this Ordinance has been or is being committed, the magistrate may issue a warrant authorizing the authorized officer to enter the domestic premises.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744493_005" name="5" temporalId="s23_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>An authorized officer who enters a place under subsection (1), (3) or (4) may require any person present at that place—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744493_013" name="a" temporalId="s23_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to give details of his identity, name and address and produce his identity card issued under the Registration of Persons Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap177">Cap. 177</ref>) for inspection by the authorized officer; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744493_021" name="b" temporalId="s23_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>who appears at the time to be responsible for or in charge of that place, to give such information or render such assistance as may be necessary to enable the authorized officer to carry out his functions under this Part.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744509_005" name="6" temporalId="s23_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>An authorized officer who enters any place under this section shall, if entry is by warrant, produce that warrant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744509_013" name="7" temporalId="s23_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A warrant issued under subsection (3) or (4) shall continue in force until the purpose for which the entry is necessary has been satisfied.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274250_001" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Cessation order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744540_004" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director may, with the consent of the Secretary, issue an order requiring persons working on a designated project to cease working on the project until the order is withdrawn, if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744540_012" name="a" temporalId="s24_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an environmental permit has not been issued for the project being undertaken;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744540_020" name="b" temporalId="s24_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an environmental permit has been withdrawn from the project being undertaken; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744540_028" name="c" temporalId="s24_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>there has been a breach of the conditions of an environmental permit issued for the project being undertaken, resulting in environmental damage.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744540_035" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director may, with the consent of the Secretary, issue an order requiring persons working on a designated project to carry out work on the project to remedy environmental damage identified by the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744556_005" name="3" temporalId="s24_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director may, with the consent of the Secretary, after issuing an order to cease working on a designated project, take direct action to remedy environmental damage identified by the Director and may recover the costs of the remedial work from the owner of, or the operator or the contractor on, the site of the designated project.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274250_003" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Recovery of costs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744571_050" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may certify the costs due and names of the persons liable for the costs, apportioning the costs if appropriate, if he is authorized to recover the costs of works carried out under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744587_005" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Costs">Without limiting the general meaning of
                    <term>costs</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">費用</term>), the costs may include supervision
                charges and the costs of materials supplied by the Director for the purpose of
                carrying out the works.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744587_012" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director shall serve a copy of his certificate on each person who is liable to pay costs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744587_020" name="4" temporalId="s25_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Annual interest at the rate of 10% commencing 1 month after the date of service of the certificate is recoverable as part of the costs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744587_028" name="5" temporalId="s25_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Payment of costs by any person is without prejudice to his right to recover the payment from any other person who is liable to pay for the costs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744587_036" name="6" temporalId="s25_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Costs certified by the Director are recoverable as a civil debt due to the Government.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744587_044" name="7" temporalId="s25_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A writ of summons initiating an action to recover costs as a civil debt due to the Government is presumed to have been served if the court is satisfied that the writ was left at the defendant’s residence or place of business or, if those are not known, that it was left at the building or land for which the claim is made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744603_005" name="8" temporalId="s25_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>A certificate purporting to be signed by the Director under subsection (1) is on its production admissible in any proceedings without further proof. The certificate is presumed, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, to be proof of the signature of the Director and of the facts certified in relation to the costs due from the person sued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744603_013" name="9" temporalId="s25_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>At any time before the costs have been wholly recovered, a copy of the certificate referred to in subsection (1) may be registered under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>) against the land or premises for which the costs arose, and the copy so registered constitutes a legal charge as defined in the Conveyancing and Property Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap219">Cap. 219</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744618_005" name="10" temporalId="s25_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>On the recovery of all of the costs certified under this section the Director shall, if there has been a registration against land or premises under subsection (9), register under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>) a certificate of satisfaction against the land or premises.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403274266_002" name="P8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part
            VIII</num><heading>Offences</heading><section id="ID_1438403274282_001" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Offences relating to environmental permit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744649_004" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person who contravenes <ref>section 9</ref> commits an offence and is liable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744649_012" name="a" temporalId="s26_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on a first conviction on indictment to a fine of $2,000,000 and to imprisonment for 6 months;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744649_020" name="b" temporalId="s26_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on a second or subsequent conviction on indictment to a fine of $5,000,000 and to imprisonment for 2 years;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744665_006" name="c" temporalId="s26_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on a first summary conviction to a fine at level 6 and to imprisonment for 6 months;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744665_014" name="d" temporalId="s26_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>on a second or subsequent summary conviction to a fine of $1,000,000 and to imprisonment for 1 year,</content></paragraph><continued>and in any case where the offence is of a continuing nature, the court or magistrate may impose a fine of $10,000 for each day on which he is satisfied the offence continued.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744665_027" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person does not commit an offence under subsection (1) if he carries out an action in response to an emergency and in the interests of public safety or public health.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744665_035" name="3" temporalId="s26_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person does not commit an offence under subsection (1) arising out of a breach of conditions of an environmental permit as set out in <ref>section 9(1)(b)</ref> if he proves that the offence was committed without his consent or connivance and that he exercised all such diligence to prevent the commission of the offence as he ought to have exercised having regard to the nature of his functions in that capacity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744681_005" name="4" temporalId="s26_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A person for whom a project is constructed, operated or decommissioned and who permits the carrying out of the project contrary to <ref>section 9</ref> commits an offence and is liable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744681_013" name="a" temporalId="s26_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on a first conviction on indictment to a fine of $2,000,000 and to imprisonment for 6 months;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744681_021" name="b" temporalId="s26_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on a second or subsequent conviction on indictment to a fine of $5,000,000 and to imprisonment for 2 years;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744681_029" name="c" temporalId="s26_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on a first summary conviction to a fine at level 6 and to imprisonment for 6 months;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744681_037" name="d" temporalId="s26_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>on a second or subsequent summary conviction to a fine of $1,000,000 and to imprisonment for 1 year,</content></paragraph><continued>and in any case where the offence is of a continuing nature, the court or magistrate may impose a fine of $10,000 for each day on which he is satisfied the offence continued.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744681_050" name="5" temporalId="s26_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person does not commit an offence under subsection (4) if he proves that the offence was committed without his consent or connivance and that he exercised all such diligence to prevent the commission of the offence as he ought to have exercised having regard to the nature of his functions in that capacity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744696_005" name="6" temporalId="s26_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A person who either alone or with an associated person, separates contiguous projects, which, if taken individually, do not meet the specified levels in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> or <ref>3</ref> to qualify as a designated project but which collectively qualify as a designated project, to avoid the purposes of this Ordinance is taken to have contravened subsection (4) if he permits the carrying out of any part of any of the contiguous projects without first applying to the Director under <ref>section 4(5)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744712_005" name="7" temporalId="s26_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>In proceedings for an offence under this section, the prosecution does not have
                to prove that the acts or omissions in question were
                accompanied
                by any intention, knowledge or negligence on the part of the defendant as any
                element of the offence.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274282_003" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Offences in relation to enforcement</heading><leadIn>A person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744743_020" name="a" temporalId="s27_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>wilfully resists, obstructs or delays any public officer in the exercise of a power conferred by <ref>section 23</ref> which he is authorized to exercise;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744759_006" name="b" temporalId="s27_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>fails without reasonable excuse to comply with a requirement duly made by a public officer in the exercise of a power under <ref>section 23</ref> which he is authorized to exercise;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744759_014" name="c" temporalId="s27_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in compliance or purported compliance with a requirement of a public officer under Part VII produces a drawing, record or document which he knows to be incorrect or inaccurate in a material respect or does not believe to be correct or accurate; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744759_022" name="d" temporalId="s27_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>wilfully or recklessly gives information which is incorrect in a material respect or withholds information as to any of the matters for which information is required to be given under Part VII,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403274297_002" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Offence to disclose confidential information obtained officially</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744774_049" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who, except in the circumstances set out in subsection (2), discloses or gives to another person any information that concerns a trade, business or profession, and has come to his knowledge or into his possession in the course of the discharge of his functions under this Ordinance commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744790_005" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A person does not commit an offence under subsection (1) if he discloses or gives the information to another person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744790_013" name="a" temporalId="s28_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to discharge his functions under this Ordinance or in connected proceedings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744790_021" name="b" temporalId="s28_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>under an order of a court under subsection (3); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744790_029" name="c" temporalId="s28_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>with the consent in writing of all persons who appear to him, after reasonable inquiry, to be interested in the confidentiality of the information.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744790_036" name="3" temporalId="s28_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where in proceedings a court considers that the justice of the case requires, the court may order the disclosure of information referred to in subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744790_044" name="4" temporalId="s28_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person who commits an offence under subsection (1) is liable on conviction to a fine at level 4 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274313_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Directors of body corporate liable in certain circumstances</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744821_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a person convicted of an offence under this Ordinance is a body corporate and it is proved that the offence was committed with the consent or connivance of, or was attributable to any neglect or omission on the part of, a director, manager, secretary or other person concerned in the management of the body corporate, the director, manager, secretary or other person also commits the offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744821_012" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a person convicted of an offence under this Ordinance is a partner in a partnership and it is proved that the offence was committed with the consent or connivance of, or was attributable to any neglect or omission on the part of, any other partner or any person concerned in the management of the partnership, the partner or the person concerned in the management also commits the offence.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403274313_003" name="P9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="P9"><num value="9">Part
            IX</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403274328_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Exemptions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744852_011" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may, in the public interest, exempt a project
                from the provisions of this Ordinance by an order published in the
                Gazette.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744868_005" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make the order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744868_013" name="a" temporalId="s30_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>subject to conditions and limitations;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744868_021" name="b" temporalId="s30_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>have effect for a period of time; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744868_029" name="c" temporalId="s30_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>be partial in operation with respect to the project or to specified
                    provisions of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744868_036" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who breaches a condition or requirement imposed under an exemption
                order is deemed to have breached an environmental permit and is subject to the
                provisions of this Ordinance that apply to the breach of an environmental
                permit.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/34">34 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403274328_003" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Protection of Government and public officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744883_064" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A public officer is not personally liable for an act or omission of his if he did it in the honest belief that the act or omission was required or authorized to discharge his functions under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744899_005" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The protection given to a public officer by subsection (1) for an act or omission does not in any way affect any liability of the Government in tort for the act or omission.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274344_002" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744915_004" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Secretary may, after consultation with the Advisory Council on the Environment, by regulation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412744915_012" name="a" temporalId="s32_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>prescribe anything required or permitted to be prescribed under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744915_020" name="b" temporalId="s32_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>prescribe the minimum qualifications and experience of persons undertaking environmental impact assessment studies;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744915_028" name="c" temporalId="s32_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>regulate appeals under Part VI and the practice and procedure of the Appeal Board;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412744915_036" name="d" temporalId="s32_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>generally, provide for the better carrying into effect of the provisions and purposes of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744915_043" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A regulation for the payment of fees may provide for different fees to be charged according to different circumstances.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274375_001" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Power of Director to set forms</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412744930_050" name="1" temporalId="s33_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may set the form of a document required under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744930_058" name="2" temporalId="s33_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director’s power under subsection (1) is subject to any express requirement under this Ordinance for a form to comply with the requirement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412744946_005" name="3" temporalId="s33_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director may include in a form a statutory declaration to be made by the person completing the form confirming that the particulars contained in the form are correct to the best of the person’s knowledge.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403274375_003" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Service of notices</heading><content>A notice to be served under this Ordinance may be served by registered post or by serving a copy personally.</content></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403274391_002" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap499/s2">s.
                2</ref>]</note><heading>Interpretation</heading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Abattoir"><term>abattoir</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">屠場</term>) means premises or a place habitually used
            for the slaughter of animals for human consumption;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="AirQualityObjective"><term>air
                quality objective</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">空氣質素指標</term>) means the air
            quality objectives prescribed in <ref>Schedule 5</ref> to the Air Pollution Control
            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap311">Cap. 311</ref>); <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2025/5">5 of 2025 s. 24</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="AircraftMaintenanceAndRepairPlant"><term>aircraft
                maintenance and repair
            plant</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">飛機維修與修理廠</term>) means a place, building or structure
            where aircraft or its parts are stored, repaired, washed or greased;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="AppealBoard"><term>Appeal
                Board</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">上訴委員會</term>) means the appeal board constituted under
                <ref>section 19</ref>;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="AssociatedPerson">
            <leadIn><term>associated
                    person</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">相聯繫的人</term>) means—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744977_062" name="a" temporalId="sch1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the spouse or minor child or minor step-child of the person;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744977_071" name="b" temporalId="sch1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a corporation of which the person is a director;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744977_080" name="c" temporalId="sch1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an employee or partner of the person;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744977_089" name="d" temporalId="sch1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the trustee of a trust of which the person, his spouse, minor child or
                    minor step-child, is a beneficiary or a discretionary object;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744977_098" name="e" temporalId="sch1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>another person who has agreed or arranged to act together with the person
                    to acquire, hold or dispose of shares or other interests in a corporation or to
                    act together in voting in the corporation;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744993_007" name="f" temporalId="sch1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>another person in accordance with whose directions the person is accustomed
                    or obliged to act;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744993_016" name="g" temporalId="sch1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>another person accustomed or obliged to act in accordance with the
                    directions of the person;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744993_025" name="h" temporalId="sch1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>a corporation in accordance with whose directions or the directions of its
                    directors the person is accustomed or obliged to act;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744993_034" name="i" temporalId="sch1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a corporation accustomed or obliged to act, or whose directors are
                    accustomed or obliged to act, in accordance with the directions of the
                    person;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744993_043" name="j" temporalId="sch1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>a corporation of which the person, either alone or together with his
                    spouse, minor child or minor step-child, is directly or indirectly entitled to
                    exercise or control the exercise of 35% or more of the voting power;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412744993_052" name="k" temporalId="sch1_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>a corporation of which the person, either alone or together with another,
                    including a corporation in which the person is entitled to exercise or control
                    the exercise of 35% or more of its voting power, is directly or indirectly
                    entitled to exercise or control the exercise of 35% or more of the voting
                    power;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745008_007" name="l" temporalId="sch1_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>a corporation of which the person controls the composition of the board of
                    directors of the corporation;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745008_016" name="m" temporalId="sch1_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><leadIn>if the person is a corporation—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745008_025" name="i" temporalId="sch1_m_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a director of the corporation;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745008_034" name="ii" temporalId="sch1_m_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a corporation which is a holding company of the corporation or a
                        subsidiary of the holding company;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745008_043" name="iii" temporalId="sch1_m_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a subsidiary of the corporation;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745008_052" name="iv" temporalId="sch1_m_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>a director or employee of the subsidiary;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745008_061" name="v" temporalId="sch1_m_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>a pension fund, provident fund or employee share scheme of the
                        corporation or of a subsidiary of the corporation;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
        </def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="BathingBeach"><term>bathing
                beach</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">泳灘</term>) means any bathing beach which is specified
            in the <ref>Fourth Schedule</ref> to the Public Health and Municipal Services (<ref href="/hk/cap132">Cap. 132</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="BulkChemicalStorageFacility"><term>bulk
                chemical storage
            facility</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">散裝化學物品貯存設施</term>) means a facility that is or may be
            used for storing materials of a hazardous nature for delivery to or by seagoing bulk
            chemical carriers and includes related product blending, drum and bottle storage and
            dispatch facilities;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Chairman"><term>Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the Chairman of the Appeal Board panel
            appointed under <ref>section 18(2)</ref>;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ChemicalWaste"><term>chemical
                waste</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">化學廢物</term>) means waste which is chemical waste within
            the meaning of Waste Disposal (Chemical Waste) (General) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap354C">Cap. 354 sub. leg. C</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="CoastalProtectionArea"><term>coastal
                protection
            area</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">海濱保護區</term>) means a coastal protection area shown in
            a
            draft plan prepared under the Town Planning Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap131">Cap.
                131</ref>) or an approved plan or partly approved plan under that Ordinance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/25">25 of 2023 s.
                    119</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ConservationArea"><term>conservation
                area</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">自然保育區</term>) means a conservation area shown in
            a
            draft plan prepared under the Town Planning Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap131">Cap.
                131</ref>) or an approved plan or partly approved plan under that Ordinance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/25">25 of 2023 s.
                    119</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ContainerBackupFacilities"><term>container
                backup
            facilities</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">貨櫃支援設施</term>) means facilities essential to the
            handling of containers which do not require (but may have) a waterfront location and
            includes container yards, empty container storage and repair depots, container freight
            stations and container vehicle parks;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ControlsTheCompositionOfTheBoardOfDirectorsOfTheCorporation">
            <leadIn><term>controls
                    the composition of the board of directors of the
                corporation</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">控制法團董事局的組成</term>) means to be able, either alone
                or with the consent or concurrence of another person, to appoint or remove a
                majority of the directors and a person is taken as having the power to appoint or
                remove a director if—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745024_054" name="a" temporalId="sch1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a director cannot be appointed without the person exercising a power in
                    favour of the prospective director; or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745039_007" name="b" temporalId="sch1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a person’s appointment as a director follows necessarily from his being a
                    director or other officer of the person;</content></paragraph>
        </def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Corporation">
            <leadIn><term>corporation</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法團</term>) means any company or other body
                corporate incorporated in Hong Kong or elsewhere, but does not include—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745039_023" name="a" temporalId="sch1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any body corporate that is incorporated in Hong Kong and is a public
                    authority or an organ or agency of the Government;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745039_032" name="b" temporalId="sch1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any corporation sole;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745039_041" name="c" temporalId="sch1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any credit union registered under the Credit Unions Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap119">Cap. 119</ref>); or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745039_050" name="d" temporalId="sch1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any corporation registered under the Building Management Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap344">Cap. 344</ref>);</content></paragraph>
        </def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="CountryPark"><term>country
                park</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">郊野公園</term>) means a country park within the meaning of
                <ref>section 2</ref> of the Country Parks Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap208">Cap.
                208</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Crematorium"><term>crematorium</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">火葬場</term>) means a crematorium within the meaning of
            the Public Health and Municipal Services Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap132">Cap.
                132</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Decommissioning"><term>decommissioning</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">解除運作</term>) means ceasing production and demolishing
            an existing plant for the development or redevelopment of the site;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="DeputyChairman"><term>Deputy
                Chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">副主席</term>) means a Deputy Chairman of the Appeal Board
            panel appointed under <ref>section 18(3)</ref>;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="DesignatedProject"><term>designated
                project</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指定工程項目</term>) means a project listed in <ref>Schedule
                2</ref> or <ref>3</ref> or specified by the Secretary under <ref>section 4(4)</ref>
            as a designated project;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Director"><term>Director</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">署長</term>) means the Director of Environmental
            Protection;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="EducationInstitution"><term>education
                institution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">敎育機構</term>)
            means an institution, organization or place which provides, or where there is provided,
            for 10 or more persons during any one day, whether or not at the same time,
            kindergarten, primary, secondary or post secondary education or any other educational
            course;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Environment">
            <leadIn><term>environment</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">環境</term>)—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745055_038" name="a" temporalId="sch1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>means the components of the earth; and</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745055_047" name="b" temporalId="sch1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>includes—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745055_056" name="i" temporalId="sch1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>land, water, air and all layers of the atmosphere;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745055_065" name="ii" temporalId="sch1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>all organic and inorganic matter and living organisms; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745055_074" name="iii" temporalId="sch1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the interacting natural systems that include any of the things referred
                        to in subparagraph (i) or (ii);</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
        </def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="EnvironmentalImpact">
            <leadIn><term>environmental
                    impact</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">環境影響</term>), for a designated project,
                means—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745055_089" name="a" temporalId="sch1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an on-site or off-site change that the project may cause in the
                    environment;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745071_006" name="b" temporalId="sch1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>an effect of the change on—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745071_015" name="i" temporalId="sch1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the
                        well-being
                        of people, flora, fauna and ecosystems;
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                            2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745071_024" name="ii" temporalId="sch1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>physical and cultural heritage;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745071_033" name="iii" temporalId="sch1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a structure, site or other thing that is of historical or
                        archaeological significance;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745071_041" name="c" temporalId="sch1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an on-site or off-site effect on any of the things referred to in paragraph
                    (b) from activities carried on for the project;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745071_050" name="d" temporalId="sch1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a change to the project that the environment may cause,</content></paragraph>
            <continued class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0">whether the change or effect
                occurs within or outside the site of the project;</continued>
        </def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="EnvironmentalImpactAssessmentReport"><term>environmental
                impact assessment
            report</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">環境影響評估報告</term>) means a report prepared under
                <ref>section 6</ref>;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="EnvironmentalImpactAssessmentStudyBrief"><term>environmental
                impact assessment study
            brief</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">環境影響評估研究概要</term>) means a study brief issued under
                <ref>section 5(7)(a)</ref>;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="EnvironmentalPermit"><term>environmental
                permit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">環境許可證</term>) means an environmental permit issued
            under <ref>section 10(5)</ref>;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ExistingUses"><term>existing
                uses</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">現有用途</term>) means those uses existed at the time when
            the application under <ref>sections 9</ref> and <ref>13</ref> are made;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Expressway"><term>expressway</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">快速公路</term>) means an expressway within the meaning of
                <ref>section 122</ref> of the Road Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap.
                374</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="FishCultureZone"><term>fish
                culture
            zone</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">魚類養殖區</term>) means a fish culture zone within the
            meaning of <ref>section 2</ref> of the Marine Fish Culture Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap353">Cap. 353</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="HealthCareInstitution"><term>health
                care
            institution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">健康護理機構</term>) means hospitals, polyclinics and
            clinics;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="HeavyRailway"><term>heavy
                railway</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">重型鐵路</term>) means railway for freight transport or for
            a passenger transit system with a capacity exceeding 40 000 passengers per hour per
            direction;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="IndustrialEstate"><term>industrial
                estate</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">工業邨</term>) means any industrial estate referred to in
                <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Hong Kong Science and Technology Parks Corporation
            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap565">Cap. 565</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2001/5">5 of 2001 s.
                40</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="LightRailway"><term>light
                railway</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">輕型鐵路</term>) means railway for a passenger transit
            system with a capacity not exceeding 40 000 passengers per hour per direction;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="MajorExtensionsOrImprovementsToExistingRoads"><term>major
                extensions or improvements to existing
            roads</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">對現有道路作重大擴建或改善</term>) means a physical addition,
            alteration or re-alignment to existing roads which results in an adverse environmental
            impact as defined in the technical memorandum;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="MarinePark"><term>marine
                park</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">海岸公園</term>) means a park within the meaning of the
            Marine Parks Ordinance
                (<ref href="/hk/cap476">Cap.
                476</ref>);
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2021</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="MarineReserve"><term>marine
                reserve</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">海岸保護區</term>) means a reserve area that falls within
            the meaning of the Marine Parks Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap476">Cap. 476</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="MaterialChange"><term>material
                change</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">實質改變</term>) means a physical addition or alteration to
            a designated project which results in an adverse environmental impact as defined in the
            technical memorandum;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="MidstreamOperations"><term>mid-stream
                operations</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">中流作業</term>) means the working of cargo by a ship while
            moored at a buoy or while at anchor;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Mitigation">
            <leadIn><term>mitigation</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">緩解</term>), for a designated project—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745102_014" name="a" temporalId="sch1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>means the elimination, reduction or control of the adverse environmental
                    impact of the project;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412745102_023" name="b" temporalId="sch1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>includes restitution by replacement, restoration, compensation or other
                    means for damage to the environment caused by the impact;</content></paragraph>
        </def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Pier"><term>pier</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">碼頭</term>) means a structure built out over the water
            and supported by pillars or piles, used as a landing place for ferries, boats, ships and
            other vessels including structures accommodating hydrofoil and jetfoil vessels;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="PlannedUse">
            
            
            <leadIn><term>planned use</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">計劃用途</term>) means the
                land use proposed in—<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/25">25 of 2023 s. 119</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
            <paragraph name="a" temporalId="sch1_a" id="ID_1692084121670_001"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a draft plan prepared under the Town Planning Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap131">Cap. 131</ref>) or an approved plan or partly approved
                    plan under that Ordinance; or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph name="b" temporalId="sch1_b" id="ID_1692084121672_002"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any other land use plans published by the Government;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/25">25 of
                            2023 s. 119</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
            
        </def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="PrimaryDistributor"><term>primary
                distributor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主要幹路</term>) means roads forming the major network of
            the urban area including roads having high capacity junctions, although they may be at
            grade or grade separated, with segregated pedestrian facilities wherever possible and
            frontage access limited if not entirely restricted, and with a
            24-hour
            stopping restriction;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2021</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ProjectProfile"><term>project
                profile</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">工程項目簡介</term>) means the description of the project
            that complies with the requirements of the technical memorandum;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="PublicCargoWorkingArea"><term>public
                cargo working
            area</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公眾貨物裝卸區</term>) means an area set out in the Port
            Control (Cargo Working Areas) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap81">Cap. 81</ref>) as a
            public cargo working area;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="QuarantineStationOrSegregationPlaceForAnimals"><term>quarantine
                station or segregation place for
            animals</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">動物檢疫站或隔離處</term>) means a place used for the quarantine
            of animals when they are imported into Hong Kong and detained there for such period as
            the veterinary officer may require;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="RailwayDepot"><term>railway
                depot</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">鐵路車廠</term>) means a facility for the storage,
            maintenance or repair of light or heavy railway rolling stock or equipment used for
            track maintenance, including areas where shunting facilities are used for operational
            purposes;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="RailwayMarshallingYard"><term>railway
                marshalling
            yard</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">鐵路調車場</term>) means a facility in a railway system
            mainly for sorting train wagons into different formations according to an order for
            operation purposes;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ReligiousInstitution"><term>religious
                institution</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">宗敎機構</term>)
            means a place or building, or a place of worship where in accordance with the practice
            of religious principles services are held or prayers said by congregations loyal to a
            belief and includes Chinese temples as set out in paragraph (b) of the definition of
                <term>Chinese
                temple</term>
            in <ref>section 2</ref> of the Chinese Temples Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap153">Cap.
                153</ref>) and ancillary offices car parks and quarters that are essential to the
            operation of the particular organization;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="RiverTradeLimits"><term>river
                trade
            limits</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">內河航限</term>) means the river trade limits defined in
            the Shipping and Port Control Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap313">Cap. 313</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="RiverTradeTerminal"><term>river
                trade
            terminal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">內河碼頭</term>) means a terminal for handling or storing
            cargo by vessels routinely operating within waters within river trade limits;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="RoadTunnel"><term>road
                tunnel</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">行車隧道</term>) means a private or public tunnel and its
            portal area within the meaning of the Road Tunnels (Government) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap368">Cap. 368</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Secretary"><term>Secretary</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">局長</term>) means the
            Secretary
            for Environment and Ecology;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ServiceReservoir"><term>service
                reservoir</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">配水庫</term>) means a place or structure where water from
            a water treatment works is stored for delivery to other service reservoirs for
            distribution to the consumers of a water supply district;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="ShipBuildingOrShipRepairingYard"><term>ship
                building or ship repairing
            yard</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船舶建造或修理場</term>) means any place, structure or building
            in which ships, boats and other sailing vessels are constructed, repaired, renewed or
            broken down into parts;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="SiteOfCulturalHeritage"><term>site
                of cultural
            heritage</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">文化遺產地點</term>) means an antiquity or monument, whether
            being a place, building, site or structure or a relic, as defined in the Antiquities and
            Monuments Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap53">Cap. 53</ref>) and any place, building, site,
            or structure or a relic identified by the Antiquities and Monuments Office to be of
            archaeological,
            historical or palaeontological significance;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2021</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="SiteOfSpecialScientificInterest"><term>site
                of special scientific
            interest</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">具有特別科學價值的地點</term>) means an area of land or water of
            special scientific interest by reason of its flora, fauna or geographical features
            identified by the Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department and listed in the
            register of sites of special scientific interest maintained by the Planning
                Department;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/ln331">L.N. 331 of 1999</ref>)</sourceNote></def><text></text><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="SpecialArea"><term>special
                area</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">特別地區</term>) means a special area as defined in the
            Country Parks Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap208">Cap. 208</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="SpecialWastes"><term>special
                wastes</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">特殊廢物</term>) includes clinical waste, animal carcasses
            and security waste, including Government documents including those to be treated by
            centralised incineration facility;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="TechnicalMemorandum"><term>technical
                memorandum</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">技術備忘錄</term>) means a technical memorandum issued under
                <ref>section 16</ref>;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="Tramway"><term>tramway</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電車軌道</term>) means the roadway over which a tram passes
            and the roadway of any bridge forming part of or leading to the roadway as defined in
            the Tramway Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap107">Cap. 107</ref>);</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="TransportDepot"><term>transport
                depot</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">運輸車廠</term>) means a facility for the construction,
            repair or maintenance of transport vehicles and their parking when not in
            operation;</def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="TrunkRoad"><term>trunk
                road</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">幹道</term>) means a road connecting the main centres of
            population being a high capacity road with no frontage access or development,
            pedestrians segregation, widely spaced grade-separated junctions, and a
            24-hour
            stopping restriction;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2021</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="TyphoonShelter"><term>typhoon
                shelter</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">避風塘</term>) means a typhoon shelter within the meaning
            of the Merchant Shipping (Local Vessels) (Typhoon Shelters) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap548E">Cap. 548 sub. leg. E</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2005/24">24 of 2005 s.
                55</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def class="first_line_indent_-24 left_indent_24 " name="WildAnimalProtectionArea"><term>wild
                animal protection
            area</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">野生動物保護區</term>) means an area designated as a
            restricted area under
            Schedule
            6 to the Wild Animals Protection Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap170">Cap. 170</ref>).
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2021</ref>)</sourceNote></def></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403274422_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
            2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap499/s4">ss. 4</ref>, <ref href="/hk/cap499/s9">9</ref>, <ref href="/hk/cap499/s10">10</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap499/s26">26</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap499/sch1">Sch. 1</ref>]</note><heading>Designated
            Projects
            Requiring
            Environmental
            Permits</heading><part id="ID_1438412745320_017" name="PI" temporalId="sch2_PI"><num value="I">Part
                I</num><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">A—Carriageways
                    for Motor
                    Vehicles, Railways
                    and
                    Depots</inline></crossHeading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><text></text><section id="ID_1453177007306_001" name="s0" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.1</num><content>A
                    carriageway for motor vehicles that is an expressway, trunk road, primary
                    distributor road or district distributor road. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_002" name="s0-1" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-1" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.2</num><content>A railway and its associated stations.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_003" name="s0-2" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-2" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.3</num><content>A tramway and its associated stations.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_004" name="s0-3" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-3" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.4</num><content>A railway siding, depot, maintenance workshop, marshalling yard or goods
                    yard.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_005" name="s0-4" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-4" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.5</num><leadIn>A tram depot located less than 100 m from the nearest boundary of an
                    existing or planned—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_078" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>residential area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_087" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>place of worship;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_096" name="c" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>educational institution; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_105" name="d" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>health care
                        institution.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_006" name="s0-5" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-5" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.6</num><leadIn>A transport depot located less than
                    100
                    m from the nearest boundary of an existing or planned—
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_121" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>residential area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_130" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>place of worship;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_139" name="c" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>educational institution; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745320_148" name="d" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>health care institution.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_007" name="s0-6" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-6" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.7</num><content>A road
                    tunnel
                    or railway tunnel more than 800 m in length between portals.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_008" name="s0-7" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-7" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.8</num><content>A
                    carriageway bridge for motor vehicles, or a railway bridge, the length between
                    abutments for which is more than 100 m, with bridge piers over the sea
                    supporting the bridge. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77
                            of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_009" name="s0-8" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-8" class="no_header"><num value="0">A.9</num><content>A
                    carriageway
                    for motor vehicles fully enclosed by decking above and by
                    structure on the sides for more than 100 m.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">B—Airports
                    and
                    Port
                    Facilities</inline></crossHeading><text></text><section id="ID_1453177007322_010" name="s0-9" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-9" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.1</num><content>An airport (including its runway and the development and
                    facilities
                    relating to aircraft maintenance, repair, fueling and fuel
                    storage, engine testing or air cargo handling).
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_011" name="s0-10" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-10" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.2</num><content>A helipad
                    (except
                    one provided solely for the provision of firefighting or medical services, or
                    solely for law enforcement, security (including national security), life-saving
                    or otherwise ensuring personal safety, or any other emergency use)
                    within 300 m of existing or planned residential development.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_012" name="s0-11" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-11" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.3</num><content>A container terminal (including its container backup facility).</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_013" name="s0-12" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-12" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.4</num><leadIn>A public cargo working area—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745336_063" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with
                        a cargo working length of more than 1 000 m; or <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745336_072" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>with a cargo working length
                        of
                        more than 500 m and within 50 m of an existing or planned—
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745336_081" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-12_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>residential area;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745336_090" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-12_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>place of worship;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745336_099" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-12_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>educational institution; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745336_108" name="iv" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-12_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>health care institution.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007322_014" name="s0-13" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-13" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.5</num><leadIn>A container backup area, container storage, container handling or container
                    packing area (including a container vehicle parking area) more than 5 ha in size
                    and within 300 m of an existing or planned—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745351_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-13_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>residential area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745351_015" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-13_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>place of worship;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745351_024" name="c" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-13_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>educational institution; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745351_033" name="d" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-13_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>health care institution.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_015" name="s0-14" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-14" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.6</num><content>A
                    ship building or ship repairing yard (including its associated facilities) that
                    is of more than 1 ha in size or with a lifting capacity of more than 20 000
                    tonnes. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_016" name="s0-15" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-15" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.7</num><content> A river trade
                    terminal.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_017" name="s0-16" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-16" class="no_header"><num value="0">B.8</num><content>A mid-stream operation facility.</content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">C—Reclamation, Hydraulic
                    and
                    Marine Facilities,
                    Dredging
                    and
                    Dumping</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007338_018" name="s0-17" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-17" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.1</num><content>Reclamation works (including associated dredging works) more than 5 ha in size.
                    </content></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_019" name="s0-18" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.2</num><subsection id="ID_1688357612873_001" name="1" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Reclamation works (including associated dredging works) that are of more
                        than 1 ha in size, and a boundary of which is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1688357612874_002" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>less than 500 m from the nearest boundary of an existing or planned
                            specified area that is wholly or partly situated on or over any
                            foreshore and sea-bed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1688357612875_003" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>less than 200 m from the nearest boundary of an existing or planned
                            specified area that is not wholly or partly situated on or over any
                            foreshore and sea-bed; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1688357612875_004" name="c" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>less than 100 m from the nearest boundary of an existing
                            residential area.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1688357612876_005" name="2" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In this item—</leadIn><def name="ForeshoreAndSeabed"><term>foreshore and sea-bed</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">前濱及海床</term>) has the meaning given by <ref>section 2</ref> of the
                        Foreshore and Sea-bed (Reclamations) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap127">Cap.
                            127</ref>);</def><def name="SpecifiedArea">
                        <leadIn><term>specified area</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明地區</term>) means—</leadIn>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612878_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>site of special scientific interest;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612879_007" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>site of cultural heritage;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612880_008" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(c)</num><content>bathing beach;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612880_009" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(d)</num><content>marine park;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612881_010" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(e)</num><content>marine reserve;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612882_011" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(f)</num><content>fish culture zone;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612882_012" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(g)</num><content>wild animal protection area;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612883_013" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(h)</num><content>coastal protection area;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612883_014" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(i)</num><content>conservation area;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612884_015" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(j)</num><content>country park; or</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612885_016" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-18_2_a"><num value="a">(k)</num><content>special area. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref> and <ref href="/hk/2023/ln113">L.N.
                                        113 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                    </def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_020" name="s0-19" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-19" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.3</num><leadIn> Reclamation works—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745383_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>resulting in
                        more
                        than
                        5%
                        decrease in cross sectional area calculated on the basis of 0.0 mPD in a sea
                        channel; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007338_021" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>occupying an area on plan
                        of
                        more than
                        10%
                        of any enclosed or semi-enclosed waterbody.
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_023" name="s0-20" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-20" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.4</num><content>A breakwater more than 1 km in length or a breakwater extending into a
                    tidal flushing channel by more than 30% of the channel width.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_024" name="s0-21" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-21" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.5</num><content>A typhoon shelter designed to provide moorings for
                    more
                    than 30 vessels.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_025" name="s0-22" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-22" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.6</num><content>A dam more than 10 m in height.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007338_026" name="s0-23" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-23" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.7</num><content>A land borrow area of more than
                    200
                    000
                        m<sup>3</sup>.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_027" name="s0-24" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.8</num><leadIn> A land borrow area of more than 50 000 m<sup>3</sup> of which—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745383_063" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>a boundary of which is less than 500 m from the nearest boundary of an
                        existing or planned—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745383_072" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>residential area;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745383_081" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>place of worship;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745383_090" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>educational institution;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745383_099" name="iv" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>health care institution;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745383_108" name="v" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_a_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>country park; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745398_008" name="vi" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_a_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>special area; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007353_028" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>wholly or partly within a—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745398_025" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>site of special scientific interest; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745398_034" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-24_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>wild animal protection area.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_029" name="s0-25" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-25" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.9</num><content>A marine borrow area.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_030" name="s0-26" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-26" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.10</num><content>A marine dumping area.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_031" name="s0-27" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-27" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.11</num><content>A public dumping area of
                    more
                    than 2 ha in size.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_032" name="s0-28" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28" class="no_header"><num value="0">C.12</num><subsection id="ID_1688357612967_017" name="1" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A dredging operation that is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1688357612968_018" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with a dredging volume of more than 500 000
                            m<sup>3</sup>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1688357612968_019" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>less than 500 m from the nearest boundary of an existing or planned
                            specified area that is wholly or partly situated on or over any
                            foreshore and sea-bed; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1688357612969_020" name="c" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>less than 200 m from the nearest boundary of an existing or planned
                            specified area that is not wholly or partly situated on or over any
                            foreshore and sea-bed.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1688357612970_021" name="2" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In this item—</leadIn><def name="ForeshoreAndSeabed"><term>foreshore and sea-bed</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">前濱及海床</term>) has the meaning given by <ref>section 2</ref> of the
                        Foreshore and Sea-bed (Reclamations) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap127">Cap.
                            127</ref>);</def><def name="SpecifiedArea">
                        <leadIn><term>specified area</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明地區</term>) means—</leadIn>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612972_022" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>site of special scientific interest;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612975_023" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>site of cultural heritage;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612977_024" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(c)</num><content>bathing beach;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612980_025" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(d)</num><content>marine park;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612980_026" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(e)</num><content>marine reserve;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612981_027" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(f)</num><content>fish culture zone;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612982_028" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(g)</num><content>wild animal protection area;</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612983_029" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(h)</num><content>coastal protection area; or</content></paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="ID_1688357612983_030" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-28_2_a"><num value="a">(i)</num><content>conservation area. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref> and <ref href="/hk/2023/ln113">L.N. 113 of
                                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                    </def></subsection></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">D—Energy
                    Supply</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007353_034" name="s0-29" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-29" class="no_header"><num value="0">D.1</num><content>An
                    electricity power plant running on fossil fuel with a production capacity of
                    more than 100 megawatts. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77
                            of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_035" name="s0-30" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-30" class="no_header"><num value="0">D.2</num><content>A
                    gas generation plant for the production of town gas (as defined by <ref>section
                        2</ref> of the Gas Safety Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap51">Cap. 51</ref>))
                    with a production capacity of more than 10 million
                        m<sup>3</sup>
                    per day. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section name="s0-31" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-31" class="no_header" id="ID_1684825932035_004"><num value="0">D.3</num><content>A wind power plant with a production capacity of more than 100 megawatts.
                        <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">E—Water Extraction
                    and
                    Water
                    Supply</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007353_036" name="s0-32" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-32" class="no_header"><num value="0">E.1</num><content>An
                    impounding reservoir.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_037" name="s0-33" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-33" class="no_header"><num value="0">E.2</num><content>Water treatment works with a
                    storage
                    facility capable of storing more than 500 tonnes of dangerous goods.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007353_038" name="s0-34" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-34" class="no_header"><num value="0">E.3</num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">F—Sewage
                    Collection,
                    Treatment, Disposal
                    and
                    Reuse</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007353_039" name="s0-35" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-35" class="no_header"><num value="0">F.1</num><content>Sewage treatment works with an installed capacity of more than
                    15 000
                        m<sup>3</sup> per day.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_040" name="s0-36" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36" class="no_header"><num value="0">F.2</num><leadIn>Sewage treatment works—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745429_014" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with an installed capacity of more than 5 000 m<sup>3</sup> per day;
                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007369_041" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>a boundary of which is less than 200 m from the nearest boundary of an
                        existing or planned—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_032" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>residential area;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_041" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>place of worship;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_050" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>educational institution;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_059" name="iv" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>health care institution;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_068" name="v" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>site of special scientific interest;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_077" name="vi" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>site of cultural heritage;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_086" name="vii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content>bathing beach;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_095" name="viii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content>marine park;
                            <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_104" name="ix" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content>marine
                            reserve; or <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745429_113" name="x" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-36_b_x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content>fish
                            culture zone. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_042" name="s0-37" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-37" class="no_header"><num value="0">F.3</num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_044" name="s0-38" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-38" class="no_header"><num value="0">F.4</num><content>A
                    facility for generating, from sewage effluent treated by a sewage treatment
                    plant, reclaimed water for use by the general public. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_045" name="s0-39" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-39" class="no_header"><num value="0">F.5</num><content>A submarine sewage pipeline with a diameter of 1 200 mm or more and a
                    length of 1 km or more.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_046" name="s0-40" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-40" class="no_header"><num value="0">F.6</num><content>A submarine sewage outfall.</content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">G—Waste
                    Storage, Transfer
                    and Disposal
                    Facilities</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007369_047" name="s0-41" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-41" class="no_header"><num value="0">G.1</num><content>A landfill for waste as defined in the Waste Disposal Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap354">Cap.
                    354</ref>).</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_048" name="s0-42" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-42" class="no_header"><num value="0">G.2</num><content>A refuse transfer station.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_049" name="s0-43" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-43" class="no_header"><num value="0">G.3</num><content>An incinerator with an installed capacity of more than
                    500
                    tonnes per day.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007369_050" name="s0-44" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-44" class="no_header"><num value="0">G.4</num><leadIn>A waste disposal facility (excluding any refuse collection
                    point)with
                    an installed capacity of more than 500 tonnes per day for the disposal of—
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745461_089" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-44_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>refuse; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007385_051" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-44_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>food,
                        chemical,
                        industrial or special wastes.
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007385_052" name="s0-45" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-45" class="no_header"><num value="0">G.5</num><leadIn>A facility for the treatment of construction waste—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745476_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-45_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with a designed capacity of
                        more
                        than 500 tonnes per day; and
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007385_053" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-45_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>a boundary of which is less than 200 m from
                        the
                        nearest boundary of
                        an
                        existing or planned—
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745476_024" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-45_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>residential area;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745476_033" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-45_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>place of worship;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745476_042" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-45_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>educational institution; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745476_051" name="iv" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-45_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>health care institution.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007385_054" name="s0-46" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-46" class="no_header"><num value="0">G.6</num><content>A waste disposal facility for pulverized fuel ash,
                    furnace
                    bottom ash or gypsum.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">H—Utility
                    Pipelines,
                    Transmission Pipelines
                    and
                    Substations</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007385_055" name="s0-47" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-47" class="no_header"><num value="0">H.1</num><content>A 400 kV electricity substation and transmission line.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007385_056" name="s0-48" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-48" class="no_header"><num value="0">H.2</num><content>A submarine gas pipeline or submarine oil pipeline.</content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                
                
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">I—Waterways
                    and
                    Drainage
                    Works</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007385_057" name="s0-49" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49" class="no_header"><num value="0">I.1</num><leadIn>A drainage channel or river training and diversion works—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745476_115" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with a channel width of more than 100 m; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007385_058" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>located
                        less than 300 m from the nearest boundary of an existing or planned—
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745492_016" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>site of special scientific interest;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745492_025" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>site of cultural heritage;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745492_034" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>marine park;
                            <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="iii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_iii" id="ID_1684825932579_005"><num value="iii">(iiia)</num><content>marine reserve; <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N.
                                    77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745492_043" name="iv" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>fish culture zone;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745492_052" name="v" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>wild animal protection area;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745492_061" name="vi" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>coastal protection area; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745492_070" name="vii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-49_b_vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content>conservation area.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007385_059" name="s0-50" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-50" class="no_header"><num value="0">I.2</num><content>A flood storage pond more than 10 ha in size.</content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">J—Mineral
                    Extraction</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007385_060" name="s0-51" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-51" class="no_header"><num value="0">J.1</num><content>A
                    petroleum or natural gas extraction facility with a production capacity of more
                    than 100 tonnes per day. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77
                            of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007385_061" name="s0-52" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-52" class="no_header"><num value="0">J.2</num><content>A mining
                    operation
                    as construed in accordance with the Mining Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap285">Cap. 285</ref>).
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007385_062" name="s0-53" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-53" class="no_header"><num value="0">J.3</num><content>A
                    surface quarry (being a quarry as defined by <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the
                    Factories and Industrial Undertakings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap59">Cap.
                        59</ref>)) at which ground surface excavation is carried out.
                        <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_063" name="s0-54" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-54" class="no_header"><num value="0">J.4</num><content>A coal industry works with a handling capacity of more than 100 tonnes per
                    day.</content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">K—Industrial
                    Facilities</inline></crossHeading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1453177007400_064" name="s0-55" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-55" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.1</num><content>An industrial estate.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_065" name="s0-56" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-56" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.2</num><content>A brewery works with
                    a
                    production capacity of more than 0.4 million hecto litres per annum.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_066" name="s0-57" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-57" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.3</num><content>A tannery or leather finishing factory with
                    a
                    production capacity of more than 500 000 m<sup>2</sup> per annum.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_067" name="s0-58" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-58" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.4</num><content>A metallurgical works with a
                    production
                    capacity of more than
                    200 000
                    tonnes per annum (expressed as metal).
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_068" name="s0-59" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-59" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.5</num><content>A cement works or concrete batching plant with a total silo capacity of
                    more than 10 000 tonnes in which cement is handled and manufactured.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_069" name="s0-60" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-60" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.6</num><content>A chemical or biochemical plant with a storage capacity of more than 500
                    tonnes and in which substances are processed or produced.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_070" name="s0-61" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-61" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.7</num><content>A
                    petroleum refinery with a production capacity of more than 500 tonnes per day.
                        <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_071" name="s0-62" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-62" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.8</num><content>A petro-chemical plant with
                    a
                    production capacity of more than 70 000 tonnes per annum.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_072" name="s0-63" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-63" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.9</num><content>A tobacco or cigarette manufacturing plant.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_073" name="s0-64" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-64" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.10</num><content>A
                    depot for the storage of, or a manufacturing plant for the manufacture of,
                    explosives (as defined by <ref>section 2</ref> of the Dangerous Goods Ordinance
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap295">Cap. 295</ref>)). <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_074" name="s0-65" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-65" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.11</num><content>A sand depot with a site area of more than 1 ha in size.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007400_075" name="s0-66" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-66" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.12</num><content>A bulk chemical storage facility with a storage capacity of more than 80
                    000 tonnes.
                    </content></section><section id="ID_1453177007416_076" name="s0-67" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-67" class="no_header"><num value="0">K.13</num><content>A dangerous goods godown with a storage capacity
                    of
                    more
                    than
                    500 tonnes.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">L—Storage, Transfer
                    and Trans-Shipment
                    of
                    Fuels</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007416_077" name="s0-68" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-68" class="no_header"><num value="0">L.1</num><content>A storage, transfer and trans-shipment of liquefied petroleum gas facility
                    with a storage capacity
                    of
                    more
                    than 200 tonnes.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007416_078" name="s0-69" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-69" class="no_header"><num value="0">L.2</num><content>A storage, transfer and trans-shipment of liquefied natural gas
                    or
                    hydrogen facility with a storage capacity of more than 200 tonnes.
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007416_079" name="s0-70" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-70" class="no_header"><num value="0">L.3</num><content>A storage, transfer and trans-shipment of coal or ore facility with a
                    storage capacity of
                    more
                    than 200 tonnes.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007416_080" name="s0-71" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-71" class="no_header"><num value="0">L.4</num><content>A storage, transfer and trans-shipment of
                    petroleum
                    facility with a storage capacity of
                    more
                    than 1 000 tonnes.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">M—Agriculture
                    and
                    Fisheries
                    Activities</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007416_081" name="s0-72" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-72" class="no_header"><num value="0">M.1</num><leadIn>A fish culture zone—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745523_103" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-72_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>more than 5 ha in size; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007416_082" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-72_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>a boundary of which is less than 500 m from the nearest boundary of an
                        existing or planned—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412745539_016" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-72_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>marine
                            park; 
                            <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-72_b_i" id="ID_1684825932916_006"><num value="i">(ia)</num><content>marine reserve; or <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1453177007416_083" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-72_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>bathing beach.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">N—Community
                    Facilities</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007416_084" name="s0-73" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-73" class="no_header"><num value="0">N.1</num><content>An abattoir with a daily slaughter capacity of more than 500
                    food
                    animals (as defined by <ref>section 3</ref> of the Slaughterhouses Regulation
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap132BU">Cap. 132 sub. leg. BU</ref>)).
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007416_085" name="s0-74" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-74" class="no_header"><num value="0">N.2</num><content>A quarantine station, or quarantine lairage, for animals.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007416_086" name="s0-75" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-75" class="no_header"><num value="0">N.3</num><content>A wholesale
                    market
                    for fish or livestock.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007416_087" name="s0-76" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-76" class="no_header"><num value="0">N.4</num><content>A crematorium.</content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">O—Tourist
                    and
                    Recreational
                    Developments</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007431_088" name="s0-77" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-77" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.1</num><content>An outdoor golf course and all managed turf areas.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007431_089" name="s0-78" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-78" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.2</num><content>A marina designed to provide moorings
                    for
                    more
                    than 30 vessels used primarily for pleasure or recreation.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007431_090" name="s0-79" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-79" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.3</num><content>An
                    open air venue designed for horse racing with a capacity to accommodate more
                    than 10 000 persons. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007431_091" name="s0-80" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-80" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.4</num><content>An
                    outdoor motor racing circuit (including one provided solely for training).
                        <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1453177007431_092" name="s0-81" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-81" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.5</num><content>An open firing range.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007431_093" name="s0-82" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-82" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.6</num><content>An open air concert venue with a capacity to accommodate more than 10 000
                    persons.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007431_094" name="s0-83" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-83" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.7</num><content>An outdoor sporting facility with a capacity to accommodate more than 10
                    000 persons.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007431_095" name="s0-84" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-84" class="no_header"><num value="0">O.8</num><content>A theme park or amusement park with a site area of more than 20 ha in size.
                        <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1999/ln205">L.N. 205 of
                        1999</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">P—Residential
                    and
                    Other
                    Developments</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007463_096" name="s0-85" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-85" class="no_header"><num value="0">P.1</num><content>A residential or recreational development, other than New Territories
                    exempted houses within Deep Bay Buffer Zone 1 or 2.</content></section><section id="ID_1453177007463_097" name="s0-86" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-86" class="no_header"><num value="0">P.2</num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><text>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </text><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Q—Miscellaneous</inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1453177007463_099" name="s0-87" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87" class="no_header"><num value="0">Q.1</num><leadIn>All projects
                    involving
                    earthworks, dredging works and other building works partly or wholly in an
                    existing or gazetted proposed country park or special area, a conservation area,
                    an existing or gazetted proposed marine park or marine reserve, a site of
                    cultural heritage, and a site of special scientific interest, except for the following—
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>minor maintenance works to roads,
                        sewers,
                        slopes, public lightings (including their associated cabling) or utilities;
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_b" id="ID_1684825933083_007"><num value="b">(ab)</num><content>minor maintenance works (including desilting works) relating to a
                        drainage channel or river; <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N.
                                77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_015" name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the
                        installation of telecommunications wires, joint boxes, power lines with a
                        voltage level of not more than 66 kV,
                        or
                        gas pipelines with a diameter of 120 mm or less;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/36">36 of 2000 s.
                                28</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>) </sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_024" name="c" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>educational,
                        recreational or public
                        enjoyment
                        facilities not otherwise designated projects listed in Parts A to P and
                        approved by the Country and Marine Parks Authority;
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_033" name="d" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>all earthworks relating to forestry, agriculture, fisheries
                        or
                        the management of vegetation or habitat;
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_042" name="e" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>New
                        Territories exempted houses or their associated structures or facilities
                        (including drainage and sewerage); <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_051" name="f" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>footpaths
                        or sitting out areas, or their associated facilities; <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_060" name="g" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>facilities
                        (including firefighting, power supply or water supply facilities, toilets
                        and sewers (including their associated sewage treatment facilities)) or
                        works (including slope, drainage and road works) relating to the management
                        and protection of marine parks, marine reserves, country parks, sites of
                        special scientific interest, conservation areas or special areas;
                            <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745570_069" name="h" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>all works not otherwise designated projects listed in Parts A to P
                        undertaken by the Country and Marine Parks Authority under <ref>section
                            4</ref> of the Country Parks Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap208">Cap.
                            208</ref>) or <ref>section 4</ref> of the Marine Parks Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap476">Cap. 476</ref>) for developing and managing
                        country
                        parks, special areas, marine parks or marine reserves;
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745585_007" name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>maintenance
                        of, or improvement works to, existing waterworks; <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1453177007510_100" name="j" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>works involving trench excavation (with a trench width of not more than
                        1.5 m) for the provision of underground water or sewage pipes (including any
                        associated works for fittings or valves); <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i" id="ID_1684825933388_008"><num value="i">(k)</num><leadIn>the following works that do not involve trench excavation—</leadIn><subparagraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i_i" id="ID_1684825933389_009"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>works for the provision of underground water or sewage pipes;
                            or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="ii" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i_ii" id="ID_1684825933390_010"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>works for the provision of above ground water or sewage pipes with
                            a diameter of 450 mm or less (including any associated works for
                            fittings or valves); <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N.
                                    77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i" id="ID_1684825933407_011"><num value="i">(l)</num><content>works for the provision of water tanks; <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i" id="ID_1684825933424_012"><num value="i">(m)</num><content>works for the provision of hydrological stations (including any
                        associated works); <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i" id="ID_1684825933441_013"><num value="i">(n)</num><content>works carried out for village supply schemes, including schemes for
                        electricity or gas supply, telecommunications, public lightings (including
                        their associated cabling), water supply and sewerage; or <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-87_i" id="ID_1684825933458_014"><num value="i">(o)</num><content>helipads, or any other facilities, provided solely for the provision of
                        firefighting or medical services, or solely for law enforcement, security
                        (including national security), life-saving or otherwise ensuring personal
                        safety, or any other emergency use. <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1453177007510_103" name="s0-88" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88" class="no_header"><num value="0">Q.2</num><leadIn>An underground rock cavern with a portal that is less than 100 m from the
                    nearest boundary of an existing or planned—</leadIn><paragraph name="a" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_a" id="ID_1684825933476_015"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>residential area;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="b" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_b" id="ID_1684825933477_016"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>place of worship;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="c" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_c" id="ID_1684825933477_017"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>educational institution;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="d" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_d" id="ID_1684825933478_018"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>health care institution;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="e" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_e" id="ID_1684825933479_019"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>site of special scientific interest;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="f" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_f" id="ID_1684825933479_020"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>site of cultural heritage;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="g" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_g" id="ID_1684825933480_021"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>country park;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="h" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_h" id="ID_1684825933481_022"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>special area;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_i" id="ID_1684825933481_023"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>conservation area;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="j" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_j" id="ID_1684825933482_024"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>bathing beach;</content></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_i" id="ID_1684825933482_025"><num value="i">(k)</num><content>marine park; or</content></paragraph><paragraph name="i" temporalId="sch2_PI_s0-88_i" id="ID_1684825933483_026"><num value="i">(l)</num><content>marine reserve. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77
                                of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438412745601_027" name="PII" temporalId="sch2_PII"><num value="II">Part
                II</num><heading>Decommissioning
                Projects</heading><section id="ID_1438412745601_046" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_PII_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Airports, including fueling and fuel storage, the aircraft maintenance and
                    repair
                    facilities.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_054" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_PII_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>A
                    petroleum refinery with a production capacity of more than 500 tonnes per day.
                        <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_062" name="s3" temporalId="sch2_PII_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>A municipal, chemical or clinical waste
                    incinerator
                    with an installed capacity of more than 500 tonnes per
                    day.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_070" name="s4" temporalId="sch2_PII_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><content>An
                    electricity power plant running on fossil fuel with a production capacity of
                    more than 100 megawatts. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77
                            of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_078" name="s5" temporalId="sch2_PII_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><content>A
                    gas generation plant for the production of town gas (as defined by <ref>section
                        2</ref> of the Gas Safety Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap51">Cap. 51</ref>))
                    with a production capacity of more than 10 million m<sup>3</sup> per day.
                        <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_086" name="s6" temporalId="sch2_PII_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_094" name="s7" temporalId="sch2_PII_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><content>An installation for storage or disposal of radioactive
                    waste.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_102" name="s8" temporalId="sch2_PII_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><content>A waste disposal facility for
                    pulverized
                    fuel ash, furnace bottom ash or
                    gypsum.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745601_110" name="s9" temporalId="sch2_PII_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><content>A metallurgical works with
                    a
                    production capacity of more than 200
                    000 tonnes per annum (expressed as
                    metal).</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_004" name="s10" temporalId="sch2_PII_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><content>A petro-chemical
                    plant
                    with a production capacity of more than 70 000 tonnes per
                    annum.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_012" name="s11" temporalId="sch2_PII_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><content>A
                    depot for the storage of, or a manufacturing plant for the manufacture of,
                    explosives (as defined by <ref>section 2</ref> of the Dangerous Goods Ordinance
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap295">Cap. 295</ref>)). <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_020" name="s12" temporalId="sch2_PII_s12" class="no_header"><num value="12">12.</num><content>A bulk chemical storage
                    facility
                    with a storage capacity of more than 80 000
                    tonnes.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_028" name="s13" temporalId="sch2_PII_s13" class="no_header"><num value="13">13.</num><content>A store for liquefied petroleum gas with a storage capacity
                    of
                    more than 200
                    tonnes.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_036" name="s14" temporalId="sch2_PII_s14" class="no_header"><num value="14">14.</num><content>A store for liquefied natural gas
                    or
                    hydrogen with a storage capacity of more than 200
                    tonnes.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_044" name="s15" temporalId="sch2_PII_s15" class="no_header"><num value="15">15.</num><content>A store for coal and
                    ore
                    with a storage capacity of more than 200
                    tonnes.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_052" name="s16" temporalId="sch2_PII_s16" class="no_header"><num value="16">16.</num><content>A store for
                    petroleum
                    with a storage capacity of more than 1 000
                    tonnes.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745617_060" name="s17" temporalId="sch2_PII_s17" class="no_header"><num value="17">17.</num><content>A
                    ship building or ship repairing yard (including its associated facilities) that
                    is of more than 1 ha in size or with a lifting capacity of more than 20 000
                    tonnes. <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                        2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></part></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403274453_001" name="sch3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="sch3"><num value="3">Schedule
            3</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap499/s4">ss. 4</ref>, <ref href="/hk/cap499/s9">9</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap499/s26">26</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap499/sch1">Sch. 1</ref>]</note><heading>Major
            Designated
            Projects
            Requiring
            Environmental
            Impact
            Assessment
            Reports</heading><section id="ID_1438412745851_020" name="s1" temporalId="sch3_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>An
                urban development or redevelopment project covering an area of more than 50 ha.
                    <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></section><section id="ID_1438412745851_028" name="s2" temporalId="sch3_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2023/ln77">L.N. 77 of
                    2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403274453_003" name="sch4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="sch4"><num value="4">Schedule
            4</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap499/s10">s. 10</ref>]</note><heading>Matters
            that
            may be Specified
            in
            Environmental
            Permit</heading><section id="ID_1438412745866_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch4_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The design, alignment, plan, layout or visual appearance of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745866_020" name="s2" temporalId="sch4_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The physical scale, scope or extent of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745866_028" name="s3" temporalId="sch4_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The methods for carrying out a designated project or the timing, phasing or
                order of the stages of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745866_036" name="s4" temporalId="sch4_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><content>The amount, rate or quality of a discharge, emission or deposit of pollutants
                or wastes from a designated project, including the colour or temperature of, or
                amount or concentration of, a contaminant, impurity or other substance in, the
                discharge, emission or
                deposit.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745866_044" name="s5" temporalId="sch4_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><content>Limits on the strength, severity or level of the environmental impact of a
                designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745882_004" name="s6" temporalId="sch4_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><leadIn>The mitigation of the environmental impact of a designated project, and the
                timing, phasing or order of mitigation measures, including—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745882_014" name="a" temporalId="sch4_s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>pollution control or environmental protection equipment, processes,
                    systems, practices or technologies;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745882_023" name="b" temporalId="sch4_s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>equipment, processes, systems, practices or technologies for the
                    prevention, reduction, reuse, recovery and recycling of wastes or
                    wastewater;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745882_032" name="c" temporalId="sch4_s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>equipment, processes, systems, practices or technologies for the management
                    of wastes, including the storage, treatment or disposal of wastes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745882_041" name="d" temporalId="sch4_s6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>acoustic barriers and enclosures, noise insulation equipment, or equipment,
                    processes, systems, practices or technologies for the avoidance, prevention,
                    reduction, minimization or control of noise;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745882_050" name="e" temporalId="sch4_s6_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>equipment, processes, systems, practices or technologies for the avoidance,
                    prevention, reduction, minimization or control of air pollution; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745882_059" name="f" temporalId="sch4_s6_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>processes, systems, practices, procedures or technologies for the
                    conservation, preservation or protection of flora, fauna, ecological habitats,
                    sites of special scientific interest, or of cultural heritage importance, or
                    resources.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438412745897_004" name="s7" temporalId="sch4_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><content>Pollution control, environmental protection or other mitigation measures to be
                carried out outside the site of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745897_012" name="s8" temporalId="sch4_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><content>Compensation or restoration measures for the conservation, preservation or
                protection of flora, fauna, ecological habitat or other ecological resources,
                including replanting, relocation, re-establishment or rehabilitation measures, to
                mitigate an adverse environmental impact of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745897_020" name="s9" temporalId="sch4_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><content>Landscaping measures to mitigate the environmental impact of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745897_028" name="s10" temporalId="sch4_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><leadIn>Programmes or exercises for monitoring the environmental impact of a designated
                project or the effectiveness of measures to mitigate its environmental impact,
                whether such impact may occur within or outside its physical boundary or site, and
                the review and audit of data and information derived from such programmes or
                exercises, including specification of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412745897_038" name="a" temporalId="sch4_s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the parameters or impact to be monitored;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745913_004" name="b" temporalId="sch4_s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the frequency of monitoring, or the procedures, practices, methods or
                    equipment to be used for monitoring, including the maintenance and calibration
                    of such equipment and quality assurance and laboratory accreditation
                    procedures;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745913_013" name="c" temporalId="sch4_s10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the standards or criteria to be used for evaluating and auditing monitoring
                    data;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745913_022" name="d" temporalId="sch4_s10_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>plans and procedures for action in response to the results of such
                    monitoring programmes or exercises, including action to intensify or increase
                    monitoring, inspect or investigate revealed or indicated problems, or take
                    remedial measures to address such problems;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412745913_031" name="e" temporalId="sch4_s10_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the nature, format or frequency of the reporting of the results and
                    findings of monitoring or action plans and
                    procedures.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438412745913_037" name="s11" temporalId="sch4_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><content>Equipment, methods, processes, systems, procedures or practices for the
                construction, operation, use, implementation or decommissioning of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745913_045" name="s12" temporalId="sch4_s12" class="no_header"><num value="12">12.</num><content>Requirements for the training, qualifications or expertise of personnel
                involved in the carrying out of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745929_004" name="s13" temporalId="sch4_s13" class="no_header"><num value="13">13.</num><content>The preparation of management plans, procedures manuals or other materials and
                documents for guiding and regulating the carrying out of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745929_012" name="s14" temporalId="sch4_s14" class="no_header"><num value="14">14.</num><content>Environmental studies, investigation or information to be obtained and
                submitted during the carrying out of a designated
                project.</content></section><text><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><section id="ID_1438412745929_020" name="s15" temporalId="sch4_s15" class="no_header"><num value="15">15.</num><content>The release to the public of reports on monitoring or auditing work or other
                reports or information in relation to the assessment or carrying out of a designated
                project.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745929_028" name="s16" temporalId="sch4_s16" class="no_header"><num value="16">16.</num><content>The requirements for carrying out of environmental monitoring by accredited
                laboratories, or environmental audit by qualified
                personnel.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412745929_036" name="s17" temporalId="sch4_s17" class="no_header"><num value="17">17.</num><content>The requirements of the implementation and completion of mitigation measures to
                be checked and certified by qualified personnel, and for the submission of certified
                reports on the status of the implementation of mitigation measures.</content></section></schedule><schedule name="sch5" temporalId="sch5" startPeriod="2025-04-11" status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1744169931160_001"><num value="5">Schedule 5</num><note role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap499/s13">s.
            13</ref>]</note><heading>Arrangements Regarding Evaluation of Air Quality Impact for
                <ref>Section 13(5A)</ref> on Account of Amendments to Air Quality Objectives by
                <ref>Section 13</ref> of Air Pollution Control (Amendment) Ordinance
                2025</heading><sourceNote>(<ref>Schedule 5</ref> added <ref href="/hk/2025/5">5 of
                2025 s. 25</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1744613745605_001" name="s1" temporalId="sch5_s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Schedule—</leadIn><def name="2025Ordinance"><term>2025 Ordinance</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">《2025年條例》</term>) means the Air Pollution Control (Amendment) Ordinance 2025
                    (<ref href="hk/2025/5">5 of 2025</ref>);</def><def name="AmendedAirQualityObjectives"><term>amended air quality objectives</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經修訂空氣質素指標</term>) means the air quality objectives
                as amended by <ref>section 13</ref> of the 2025 Ordinance;</def><def name="CommencementDate">*<term>commencement date</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">生效日期</term>) means the date on which <ref>section 13</ref>
                of the 2025 Ordinance comes into operation;</def><def name="PreamendedAirQualityObjectives"><term>pre-amended air quality
                    objectives</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">原有空氣質素指標</term>) means the air
                quality objectives as in force immediately before the commencement date;</def><def name="TransitionalPeriod"><term>transitional period</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">過渡期</term>) means the period of 36 months beginning on the
                commencement date.</def><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1744613745652_011">
                <content>Editorial Note:</content>
                <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 11 April
                    2025.</content>
            </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1744613745621_002" name="s2" temporalId="sch5_s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Application of air quality objectives to applications under <ref>section
                    13(1)</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1744613745621_003" name="1" temporalId="sch5_s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>This section applies to an application for a variation of the conditions of
                    an environmental permit under <ref>section 13(1)</ref> if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1744613745621_004" name="a" temporalId="sch5_s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the environmental permit was issued before the commencement date;
                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1744613745621_005" name="b" temporalId="sch5_s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the application is made before the expiry of the transitional
                        period.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1744613745636_006" name="2" temporalId="sch5_s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For an application mentioned in subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1744613745636_007" name="a" temporalId="sch5_s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>the pre-amended air quality objectives continue to have effect as a
                        criterion for evaluating air quality impact under <ref>section 1</ref>.1(a)
                        of Annex 4 to the technical memorandum for the purposes of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1744613745636_008" name="1" temporalId="sch5_s2_2_a_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content><ref>sections 5</ref>, <ref>6</ref>, <ref>7</ref> and <ref>8</ref>,
                            as applied in relation to the application because of <ref>section
                                13(4)</ref>; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1744613745636_009" name="2" temporalId="sch5_s2_2_a_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content><ref>section 13(5)(b)</ref>; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1744613745652_010" name="b" temporalId="sch5_s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the amended air quality objectives do not have effect as such a
                        criterion for those purposes.</content></paragraph></subsection></section></schedule></main></ordinance>