<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 332 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>332A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap332A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-04-23</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403019284_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-04-23">Trade
                                    Union Registration Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap332/s59">Cap.
                                                332,
                                                section
                                    59</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 April 1962]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403019284_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These regulations may be cited as the Trade Union Registration Regulations.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019299_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Contents of the register</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969765_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The following particulars regarding any trade union or trade union federation shall be recorded by or at the direction of the Registrar in the register—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969765_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the name and the date of registration of the trade union or trade union federation and its rules;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969765_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the address of the head office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969765_028" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the amalgamation of the trade union or trade union federation, as the case may be, with any other trade union or trade union federation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969765_036" name="d" temporalId="s2_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the dissolution of the trade union or trade union federation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969765_044" name="e" temporalId="s2_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the cancellation of the registration of the trade union or trade union federation; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969765_052" name="f" temporalId="s2_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><leadIn>any change in—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969765_060" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_f_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the name;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969765_068" name="ii" temporalId="s2_1_f_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the rules; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969765_076" name="iii" temporalId="s2_1_f_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the address of the registered office, of the trade union or trade union federation.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969780_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every entry in the register and any amendment thereto shall be signed or initialled by the Registrar or the Deputy Registrar of Trade Unions.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019299_004" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Inspection of register</heading><content>The register may, on application in writing to the Registrar, be inspected, free of charge, at the Registry of Trade Unions during office hours, by any member of the public.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019315_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Inspection of accounts, etc. of registered trade unions</heading><content>Any member of a registered trade union may, on application in writing to the Registrar, inspect free of charge, at the Registry of Trade Unions during office hours, any documents, being documents required by law to be filed with the Registrar, relating to such registered trade union or to any registered trade union federation to which such registered trade union is a party.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019330_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Provisions as to submission for registration of rules on application for registration of trade union</heading><leadIn>Where rules are sent to the Registrar for registration by a trade union or trade union federation that has applied for registration under the Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969827_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>two copies of the rules shall be sent; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969827_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a trade union, both copies of the same shall be signed by each of the persons who has signed the application for registration of the trade union or, if, by reason of death or illness or any other good cause, any such person is unable or ineligible to sign such copies, by some other voting member of such trade union; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969827_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of a trade union federation, both copies of the same shall be signed by the chairman and one other officer of each of the registered trade unions comprised therein.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/ln44">L.N. 44 of 1971</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019330_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Documents to be issued on registration of a trade union</heading><leadIn>Upon the registration of a trade union or a trade union federation, the Registrar shall issue to the trade union or the trade union federation, as the case may be, the following documents—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969843_049" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a copy of the Ordinance and of these regulations;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969843_057" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a certificate of registration; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969843_065" name="c" temporalId="s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a copy of the rules of the trade union or trade union federation certified by the Registrar as complying, in his opinion, with the provisions of <ref>section 18</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403019346_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Use of name</heading><content>No registered trade union or registered trade union federation shall display or otherwise in any manner make use of any name purporting to be the name of the trade union or of the federation except the name under which such trade union or such trade union federation is for the time being registered.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019346_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Application for registration of change of name to be accompanied by certificate of registration</heading><content>Where, in accordance with <ref>section 23</ref> of the Ordinance, application is made to the Registrar for the registration of a change of the name of any registered trade union or registered trade union federation, the certificate of registration issued in respect of such trade union or trade union federation shall be sent to the Registrar at the same time as such application is made.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019362_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Procedure on registration of change of name</heading><leadIn>Where, under <ref>section 23</ref> of the Ordinance, the Registrar registers a change of the name of any registered trade union or registered trade union federation, he shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969905_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>amend, accordingly, the certificate of registration issued by him in respect of the trade union or trade union federation, and return such certificate to the trade union or trade union federation; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969905_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if he thinks fit, issue a new certificate of registration.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403019362_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Provisions as to submission for registration of wholly new rules or altered, amended or added rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969921_012" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where wholly new rules are sent to the Registrar for registration by a registered trade union—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969921_020" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>two copies of the rules shall be sent;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/ln44">L.N. 44 of 1971</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969921_028" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an application for the registration thereof shall be made in the prescribed form and shall be signed by the chairman and one other officer of such trade union; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969921_036" name="c" temporalId="s10_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>both copies of such rules shall be signed by not less than
                    7
                    voting members of the trade union.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/ln44">L.N. 44 of
                        1971</ref>; <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969921_043" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where an alteration to or amendment of a registered rule, or an addition to the registered rules, of a registered trade union is sent to the Registrar for registration by a registered trade union—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969921_051" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an application for the registration of the amended or altered rule or the rule so added shall be made in the prescribed form and shall be signed by the chairman and one other officer of the trade union; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969936_006" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>there shall be sent to the Registrar at the same time as such application for registration—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969936_014" name="i" temporalId="s10_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>one copy of the registered rules marked so as to indicate the alteration, amendment or addition, as the case may be; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969936_022" name="ii" temporalId="s10_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>one copy of the text of the amendment, alteration or addition, as the
                        case may be, which shall be signed by not less than
                        7
                        voting members of the trade union.
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019377_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Procedure on registration of amalgamation of trade unions, etc.</heading><leadIn>Where, under <ref>section 6</ref> of the Ordinance, the Registrar registers a trade union or trade union federation formed by the amalgamation of two or more trade unions or trade union federations, as the case may be, he shall issue—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969952_073" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>one certificate of registration in the name under which such trade unions or trade union federations are amalgamated; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969968_006" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy of the rules of the trade union or trade union federation certified by him as complying, in his opinion, with the provisions of <ref>section 18</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403019393_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Loss, etc. of certificate</heading><content>If the Registrar is satisfied that a certificate of registration has been lost, destroyed or defaced, he may issue, free of charge, a duplicate thereof.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019393_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Certificate of registration to be returned on cancellation of
            registration</heading><content>Where the registration of a registered trade union or a registered trade union
            federation is cancelled, the person for the time being having custody of the certificate
            of registration of the trade union or trade union federation shall, within
            14
            days of the publication in the Gazette, in accordance with <ref>section 66</ref> of the
            Ordinance, of a notice of the fact that the registration has been cancelled, return such
            certificate to the Registrar.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019408_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Accounts of trade union to include accounts of any branch, etc., thereof</heading><content>Every registered trade union shall include in its statement of account the accounts of any branch of the trade union and of every business or charitable, cultural, educational or medical undertaking that is operated by or in the name of the trade union.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/ln44">L.N. 44 of 1971</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019408_004" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Access to books for purposes of audit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411970030_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every auditor approved by the Registrar for the purpose of auditing the annual statement of account, required by <ref>section 36</ref> of the Ordinance, of a trade union or trade union federation shall be granted access by every person having the custody or control of any of the books and accounts of the trade union or trade union federation to all of such books and accounts in his custody or control.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411970030_012" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall conceal any book or account of a registered trade union or registered trade union federation from any such auditor or deny any such auditor access to any such book or account or obstruct any such auditor in any examination thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019424_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Audit of annual statement of account</heading><leadIn>Every auditor approved by the Registrar for the purpose of auditing the annual statement of account, required by <ref>section 36</ref> of the Ordinance, of a registered trade union or registered trade union federation shall examine every balance sheet and every statement of receipts and expenditure of the trade union or trade union federation relevant to the period under audit and shall verify them against all accounts or vouchers relating thereto, and shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411970061_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if such be the case, sign the annual statement of account as exhibiting a true and correct view of the affairs of the trade union or trade union federation; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411970061_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>report in writing to the Registrar in what respect he finds such statement of account to be incorrect, unsupported by vouchers or not in accordance with any requirement of the Ordinance or any regulations made thereunder or any rules of the trade union or trade union federation, as the case may be.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403019424_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Offences and penalty</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411970077_026" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who contravenes <ref>regulation 13</ref> shall be guilty of an
                offence and shall be liable to a fine
                at
                level 1, and shall be liable in addition to a fine of
                $10
                for each day during which it is proved to the satisfaction of the court that the
                offence has continued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411970092_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who contravenes paragraph (2) of <ref>regulation 15</ref> shall be
                guilty of an offence and shall be liable to a fine
                at
                level 1.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411970092_013" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any trade union or trade union federation that contravenes <ref>regulation
                    7</ref> shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction
                to a fine
                at
                level 1.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411970092_021" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any trade union that contravenes <ref>regulation 14</ref> shall be guilty of an
                offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1971/ln44">L.N. 44 of
                    1971</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></main></subLeg>