<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 558 sub. leg. B</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>558B</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap558B!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-02-06</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403442400_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-02-06">International
                                    Organizations
                                    (Privileges
                                    and
                                    Immunities)
                                    (World
                                    Trade
                                    Organization)
                                    Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap558/s3">Cap.
                                                558, section
                                    3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                                2020</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[7 July 2005]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403442400_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                        2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403442415_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order—</leadIn><def name="1947Convention"><term>1947
                Convention</term>
                (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">1947年公約</term>》) means the Convention on the
            Privileges and Immunities of the Specialized Agencies, approved by the General Assembly
            of the United Nations by resolution adopted on 21 November 1947;</def><def name="WTO"><term>WTO</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">世貿組織</term>) means the World Trade Organization
            established in Geneva on 1 January 1995 under the Marrakesh Agreement Establishing the
            World Trade Organization signed at Marrakesh on 15 April 1994.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403442415_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Provisions of 1947 Convention have force of law in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413323062_025" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It is declared that the provisions of the 1947 Convention as specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall have the force of law in Hong Kong and shall for that purpose be construed in accordance with the other provisions of this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323078_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In applying those provisions of the 1947 Convention—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413323078_013" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a reference to any specialized agency, however expressed, shall be construed as a reference to the WTO, and, without limiting the generality of the foregoing, the reference to “meetings convened by a specialized agency” in <ref>section 1(vi)</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed accordingly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323078_021" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a reference to any member, however expressed and whether with or without reference to any specialized agency (with the exception of <ref>section 13(f)</ref> of the 1947 Convention), shall be construed as a reference to a WTO member, and, without limiting the generality of the foregoing, the reference to “representatives of members” in <ref>section 1(v)</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed accordingly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323094_006" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438413323094_009" name="i" temporalId="s3_2_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the reference to “will not be sold in the country into which they were imported except under conditions agreed to with the Government of that country” in <ref>section 9(b)</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed as a reference to “will not be sold in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China except under conditions agreed to with the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China”;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413323109_007" name="ii" temporalId="s3_2_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the reference to “Have the right to import free of duty their furniture and effects at the time of first taking up their post in the country in question” in <ref>section 19(f)</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed as a reference to “Have the right to import free of duty their furniture and effects at the time of first taking up their post in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China”;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323125_006" name="d" temporalId="s3_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the reference to “the territory of each State party to this Convention in respect of that agency” in <ref>section 11</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed as a reference to the area of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323125_014" name="e" temporalId="s3_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the reference to “the Government of such State” in <ref>section 11</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed as a reference to the Central People’s Government of the People’s Republic of China;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323140_006" name="f" temporalId="s3_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>without prejudice to the generality of paragraph (a), the reference to “Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the adoption of appropriate security precautions to be determined by agreement between a State party to this Convention and a specialized agency” in <ref>section 12</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed as a reference to “Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the adoption of appropriate security precautions to be determined by agreement between the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the WTO”;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323156_006" name="g" temporalId="s3_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>notwithstanding the generality of paragraph (b), the reference to “present
                    in a member State” in <ref>section 15</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be
                    construed as a reference to “present in the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region of the People’s Republic of
                    China”;<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323156_014" name="h" temporalId="s3_2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content><ref>section 17</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed as if it read as follows: “The provisions of <ref>sections 13(a)</ref>, (b), (c) and (f), 14 and 15 are not applicable in relation to the authorities of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China in the case where the person concerned is a permanent resident of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China or is or has been a representative of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China.”;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323187_006" name="i" temporalId="s3_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the reference to “<ref>sections 19</ref> <fillIn class=" width_7">.</fillIn>” in <ref>section 21</ref> of the 1947 Convention shall be construed as a reference to “<ref>section 19(a)</ref>, (b) and (f)”.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323187_013" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the avoidance of doubt, a reference to any functions or duties of the representatives of WTO members in <ref>sections 13</ref> and <ref>14</ref> of the 1947 Convention means the functions or duties, as the case may be, of such representatives as referred to in those sections, which are construed in accordance with subsection (2), relating to the meetings convened by the WTO.</content></subsection></section><schedule id="ID_1438403442431_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap558B/s3">s. 3</ref>]</note><heading>Provisions
            of 1947
            Convention
            Having
            Force
            of
            Law
            in
            Hong
            Kong</heading><crossHeading><i>Article I—Definitions and Scope</i></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i><ref>Section 1</ref></i></inline></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0">In this
            Convention:<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1504767688845_001" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">(iv)</num><content>For the purposes of article III, the words “<term class="old_format">property
                    and assets</term>” shall also include property and funds administered by a
                specialized agency in furtherance of its constitutional functions.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1504767688845_002" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">(v) </num><content>For the purposes of articles V
                    <fillIn class=" width_9">.</fillIn>,
                the expression “<term class="old_format">representatives of members</term>” shall be
                deemed to include all representatives, alternates, advisers, technical experts and
                secretaries of delegations.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1504767688861_003" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">(vi)</num><content>In <ref>sections 13</ref>, <ref>14</ref>, <ref>15</ref>
                <fillIn class=" width_9">.</fillIn>, the expression “<term class="old_format">meetings
                    convened by a specialized agency</term>” means meetings: (1) of its assembly and
                of its executive body (however designated), and (2) of any commission provided for
                in its constitution; (3) of any international conference convened by it; and (4) of
                any committee of any of these bodies.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1504767688861_004" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">(vii) </num><content>The term “<term class="old_format">executive head</term>” means the principal
                executive official of the specialized agency in question, whether designated
                “Director-General” or
                otherwise.</content></paragraph><text>
            <center><inline class="not_bold">...</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><crossHeading><i>Article II—Juridical Personality</i></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i><ref>Section
            3</ref></i></inline></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified"><marker role="blank-line"></marker>The
            specialized agencies shall possess juridical personality. They shall have the capacity
            (a)
            to contract,
            (b)
            to acquire and dispose of immovable and movable property,
            (c)
            to institute legal
            proceedings.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><i>Article III—Property, Funds and Assets</i></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i><ref>Section
            4</ref></i></inline></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified"><marker role="blank-line"></marker>The
            specialized agencies, their property and assets, wherever located and by whomsoever
            held, shall enjoy immunity from every form of legal process except in so far as in any
            particular case they have expressly waived their immunity. It is, however, understood
            that no waiver of immunity shall extend to any measure of
            execution.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                5</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The premises of the
            specialized agencies shall be inviolable. The property and assets of the specialized
            agencies, wherever located and by whomsoever held, shall be immune from search,
            requisition, confiscation, expropriation and any other form of interference, whether by
            executive, administrative, judicial or legislative
            action.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                6</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The archives of the
            specialized agencies, and in general all documents belonging to them or held by them,
            shall be inviolable, wherever
            located.</text><text>
            <center><inline class="not_bold">...</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                9</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The specialized agencies,
            their assets, income and other property shall
            be:</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(a)
            Exempt from all direct taxes; it is understood, however, that the specialized agencies
            will not claim exemption from taxes which are, in fact, no more than charges for public
            utility services;</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(b)
            Exempt from customs duties and prohibitions and restrictions on imports and exports in
            respect of articles imported or exported by the specialized agencies for their official
            use; it is understood, however, that articles imported under such exemption will not be
            sold in the country into which they were imported except under conditions agreed to with
            the Government of that country;</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(c)
            Exempt from duties and prohibitions and restrictions on imports and exports in respect
            of their
            publications.</text><text>
            <center><inline class="not_bold">...</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><crossHeading><i>Article IV—Facilities in respect of Communications</i></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i><ref>Section 11</ref></i></inline></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">Each specialized agency
            shall enjoy, in the territory of each State party to this Convention in respect of that
            agency, for its official communications, treatment not less favourable than that
            accorded by the Government of such State to any other Government, including the latter’s
            diplomatic mission in the matter of priorities, rates and taxes on mails, cables,
            telegrams, radiograms, telephotos, telephone and other communications, and press rates
            for information to the press and
            radio.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                12</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">No censorship shall be
            applied to the official correspondence and other official communications of the
            specialized
            agencies.</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The specialized agencies
            shall have the right to use codes and to dispatch and receive correspondence by courier
            or in sealed bags, which shall have the same immunities and privileges as diplomatic
            couriers and bags.</text><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the adoption of appropriate
            security precautions to be determined by agreement between a State party to this
            Convention and a specialized
            agency.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><i>Article V—Representatives of Members</i></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i><ref>Section
            13</ref></i></inline></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified"><marker role="blank-line"></marker>Representatives
            of members at meetings convened by a specialized agency shall, while exercising their
            functions and during their journeys to and from the place of meeting, enjoy the
            following privileges and
            immunities:</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(a)
            Immunity from personal arrest or detention and from seizure of their personal baggage,
            and in respect of words spoken or written and all acts done by them in their official
            capacity, immunity from legal process of every kind;</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(b)
            Inviolability for all papers and documents;</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(c)
            The right to use codes and to receive papers or correspondence by courier or in sealed
            bags;</text><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(f)
            The same immunities and facilities in respect of their personal baggage as are accorded
            to members of comparable rank of diplomatic
            missions.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                14</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">In order to secure for the
            representatives of members of the specialized agencies at meetings convened by them
            complete freedom of speech and complete independence in the discharge of their duties,
            the immunity from legal process in respect of words spoken or written and all acts done
            by them in discharging their duties shall continue to be accorded, notwithstanding that
            the persons concerned are no longer engaged in the discharge of such
            duties.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                15</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">Where the incidence of any
            form of taxation depends upon residence, periods during which the representatives of
            members of the specialized agencies at meetings convened by them are present in a member
            State for the discharge of their duties shall not be considered as periods of
            residence.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                16</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">Privileges and immunities
            are accorded to the representatives of members, not for the personal benefit of the
            individuals themselves, but in order to safeguard the independent exercise of their
            functions in connexion with the specialized agencies. Consequently, a member not only
            has the right but is under a duty to waive the immunity of its representatives in any
            case where, in the opinion of the member, the immunity would impede the course of
            justice, and where it can be waived without prejudice to the purpose for which the
            immunity is
            accorded.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                17</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The provisions of
                <ref>sections 13</ref>, <ref>14</ref> and <ref>15</ref> are not applicable in
            relation to the authorities of a State of which the person is a national or of which he
            is or has been a
            representative.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><i>Article VI—Officials</i></crossHeading><text>
            <center><inline class="not_bold">...</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text>
            
            
            <center><i><ref>Section
                        19</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
            
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">Officials
            of the specialized agencies
            shall:</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(a)
            Be immune from legal process in respect of words spoken or written and all acts
            performed by them in their official capacity;</text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(b)
            Enjoy the same exemptions from taxation in respect of the salaries and emoluments paid
            to them by the specialized agencies and on the same conditions as are enjoyed by
            officials of the United Nations;</text><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">(f)
            Have the right to import free of duty their furniture and effects at the time of first
            taking up their post in the country in
            question.</text><text>
            
            
            <center><inline class="not_bold">...</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
            
        </text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                21</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">In addition to the
            immunities and privileges specified in <ref>sections 19</ref>
            <fillIn class=" width_7">.</fillIn>, the executive head of each specialized agency,
            including any official acting on his behalf during his absence from duty, shall be
            accorded in respect of himself, his spouse and minor children, the privileges and
            immunities, exemptions and facilities accorded to diplomatic envoys, in accordance with
            international
            law.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>
            <center><i><ref>Section
                22</ref></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">Privileges and immunities
            are granted to officials in the interests of the specialized agencies only and not for
            the personal benefit of the individuals themselves. Each specialized agency shall have
            the right and the duty to waive the immunity of any official in any case where, in its
            opinion, the immunity would impede the course of justice and can be waived without
            prejudice to the interests of the specialized
            agency.</text><text>
            <center><inline class="not_bold">...</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></center>
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>