<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en" reason="inEffect" status="operational"><meta><docName>Cap. 520 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>520A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap520A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-08-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle status="operational" reason="inEffect" id="ID_1588923154370_001" name="shortTitle" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2023-11-09">Discovery
            Bay
            Tunnel
            Link
            Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap520/s28">Cap. 520, section 28</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of
            2023</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[14
            April 2000]<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote><ref href="hk/2000/ln75">L.N.
                    75 of 2000</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403317478_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403317494_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ControlCentre"><term>control
                centre</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">控制中心</term>) means the control centre referred to in
                <ref>section 3(b)</ref> but does not include a minor control centre referred to in
                <ref>section 3(c)</ref>;</def><def name="Lane"><term>lane</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">行車綫</term>) means a traffic lane in the tunnel
            area;</def><def name="LightSignal"><term>light
                signal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">管制燈號</term>) means an illuminated signal to control
            vehicular traffic within the tunnel area;</def><def name="RoadMarking"><term>road
                marking</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">道路標記</term>) means a line, word, mark or device placed
            on, or set into, the surface of a road for conveying to persons using the road any
            warning, information, requirement, restriction, prohibition or direction;</def><def name="TollBooth"><term>toll
                booth</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">收費亭</term>) means a structure erected at the entrance
            to, or exit from, a lane in the tunnel area for the purpose of collecting tolls;</def><def name="TrafficSign"><term>traffic
                sign</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">交通標誌</term>) means a sign, object or device for
            conveying to persons using a road any warning, information, requirement, restriction,
            prohibition or direction;</def><def name="TunnelManager"><term>Tunnel
                Manager</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">隧道經理</term>) means the tunnel officer appointed to
            control and manage the tunnel area.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403317509_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Traffic control</heading><leadIn>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922178_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>erect and maintain adequate and efficient traffic signs and light signals, and place and maintain adequate and efficient road markings, in the tunnel area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922178_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>provide and maintain a control centre which shall—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922178_028" name="i" temporalId="s3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>be situated at the western entrance to the tunnel;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922178_036" name="ii" temporalId="s3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>contain adequate and appropriate equipment for the regulation, control, restriction and guidance of vehicles and persons using or employed in the tunnel area; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922178_044" name="iii" temporalId="s3_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>be manned at all times by an adequate number of persons trained in the use of equipment provided for the purposes mentioned in subparagraph (ii) and who are fully conversant with emergency traffic arrangements;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922178_051" name="c" temporalId="s3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>provide and maintain a minor control centre at the eastern entrance to the tunnel which shall—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922193_006" name="i" temporalId="s3_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>be equipped with direct telephone link or intercom to the control centre; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922193_014" name="ii" temporalId="s3_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>be manned at all times by a tunnel officer; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922193_021" name="d" temporalId="s3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>provide adequate number of patrol vehicles and speed check equipment, the type, specification and quantity of which shall be subject to the prior approval of the Commissioner.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403317509_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Traffic signs, light signals and road markings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922225_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In order to comply with <ref>section 3(a)</ref>, the Company may cause or permit to be erected or placed in the tunnel area—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922225_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any traffic sign, light signal or road marking of the size, colour and type prescribed in bylaws made under the Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922225_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any warning or informatory traffic sign or road marking or any
                    supplementary plate that may be used with any such traffic sign or road marking
                    of the size, colour and type shown in <ref>Schedules 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> to
                    the Road Traffic (Traffic Control) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374G">Cap. 374
                        sub. leg.
                        G</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922240_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the Commissioner approves each such erection or placing, any regulatory
                    traffic sign, light signal or road marking or any supplementary plate that may
                    be used with any such traffic sign, light signal or road marking of the size,
                    colour and type shown in <ref>Schedules 1</ref>, <ref>2</ref> and <ref>3</ref>
                    to the Road Traffic (Traffic Control) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap374G">Cap.
                        374 sub. leg. G</ref>);
                        and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of
                            2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922240_014" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any traffic sign, light signal or road marking as it may think appropriate for the giving of advice and information to persons using the tunnel area.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922240_021" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Company may by the erection or placing of an appropriate sign cancel, alter or temporarily suspend the operation of any traffic sign, light signal or road marking erected or placed under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref>, (b) or (d).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922256_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Company shall, if directed to do so by the Commissioner, remove or alter at its own cost any traffic sign, light signal or road marking erected or placed in the tunnel area under subsection (1) or (2).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317525_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Communication</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922271_028" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner, provide and maintain in efficient working order at all times—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922271_036" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>direct telecommunications links, including direct telephone link, between the control centre and—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/36">36 of 2000 s. 28</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922271_044" name="i" temporalId="s5_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a regional command and control centre of the Hong Kong Police Force;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922287_007" name="ii" temporalId="s5_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the communication centre of the Fire Services Department; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922287_015" name="iii" temporalId="s5_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the Emergency Transport Coordination Centre of the Transport Department;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922287_022" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an emergency communication system in the Tunnel Link for officers of the Fire Services Department to communicate with the communication centre of that department;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922287_030" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a radio re-broadcasting system for the transmission of messages on traffic conditions and arrangements from the control centre to persons using the tunnel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922287_038" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a video output port in the control centre for the central closed circuit television system of the Tunnel Link for the installation of closed circuit television monitor to the Emergency Transport Coordination Centre of the Transport Department; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922287_046" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>an emergency telephone system for users of the Tunnel Link to communicate with the control centre in case of emergency.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922287_053" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Company shall, without delay, report any diversion or interruption of traffic within the tunnel area that may affect the flow of traffic outside that area to a regional command and control centre of the Hong Kong Police Force and to an officer designated by the Commissioner.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317540_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Recovery and rescue</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922318_020" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922318_028" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>provide an adequate number of trained personnel and service vehicles suitable for dealing with vehicular breakdowns, accidents and obstruction in the tunnel area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922318_036" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>ensure that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922318_044" name="i" temporalId="s6_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the vehicles referred to in paragraph (a) are of the type, specification and quantity for which the Commissioner has given prior approval and are manned and maintained at all times in a state of readiness; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922334_007" name="ii" temporalId="s6_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>while any such vehicle is present in a lane, a 2-way radio link is maintained between the vehicle and the control centre; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922334_014" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>provide and maintain at all times adequate and efficient first aid equipment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922334_021" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Director of Fire Services, provide and maintain adequate and efficient fire service installations and equipment in the tunnel area at all times.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922334_029" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Company shall in the event of fire, traffic accident or injury to persons in the tunnel area, conduct fire fighting operation and render first aid treatment to the injured persons as soon as and so far as it is reasonably practicable prior to the arrival of those officers of the Fire Services Department and Hong Kong Police Force, and offer assistance to those officers in the course of any fire fighting or rescue operation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317540_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Air quality and ventilation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922365_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922365_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>provide and maintain in good working order at all times an adequate system of ventilation for the health and safety of persons using or employed in the tunnel area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922365_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>provide equipment for the continuous measurement and recording of the concentration of carbon monoxide gas, nitrogen dioxide gas and extinction coefficient in the tunnel and for visual and audible alarm warnings to be given in the control centre if the concentration exceeds the level specified in subsection (2); where the equipment for measuring nitrogen dioxide gas is not commercially available in the market, equipment for the continuous measurement and recording of nitric oxide gas shall be provided subject to it being immediately replaced by equipment for measuring nitrogen dioxide gas when such equipment is available; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922381_006" name="c" temporalId="s7_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>submit monthly report with statistical data showing the results of the continuous measurements referred to in paragraph (b) to the Commissioner, in a form and containing the information required by him.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922396_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Company shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922396_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the concentration of carbon monoxide gas in the tunnel does not during any 5-minute period exceed an average of 100 parts per million by volume;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922396_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the concentration of nitrogen dioxide gas in the tunnel does not during any 5-minute period exceed an average of 1 part per million by volume or; where the Company has provided the equipment for measuring nitric oxide gas under subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref>, the concentration of nitric oxide gas in the tunnel does not during any 5-minute period exceed an average of 11.4 parts per million by volume; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922396_029" name="c" temporalId="s7_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the visibility in the tunnel does not during any 5-minute period exceed an extinction coefficient of 0.005 per metre.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317556_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Order and cleanliness, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922427_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner, keep the tunnel area in a clean and orderly condition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922427_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Company shall ensure that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922427_020" name="a" temporalId="s8_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the tunnel washing equipment is of the type, specification and quantity approved by the Commissioner; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922427_028" name="b" temporalId="s8_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the discharge of wash water from regular tunnel washing meets the
                    prevailing standards for effluents as specified in the Technical Memorandum
                    Standards for Effluents Discharged into Drainage and Sewerage Systems, Inland
                    and Coastal Waters.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s.
                    149</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317556_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Illumination</heading><leadIn>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922443_042" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>provide adequate and efficient illumination within the tunnel area; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922459_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>ensure that the illumination referred to in paragraph (a) is varied having regard to the light conditions outside the tunnel.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403317572_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Electricity supply</heading><leadIn>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922474_005" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>provide connection to 2 independent outside sources of electric power so that, if there is failure of one source, adequate electric power continues to be available for the full operation of the tunnel facilities;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922474_013" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>install and maintain an uninterruptible power supply system to operate the following essential equipment in the tunnel area for a minimum of 30 minutes—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922474_021" name="i" temporalId="s10_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>emergency lighting including essential tunnel lighting;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922474_029" name="ii" temporalId="s10_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>essential communication system;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922474_037" name="iii" temporalId="s10_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>computer system;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922474_045" name="iv" temporalId="s10_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>essential control and monitoring system;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922474_053" name="v" temporalId="s10_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>traffic control and surveillance system; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922474_061" name="vi" temporalId="s10_b_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>toll collection system;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922474_068" name="c" temporalId="s10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>in addition to the requirements mentioned in paragraphs (a) and (b), provide and maintain in a state of readiness and in efficient working order at all times an electricity generating apparatus which, in the event of failure of the outside sources of electric power, will be sufficient to operate the following emergency systems and equipment in the tunnel area for a minimum of 6 hours—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922474_076" name="i" temporalId="s10_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>fire services systems;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922490_007" name="ii" temporalId="s10_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>all loads backed up by uninterruptible power supply;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922490_015" name="iii" temporalId="s10_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>emergency power points inside the tunnel;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922490_023" name="iv" temporalId="s10_c_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>air-conditioning for computer rooms, control rooms and uninterruptible power supply rooms;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922490_031" name="v" temporalId="s10_c_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>mechanical ventilation for battery rooms; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412922490_039" name="vi" temporalId="s10_c_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>emergency lighting, essential tunnel lighting and essential power points for ancillary buildings of the Tunnel Link; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922490_046" name="d" temporalId="s10_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>maintain in efficient working order at all times an emergency power supply for use in the tunnel by the Fire Services Department.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403317587_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Control of dangerous goods</heading><content>The Company shall take measures to prevent or control the carriage of dangerous goods through the Tunnel Link to the satisfaction of the Commissioner.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403317587_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Adequate manning requirements</heading><leadIn>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922537_019" name="a" temporalId="s12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>deploy adequate and efficient personnel for the safe and orderly passage of motor vehicles through the Tunnel Link and the control and safety of motor vehicles and persons in the tunnel area in accordance with the manning requirements approved by the Commissioner; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922537_027" name="b" temporalId="s12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>ensure that all the tunnel officers, who are engaged in traffic control and operational duties, are trained in fire fighting procedures, first aid techniques and the use of fire fighting and first aid equipment.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403317603_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Display of notices of tolls and sale thereof</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922552_026" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Company shall, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner cause to be displayed at both ends of the Tunnel Link, in conspicuous places, notices stating the toll payable in respect of each category of motor vehicle.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922568_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Company shall cause printed copies of a list of the tolls currently chargeable by the Company to be kept at the registered office of the Company and to be available for sale to any person at a reasonable charge.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317618_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Records on tunnel operation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922583_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Company shall at all times maintain, in form and substance satisfactory to the Commissioner, records relating to the operation of the Tunnel Link including—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922583_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the frequency, duration, location, time and nature of any equipment failure and of any remedial action taken;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922583_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the details of accidents or incidents that occurred in the tunnel area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922583_028" name="c" temporalId="s14_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the volume of traffic passing through the Tunnel Link during each hour by vehicle type;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922583_036" name="d" temporalId="s14_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the breakdown, according to vehicle type, of tolls collected on each day;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922583_044" name="e" temporalId="s14_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the times at which each toll booth is kept open and the starting and finishing times at which it is operated by a particular tunnel officer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922583_052" name="f" temporalId="s14_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>all cash and other receipts deriving from the use of the Tunnel Link;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922583_060" name="g" temporalId="s14_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>air quality and ventilation fan operation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922599_006" name="h" temporalId="s14_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>books and records for financial assessment; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922599_014" name="i" temporalId="s14_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the staffing situation in connection with the operation of the Tunnel Link.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922599_021" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Commissioner may, with such assistance from the Company as the Commissioner may reasonably require, have free access to and make copies of records maintained under subsection (1).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317618_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Records on tunnel maintenance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412922615_067" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Company shall at all times maintain, in form and substance satisfactory to the Director of Highways, records relating to the inspections, routine maintenance, repair and replacement of the tunnel area and the tunnel facilities including—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922615_075" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the time, duration, location and nature of inspection and maintenance works;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922630_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the time, duration, location and nature of failure or defects of the tunnel facilities;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922630_014" name="c" temporalId="s15_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the time, duration and location of parts, equipment and facilities replaced; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922630_022" name="d" temporalId="s15_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the staffing situation in connection with the maintenance of the tunnel area and tunnel facilities.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412922630_029" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director of Highways may, with such assistance from the Company as the Director of Highways may reasonably require, have free access to and make copies of records maintained under subsection (1).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403317650_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-09" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Uniforms and identification</heading><leadIn>A tunnel officer on duty shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412922646_051" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>except in the case of the Tunnel Manager, wear a uniform of a design approved by the Commissioner of Police;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922646_059" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>carry such means of identity issued by the Company and approved by the Commissioner; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412922646_067" name="c" temporalId="s16_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>promptly produce to any person who on reasonable grounds requests him to do so his means of identity and evidence of appointment.</content></paragraph></section></main></subLeg>