<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 374 sub. leg. P</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>374P</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap374P!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2018-06-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403131042_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2018-06-28">Specification of Traffic Signs and Road Markings for Private Roads Notice</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap374G/s3A">Cap. 374 sub. leg. G, regulations 3A</ref> and <ref href="/hk/cap374G/s8A">8A</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[1 July 1989]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2018/er3">E.R. 3 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403131042_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>This notice may be cited as the Specification of Traffic Signs and Road Markings for Private Roads Notice.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403131058_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Traffic signs which may be erected or placed on private road by or with the permission of the owner of that road</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412330500_018" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The traffic signs specified in any of the Figure Nos. 102, 106, 107, 108, 109, 112, 121 to 127 inclusive, 137, 138, 139, 148, 150 to 153 inclusive, 205, 207, 208, 210, 217, 218, 219, 221, 222, 224, 225, 235, 236, 263, 302, 304, 310, 311, 313, 402, 412, 413, 418, 423, 424 or 425 in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the regulations are declared to be traffic signs that may be erected or placed on or near any private road, by or with the permission in writing of the owner of that road, subject to the condition that the erection or placement of any such traffic sign on or near any such road shall, as far as is reasonably practicable, be in accordance with any directions relating thereto specified in any code of practice prescribed under <ref>section 109(4A)</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412330531_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Traffic signs which are light signals are declared to be traffic signs that may be erected or placed on or near any private road, by or with the permission in writing of the owner of that road, subject to the conditions that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412330531_013" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the size, colour and type of the light signals shall be in accordance with <ref>paragraph 2 of Schedule 3</ref> to the regulations;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412330531_021" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the light signals shall not be so erected or placed except for alternate one way working; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412330531_029" name="c" temporalId="s2_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the erection or placement of any light signals on or near any such road shall, as far as is reasonably practicable, be in accordance with any directions relating thereto specified in any code of practice prescribed under <ref>section 109(4A)</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403131058_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Road markings which may be placed on private road by or with the permission of the owner of that road</heading><leadIn>The road markings specified in any of the Figure Nos. 506, 508, 509, 517, 601 to 609 inclusive, 615, 617 or 618 in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> to the regulations are declared to be road markings that may be placed on or near any private road, by or with the permission in writing of the owner of that road, subject to the conditions that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412330562_027" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>the road marking specified in Figure No. 617 of that <ref>Schedule</ref> shall not be placed on or near any such road unless, in conjunction with that road marking, there is also—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412330562_035" name="i" temporalId="s3_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>placed on or near that road the road marking specified in Figure No. 618 of that <ref>Schedule</ref>; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412330562_043" name="ii" temporalId="s3_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>erected or placed on or near that road the traffic sign specified in Figure
                    No. 263 in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the regulations;
                    and<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412330578_006" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the placement of any such road marking on or near any such road shall, as far as is reasonably practicable, be in accordance with any directions relating thereto specified in any code of practice prescribed under <ref>section 109(4A)</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></paragraph></section></main></subLeg>