<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 503 sub. leg. Y</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>503Y</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap503Y!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-12-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403285982_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-12-29">Fugitive
            Offenders (Republic
            of
            Korea)
            Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap503/s3">Cap. 503, section
                3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of
            2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[11 February 2007]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2007/ln13">L.N. 13 of 2007</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403285982_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403285997_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Procedures in Ordinance to apply between Hong Kong and Republic of Korea</heading><content>In relation to the arrangements for the surrender of fugitive offenders the terms of which are recited in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, it is directed that the procedures in the Ordinance shall apply as between Hong Kong and the Republic of Korea subject to the limitations, restrictions, exceptions and qualifications contained in the terms of the arrangements.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403286013_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap503Y/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Agreement
            for
            the Surrender
            of
            Fugitive
            Offenders between
            the Government
            of
            the
            Hong
            Kong
            Special
            Administrative Region
            of
            the
            People’s Republic
            of China
            and
            the Government
            of
            the Republic
            of
                Korea<ref idref="ID_1600067337359_013"><sup>#</sup></ref><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36 align_justified">The Government of the Hong
            Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China (“Hong Kong Special
            Administrative Region”), having been duly authorized to conclude this Agreement by the
            Central People’s Government of the People’s Republic of China, and the Government of the
            Republic of Korea (hereinafter referred to as “the
            Parties”),</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36">Desiring to make provisions for the
            reciprocal surrender of fugitive
            offenders,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36">Affirming their respect for each other’s
            legal system and judicial
            institutions,</text><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36">Have agreed as
            follows:</leadIn><crossHeading>ARTICLE 1</crossHeading><crossHeading>Obligation to
            Surrender<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36 align_justified">The Parties agree to
            surrender to each other, subject to the provisions laid down in this Agreement, any
            person who is found in the jurisdiction of the Requested Party and who is wanted by the
            Requesting Party for prosecution or for the imposition or enforcement of a sentence in
            respect of an offence referred to in Article 2 of this
            Agreement.</text><crossHeading>ARTICLE 2</crossHeading><crossHeading>Offences<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843616_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>Surrender of fugitive offenders shall be granted for an offence coming within
                any of the descriptions of offences specified in the Annex to this Agreement, which
                shall form an integral part of this Agreement, in so far as the offence is,
                according to the laws of both Parties, punishable by imprisonment or other form of
                detention for more than one year, or by a more severe penalty.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843616_029" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><leadIn>In determining whether an offence is against the laws of both Parties:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_001" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843632_006" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it shall not matter whether the laws of the Parties place the offence
                    within the same category of offence or denominate the offence by the same
                    terminology;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843632_015" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the totality of the conduct alleged against the person whose surrender is
                    sought shall be taken into account and it shall not matter whether, under the
                    laws of the Parties, the constituent elements of the offence differ.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843632_022" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>Where surrender of a fugitive offender is requested for the purpose of carrying
                out a sentence, a further requirement shall be that a period of imprisonment or
                detention of at least six (6) months remains to be served.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843647_005" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="4" class="align_left">4.</num><content>Where the surrender of a fugitive offender is requested for the purpose of
                carrying out a sentence, the Requested Party may refuse surrender if it appears that
                the conviction was obtained in his absence and he did not have the opportunity of
                being tried in his presence, unless he has the opportunity to have his case retried
                in his presence. Requests for the surrender of persons convicted in their absence
                shall be accompanied by the supporting documents referred to in <ref>paragraph
                    3</ref> of Article 8 as well as the supporting documents referred to in
                    <ref>paragraph 4</ref> of Article 8.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843663_005" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="5" class="align_left">5.</num><leadIn>Surrender may be granted pursuant to the provisions of this Agreement in respect
                of an offence, provided that:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_002" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843663_015" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it was an offence in the Requesting Party at the time of the conduct
                    constituting the offence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843663_024" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the conduct alleged would, if it had taken place in the jurisdiction of the
                    Requested Party at the time of the making of the request for surrender, have
                    constituted an offence against the law in force in the jurisdiction of the
                    Requested Party.</content></paragraph></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 3</crossHeading><crossHeading>Surrender of
            Nationals<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843678_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region reserves the
                right to refuse the surrender of nationals of the People’s Republic of China. The
                Government of the Republic of Korea reserves the right to refuse the surrender of
                its nationals.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843678_029" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>Where the Requested Party exercises this right, the Requesting Party may
                request that the case be submitted to the authorities of the Requested Party in
                order that proceedings for prosecution of the person may be considered. That Party
                shall inform the Requesting Party of any action taken and the outcome of any
                prosecution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843694_005" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>Nationality shall be determined at the time of the commission of the offence
                for which surrender is
                requested.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 4</crossHeading><crossHeading>Death
            Penalty<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified ">If the offence for which
            surrender of a fugitive offender is requested under this Agreement is punishable
            according to the law of the Requesting Party with the death penalty, and if in respect
            of such an offence the death penalty is not provided for by the law of the Requested
            Party or is not normally carried out, surrender may be refused unless the Requesting
            Party gives such assurances as the Requested Party considers sufficient that the death
            penalty will not be imposed or, if imposed, will not be carried out.</text><crossHeading>ARTICLE 5</crossHeading><crossHeading>Mandatory Refusal of
            Surrender<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36 align_justified">Surrender shall not be
            granted under this Agreement in any of the following circumstances:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_003" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843710_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>when the Requested Party has substantial grounds for believing that the
                    offence for which surrender is requested is a political offence or an offence
                    connected with a political offence. Reference to a political offence shall not
                    include the following offences:</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412843710_039" name="i" temporalId="sch0_0_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the taking or attempted taking of the life or an attack on the person
                        of a Head of State or Head of Government or a member of the person’s
                        immediate family; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412843725_008" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any offence which, by reason of a multilateral international agreement,
                        the Parties must not treat as a political offence or an offence connected
                        with a political offence;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843725_016" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>when the person sought is being prosecuted by the Requested Party for the
                    offence for which the surrender is requested;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843725_025" name="c" temporalId="sch0_0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>when the person sought has been finally convicted or acquitted by the
                    Requested Party for the offence for which the person’s surrender is
                    requested;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843741_007" name="d" temporalId="sch0_0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>when the prosecution or the punishment for the offence for which surrender
                    is requested would be barred by reasons prescribed under the law of either Party
                    including a law relating to the lapse of time;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843741_016" name="e" temporalId="sch0_0_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>when the Requested Party has substantial grounds for believing that the
                    request for surrender has been presented with a view to prosecuting or punishing
                    the person sought, by reason of race, religion, nationality or political
                    opinion, or that that person’s position may be prejudiced for any of those
                    reasons.</content></paragraph></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 6</crossHeading><crossHeading>Discretionary Refusal of
            Surrender<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36 align_justified">Surrender may be refused
            under this Agreement in any of the following circumstances:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_004" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843756_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>when the offence for which surrender is sought is regarded under the law of
                    the Requested Party as having been committed in whole or in part within the
                    territory or area of the Requested Party, and in case of such refusal the
                    Requesting Party may request that the case be submitted to the authorities of
                    the Requested Party in order that proceedings for prosecution may be
                    considered;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843756_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>when the person sought has been finally acquitted or convicted in a third
                    jurisdiction for the same offence for which surrender is requested and, if
                    convicted, the sentence imposed has been fully enforced or is no longer
                    enforceable;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843772_007" name="c" temporalId="sch0_0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>when, in exceptional cases, the Requested Party while also taking into
                    account the seriousness of the offence and the interests of the Requesting Party
                    deems that, because of the personal circumstances of the person sought, the
                    surrender would be incompatible with humanitarian considerations; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843772_016" name="d" temporalId="sch0_0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>when it appears to the Requested Party that, by reason of the passage of
                    time since the person is alleged to have committed the offence for which
                    surrender is sought or to have become unlawfully at large it would, having
                    regard to all the circumstances, be unjust or oppressive to return
                    him.</content></paragraph></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 7</crossHeading><crossHeading>Postponed or Temporary
            Surrender<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843788_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>If the person sought is being proceeded against or under punishment in the
                jurisdiction of the Requested Party for an offence other than that for which the
                person’s surrender is requested, the person’s surrender may be deferred until the
                conclusion of the proceedings and the execution of any punishment awarded to
                him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843788_029" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>If the request for surrender is granted in the case of a person who is being
                proceeded against or under punishment in the jurisdiction of the Requested Party for
                an offence other than that for which the person’s surrender is requested, the
                Requested Party may temporarily surrender the person sought to the Requesting Party
                for the purpose of prosecution. The person so surrendered shall be kept in custody
                in the Requesting Party and shall be returned to the Requested Party after the
                conclusion of the proceedings against that person, in accordance with conditions to
                be determined between the Parties.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 8</crossHeading><crossHeading>Request and Supporting
            Documents<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843819_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>Requests for surrender shall be made in writing to the competent authority of
                the Requested Party through the Consulate General of the Republic of Korea in Hong
                Kong, unless the Parties otherwise agree. The competent authority for the Republic
                of Korea shall be the Ministry of Justice and the competent authority for the Hong
                Kong Special Administrative Region shall be the Department of Justice, unless a
                different competent authority is notified by either Party to the other.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843834_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><leadIn>The request shall be accompanied by:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_005" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843834_015" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>as accurate a description as possible of the person sought, together with
                    any other information which would help to establish the person’s identity and
                    nationality including, if known, his or her whereabouts;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843834_024" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a statement and particulars of the offence for which surrender is
                    requested;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843850_007" name="c" temporalId="sch0_0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the text of the legal provisions, if any, creating the offence, and a
                    statement of the punishment which can be imposed for it and whether any time
                    limit is imposed on the institution of proceedings, or on the execution of any
                    punishment imposed, for that offence.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843850_014" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><leadIn>A request for surrender of a person who is sought for prosecution shall also be
                accompanied by:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_006" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843850_024" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a warrant of arrest issued by a judge or magistrate of the Requesting Party
                    or a copy of that warrant; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843850_033" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>such evidence as, according to the law of the Requested Party, would permit
                    a decision to be taken to surrender that person for the offence for which
                    surrender is requested.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843866_005" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="4" class="align_left">4.</num><leadIn>If the request relates to a person already convicted or sentenced, it shall also
                be accompanied by:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_007" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843866_015" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a copy of the certificate of the conviction or sentence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843866_024" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438412843866_027" name="i" temporalId="sch0_0_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the person was convicted but not sentenced, a statement to that
                        effect by the appropriate court and a copy of the warrant of arrest;
                        or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412843866_035" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the person was sentenced, a statement that the sentence is
                        enforceable and indicating how much of the sentence has still to be
                        served.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843881_005" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="5" class="align_left">5.</num><leadIn>Documents supporting a request for surrender shall be admitted in evidence as
                proof of the facts contained therein if duly authenticated. Documents are duly
                authenticated if they purport to be:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_008" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843881_015" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>signed or certified by a judge, magistrate, prosecutor or an official of
                    the Requesting Party; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843881_024" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>sealed with the official seal of the competent authority of the Requesting
                    Party.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843881_031" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="6" class="align_left">6.</num><content>All documents submitted in accordance with this Agreement shall be in or
                translated into an official language of the Requested Party, unless the Requested
                Party dispenses with this requirement.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 9</crossHeading><crossHeading>Provisional
            Arrest<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843897_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><leadIn>In urgent cases, the person sought may, in accordance with the law of the
                Requested Party, be provisionally arrested on the application of the competent
                authority of the Requesting Party. The application for provisional arrest shall
                contain:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337344_009" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412843897_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a description of the person sought;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843897_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the location of the person sought, if known;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843912_007" name="c" temporalId="sch0_0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a brief statement of the facts of the case, including, if possible, the
                    time and location of the offence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843912_016" name="d" temporalId="sch0_0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a description of the laws violated and the sentence prescribed by the
                    law;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843912_025" name="e" temporalId="sch0_0_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a statement of the existence of a warrant of arrest or a judgement of
                    conviction against the person sought; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412843912_034" name="f" temporalId="sch0_0_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>a statement that a request for surrender of the person sought will
                    follow.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843912_041" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>An application for provisional arrest may be forwarded to the competent
                authority of the Requested Party by any means affording a record in writing through
                the same channels as a request for surrender or through direct contact between the
                competent authorities of both Parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843928_005" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>On receipt of such an application, the Requested Party shall take the necessary
                steps to secure the arrest of the person sought and the Requesting Party shall be
                promptly notified of the result of its request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843928_014" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="4" class="align_left">4.</num><content>The provisional arrest of the person sought shall be terminated upon the
                expiration of forty-five (45) days from the date of arrest if the request for
                surrender has not been received unless the Requesting Party can justify continued
                provisional arrest of the person sought, in which case the period of provisional
                arrest shall be terminated upon the expiration of a further fifteen (15) days. This
                provision shall not prevent the re-arrest or surrender of the person sought if the
                request for surrender is received subsequently.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 10</crossHeading><crossHeading>Surrender by
            Consent<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843944_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>If the person sought consents to surrender to the Requesting Party, the
                Requested Party may surrender the person as expeditiously as possible without
                further proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843959_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>To the extent required under the law of the Requested Party, the provisions of
                Article 16 shall apply to a person surrendered pursuant to this Article.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 11</crossHeading><crossHeading>Additional
            Information<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843959_029" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>If the information communicated by the Requesting Party is found to be
                insufficient to allow the Requested Party to make a decision in pursuance of this
                Agreement, the latter Party shall request the necessary supplementary information
                and may fix a time-limit for receipt thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843959_038" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>If the person whose surrender is sought is under arrest and the additional
                information furnished is not sufficient in accordance with this Agreement or is not
                received within the time specified, the person may be released from custody. Such
                release shall not preclude the Requesting Party from making a fresh request for the
                surrender of that person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843975_005" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>Where the person is released from custody in accordance with <ref>paragraph
                    2</ref>, the Requested Party shall notify the Requesting Party as soon as
                practicable.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 12</crossHeading><crossHeading>Concurrent
            Requests<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412843975_029" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>If the Requested Party receives requests from the other Party and from any
                other jurisdiction for the surrender of the same person either for the same offence
                or for different offences, the Requested Party shall determine to which jurisdiction
                the person is to be surrendered and shall notify each requesting jurisdiction of its
                decision.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412843990_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>In determining to which jurisdiction a person is to be surrendered, the
                Requested Party shall have regard to all the circumstances including the provisions
                in this regard in any agreements in force between the Requested Party and the
                Requesting Party or other jurisdictions, the relative seriousness and place of
                commission of the offences, the respective dates of the requests, the nationality
                and the ordinary place of residence of the person sought, and the possibility of
                subsequent surrender to another jurisdiction, and shall furnish the other Party with
                information justifying its decision in the event of surrender of the fugitive to
                another
                jurisdiction.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 13</crossHeading><crossHeading>Representation and
            Costs<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844006_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>The Requested Party shall, if asked by the Requesting Party, make the necessary
                arrangements for the Requesting Party’s legal representation and assistance in any
                proceedings arising out of a request for the surrender of a fugitive offender. In
                the event that the Requesting Party arranges its own legal representation and
                assistance, it shall bear any costs incurred.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844022_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>The Requesting Party shall bear the expenses related to the translation of
                documents and the transportation of the person surrendered from the Requested Party
                to the Requesting Party. The Requested Party shall pay all other expenses incurred
                in its jurisdiction by reason of the proceedings.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 14</crossHeading><crossHeading>Surrender<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844037_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>The Requested Party shall, as soon as a decision on the request for surrender
                has been made, communicate that decision to the Requesting Party. Reasons shall be
                given for any complete or partial refusal of a request for surrender.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844037_029" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>The Requested Party shall surrender the person sought to the appropriate
                authorities of the Requesting Party at a mutually convenient location in the
                jurisdiction of the Requested Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844037_038" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>paragraph 4</ref> of this Article, if the
                Requesting Party does not take custody of the person sought within the time
                prescribed by the law of the Requested Party, the person may be released and the
                Requested Party may subsequently refuse to surrender the person for the same
                offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844053_005" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="4" class="align_left">4.</num><content>If circumstances beyond its control prevent a Party from surrendering or taking
                over the person to be surrendered, it shall notify the other Party. In that case,
                the two Parties shall agree upon a new date for surrender and the provisions of
                    <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of this Article shall apply.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 15</crossHeading><crossHeading>Surrender of
            Property<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844068_004" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><leadIn>To the extent permitted under the laws of the Requested Party, when a request
                for surrender of a fugitive offender is granted, the Requested Party shall hand over
                to the Requesting Party all property, including sums of money:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337359_010" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412844068_014" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>which may serve as proof of the offence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844068_023" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>which have been acquired by the person sought as a result of the offence
                    and are in the person’s possession or discovered subsequently.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844068_030" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>If the property in question is liable to seizure or confiscation within the
                jurisdiction of the Requested Party, that Party may, in connection with pending
                proceedings, temporarily retain it or hand it over to the Requesting Party on
                condition it is returned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844084_005" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>These provisions shall not prejudice the rights of the Requested Party or of
                any person other than the person sought. When such rights exist, the property shall
                on request be returned to the Requested Party without charge as soon as possible
                after the end of the proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844084_014" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="4" class="align_left">4.</num><content>The property mentioned in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> shall, if the Requesting Party
                so requests, be handed over to that Party to the extent permitted by the laws of the
                Requested Party, even if the surrender cannot be carried out due to the death or
                escape of the person
                sought.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 16</crossHeading><crossHeading>Rule of
            Speciality<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844100_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><leadIn>A fugitive offender who has been surrendered shall not be proceeded against,
                sentenced or detained with a view to the carrying out of a sentence for any offence
                committed prior to surrender other than:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337359_011" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412844100_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the offence in respect of which surrender is granted;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844100_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an equivalent or lesser offence, however described, based on the facts in
                    respect of which his surrender was granted, provided such offence is one for
                    which he could be surrendered under this Agreement;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844115_007" name="c" temporalId="sch0_0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any other offence being an offence for which surrender may be granted under
                    this Agreement and the Requested Party consents;</content></paragraph></subsection><continued class="left_indent_0 align_justified">unless that person has first had an
            opportunity to leave the jurisdiction of the Requesting Party and has not done so within
            forty (40) days of having been free to do so or has returned voluntarily to that
            jurisdiction having left it.</continued><subsection id="ID_1438412844115_021" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>A Party whose consent is requested under subparagraph (c) of <ref>paragraph
                    1</ref> of this Article may require the submission of any document referred to
                in Article 8 and any statement made by the surrendered person on the
                matter.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 17</crossHeading><crossHeading>Re-surrender<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844131_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><leadIn>Where a person has been surrendered to the Requesting Party, that Party shall
                not surrender the person to any other jurisdiction for an offence committed before
                that person’s surrender unless:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_36" id="ID_1600067337359_012" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1438412844131_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Requested Party consents; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844131_039" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the person has first had an opportunity to leave the jurisdiction of the
                    Requesting Party and has not done so within forty (40) days of having been free
                    to do so or has returned voluntarily to that jurisdiction having left
                    it.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844146_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>A Party whose consent is requested under subparagraph (a) of <ref>paragraph
                    1</ref> of this Article may require the production of the documents submitted by
                the other jurisdiction in support of its request for surrender.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 18</crossHeading><crossHeading>Transit<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844146_029" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>To the extent permitted by its law, the right to transport through the
                jurisdiction of one of the Parties a person surrendered to the other Party by a
                third party may be granted on request made by any means affording a record in
                writing. The request for transit shall contain a description of the person being
                transported and a brief statement of the facts of the case. The request for transit
                may be forwarded to the competent authority of the Requested Party through the same
                channels as a request for surrender or through direct contact between the competent
                authorities of both Parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844162_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>Permission for the transit of a person surrendered shall include authorization
                for accompanying officials to hold that person in custody or request and obtain
                assistance from authorities in the Party of transit in maintaining
                custody.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844178_005" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>Where a person is being held in custody pursuant to <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of
                this Article, the Party in whose jurisdiction the person is being held may direct
                that the person be released if transportation is not continued within a reasonable
                time.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844178_014" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="4" class="align_left">4.</num><content>Authorization for transit shall not be required when air transport is to be
                used and no landing is scheduled in the jurisdiction of the Party of transit. If an
                unscheduled landing occurs in the jurisdiction of that Party, it may require the
                other Party to furnish a request for transit as provided in <ref>paragraph 1</ref>
                of this Article. The Party of transit shall, within the limits permitted by its law,
                detain the person to be transported until the transportation is continued, provided
                that the request is received within ninety-six (96) hours of the unscheduled
                landing.</content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 19</crossHeading><crossHeading>Consultations<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844193_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>The Parties shall, at the request of either Party, promptly hold consultations
                concerning the interpretation, application or implementation of this
                Agreement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844209_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>The competent authorities of the Parties may consult each other directly in
                connection with the processing of individual
                cases.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>ARTICLE 20</crossHeading><crossHeading>Entry Into Force and
            Termination<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412844209_029" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content>This Agreement shall enter into force thirty (30) days after the date on which
                the Parties have notified each other in writing that their respective requirements
                for the entry into force of this Agreement have been complied with.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844224_005" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="2" class="align_left">2.</num><content>This Agreement shall apply to requests made after its entry into force
                regardless of the date of commission of the offence or offences.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412844224_014" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><num value="3" class="align_left">3.</num><content>Either of the Parties may terminate this Agreement at any time by giving notice
                in writing to the other. In that event, this Agreement shall cease to have effect
                six (6) months after the receipt of the notice.</content></subsection><text class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the
            undersigned, being duly authorized by their respective Governments, have signed this
            Agreement.</text><text class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified">Done in duplicate at Hong
            Kong this twenty-sixth day of June 2006 in the Chinese, English and Korean languages,
            all texts being equally authentic.</text><crossHeading><inline>ANNEX</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Descriptions of Offences referred to in Article
                2<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></inline></crossHeading><paragraph id="ID_1438412844240_028" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The unlawful taking of human life; assault with intent to commit
                murder.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844240_037" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Aiding, abetting, counselling or procuring
                suicide.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844240_046" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Maliciously wounding; maiming; inflicting grievous or actual bodily harm;
                assault occasioning actual bodily harm; threats to kill; intentional or reckless
                endangering of life whether by means of a weapon, a dangerous substance or
                otherwise; offences relating to unlawful wounding or injuring.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844256_005" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Offences of a sexual nature including rape; sexual assault; indecent assault;
                unlawful sexual acts on children; statutory sexual offences.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844256_014" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Gross indecency with a child, a mental defective or an unconscious
                person.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844256_023" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Kidnapping; abduction; unlawful imprisonment or detention; dealing or
                trafficking in slaves or other persons; taking a hostage.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844256_032" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Criminal intimidation.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844271_005" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Offences against the law relating to dangerous drugs including narcotics and
                psychotropic substances and precursors and essential chemicals used in the illegal
                manufacture of narcotic drugs and psychotropic substances and offences related to
                the proceeds of drug trafficking.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844271_014" name="9" temporalId="sch0_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Obtaining property or pecuniary advantage by deception; theft; robbery;
                burglary (including breaking and entering) or similar offences; embezzlement;
                blackmail; extortion; handling or receiving stolen property; false accounting; any
                other offence in respect of property or fiscal matters involving fraud; any offence
                against the law relating to unlawful deprivation of property.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844287_005" name="10" temporalId="sch0_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Offences against bankruptcy law or insolvency law.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844287_014" name="11" temporalId="sch0_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>Offences against the law relating to companies including offences committed by
                officers, directors and promoters.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844287_023" name="12" temporalId="sch0_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>Offences relating to securities and futures trading.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844302_005" name="13" temporalId="sch0_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>Any offence relating to counterfeiting; any offence against the law relating to
                forgery or uttering what is
                forged.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844302_014" name="14" temporalId="sch0_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content>Offences against the laws relating to protection of intellectual property,
                including copyright, patents, trademarks, designs or trade secrets.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844302_023" name="15" temporalId="sch0_15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content>An offence against the law relating to bribery, corruption, secret commissions
                and breach of trust.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844302_032" name="16" temporalId="sch0_16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content>Perjury and subornation of perjury.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844318_005" name="17" temporalId="sch0_17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content>Offences relating to the perversion or obstruction of the course of
                justice.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844318_014" name="18" temporalId="sch0_18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content>Arson; criminal damage or mischief including mischief in relation to computer
                data.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844318_023" name="19" temporalId="sch0_19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content>An offence against the law relating to firearms.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844318_032" name="20" temporalId="sch0_20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content>An offence against the law relating to explosives.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844334_005" name="21" temporalId="sch0_21"><num value="21">(21)</num><content>An offence against laws relating to environmental pollution or protection of
                public health. </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844334_014" name="22" temporalId="sch0_22"><num value="22">(22)</num><content>Mutiny or any mutinous act committed on board a vessel at sea.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844334_023" name="23" temporalId="sch0_23"><num value="23">(23)</num><content>Piracy involving ships or aircraft.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844334_032" name="24" temporalId="sch0_24"><num value="24">(24)</num><content>Unlawful use, seizure or exercise of control of an aircraft, vessel or other
                means of transportation.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844334_041" name="25" temporalId="sch0_25"><num value="25">(25)</num><content>Genocide or direct and public incitement to commit genocide.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844349_005" name="26" temporalId="sch0_26"><num value="26">(26)</num><content>Facilitating or permitting the escape of a person from custody.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844349_014" name="27" temporalId="sch0_27"><num value="27">(27)</num><content>An offence against the laws relating to the control of exportation or
                importation of goods of any type, or the international transfer of funds.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844349_023" name="28" temporalId="sch0_28"><num value="28">(28)</num><content>Smuggling; offences against the laws relating to import and export of
                prohibited items, including historical and archaeological items.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844365_005" name="29" temporalId="sch0_29"><num value="29">(29)</num><content>Immigration offences including fraudulent acquisition or use of a passport or
                visa.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844365_014" name="30" temporalId="sch0_30"><num value="30">(30)</num><content>Arranging or facilitating for financial gain, the illegal entry of persons into
                the jurisdiction of the Requesting Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844365_023" name="31" temporalId="sch0_31"><num value="31">(31)</num><content>An offence relating to gambling or lotteries.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844365_032" name="32" temporalId="sch0_32"><num value="32">(32)</num><content>Offences relating to the unlawful termination of pregnancy.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844365_041" name="33" temporalId="sch0_33"><num value="33">(33)</num><content>Stealing, abandoning, exposing or unlawfully detaining a child; any other
                offences involving the exploitation of children.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844380_005" name="34" temporalId="sch0_34"><num value="34">(34)</num><content>Offences against the laws relating to prostitution and premises kept for the
                purposes of prostitution.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844380_014" name="35" temporalId="sch0_35"><num value="35">(35)</num><content>Offences involving the unlawful use of computers.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844380_023" name="36" temporalId="sch0_36"><num value="36">(36)</num><content>Offences relating to fiscal matters, taxes or duties, notwithstanding that the
                law of the Requested Party does not impose the same kind of tax or duty or does not
                contain a tax, duty or customs regulation of the same kind as the law of the
                Requesting Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844396_005" name="37" temporalId="sch0_37"><num value="37">(37)</num><content>Offences relating to unlawful escape from custody or flight to avoid
                prosecution; mutiny in prison.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844396_014" name="38" temporalId="sch0_38"><num value="38">(38)</num><content>Offences relating to women and girls.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844396_023" name="39" temporalId="sch0_39"><num value="39">(39)</num><content>Offences against the law relating to false or misleading descriptions of
                goods.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844396_032" name="40" temporalId="sch0_40"><num value="40">(40)</num><content>Offences relating to the possession or laundering of proceeds obtained from the
                commission of any offence for which surrender may be granted under this
                Agreement.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844412_005" name="41" temporalId="sch0_41"><num value="41">(41)</num><content>Impeding the arrest or prosecution of a person who has or is believed to have
                committed an offence for which surrender may be granted under this
                Agreement.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844412_014" name="42" temporalId="sch0_42"><num value="42">(42)</num><content>Offences for which fugitive offenders may be surrendered under international
                conventions binding on the Parties; offences created as a result of decisions of
                international organisations which are binding on the
                Parties.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844412_023" name="43" temporalId="sch0_43"><num value="43">(43)</num><content>Conspiracy to commit fraud or to defraud.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844412_032" name="44" temporalId="sch0_44"><num value="44">(44)</num><content>Conspiracy to commit, or any type of association to commit, any offence for
                which surrender may be granted under this Agreement.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844427_005" name="45" temporalId="sch0_45"><num value="45">(45)</num><content>Aiding, abetting, counselling or procuring the commission of, inciting, being
                an accessory before or after the fact to, or attempting to commit any offence for
                which surrender may be granted under this Agreement.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412844427_014" name="46" temporalId="sch0_46"><num value="46">(46)</num><content>Any other offence which is punishable under the laws of both Parties by
                imprisonment or other form of detention for more than one year, or by a more severe
                penalty, unless surrender for such offence is not permitted by the laws of the
                Requested Party.</content></paragraph><statutoryNote id="ID_1600067337359_013" type="footnote">
            <content>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="font_size_8.5">
                    <colgroup>
                        <col width="9%"></col>
                        <col width="91%"></col>
                    </colgroup>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>Note: <sup>#</sup></td>
                            <td colspan="1" class="align_justified">The Agreement for the Surrender
                                of Fugitive Offenders between the Government of the Hong Kong
                                Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and
                                the Government of the Republic of Korea was done in the Chinese,
                                English and Korean languages, each text being equally authentic. The
                                Korean text of the Agreement is available for inspection at the
                                Security Bureau of the Government of the HKSAR.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </content>
        </statutoryNote></schedule></main></subLeg>