<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 503 sub. leg. AB</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>503AB</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap503AB!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-02-25</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403283844_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-02-25">Fugitive
                                    Offenders (Corruption) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap503/s3">Cap.
                                                503, section
                                    3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                                2021</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[21 December 2007]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2007/ln199">L.N. 199 of
                                                  2007</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403283860_002" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403283860_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Procedures in Ordinance to apply between Hong Kong and certain places outside Hong Kong</heading><content>In relation to the arrangements for the surrender of fugitive offenders the terms of which are recited in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, it is directed that the procedures in the Ordinance shall apply as between Hong Kong and the places outside Hong Kong to which the arrangements relate subject to the limitations, restrictions, exceptions and qualifications contained in the terms of the arrangements.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403283891_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap503AB/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>United
            Nations Convention against Corruption</heading><crossHeading class="align_center ">PREAMBLE</crossHeading><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>The States Parties to this
                Convention,</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Concerned</i> about the seriousness of
            problems and threats posed by corruption to the stability and security of societies,
            undermining the institutions and values of democracy, ethical values and justice and
            jeopardizing sustainable development and the rule of
            law,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Concerned also</i> about the links
            between corruption and other forms of crime, in particular organized crime and economic
            crime, including
            money-laundering,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Concerned further</i> about cases of
            corruption that involve vast quantities of assets, which may constitute a substantial
            proportion of the resources of States, and that threaten the political stability and
            sustainable development of those
            States,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced</i> that corruption is no
            longer a local matter but a transnational phenomenon that affects all societies and
            economies, making international cooperation to prevent and control it
            essential,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced also</i> that a comprehensive
            and multidisciplinary approach is required to prevent and combat corruption
            effectively,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced further</i> that the
            availability of technical assistance can play an important role in enhancing the ability
            of States, including by strengthening capacity and by institution-building, to prevent
            and combat corruption
            effectively,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced</i> that the illicit
            acquisition of personal wealth can be particularly damaging to democratic institutions,
            national economies and the rule of
            law,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Determined</i> to prevent, detect and
            deter in a more effective manner international transfers of illicitly acquired assets
            and to strengthen international cooperation in asset
            recovery,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Acknowledging</i> the fundamental
            principles of due process of law in criminal proceedings and in civil or administrative
            proceedings to adjudicate property
            rights,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Bearing in mind</i> that the prevention
            and eradication of corruption is a responsibility of all States and that they must
            cooperate with one another, with the support and involvement of individuals and groups
            outside the public sector, such as civil society, non-governmental organizations and
            community-based organizations, if their efforts in this area are to be
            effective,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Bearing also in mind</i> the principles
            of proper management of public affairs and public property, fairness, responsibility and
            equality before the law and the need to safeguard integrity and to foster a culture of
            rejection of corruption,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Commending</i> the work of the
            Commission on Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice and the United Nations Office on
            Drugs and Crime in preventing and combating
            corruption,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Recalling</i> the work carried out by
            other international and regional organizations in this field, including the activities
            of the African Union, the Council of Europe, the Customs Cooperation Council (also known
            as the World Customs Organization), the European Union, the League of Arab States, the
            Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development and the Organization of American
            States,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Taking note with appreciation</i> of
            multilateral instruments to prevent and combat corruption, including, inter alia, the
            Inter-American Convention against Corruption, adopted by the Organization of American
            States on 29 March 1996, the Convention on the Fight against Corruption involving
            Officials of the European Communities or Officials of Member States of the European
            Union, adopted by the Council of the European Union on 26 May 1997, the Convention on
            Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials in International Business Transactions,
            adopted by the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development on 21 November
            1997, the Criminal Law Convention on Corruption, adopted by the Committee of Ministers
            of the Council of Europe on 27 January 1999, the Civil Law Convention on Corruption,
            adopted by the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe on 4 November 1999, and
            the African Union<inline class="width_3"> </inline>Convention on Preventing and
            Combating Corruption, adopted by the Heads of State and Government of the African Union
            on 12 July 2003,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Welcoming</i> the entry into force on 29
            September 2003 of the United Nations Convention against Transnational Organized
            Crime,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Have agreed as
            follows:</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading>Chapter I<marker role="blank-line"></marker>General provisions</crossHeading><text class="align_center"><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><i>Article
                1<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>Statement of
            purpose</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><leadIn class="left_indent_24">The purposes of this Convention are:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_001" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>To promote and strengthen measures to prevent and combat corruption more
                efficiently and effectively;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_002" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>To promote, facilitate and support international cooperation and technical
                assistance in the prevention of and fight against corruption, including in asset
                recovery;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_003" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>To promote integrity, accountability and proper management of public affairs
                and public property.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article 2</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><i>Use of
                    terms</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_24">For the purposes of this Convention:</text><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_004" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>“Public official” shall mean: (i) any person holding a legislative, executive,
                administrative or judicial office of a State Party, whether appointed or elected,
                whether permanent or temporary, whether paid or unpaid, irrespective of that
                person’s seniority; (ii) any other person who performs a public function, including
                for a public agency or public enterprise, or provides a public service, as defined
                in the domestic law of the State Party and as applied in the pertinent area of law
                of that State Party; (iii) any other person defined as a “public official” in the
                domestic law of a State Party. However, for the purpose of some specific measures
                contained in chapter II of this Convention, “public official” may mean any person
                who performs a public function or provides a public service as defined in the
                domestic law of the State Party and as applied in the pertinent area of law of that
                State Party;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_005" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>“Foreign public official” shall mean any person holding a legislative,
                executive, administrative or judicial office of a foreign country, whether appointed
                or elected; and any person exercising a public function for a foreign country,
                including for a public agency or public enterprise; </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_006" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>“Official of a public international organization” shall mean an international
                civil servant or any person who is authorized by such an organization to act on
                behalf of that organization;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_007" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>“Property” shall mean assets of every kind, whether corporeal or incorporeal,
                movable or immovable, tangible or intangible, and legal documents or instruments
                evidencing title to or interest in such assets;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_008" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>“Proceeds of crime” shall mean any property derived from or obtained, directly
                or indirectly, through the commission of an offence;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_009" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>“Freezing” or “seizure” shall mean temporarily prohibiting the transfer,
                conversion, disposition or movement of property or temporarily assuming custody or
                control of property on the basis of an order issued by a court or other competent
                authority;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_010" name="g" temporalId="sch0_g"><num class="align_left" value="g">(g)</num><content>“Confiscation”, which includes forfeiture where applicable, shall mean the
                permanent deprivation of property by order of a court or other competent
                authority;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_011" name="h" temporalId="sch0_h"><num class="align_left" value="h">(h)</num><content>“Predicate offence” shall mean any offence as a result of which proceeds have
                been generated that may become the subject of an offence as defined in article 23 of
                this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(i)</num><content>“Controlled delivery” shall mean the technique of allowing illicit or suspect
                consignments to pass out of, through or into the territory of one or more States,
                with the knowledge and under the supervision of their competent authorities, with a
                view to the investigation of an offence and the identification of persons involved
                in the commission of the offence.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article 3</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><i>Scope
                    of
                application</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></inline></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_013" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>This Convention shall apply, in accordance with its terms, to the prevention,
                investigation and prosecution of corruption and to the freezing, seizure,
                confiscation and return of the proceeds of offences established in accordance with
                this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_014" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>For the purposes of implementing this Convention, it shall not be necessary,
                except as otherwise stated herein, for the offences set forth in it to result in
                damage or harm to state property.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                4</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Protection of
                    sovereignty</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_015" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>States Parties shall carry out their obligations under this Convention in a
                manner consistent with the principles of sovereign equality and territorial
                integrity of States and that of non-intervention in the domestic affairs of other
                States.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_016" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Nothing in this Convention shall entitle a State Party to undertake in the
                territory of another State the exercise of jurisdiction and performance of functions
                that are reserved exclusively for the authorities of that other State by its
                domestic law.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>Chapter
            II<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Preventive
            measures</crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                5</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Preventive anti-corruption policies and
            practices</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_017" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                legal system, develop and implement or maintain effective, coordinated
                anti-corruption policies that promote the participation of society and reflect the
                principles of the rule of law, proper management of public affairs and public
                property, integrity, transparency and accountability.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_018" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall endeavour to establish and promote effective practices
                aimed at the prevention of corruption.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_019" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall endeavour to periodically evaluate relevant legal
                instruments and administrative measures with a view to determining their adequacy to
                prevent and fight corruption.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_020" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>States Parties shall, as appropriate and in accordance with the fundamental
                principles of their legal system, collaborate with each other and with relevant
                international and regional organizations in promoting and developing the measures
                referred to in this article. That collaboration may include participation in
                international programmes and projects aimed at the prevention of
                corruption.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                6</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Preventive anti-corruption body or
            bodies</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_021" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                legal system, ensure the existence of a body or bodies, as appropriate, that prevent
                corruption by such means as:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109226_022" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Implementing the policies referred to in article 5 of this Convention and,
                where appropriate, overseeing and coordinating the implementation of those
                policies;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_023" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Increasing and disseminating knowledge about the prevention of
                corruption.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_024" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall grant the body or bodies referred to in paragraph 1 of
                this article the necessary independence, in accordance with the fundamental
                principles of its legal system, to enable the body or bodies to carry out its or
                their functions effectively and free from any undue influence. The necessary
                material resources and specialized staff, as well as the training that such staff
                may require to carry out their functions, should be provided.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_025" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall inform the Secretary-General of the United Nations of
                the name and address of the authority or authorities that may assist other States
                Parties in developing and implementing specific measures for the prevention of
                corruption.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                7</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Public
            sector</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_026" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall, where appropriate and in accordance with the
                fundamental principles of its legal system, endeavour to adopt, maintain and
                strengthen systems for the recruitment, hiring, retention, promotion and retirement
                of civil servants and, where appropriate, other non-elected public
                officials:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_027" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>That are based on principles of efficiency, transparency and objective criteria
                such as merit, equity and aptitude;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_028" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>That include adequate procedures for the selection and training of individuals
                for public positions considered especially vulnerable to corruption and the
                rotation, where appropriate, of such individuals to other positions;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_029" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>That promote adequate remuneration and equitable pay scales, taking into
                account the level of economic development of the State Party;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_030" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>That promote education and training programmes to enable them to meet the
                requirements for the correct, honourable and proper performance of public functions
                and that provide them with specialized and appropriate training to enhance their
                awareness of the risks of corruption inherent in the performance of their functions.
                Such programmes may make reference to codes or standards of conduct in applicable
                areas.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_031" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall also consider adopting appropriate legislative and
                administrative measures, consistent with the objectives of this Convention and in
                accordance with the fundamental principles of its domestic law, to prescribe
                criteria concerning candidature for and election to public office.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_032" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall also consider taking appropriate legislative and
                administrative measures, consistent with the objectives of this Convention and in
                accordance with the fundamental principles of its domestic law, to enhance
                transparency in the funding of candidatures for elected public office and, where
                applicable, the funding of political parties.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_033" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                domestic law, endeavour to adopt, maintain and strengthen systems that promote
                transparency and prevent conflicts of interest.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                8</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Codes of conduct for public
            officials</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_034" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>In order to fight corruption, each State Party shall promote, inter alia,
                integrity, honesty and responsibility among its public officials, in accordance with
                the fundamental principles of its legal system.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_035" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>In particular, each State Party shall endeavour to apply, within its own
                institutional and legal systems, codes or standards of conduct for the correct,
                honourable and proper performance of public functions.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_036" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>For the purposes of implementing the provisions of this article, each State
                Party shall, where appropriate and in accordance with the fundamental principles of
                its legal system, take note of the relevant initiatives of regional, interregional
                and multilateral organizations, such as the International Code of Conduct for Public
                Officials contained in the annex to General Assembly resolution 51/59 of 12 December
                1996.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_037" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Each State Party shall also consider, in accordance with the fundamental
                principles of its domestic law, establishing measures and systems to facilitate the
                reporting by public officials of acts of corruption to appropriate authorities, when
                such acts come to their notice in the performance of their functions.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_038" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>Each State Party shall endeavour, where appropriate and in accordance with the
                fundamental principles of its domestic law, to establish measures and systems
                requiring public officials to make declarations to appropriate authorities
                regarding, inter alia, their outside activities, employment, investments, assets and
                substantial gifts or benefits from which a conflict of interest may result with
                respect to their functions as public officials.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_039" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider taking, in accordance with the fundamental
                principles of its domestic law, disciplinary or other measures against public
                officials who violate the codes or standards established in accordance with this
                article.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                9</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Public procurement and management</i><br></br><i>of public
                    finances</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_040" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                legal system, take the necessary steps to establish appropriate systems of
                procurement, based on transparency, competition and objective criteria in
                decision-making, that are effective, inter alia, in preventing corruption. Such
                systems, which may take into account appropriate threshold values in their
                application, shall address, inter alia:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_041" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The public distribution of information relating to procurement procedures and
                contracts, including information on invitations to tender and relevant or pertinent
                information on the award of contracts, allowing potential tenderers sufficient time
                to prepare and submit their tenders;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_042" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The establishment, in advance, of conditions for participation, including
                selection and award criteria and tendering rules, and their publication;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_043" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>The use of objective and predetermined criteria for public procurement
                decisions, in order to facilitate the subsequent verification of the correct
                application of the rules or procedures;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_044" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>An effective system of domestic review, including an effective system of
                appeal, to ensure legal recourse and remedies in the event that the rules or
                procedures established pursuant to this paragraph are not followed;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109242_045" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>Where appropriate, measures to regulate matters regarding personnel responsible
                for procurement, such as declaration of interest in particular public procurements,
                screening procedures and training requirements.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_046" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                legal system, take appropriate measures to promote transparency and accountability
                in the management of public finances. Such measures shall encompass, inter
                alia:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_047" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Procedures for the adoption of the national budget;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_048" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Timely reporting on revenue and expenditure;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_049" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>A system of accounting and auditing standards and related oversight;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_050" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>Effective and efficient systems of risk management and internal control;
                and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_051" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>Where appropriate, corrective action in the case of failure to comply with the
                requirements established in this paragraph.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_052" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall take such civil and administrative measures as may be
                necessary, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its domestic law, to
                preserve the integrity of accounting books, records, financial statements or other
                documents related to public expenditure and revenue and to prevent the falsification
                of such documents.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                10</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Public
            reporting</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="first_line_indent_24">Taking into account the need to combat corruption, each
            State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its domestic law,
            take such measures as may be necessary to enhance transparency in its public
            administration, including with regard to its organization, functioning and
            decision-making processes, where appropriate. Such measures may include, inter
            alia:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_053" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Adopting procedures or regulations allowing members of the general public to
                obtain, where appropriate, information on the organization, functioning and
                decision-making processes of its public administration and, with due regard for the
                protection of privacy and personal data, on decisions and legal acts that concern
                members of the public;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_054" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Simplifying administrative procedures, where appropriate, in order to
                facilitate public access to the competent decision-making authorities; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_055" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Publishing information, which may include periodic reports on the risks of
                corruption in its public administration.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                11</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Measures relating to the judiciary and</i><br></br><i>prosecution
                    services</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_056" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Bearing in mind the independence of the judiciary and its crucial role in
                combating corruption, each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental
                principles of its legal system and without prejudice to judicial independence, take
                measures to strengthen integrity and to prevent opportunities for corruption among
                members of the judiciary. Such measures may include rules with respect to the
                conduct of members of the judiciary.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_057" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Measures to the same effect as those taken pursuant to paragraph 1 of this
                article may be introduced and applied within the prosecution service in those States
                Parties where it does not form part of the judiciary but enjoys independence similar
                to that of the judicial service.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                12</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Private
            sector</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_058" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall take measures, in accordance with the fundamental
                principles of its domestic law, to prevent corruption involving the private sector,
                enhance accounting and auditing standards in the private sector and, where
                appropriate, provide effective, proportionate and dissuasive civil, administrative
                or criminal penalties for failure to comply with such measures.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_059" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Measures to achieve these ends may include, inter alia: </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_060" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Promoting cooperation between law enforcement agencies and relevant private
                entities;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_061" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Promoting the development of standards and procedures designed to safeguard the
                integrity of relevant private entities, including codes of conduct for the correct,
                honourable and proper performance of the activities of business and all relevant
                professions and the prevention of conflicts of interest, and for the promotion of
                the use of good commercial practices among businesses and in the contractual
                relations of businesses with the State;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_062" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Promoting transparency among private entities, including, where appropriate,
                measures regarding the identity of legal and natural persons involved in the
                establishment and management of corporate entities;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_063" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>Preventing the misuse of procedures regulating private entities, including
                procedures regarding subsidies and licences granted by public authorities for
                commercial activities;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_064" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>Preventing conflicts of interest by imposing restrictions, as appropriate and
                for a reasonable period of time, on the professional activities of former public
                officials or on the employment of public officials by the private sector after their
                resignation or retirement, where such activities or employment relate directly to
                the functions held or supervised by those public officials during their
                tenure;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_065" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>Ensuring that private enterprises, taking into account their structure and
                size, have sufficient internal auditing controls to assist in preventing and
                detecting acts of corruption and that the accounts and required financial statements
                of such private enterprises are subject to appropriate auditing and certification
                procedures.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_066" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>In order to prevent corruption, each State Party shall take such measures as
                may be necessary, in accordance with its domestic laws and regulations regarding the
                maintenance of books and records, financial statement disclosures and accounting and
                auditing standards, to prohibit the following acts carried out for the purpose of
                committing any of the offences established in accordance with this
                Convention:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_067" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The establishment of off-the-books accounts;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_068" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The making of off-the-books or inadequately identified transactions;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109257_069" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>The recording of non-existent expenditure;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_070" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>The entry of liabilities with incorrect identification of their
                objects;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_071" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>The use of false documents; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_072" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>The intentional destruction of bookkeeping documents earlier than foreseen by
                the law.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_073" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Each State Party shall disallow the tax deductibility of expenses that
                constitute bribes, the latter being one of the constituent elements of the offences
                established in accordance with articles 15 and 16 of this Convention and, where
                appropriate, other expenses incurred in furtherance of corrupt conduct.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                13</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Participation of
            society</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_074" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall take appropriate measures, within its means and in
                accordance with fundamental principles of its domestic law, to promote the active
                participation of individuals and groups outside the public sector, such as civil
                society, non-governmental organizations and community-based organizations, in the
                prevention of and the fight against corruption and to raise public awareness
                regarding the existence, causes and gravity of and the threat posed by corruption.
                This participation should be strengthened by such measures as:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_075" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Enhancing the transparency of and promoting the contribution of the public to
                decision-making processes;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_076" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Ensuring that the public has effective access to information; </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_077" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Undertaking public information activities that contribute to non-tolerance of
                corruption, as well as public education programmes, including school and university
                curricula;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_078" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>Respecting, promoting and protecting the freedom to seek, receive, publish and
                disseminate information concerning corruption. That freedom may be subject to
                certain restrictions, but these shall only be such as are provided for by law and
                are necessary:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_079" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(i)</num><content>For respect of the rights or reputations of others;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1613629252776_001" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(ii)</num><content>For the protection of national security or ordre public or of public health or
                morals.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_080" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall take appropriate measures to ensure that the relevant
                anti-corruption bodies referred to in this Convention are known to the public and
                shall provide access to such bodies, where appropriate, for the reporting, including
                anonymously, of any incidents that may be considered to constitute an offence
                established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                14</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Measures to prevent
            money-laundering</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_081" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_082" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Institute a comprehensive domestic regulatory and supervisory regime for banks
                and non-bank financial institutions, including natural or legal persons that provide
                formal or informal services for the transmission of money or value and, where
                appropriate, other bodies particularly susceptible to money-laundering, within its
                competence, in order to deter and detect all forms of money-laundering, which regime
                shall emphasize requirements for customer and, where appropriate, beneficial owner
                identification, record-keeping and the reporting of suspicious
                transactions;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_083" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Without prejudice to article 46 of this Convention, ensure that administrative,
                regulatory, law enforcement and other authorities dedicated to combating
                money-laundering (including, where appropriate under domestic law, judicial
                authorities) have the ability to cooperate and exchange information at the national
                and international levels within the conditions prescribed by its domestic law and,
                to that end, shall consider the establishment of a financial intelligence unit to
                serve as a national centre for the collection, analysis and dissemination of
                information regarding potential money-laundering.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_084" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>States Parties shall consider implementing feasible measures to detect and
                monitor the movement of cash and appropriate negotiable instruments across their
                borders, subject to safeguards to ensure proper use of information and without
                impeding in any way the movement of legitimate capital. Such measures may include a
                requirement that individuals and businesses report the cross-border transfer of
                substantial quantities of cash and appropriate negotiable instruments.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_085" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>States Parties shall consider implementing appropriate and feasible measures to
                require financial institutions, including money remitters: </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_086" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>To include on forms for the electronic transfer of funds and related messages
                accurate and meaningful information on the originator;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_087" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>To maintain such information throughout the payment chain; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_088" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>To apply enhanced scrutiny to transfers of funds that do not contain complete
                information on the originator.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109273_089" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>In establishing a domestic regulatory and supervisory regime under the terms of
                this article, and without prejudice to any other article of this Convention, States
                Parties are called upon to use as a guideline the relevant initiatives of regional,
                interregional and multilateral organizations against money-laundering.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_090" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>States Parties shall endeavour to develop and promote global, regional,
                subregional and bilateral cooperation among judicial, law enforcement and financial
                regulatory authorities in order to combat
                money-laundering.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>Chapter
            III<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Criminalization
            and law
            enforcement</crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                15</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Bribery of national public
            officials</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Each State Party shall
            adopt such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal
            offences, when committed intentionally:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_091" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The promise, offering or giving, to a public official, directly or indirectly,
                of an undue advantage, for the official himself or herself or another person or
                entity, in order that the official act or refrain from acting in the exercise of his
                or her official duties;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_092" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The solicitation or acceptance by a public official, directly or indirectly, of
                an undue advantage, for the official himself or herself or another person or entity,
                in order that the official act or refrain from acting in the exercise of his or her
                official duties.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                16</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Bribery of foreign public officials and officials
                    of</i><br></br><i>public international
            organizations</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_093" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall adopt such legislative and other measures as may be
                necessary to establish as a criminal offence, when committed intentionally, the
                promise, offering or giving to a foreign public official or an official of a public
                international organization, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage, for the
                official himself or herself or another person or entity, in order that the official
                act or refrain from acting in the exercise of his or her official duties, in order
                to obtain or retain business or other undue advantage in relation to the conduct of
                international business.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_094" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider adopting such legislative and other measures as
                may be necessary to establish as a criminal offence, when committed intentionally,
                the solicitation or acceptance by a foreign public official or an official of a
                public international organization, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage,
                for the official himself or herself or another person or entity, in order that the
                official act or refrain from acting in the exercise of his or her official
                duties.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                17</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Embezzlement, misappropriation or other diversion</i><br></br><i>of
                    property by a public
            official</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall adopt such
            legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal offences,
            when committed intentionally, the embezzlement, misappropriation or other diversion by a
            public official for his or her benefit or for the benefit of another person or entity,
            of any property, public or private funds or securities or any other thing of value
            entrusted to the public official by virtue of his or her
            position.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                18</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Trading in
            influence</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Each State Party shall consider
            adopting such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as
            criminal offences, when committed intentionally:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_095" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The promise, offering or giving to a public official or any other person,
                directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage in order that the public official or
                the person abuse his or her real or supposed influence with a view to obtaining from
                an administration or public authority of the State Party an undue advantage for the
                original instigator of the act or for any other person;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_096" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The solicitation or acceptance by a public official or any other person,
                directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage for himself or herself or for another
                person in order that the public official or the person abuse his or her real or
                supposed influence with a view to obtaining from an administration or public
                authority of the State Party an undue advantage.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                19</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Abuse of
            functions</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider adopting such legislative
            and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal offence, when
            committed intentionally, the abuse of functions or position, that is, the performance of
            or failure to perform an act, in violation of laws, by a public official in the
            discharge of his or her functions, for the purpose of obtaining an undue advantage for
            himself or herself or for another person or entity.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                20</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold "><i>Illicit
            enrichment</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Subject to its constitution and the fundamental
            principles of its legal system, each State Party shall consider adopting such
            legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal offence,
            when committed intentionally, illicit enrichment, that is, a significant increase in the
            assets of a public official that he or she cannot reasonably explain in relation to his
            or her lawful income.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                21</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Bribery in the private
            sector</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Each State Party shall consider adopting
            such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal
            offences, when committed intentionally in the course of economic, financial or
            commercial activities:</text><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_097" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The promise, offering or giving, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage
                to any person who directs or works, in any capacity, for a private sector entity,
                for the person himself or herself or for another person, in order that he or she, in
                breach of his or her duties, act or refrain from acting;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_098" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The solicitation or acceptance, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage
                by any person who directs or works, in any capacity, for a private sector entity,
                for the person himself or herself or for another person, in order that he or she, in
                breach of his or her duties, act or refrain from
                acting.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                22</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Embezzlement of property in the private
            sector</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider adopting such legislative
            and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal offence, when
            committed intentionally in the course of economic, financial or commercial activities,
            embezzlement by a person who directs or works, in any capacity, in a private sector
            entity of any property, private funds or securities or any other thing of value
            entrusted to him or her by virtue of his or her position.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                23</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Laundering of proceeds of
            crime</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_099" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall adopt, in accordance with fundamental principles of its
                domestic law, such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish
                as criminal offences, when committed intentionally:</content></subsection><text class="first_line_indent_24" name="a" temporalId="sch0_P23_s1_a">(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The conversion or
            transfer of property, knowing that such property is the proceeds of crime, for the
            purpose of concealing or disguising the illicit origin of the property or of helping any
            person who is involved in the commission of the predicate offence to evade the legal
            consequences of his or her action;</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(ii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The concealment or disguise of the true nature, source, location,
            disposition, movement or ownership of or rights with respect to property, knowing that
            such property is the proceeds of crime;</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Subject to the basic concepts of its legal system:</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The acquisition, possession or use of property, knowing, at the time of
            receipt, that such property is the proceeds of crime;</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(ii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Participation in, association with or conspiracy to commit, attempts to
            commit and aiding, abetting, facilitating and counselling the commission of any of the
            offences established in accordance with this article.</text><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_100" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>For purposes of implementing or applying paragraph 1 of this article:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_101" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Each State Party shall seek to apply paragraph 1 of this article to the widest
                range of predicate offences;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_102" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Each State Party shall include as predicate offences at a minimum a
                comprehensive range of criminal offences established in accordance with this
                Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_103" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>For the purposes of subparagraph (b) above, predicate offences shall include
                offences committed both within and outside the jurisdiction of the State Party in
                question. However, offences committed outside the jurisdiction of a State Party
                shall constitute predicate offences only when the relevant conduct is a criminal
                offence under the domestic law of the State where it is committed and would be a
                criminal offence under the domestic law of the State Party implementing or applying
                this article had it been committed there;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_104" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>Each State Party shall furnish copies of its laws that give effect to this
                article and of any subsequent changes to such laws or a description thereof to the
                Secretary-General of the United Nations;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109288_105" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>If required by fundamental principles of the domestic law of a State Party, it
                may be provided that the offences set forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this
                article do not apply to the persons who committed the predicate
                offence.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                24</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Concealment</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Without prejudice to the provisions of article 23 of this
            Convention, each State Party shall consider adopting such legislative and other measures
            as may be necessary to establish as a criminal offence, when committed intentionally
            after the commission of any of the offences established in accordance with this
            Convention without having participated in such offences, the concealment or continued
            retention of property when the person involved knows that such property is the result of
            any of the offences established in accordance with this Convention.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                25</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Obstruction of
            justice</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall adopt such legislative and other
            measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal offences, when committed
            intentionally:</text><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_106" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The use of physical force, threats or intimidation or the promise, offering or
                giving of an undue advantage to induce false testimony or to interfere in the giving
                of testimony or the production of evidence in a proceeding in relation to the
                commission of offences established in accordance with this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_107" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The use of physical force, threats or intimidation to interfere with the
                exercise of official duties by a justice or law enforcement official in relation to
                the commission of offences established in accordance with this Convention. Nothing
                in this subparagraph shall prejudice the right of States Parties to have legislation
                that protects other categories of public official.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                26</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Liability of legal
            persons</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_108" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall adopt such measures as may be necessary, consistent with
                its legal principles, to establish the liability of legal persons for participation
                in the offences established in accordance with this Convention. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_109" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Subject to the legal principles of the State Party, the liability of legal
                persons may be criminal, civil or administrative.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_110" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Such liability shall be without prejudice to the criminal liability of the
                natural persons who have committed the offences.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_111" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Each State Party shall, in particular, ensure that legal persons held liable in
                accordance with this article are subject to effective, proportionate and dissuasive
                criminal or non-criminal sanctions, including monetary sanctions.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                27</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Participation and
            attempt</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_112" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall adopt such legislative and other measures as may be
                necessary to establish as a criminal offence, in accordance with its domestic law,
                participation in any capacity such as an accomplice, assistant or instigator in an
                offence established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_113" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party may adopt such legislative and other measures as may be
                necessary to establish as a criminal offence, in accordance with its domestic law,
                any attempt to commit an offence established in accordance with this
                Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_114" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party may adopt such legislative and other measures as may be
                necessary to establish as a criminal offence, in accordance with its domestic law,
                the preparation for an offence established in accordance with this
                Convention.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                28</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Knowledge, intent and purpose as elements</i><br></br><i>of an
                    offence</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Knowledge, intent or purpose required as an element of an
            offence established in accordance with this Convention may be inferred from objective
            factual circumstances.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                29</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Statute of
            limitations</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall, where appropriate, establish
            under its domestic law a long statute of limitations period in which to commence
            proceedings for any offence established in accordance with this Convention and establish
            a longer statute of limitations period or provide for the suspension of the statute of
            limitations where the alleged offender has evaded the administration of
            justice.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                30</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Prosecution, adjudication and
            sanctions</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_115" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall make the commission of an offence established in
                accordance with this Convention liable to sanctions that take into account the
                gravity of that offence.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_116" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary to establish or
                maintain, in accordance with its legal system and constitutional principles, an
                appropriate balance between any immunities or jurisdictional privileges accorded to
                its public officials for the performance of their functions and the possibility,
                when necessary, of effectively investigating, prosecuting and adjudicating offences
                established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_117" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall endeavour to ensure that any discretionary legal powers
                under its domestic law relating to the prosecution of persons for offences
                established in accordance with this Convention are exercised to maximize the
                effectiveness of law enforcement measures in respect of those offences and with due
                regard to the need to deter the commission of such offences.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_118" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>In the case of offences established in accordance with this Convention, each
                State Party shall take appropriate measures, in accordance with its domestic law and
                with due regard to the rights of the defence, to seek to ensure that conditions
                imposed in connection with decisions on release pending trial or appeal take into
                consideration the need to ensure the presence of the defendant at subsequent
                criminal proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_119" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>Each State Party shall take into account the gravity of the offences concerned
                when considering the eventuality of early release or parole of persons convicted of
                such offences.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_120" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>Each State Party, to the extent consistent with the fundamental principles of
                its legal system, shall consider establishing procedures through which a public
                official accused of an offence established in accordance with this Convention may,
                where appropriate, be removed, suspended or reassigned by the appropriate authority,
                bearing in mind respect for the principle of the presumption of innocence.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_121" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">7.</num><content>Where warranted by the gravity of the offence, each State Party, to the extent
                consistent with the fundamental principles of its legal system, shall consider
                establishing procedures for the disqualification, by court order or any other
                appropriate means, for a period of time determined by its domestic law, of persons
                convicted of offences established in accordance with this Convention from:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_122" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Holding public office; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_123" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Holding office in an enterprise owned in whole or in part by the
                State.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109304_124" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num class="align_left" value="8">8.</num><content>Paragraph 1 of this article shall be without prejudice to the exercise of
                disciplinary powers by the competent authorities against civil servants.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_125" name="9" temporalId="sch0_9"><num class="align_left" value="9">9.</num><content>Nothing contained in this Convention shall affect the principle that the
                description of the offences established in accordance with this Convention and of
                the applicable legal defences or other legal principles controlling the lawfulness
                of conduct is reserved to the domestic law of a State Party and that such offences
                shall be prosecuted and punished in accordance with that law. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_126" name="10" temporalId="sch0_10"><num class="align_left" value="10">10.</num><content>States Parties shall endeavour to promote the reintegration into society of
                persons convicted of offences established in accordance with this
                Convention.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                31</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Freezing, seizure and
            confiscation</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_127" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall take, to the greatest extent possible within its
                domestic legal system, such measures as may be necessary to enable confiscation
                of:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_128" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Proceeds of crime derived from offences established in accordance with this
                Convention or property the value of which corresponds to that of such
                proceeds;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_129" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Property, equipment or other instrumentalities used in or destined for use in
                offences established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_130" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary to enable the
                identification, tracing, freezing or seizure of any item referred to in
                    <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article for the purpose of eventual
                confiscation.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_131" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall adopt, in accordance with its domestic law, such
                legislative and other measures as may be necessary to regulate the administration by
                the competent authorities of frozen, seized or confiscated property covered in
                paragraphs 1 and 2 of this article.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_132" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>If such proceeds of crime have been transformed or converted, in part or in
                full, into other property, such property shall be liable to the measures referred to
                in this article instead of the proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_133" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>If such proceeds of crime have been intermingled with property acquired from
                legitimate sources, such property shall, without prejudice to any powers relating to
                freezing or seizure, be liable to confiscation up to the assessed value of the
                intermingled proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_134" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>Income or other benefits derived from such proceeds of crime, from property
                into which such proceeds of crime have been transformed or converted or from
                property with which such proceeds of crime have been intermingled shall also be
                liable to the measures referred to in this article, in the same manner and to the
                same extent as proceeds of crime.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_135" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">7.</num><content>For the purpose of this article and article 55 of this Convention, each State
                Party shall empower its courts or other competent authorities to order that bank,
                financial or commercial records be made available or seized. A State Party shall not
                decline to act under the provisions of this paragraph on the ground of bank
                secrecy.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_136" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num class="align_left" value="8">8.</num><content>States Parties may consider the possibility of requiring that an offender
                demonstrate the lawful origin of such alleged proceeds of crime or other property
                liable to confiscation, to the extent that such a requirement is consistent with the
                fundamental principles of their domestic law and with the nature of judicial and
                other proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_137" name="9" temporalId="sch0_9"><num class="align_left" value="9">9.</num><content>The provisions of this article shall not be so construed as to prejudice the
                rights of bona fide third parties.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_138" name="10" temporalId="sch0_10"><num class="align_left" value="10">10.</num><content>Nothing contained in this article shall affect the principle that the measures
                to which it refers shall be defined and implemented in accordance with and subject
                to the provisions of the domestic law of a State Party.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold "><i>Article
                32</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold "><i>Protection of witnesses, experts and
            victims</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_139" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall take appropriate measures in accordance with its
                domestic legal system and within its means to provide effective protection from
                potential retaliation or intimidation for witnesses and experts who give testimony
                concerning offences established in accordance with this Convention and, as
                appropriate, for their relatives and other persons close to them.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_140" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>The measures envisaged in paragraph 1 of this article may include, inter alia,
                without prejudice to the rights of the defendant, including the right to due
                process:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_141" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Establishing procedures for the physical protection of such persons, such as,
                to the extent necessary and feasible, relocating them and permitting, where
                appropriate, non-disclosure or limitations on the disclosure of information
                concerning the identity and whereabouts of such persons;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109320_142" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Providing evidentiary rules to permit witnesses and experts to give testimony
                in a manner that ensures the safety of such persons, such as permitting testimony to
                be given through the use of communications technology such as video or other
                adequate means.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_143" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>States Parties shall consider entering into agreements or arrangements with
                other States for the relocation of persons referred to in paragraph 1 of this
                article.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_144" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>The provisions of this article shall also apply to victims insofar as they are
                witnesses.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_145" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>Each State Party shall, subject to its domestic law, enable the views and
                concerns of victims to be presented and considered at appropriate stages of criminal
                proceedings against offenders in a manner not prejudicial to the rights of the
                defence.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                33</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Protection of reporting
            persons</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider incorporating into its
            domestic legal system appropriate measures to provide protection against any unjustified
            treatment for any person who reports in good faith and on reasonable grounds to the
            competent authorities any facts concerning offences established in accordance with this
            Convention.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                34</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Consequences of acts of
            corruption</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">With due regard to the rights of third parties acquired
            in good faith, each State Party shall take measures, in accordance with the fundamental
            principles of its domestic law, to address consequences of corruption. In this context,
            States Parties may consider corruption a relevant factor in legal proceedings to annul
            or rescind a contract, withdraw a concession or other similar instrument or take any
            other remedial action.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                35</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Compensation for
            damage</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall take such measures as may be
            necessary, in accordance with principles of its domestic law, to ensure that entities or
            persons who have suffered damage as a result of an act of corruption have the right to
            initiate legal proceedings against those responsible for that damage in order to obtain
            compensation.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                36</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Specialized
            authorities</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall, in accordance with the
            fundamental principles of its legal system, ensure the existence of a body or bodies or
            persons specialized in combating corruption through law enforcement. Such body or bodies
            or persons shall be granted the necessary independence, in accordance with the
            fundamental principles of the legal system of the State Party, to be able to carry out
            their functions effectively and without any undue influence. Such persons or staff of
            such body or bodies should have the appropriate training and resources to carry out
            their tasks.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                37</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Cooperation with law enforcement
            authorities</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_146" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall take appropriate measures to encourage persons who
                participate or who have participated in the commission of an offence established in
                accordance with this Convention to supply information useful to competent
                authorities for investigative and evidentiary purposes and to provide factual,
                specific help to competent authorities that may contribute to depriving offenders of
                the proceeds of crime and to recovering such proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_147" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider providing for the possibility, in appropriate
                cases, of mitigating punishment of an accused person who provides substantial
                cooperation in the investigation or prosecution of an offence established in
                accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_148" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider providing for the possibility, in accordance
                with fundamental principles of its domestic law, of granting immunity from
                prosecution to a person who provides substantial cooperation in the investigation or
                prosecution of an offence established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_149" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Protection of such persons shall be, mutatis mutandis, as provided for in
                article 32 of this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_150" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>Where a person referred to in paragraph 1 of this article located in one State
                Party can provide substantial cooperation to the competent authorities of another
                State Party, the States Parties concerned may consider entering into agreements or
                arrangements, in accordance with their domestic law, concerning the potential
                provision by the other State Party of the treatment set forth in paragraphs 2 and 3
                of this article.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                38</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Cooperation between national
            authorities</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall take such measures as may be
            necessary to encourage, in accordance with its domestic law, cooperation between, on the
            one hand, its public authorities, as well as its public officials, and, on the other
            hand, its authorities responsible for investigating and prosecuting criminal offences.
            Such cooperation may include:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_151" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Informing the latter authorities, on their own initiative, where there are
                reasonable grounds to believe that any of the offences established in accordance
                with articles 15, 21 and 23 of this Convention has been committed; or</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_152" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Providing, upon request, to the latter authorities all necessary
                information.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                39</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Cooperation between national authorities</i><br></br><i>and the
                    private
            sector</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_153" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary to encourage, in
                accordance with its domestic law, cooperation between national investigating and
                prosecuting authorities and entities of the private sector, in particular financial
                institutions, relating to matters involving the commission of offences established
                in accordance with this Convention. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_154" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider encouraging its nationals and other persons
                with a habitual residence in its territory to report to the national investigating
                and prosecuting authorities the commission of an offence established in accordance
                with this Convention.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                40</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Bank
            secrecy</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall ensure that, in the case of
            domestic criminal investigations of offences established in accordance with this
            Convention, there are appropriate mechanisms available within its domestic legal system
            to overcome obstacles that may arise out of the application of bank secrecy laws. </text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                41</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Criminal
            record</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party may adopt such legislative or other
            measures as may be necessary to take into consideration, under such terms as and for the
            purpose that it deems appropriate, any previous conviction in another State of an
            alleged offender for the purpose of using such information in criminal proceedings
            relating to an offence established in accordance with this Convention.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                42</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Jurisdiction</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_155" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall adopt such measures as may be necessary to establish its
                jurisdiction over the offences established in accordance with this Convention
                when:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_156" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The offence is committed in the territory of that State Party; or </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_157" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The offence is committed on board a vessel that is flying the flag of that
                State Party or an aircraft that is registered under the laws of that State Party at
                the time that the offence is committed.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_158" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Subject to article 4 of this Convention, a State Party may also establish its
                jurisdiction over any such offence when:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_159" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The offence is committed against a national of that State Party; or</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_160" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The offence is committed by a national of that State Party or a stateless
                person who has his or her habitual residence in its territory; or</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109335_161" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>The offence is one of those established in accordance with article 23,
                paragraph 1(b)(ii), of this Convention and is committed outside its territory with a
                view to the commission of an offence established in accordance with article 23,
                paragraph 1(a)(i) or (ii) or (b)(i), of this Convention within its territory;
                or</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_162" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>The offence is committed against the State Party. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_163" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>For the purposes of article 44 of this Convention, each State Party shall take
                such measures as may be necessary to establish its jurisdiction over the offences
                established in accordance with this Convention when the alleged offender is present
                in its territory and it does not extradite such person solely on the ground that he
                or she is one of its nationals.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_164" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Each State Party may also take such measures as may be necessary to establish
                its jurisdiction over the offences established in accordance with this Convention
                when the alleged offender is present in its territory and it does not extradite him
                or her.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_165" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>If a State Party exercising its jurisdiction under paragraph 1 or 2 of this
                article has been notified, or has otherwise learned, that any other States Parties
                are conducting an investigation, prosecution or judicial proceeding in respect of
                the same conduct, the competent authorities of those States Parties shall, as
                appropriate, consult one another with a view to coordinating their
                actions.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_166" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>Without prejudice to norms of general international law, this Convention shall
                not exclude the exercise of any criminal jurisdiction established by a State Party
                in accordance with its domestic law.</content></subsection><crossHeading>Chapter
            IV<marker role="blank-line"></marker>International
            cooperation</crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold "><i>Article
                43</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold "><i>International
            cooperation</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_167" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>States Parties shall cooperate in criminal matters in accordance with articles
                44 to 50 of this Convention. Where appropriate and consistent with their domestic
                legal system, States Parties shall consider assisting each other in investigations
                of and proceedings in civil and administrative matters relating to
                corruption.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_168" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>In matters of international cooperation, whenever dual criminality is
                considered a requirement, it shall be deemed fulfilled irrespective of whether the
                laws of the requested State Party place the offence within the same category of
                offence or denominate the offence by the same terminology as the requesting State
                Party, if the conduct underlying the offence for which assistance is sought is a
                criminal offence under the laws of both States
                Parties.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                44</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Extradition</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_169" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>This article shall apply to the offences established in accordance with this
                Convention where the person who is the subject of the request for extradition is
                present in the territory of the requested State Party, provided that the offence for
                which extradition is sought is punishable under the domestic law of both the
                requesting State Party and the<inline class="width_3"> </inline>requested State
                Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_170" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph 1 of this article, a State Party
                whose law so permits may grant the extradition of a person for any of the offences
                covered by this Convention that are not punishable under its own domestic
                law.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_171" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>If the request for extradition includes several separate offences, at least one
                of which is extraditable under this article and some of which are not extraditable
                by reason of their period of imprisonment but are related to offences established in
                accordance with this Convention, the requested State Party may apply this article
                also in respect of those offences.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_172" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Each of the offences to which this article applies shall be deemed to be
                included as an extraditable offence in any extradition treaty existing between
                States Parties. States Parties undertake to include such offences as extraditable
                offences in every extradition treaty to be concluded between them. A State Party
                whose law so permits, in case it uses this Convention as the basis for extradition,
                shall not consider any of the offences established in accordance with this
                Convention to be a political offence.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_173" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>If a State Party that makes extradition conditional on the existence of a
                treaty receives a request for extradition from another State Party with which it has
                no extradition treaty, it may consider this Convention the legal basis for
                extradition in respect of any offence to which this article applies.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_174" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>A State Party that makes extradition conditional on the existence of a treaty
                shall:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_175" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>At the time of deposit of its instrument of ratification, acceptance or
                approval of or accession to this Convention, inform the Secretary-General of the
                United Nations whether it will take this Convention as the legal basis for
                cooperation on extradition with other States Parties to this Convention;
                and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_176" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>If it does not take this Convention as the legal basis for cooperation on
                extradition, seek, where appropriate, to conclude treaties on extradition with other
                States Parties to this Convention in order to implement this article. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_177" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">7.</num><content>States Parties that do not make extradition conditional on the existence of a
                treaty shall recognize offences to which this article applies as extraditable
                offences between themselves.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_178" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num class="align_left" value="8">8.</num><content>Extradition shall be subject to the conditions provided for by the domestic law
                of the requested State Party or by applicable extradition treaties, including, inter
                alia, conditions in relation to the minimum penalty requirement for extradition and
                the grounds upon which the requested State Party may refuse extradition.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_179" name="9" temporalId="sch0_9"><num class="align_left" value="9">9.</num><content>States Parties shall, subject to their domestic law, endeavour to expedite
                extradition procedures and to simplify evidentiary requirements relating thereto in
                respect of any offence to which this article applies.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109351_180" name="10" temporalId="sch0_10"><num class="align_left" value="10">10.</num><content>Subject to the provisions of its domestic law and its extradition treaties, the
                requested State Party may, upon being satisfied that the circumstances so warrant
                and are urgent and at the request of the requesting State Party, take a person whose
                extradition is sought and who is present in its territory into custody or take other
                appropriate measures to ensure his or her presence at extradition
                proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_181" name="11" temporalId="sch0_11"><num class="align_left" value="11">11.</num><content>A State Party in whose territory an alleged offender is found, if it does not
                extradite such person in respect of an offence to which this article applies solely
                on the ground that he or she is one of its nationals, shall, at the request of the
                State Party seeking extradition, be obliged to submit the case without undue delay
                to its competent authorities for the purpose of prosecution. Those authorities shall
                take their decision and conduct their proceedings in the same manner as in the case
                of any other offence of a grave nature under the domestic law of that State Party.
                The States Parties concerned shall cooperate with each other, in particular on
                procedural and evidentiary aspects, to ensure the efficiency of such
                prosecution.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_182" name="12" temporalId="sch0_12"><num class="align_left" value="12">12.</num><content>Whenever a State Party is permitted under its domestic law to extradite or
                otherwise surrender one of its nationals only upon the condition that the person
                will be returned to that State Party to serve the sentence imposed as a result of
                the trial or proceedings for which the extradition or surrender of the person was
                sought and that State Party and the State Party seeking the extradition of the
                person agree with this option and other terms that they may deem appropriate, such
                conditional extradition or surrender shall be sufficient to discharge the obligation
                set forth in <ref>paragraph 11</ref> of this article.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_183" name="13" temporalId="sch0_13"><num class="align_left" value="13">13.</num><content>If extradition, sought for purposes of enforcing a sentence, is refused because
                the person sought is a national of the requested State Party, the requested State
                Party shall, if its domestic law so permits and in conformity with the requirements
                of such law, upon application of the requesting State Party, consider the
                enforcement of the sentence imposed under the domestic law of the requesting State
                Party or the remainder thereof.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_184" name="14" temporalId="sch0_14"><num class="align_left" value="14">14.</num><content>Any person regarding whom proceedings are being carried out in connection with
                any of the offences to which this article applies shall be guaranteed fair treatment
                at all stages of the proceedings, including enjoyment of all the rights and
                guarantees provided by the domestic law of the State Party in the territory of which
                that person is present.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_185" name="15" temporalId="sch0_15"><num class="align_left" value="15">15.</num><content>Nothing in this Convention shall be interpreted as imposing an obligation to
                extradite if the requested State Party has substantial grounds for believing that
                the request has been made for the purpose of prosecuting or punishing a person on
                account of that person’s sex, race, religion, nationality, ethnic origin or
                political opinions or that compliance with the request would cause prejudice to that
                person’s position for any one of these reasons.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_186" name="16" temporalId="sch0_16"><num class="align_left" value="16">16.</num><content>States Parties may not refuse a request for extradition on the sole ground that
                the offence is also considered to involve fiscal matters.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_187" name="17" temporalId="sch0_17"><num class="align_left" value="17">17.</num><content>Before refusing extradition, the requested State Party shall, where
                appropriate, consult with the requesting State Party to provide it with ample
                opportunity to present its opinions and to provide information relevant to its
                allegation.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_188" name="18" temporalId="sch0_18"><num class="align_left" value="18">18.</num><content>States Parties shall seek to conclude bilateral and multilateral agreements or
                arrangements to carry out or to enhance the effectiveness of extradition.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                45</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Transfer of sentenced
            persons</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">States Parties may consider entering into bilateral or
            multilateral agreements or arrangements on the transfer to their territory of persons
            sentenced to imprisonment or other forms of deprivation of liberty for offences
            established in accordance with this Convention in order that they may complete their
            sentences there.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                46</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Mutual legal
            assistance</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_189" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>States Parties shall afford one another the widest measure of mutual legal
                assistance in investigations, prosecutions and judicial proceedings in relation to
                the offences covered by this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_190" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Mutual legal assistance shall be afforded to the fullest extent possible under
                relevant laws, treaties, agreements and arrangements of the requested State Party
                with respect to investigations, prosecutions and judicial proceedings in relation to
                the offences for which a legal person may be held liable in accordance with article
                26 of this Convention in the requesting State Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_191" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Mutual legal assistance to be afforded in accordance with this article may be
                requested for any of the following purposes:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_192" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Taking evidence or statements from persons;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_193" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Effecting service of judicial documents;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_194" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Executing searches and seizures, and freezing;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_195" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>Examining objects and sites;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_196" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>Providing information, evidentiary items and expert evaluations;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_197" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>Providing originals or certified copies of relevant documents and records,
                including government, bank, financial, corporate or business records;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109367_198" name="g" temporalId="sch0_g"><num class="align_left" value="g">(g)</num><content>Identifying or tracing proceeds of crime, property, instrumentalities or other
                things for evidentiary purposes;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_199" name="h" temporalId="sch0_h"><num class="align_left" value="h">(h)</num><content>Facilitating the voluntary appearance of persons in the requesting State
                Party;<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_200" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(i)</num><content>Any other type of assistance that is not contrary to the domestic law of the
                requested State Party;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_201" name="j" temporalId="sch0_j"><num class="align_left" value="j">(j)</num><content>Identifying, freezing and tracing proceeds of crime in accordance with the
                provisions of chapter V of this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_202" name="k" temporalId="sch0_k"><num class="align_left" value="k">(k)</num><content>The recovery of assets, in accordance with the provisions of chapter V of this
                Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_203" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Without prejudice to domestic law, the competent authorities of a State Party
                may, without prior request, transmit information relating to criminal matters to a
                competent authority in another State Party where they believe that such information
                could assist the authority in undertaking or successfully concluding inquiries and
                criminal proceedings or could result in a request formulated by the latter State
                Party pursuant to this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_204" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>The transmission of information pursuant to paragraph 4 of this article shall
                be without prejudice to inquiries and criminal proceedings in the State of the
                competent authorities providing the information. The competent authorities receiving
                the information shall comply with a request that said information remain
                confidential, even temporarily, or with restrictions on its use. However, this shall
                not prevent the receiving State Party from disclosing in its proceedings information
                that is exculpatory to an accused person. In such a case, the receiving State Party
                shall notify the<inline class="width_3"> </inline>transmitting State Party prior to
                the disclosure and, if so requested, consult with the transmitting State Party. If,
                in an exceptional case, advance notice is not possible, the receiving State Party
                shall inform the transmitting State Party of the disclosure without delay.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_205" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>The provisions of this article shall not affect the obligations under any other
                treaty, bilateral or multilateral, that governs or will govern, in whole or in part,
                mutual legal assistance.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_206" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">7.</num><content>Paragraphs 9 to 29 of this article shall apply to requests made pursuant to
                this article if the States Parties in question are not bound by a treaty of mutual
                legal assistance. If those States Parties are bound by such a treaty, the
                corresponding provisions of that treaty shall apply unless the States Parties agree
                to apply paragraphs 9 to 29 of this article in lieu thereof. States Parties are
                strongly encouraged to apply those paragraphs if they facilitate
                cooperation.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_207" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num class="align_left" value="8">8.</num><content>States Parties shall not decline to render mutual legal assistance pursuant to
                this article on the ground of bank secrecy.</content></subsection><text name="s9" temporalId="sch0_P46_s9" class="first_line_indent_24">9.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A requested State
            Party, in responding to a request for assistance pursuant to this article in the absence
            of dual criminality, shall take into account the purposes of this Convention, as set
            forth in article 1;</text><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_208" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>States Parties may decline to render assistance pursuant to this article on the
                ground of absence of dual criminality. However, a requested State Party shall, where
                consistent with the basic concepts of its legal system, render assistance that does
                not involve coercive action. Such assistance may be refused when requests involve
                matters of a de minimis nature or matters for which the cooperation or assistance
                sought is available under other provisions of this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_209" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Each State Party may consider adopting such measures as may be necessary to
                enable it to provide a wider scope of assistance pursuant to this article in the
                absence of dual criminality.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_210" name="10" temporalId="sch0_10"><num class="align_left" value="10">10.</num><content>A person who is being detained or is serving a sentence in the territory of one
                State Party whose presence in another State Party is requested for purposes of
                identification, testimony or otherwise providing assistance in obtaining evidence
                for investigations, prosecutions or judicial proceedings in relation to offences
                covered by this Convention may be transferred if the following conditions are
                met:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_211" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The person freely gives his or her informed consent;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_212" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The competent authorities of both States Parties agree, subject to such
                conditions as those States Parties may deem appropriate.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_213" name="11" temporalId="sch0_11"><num class="align_left" value="11">11.</num><content>For the purposes of paragraph 10 of this article:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_214" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The State Party to which the person is transferred shall have the authority and
                obligation to keep the person transferred in custody, unless otherwise requested or
                authorized by the State Party from which the person was transferred;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_215" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The State Party to which the person is transferred shall without delay
                implement its obligation to return the person to the custody of the State Party from
                which the person was transferred as agreed beforehand, or as otherwise agreed, by
                the competent authorities of both States Parties; </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_216" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>The State Party to which the person is transferred shall not require the State
                Party from which the person was transferred to initiate extradition proceedings for
                the return of the person;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109382_217" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>The person transferred shall receive credit for service of the sentence being
                served in the State from which he or she was transferred for time spent in the
                custody of the State Party to which he or she was transferred.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_218" name="12" temporalId="sch0_12"><num class="align_left" value="12">12.</num><content>Unless the State Party from which a person is to be transferred in accordance
                with paragraphs 10 and 11 of this article so agrees, that person, whatever his or
                her nationality, shall not be prosecuted, detained, punished or subjected to any
                other restriction of his or her personal liberty in the territory of the State to
                which that person is transferred in respect of acts, omissions or convictions prior
                to his or her departure from the territory of the State from which he or she was
                transferred.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_219" name="13" temporalId="sch0_13"><num class="align_left" value="13">13.</num><content>Each State Party shall designate a central authority that shall have the
                responsibility and power to receive requests for mutual legal assistance and either
                to execute them or to transmit them to the competent authorities for execution.
                Where a State Party has a special region or territory with a separate system of
                mutual legal assistance, it may designate a distinct central authority that shall
                have the same function for that region or territory. Central authorities shall
                ensure the speedy and proper execution or transmission of the requests received.
                Where the central authority transmits the request to a competent authority for
                execution, it shall encourage the speedy and proper execution of the request by the
                competent authority. The Secretary-General of the United Nations shall be notified
                of the central authority designated for this purpose at the time each State Party
                deposits its instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval of or accession to
                this Convention. Requests for mutual legal assistance and any communication related
                thereto shall be transmitted to the central authorities designated by the States
                Parties. This requirement shall be without prejudice to the right of a State Party
                to require that such requests and communications be addressed to it through
                diplomatic channels and, in urgent circumstances, where the States Parties agree,
                through the International Criminal Police Organization, if possible.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_220" name="14" temporalId="sch0_14"><num class="align_left" value="14">14.</num><content>Requests shall be made in writing or, where possible, by any means capable of
                producing a written record, in a language acceptable to the requested State Party,
                under conditions allowing that State Party to establish authenticity. The
                Secretary-General of the United Nations shall be notified of the language or
                languages acceptable to each State Party at the time it deposits its instrument of
                ratification, acceptance or approval of or accession to this Convention. In urgent
                circumstances and where agreed by the States Parties, requests may be made orally
                but shall be confirmed in writing forthwith.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_221" name="15" temporalId="sch0_15"><num class="align_left" value="15">15.</num><content>A request for mutual legal assistance shall contain:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_222" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>The identity of the authority making the request;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_223" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>The subject matter and nature of the investigation, prosecution or judicial
                proceeding to which the request relates and the name and functions of the authority
                conducting the investigation, prosecution or judicial proceeding;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_224" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>A summary of the relevant facts, except in relation to requests for the purpose
                of service of judicial documents;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_225" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>A description of the assistance sought and details of any particular procedure
                that the requesting State Party wishes to be followed;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_226" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>Where possible, the identity, location and nationality of any person concerned;
                and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_227" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>The purpose for which the evidence, information or action is
                sought.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_228" name="16" temporalId="sch0_16"><num class="align_left" value="16">16.</num><content>The requested State Party may request additional information when it appears
                necessary for the execution of the request in accordance with its domestic law or
                when it can facilitate such execution.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_229" name="17" temporalId="sch0_17"><num class="align_left" value="17">17.</num><content>A request shall be executed in accordance with the domestic law of the
                requested State Party and, to the extent not contrary to the domestic law of the
                requested State Party and where possible, in accordance with the procedures
                specified in the request.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_230" name="18" temporalId="sch0_18"><num class="align_left" value="18">18.</num><content>Wherever possible and consistent with fundamental principles of domestic law,
                when an individual is in the territory of a State Party and has to be heard as a
                witness or expert by the judicial authorities of another State Party, the first
                State Party may, at the request of the other, permit the hearing to take place by
                video conference if it is not possible or desirable for the individual in question
                to appear in person in the territory of the requesting State Party. States Parties
                may agree that the hearing shall be conducted by a judicial authority of the
                requesting State Party and attended by a judicial authority of the requested State
                Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_231" name="19" temporalId="sch0_19"><num class="align_left" value="19">19.</num><content>The requesting State Party shall not transmit or use information or evidence
                furnished by the requested State Party for investigations, prosecutions or judicial
                proceedings other than those stated in the request without the prior consent of the
                requested State Party. Nothing in this paragraph shall prevent the requesting State
                Party from disclosing in its proceedings information or evidence that is exculpatory
                to an accused person. In the latter case, the requesting State Party shall notify
                the requested State Party prior to the disclosure and, if so requested, consult with
                the requested State Party. If, in an exceptional case, advance notice is not
                possible, the requesting State Party shall inform the requested State Party of the
                disclosure without delay.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_232" name="20" temporalId="sch0_20"><num class="align_left" value="20">20.</num><content>The requesting State Party may require that the requested State Party keep
                confidential the fact and substance of the request, except to the extent necessary
                to execute the request. If the requested State Party cannot comply with the
                requirement of confidentiality, it shall promptly inform the requesting State
                Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_233" name="21" temporalId="sch0_21"><num class="align_left" value="21">21.</num><content>Mutual legal assistance may be refused:<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_234" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>If the request is not made in conformity with the provisions of this
                article;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_235" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>If the requested State Party considers that execution of the request is likely
                to prejudice its sovereignty, security, <i>ordre public</i> or other essential
                interests;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_236" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>If the authorities of the requested State Party would be prohibited by its
                domestic law from carrying out the action requested with regard to any similar
                offence, had it been subject to investigation, prosecution or judicial proceedings
                under their own jurisdiction;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109398_237" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>If it would be contrary to the legal system of the requested State Party
                relating to mutual legal assistance for the request to be granted.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_238" name="22" temporalId="sch0_22"><num class="align_left" value="22">22.</num><content>States Parties may not refuse a request for mutual legal assistance on the sole
                ground that the offence is also considered to involve fiscal matters.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_239" name="23" temporalId="sch0_23"><num class="align_left" value="23">23.</num><content>Reasons shall be given for any refusal of mutual legal assistance. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_240" name="24" temporalId="sch0_24"><num class="align_left" value="24">24.</num><content>The requested State Party shall execute the request for mutual legal assistance
                as soon as possible and shall take as full account as possible of any deadlines
                suggested by the requesting State Party and for which reasons are given, preferably
                in the request. The requesting State Party may make reasonable requests for
                information on the status and progress of measures taken by the requested State
                Party to satisfy its request. The requested State Party shall respond to reasonable
                requests by the requesting State Party on the status, and progress in its handling,
                of the request. The requesting State Party shall promptly inform the requested State
                Party when the assistance sought is no longer required.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_241" name="25" temporalId="sch0_25"><num class="align_left" value="25">25.</num><content>Mutual legal assistance may be postponed by the requested State Party on the
                ground that it interferes with an ongoing investigation, prosecution or judicial
                proceeding.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_242" name="26" temporalId="sch0_26"><num class="align_left" value="26">26.</num><content>Before refusing a request pursuant to paragraph 21 of this article or
                postponing its execution pursuant to paragraph 25 of this article, the requested
                State Party shall consult with the requesting State Party to consider whether
                assistance may be granted subject to such terms and conditions as it deems
                necessary. If the requesting State Party accepts assistance subject to those
                conditions, it shall comply with the conditions.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_243" name="27" temporalId="sch0_27"><num class="align_left" value="27">27.</num><content>Without prejudice to the application of paragraph 12 of this article, a
                witness, expert or other person who, at the request of the requesting State Party,
                consents to give evidence in a proceeding or to assist in an investigation,
                prosecution or judicial proceeding in the territory of the requesting State Party
                shall not be prosecuted, detained, punished or subjected to any other restriction of
                his or her personal liberty in that territory in respect of acts, omissions or
                convictions prior to his or her departure from the territory of the requested State
                Party. Such safe conduct shall cease when the witness, expert or other person having
                had, for a period of fifteen consecutive days or for any period agreed upon by the
                States Parties from the date on which he or she has been officially informed that
                his or her presence is no longer required by the judicial authorities, an
                opportunity of leaving, has nevertheless remained voluntarily in the territory of
                the requesting State Party or, having left it, has returned of his or her own free
                will.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_244" name="28" temporalId="sch0_28"><num class="align_left" value="28">28.</num><content>The ordinary costs of executing a request shall be borne by the requested State
                Party, unless otherwise agreed by the States Parties concerned. If expenses of a
                substantial or extraordinary nature are or will be required to fulfil the request,
                the States Parties shall consult to determine the terms and conditions under which
                the request will be executed, as well as the manner in which the costs shall be
                borne.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_245" name="29" temporalId="sch0_29"><num class="align_left" value="29">29.</num><content>The requested State Party:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_246" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Shall provide to the requesting State Party copies of government records,
                documents or information in its possession that under its domestic law are available
                to the general public;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_247" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>May, at its discretion, provide to the requesting State Party in whole, in part
                or subject to such conditions as it deems appropriate, copies of any government
                records, documents or information in its possession that under its domestic law are
                not available to the general public. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_248" name="30" temporalId="sch0_30"><num class="align_left" value="30">30.</num><content>States Parties shall consider, as may be necessary, the possibility of
                concluding bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements that would serve the
                purposes of, give practical effect to or enhance the provisions of this
                article.</content></subsection><text id="ID_1438412812868_005" name="sf" temporalId="sch0_P46_sf" class="first_line_indent_24"></text><text id="ID_1438412812946_004" name="s6" temporalId="sch0_P46_s6" class="first_line_indent_24"></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                47</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Transfer of criminal
            proceedings</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall consider the possibility of
            transferring to one another proceedings for the prosecution of an offence established in
            accordance with this Convention in cases where such transfer is considered to be in the
            interests of the proper administration of justice, in particular in cases where several
            jurisdictions are involved, with a view to concentrating the prosecution.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                48</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Law enforcement
            cooperation</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_249" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>States Parties shall cooperate closely with one another, consistent with their
                respective domestic legal and<inline class="width_3"> </inline>administrative
                systems, to enhance the effectiveness of law enforcement action to combat the
                offences covered by this Convention. States Parties shall, in particular, take
                effective measures:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_250" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>To enhance and, where necessary, to establish channels of communication between
                their competent authorities, agencies and services in order to facilitate the secure
                and rapid exchange of information concerning all aspects of the offences covered by
                this Convention, including, if the States Parties concerned deem it appropriate,
                links with other criminal activities;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_251" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>To cooperate with other States Parties in conducting inquiries with respect to
                offences covered by this Convention concerning:</content></subsection><text name="si" temporalId="sch0_P48_si" class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24 align_justified">(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The identity, whereabouts and activities of persons suspected of involvement
            in such offences or the location of other persons concerned;</text><text name="sii" temporalId="sch0_P48_sii" class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24 align_justified">(ii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The movement of proceeds of crime or property derived from the commission of
            such offences;</text><text name="siii" temporalId="sch0_P48_siii" class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24 align_justified">(iii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The movement of property, equipment or other instrumentalities used or
            intended for use in the commission of such offences;</text><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_252" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>To provide, where appropriate, necessary items or quantities of substances for
                analytical or investigative purposes;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_253" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>To exchange, where appropriate, information with other States Parties
                concerning specific means and methods used to commit offences covered by this
                Convention, including the use of false identities, forged, altered or false
                documents and other means of concealing activities;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_254" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>To facilitate effective coordination between their competent authorities,
                agencies and services and to promote the exchange of personnel and other experts,
                including, subject to bilateral agreements or arrangements between the States
                Parties concerned, the posting of liaison officers;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_255" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>To exchange information and coordinate administrative and other measures taken
                as appropriate for the purpose of early identification of the offences covered by
                this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109413_256" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>With a view to giving effect to this Convention, States Parties shall consider
                entering into bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements on direct
                cooperation between their law enforcement agencies and, where such agreements or
                arrangements already exist, amending them. In the absence of such agreements or
                arrangements between the States Parties concerned, the States Parties may consider
                this Convention to be the basis for mutual law enforcement cooperation in respect of
                the offences covered by this Convention. Whenever appropriate, States Parties shall
                make full use of agreements or arrangements, including international or regional
                organizations, to enhance the cooperation between their law enforcement
                agencies.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_257" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>States Parties shall endeavour to cooperate within their means to respond to
                offences covered by this Convention committed through the use of modern
                technology.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                49</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Joint
            investigations</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall consider concluding bilateral or
            multilateral agreements or arrangements whereby, in relation to matters that are the
            subject of investigations, prosecutions or judicial proceedings in one or more States,
            the competent authorities concerned may establish joint investigative bodies. In the
            absence of such agreements or arrangements, joint investigations may be undertaken by
            agreement on a case-by-case basis. The States Parties involved shall ensure that the
            sovereignty of the State Party in whose territory such investigation is to take place is
            fully respected.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold "><i>Article
                50</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Special investigative
            techniques</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_258" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>In order to combat corruption effectively, each State Party shall, to the
                extent permitted by the basic principles of its domestic legal system and in
                accordance with the conditions prescribed by its domestic law, take such measures as
                may be necessary, within its means, to allow for the appropriate use by its
                competent authorities of controlled delivery and, where it deems appropriate, other
                special investigative techniques, such as electronic or other forms of surveillance
                and undercover operations, within its territory, and to allow for the admissibility
                in court of evidence derived therefrom.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_259" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>For the purpose of investigating the offences covered by this Convention,
                States Parties are encouraged to conclude, when necessary, appropriate bilateral or
                multilateral agreements or arrangements for using such special investigative
                techniques in the context of cooperation at the international level. Such agreements
                or arrangements shall be concluded and implemented in full compliance with the
                principle of sovereign equality of States and shall be carried out strictly in
                accordance with the terms of those agreements or arrangements.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_260" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>In the absence of an agreement or arrangement as set forth in paragraph 2 of
                this article, decisions to use such special investigative techniques at the
                international level shall be made on a case-by-case basis and may, when necessary,
                take into consideration financial arrangements and understandings with respect to
                the exercise of jurisdiction by the States Parties concerned.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_261" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Decisions to use controlled delivery at the international level may, with the
                consent of the States Parties concerned, include methods such as intercepting and
                allowing the goods or funds to continue intact or be removed or replaced in whole or
                in part.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>Chapter
            V<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Asset
            recovery</crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                51</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold "><i>General
            provision</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">The return of assets pursuant to this chapter is a
            fundamental principle of this Convention, and States Parties shall afford one another
            the widest measure of cooperation and assistance in this regard.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                52</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Prevention and detection of transfers of proceeds of
                crime</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_262" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Without prejudice to article 14 of this Convention, each State Party shall take
                such measures as may be necessary, in accordance with its domestic law, to require
                financial institutions within its jurisdiction to verify the identity of customers,
                to take reasonable steps to determine the identity of beneficial owners of funds
                deposited into high-value accounts and to conduct enhanced scrutiny of accounts
                sought or maintained by or on behalf of individuals who are, or have been, entrusted
                with prominent public functions and their family members and close associates. Such
                enhanced scrutiny shall be reasonably designed to detect suspicious transactions for
                the purpose of reporting to competent authorities and should not be so construed as
                to discourage or prohibit financial institutions from doing business with any
                legitimate customer.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_263" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>In order to facilitate implementation of the measures provided for in paragraph
                1 of this article, each State Party, in accordance with its domestic law and
                inspired by relevant initiatives of regional, interregional and multilateral
                organizations against money-laundering, shall:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_264" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Issue advisories regarding the types of natural or legal person to whose
                accounts financial institutions within its jurisdiction will be expected to apply
                enhanced scrutiny, the types of accounts and transactions to which to pay particular
                attention and appropriate account-opening, maintenance and record-keeping measures
                to take concerning such accounts; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_265" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Where appropriate, notify financial institutions within its jurisdiction, at
                the request of another State Party or on its own initiative, of the identity of
                particular natural or legal persons to whose accounts such institutions will be
                expected to apply enhanced scrutiny, in addition to those whom the financial
                institutions may otherwise identify.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_266" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>In the context of paragraph 2(a) of this article, each State Party shall
                implement measures to ensure that its financial institutions maintain adequate
                records, over an appropriate period of time, of accounts and transactions involving
                the persons mentioned in paragraph 1 of this article, which should, as a minimum,
                contain information relating to the identity of the customer as well as, as far as
                possible, of the beneficial owner.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_267" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>With the aim of preventing and detecting transfers of proceeds of offences
                established in accordance with this Convention, each State Party shall implement
                appropriate and effective measures to prevent, with the help of its regulatory and
                oversight bodies, the establishment of banks that have no physical presence and that
                are not affiliated with a regulated financial group. Moreover, States Parties may
                consider requiring their financial institutions to refuse to enter into or continue
                a correspondent banking relationship with such institutions and to guard against
                establishing relations with foreign financial institutions that permit their
                accounts to be used by banks that have no physical presence and that are not
                affiliated with a regulated financial group.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_268" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider establishing, in accordance with its domestic
                law, effective financial disclosure systems for appropriate public officials and
                shall provide for appropriate sanctions for non-compliance. Each State Party shall
                also consider taking such measures as may be necessary to permit its competent
                authorities to share that information with the competent authorities in other States
                Parties when necessary to investigate, claim and recover proceeds of offences
                established in accordance with this Convention. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_269" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider taking such measures as may be necessary, in
                accordance with its domestic law, to require appropriate public officials having an
                interest in or signature or other authority over a financial account in a foreign
                country to report that relationship to appropriate authorities and to maintain
                appropriate records related to such accounts. Such measures shall also provide for
                appropriate sanctions for non-compliance.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                53</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Measures for direct recovery of
            property</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall, in accordance with its domestic
            law:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_270" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Take such measures as may be necessary to permit another State Party to
                initiate civil action in its courts to establish title to or ownership of property
                acquired through the commission of an offence established in accordance with this
                Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_271" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Take such measures as may be necessary to permit its courts to order those who
                have committed offences established in accordance with this Convention to pay
                compensation or damages to another State Party that has been harmed by such
                offences; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_272" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Take such measures as may be necessary to permit its courts or competent
                authorities, when having to decide on confiscation, to recognize another State
                Party’s claim as a legitimate owner of property acquired through the commission of
                an offence established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                54</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Mechanisms for recovery of property
                    through</i><br></br><i>international cooperation in
            confiscation</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_273" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party, in order to provide mutual legal assistance pursuant to
                article 55 of this Convention with respect to property acquired through or involved
                in the commission of an offence established in accordance with this Convention,
                shall, in accordance with its domestic law:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_274" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Take such measures as may be necessary to permit its competent authorities to
                give effect to an order of confiscation issued by a court of another State
                Party;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109429_275" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Take such measures as may be necessary to permit its competent authorities,
                where they have jurisdiction, to order the confiscation of such property of foreign
                origin by adjudication of an offence of money-laundering or such other offence as
                may be within its jurisdiction or by other procedures authorized under its domestic
                law; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_276" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Consider taking such measures as may be necessary to allow confiscation of such
                property without a criminal conviction in cases in which the offender cannot be
                prosecuted by reason of death, flight or absence or in other appropriate
                cases.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_277" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party, in order to provide mutual legal assistance upon a request
                made pursuant to paragraph 2 of article 55 of this Convention, shall, in accordance
                with its domestic law:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_278" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Take such measures as may be necessary to permit its competent authorities to
                freeze or seize property upon a freezing or seizure order issued by a court or
                competent authority of a requesting State Party that provides a reasonable basis for
                the requested State Party to believe that there are sufficient grounds for taking
                such actions and that the property would eventually be subject to an order of
                confiscation for purposes of paragraph 1(a) of this article;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_279" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Take such measures as may be necessary to permit its competent authorities to
                freeze or seize property upon a request that provides a reasonable basis for the
                requested State Party to believe that there are sufficient grounds for taking such
                actions and that the property would eventually be subject to an order of
                confiscation for purposes of paragraph 1(a) of this article; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_280" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Consider taking additional measures to permit its competent authorities to
                preserve property for confiscation, such as on the basis of a foreign arrest or
                criminal charge related to the acquisition of such property. </content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                55</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>International cooperation for purposes of
                confiscation</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_281" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>A State Party that has received a request from another State Party having
                jurisdiction over an offence established in accordance with this Convention for
                confiscation of proceeds of crime, property, equipment or other instrumentalities
                referred to in article 31, paragraph 1, of this Convention situated in its territory
                shall, to the greatest extent possible within its domestic legal system:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_282" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Submit the request to its competent authorities for the purpose of obtaining an
                order of confiscation and, if such an order is granted, give effect to it;
                or</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_283" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Submit to its competent authorities, with a view to giving effect to it to the
                extent requested, an order of confiscation issued by a court in the territory of the
                requesting State Party in accordance with articles 31, paragraph 1, and 54,
                paragraph 1(a), of this Convention insofar as it relates to proceeds of crime,
                property, equipment or other instrumentalities referred to in article 31, paragraph
                1, situated in the territory of the requested State Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_284" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Following a request made by another State Party having jurisdiction over an
                offence established in accordance with this Convention, the requested State Party
                shall take measures to identify, trace and freeze or seize proceeds of crime,
                property, equipment or other instrumentalities referred to in article 31, paragraph
                1, of this Convention for the purpose of eventual confiscation to be ordered either
                by the requesting State Party or, pursuant to a request under paragraph 1 of this
                article, by the requested State Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_285" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>The provisions of article 46 of this Convention are applicable, mutatis
                mutandis, to this article. In addition to the information specified in article 46,
                paragraph 15, requests made pursuant to this article shall contain:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_286" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>In the case of a request pertaining to paragraph 1(a) of this article, a
                description of the property to be confiscated, including, to the extent possible,
                the location and, where relevant, the estimated value of the property and a
                statement of the facts relied upon by the requesting State Party sufficient to
                enable the requested State Party to seek the order under its domestic law;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_287" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>In the case of a request pertaining to paragraph 1(b) of this article, a
                legally admissible copy of an order of confiscation upon which the request is based
                issued by the requesting State Party, a statement of the facts and information as to
                the extent to which execution of the order is requested, a statement specifying the
                measures taken by the requesting State Party to provide adequate notification to
                bona fide third parties and to ensure due process and a statement that the
                confiscation order is final;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_288" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>In the case of a request pertaining to paragraph 2 of this article, a statement
                of the facts relied upon by the requesting State Party and a description of the
                actions requested and, where available, a legally admissible copy of an order on
                which the request is based. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_289" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>The decisions or actions provided for in paragraphs 1 and 2 of this article
                shall be taken by the requested State Party in accordance with and subject to the
                provisions of its domestic law and its procedural rules or any bilateral or
                multilateral agreement or arrangement to which it may be bound in relation to the
                requesting State Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_290" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>Each State Party shall furnish copies of its laws and regulations that give
                effect to this article and of any subsequent changes to such laws and regulations or
                a description thereof to the Secretary-General of the United Nations.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_291" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>If a State Party elects to make the taking of the measures referred to in
                paragraphs 1 and 2 of this article conditional on the existence of a relevant
                treaty, that State Party shall consider this Convention the necessary and sufficient
                treaty basis.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_292" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">7.</num><content>Cooperation under this article may also be refused or provisional measures
                lifted if the requested State Party does not receive sufficient and timely evidence
                or if the property is of a <i>de minimis</i> value.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_293" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num class="align_left" value="8">8.</num><content>Before lifting any provisional measure taken pursuant to this article, the
                requested State Party shall, wherever possible, give the requesting State Party an
                opportunity to present its reasons in favour of continuing the measure.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_294" name="9" temporalId="sch0_9"><num class="align_left" value="9">9.</num><content>The provisions of this article shall not be construed as prejudicing the rights
                of bona fide third parties.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                56</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Special
            cooperation</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Without prejudice to its domestic law, each State Party
            shall endeavour to take measures to permit it to forward, without prejudice to its own
            investigations, prosecutions or judicial proceedings, information on proceeds of
            offences established in accordance with this Convention to another State Party without
            prior request, when it considers that the disclosure of such information might assist
            the receiving State Party in initiating or carrying out investigations, prosecutions or
            judicial proceedings or might lead to a request by that State Party under this chapter
            of the Convention.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                57</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Return and disposal of
            assets</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109445_295" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Property confiscated by a State Party pursuant to article 31 or 55 of this
                Convention shall be disposed of, including by return to its prior legitimate owners,
                pursuant to paragraph 3 of this article, by that State Party in accordance with the
                provisions of this Convention and its domestic law.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_296" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party shall adopt such legislative and other measures, in accordance
                with the fundamental principles of its domestic law, as may be necessary to enable
                its competent authorities to return confiscated property, when acting on the request
                made by another State Party, in accordance with this Convention, taking into account
                the rights of bona fide third parties.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_297" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>In accordance with articles 46 and 55 of this Convention and paragraphs 1 and 2
                of this article, the requested State Party shall:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_298" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>In the case of embezzlement of public funds or of laundering of embezzled
                public funds as referred to in articles 17 and 23 of this Convention, when
                confiscation was executed in accordance with article 55 and on the basis of a final
                judgement in the requesting State Party, a requirement that can be waived by the
                requested State Party, return the confiscated property to the requesting State
                Party;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_299" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>In the case of proceeds of any other offence covered by this Convention, when
                the confiscation was executed in accordance with article 55 of this Convention and
                on the basis of a final judgement in the requesting State Party, a requirement that
                can be waived by the requested State Party, return the confiscated property to the
                requesting State Party, when the requesting State Party reasonably establishes its
                prior ownership of such confiscated property to the requested State Party or when
                the requested State Party recognizes damage to the requesting State Party as a basis
                for returning the confiscated property;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_300" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>In all other cases, give priority consideration to returning confiscated
                property to the requesting State Party, returning such property to its prior
                legitimate owners or compensating the victims of the crime. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_301" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Where appropriate, unless States Parties decide otherwise, the requested State
                Party may deduct reasonable expenses incurred in investigations, prosecutions or
                judicial proceedings leading to the return or disposition of confiscated property
                pursuant to this article.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_302" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>Where appropriate, States Parties may also give special consideration to
                concluding agreements or mutually acceptable arrangements, on a case-by-case basis,
                for the final disposal of confiscated property.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                58</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Financial intelligence
            unit</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall cooperate with one another for the
            purpose of preventing and combating the transfer of proceeds of offences established in
            accordance with this Convention and of promoting ways and means of recovering such
            proceeds and, to that end, shall consider establishing a financial intelligence unit to
            be responsible for receiving, analysing and disseminating to the competent authorities
            reports of suspicious financial transactions.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                59</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Bilateral and multilateral agreements and
                arrangements</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall consider concluding bilateral or
            multilateral agreements or arrangements to enhance the effectiveness of international
            cooperation undertaken pursuant to this chapter of the Convention. </text><crossHeading>Chapter
            VI<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Technical
            assistance and information
            exchange</crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                60</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Training and technical
            assistance</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_303" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall, to the extent necessary, initiate, develop or improve
                specific training programmes for its personnel responsible for preventing and
                combating corruption. Such training programmes could deal, inter alia, with the
                following areas:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_304" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Effective measures to prevent, detect, investigate, punish and control
                corruption, including the use of evidence-gathering and investigative
                methods;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_305" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Building capacity in the development and planning of strategic anti-corruption
                policy;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_306" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Training competent authorities in the preparation of requests for mutual legal
                assistance that meet the requirements of this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_307" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>Evaluation and strengthening of institutions, public service management and the
                management of public finances, including public procurement, and the private
                sector;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_308" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>Preventing and combating the transfer of proceeds of offences established in
                accordance with this Convention and recovering such proceeds;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_309" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>Detecting and freezing of the transfer of proceeds of offences established in
                accordance with this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_310" name="g" temporalId="sch0_g"><num class="align_left" value="g">(g)</num><content>Surveillance of the movement of proceeds of offences established in accordance
                with this Convention and of the methods used to transfer, conceal or disguise such
                proceeds;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_311" name="h" temporalId="sch0_h"><num class="align_left" value="h">(h)</num><content>Appropriate and efficient legal and administrative mechanisms<inline class="width_3"> </inline>and methods for facilitating the return of proceeds of
                offences established in accordance with this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_312" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(i)</num><content>Methods used in protecting victims and witnesses who cooperate with judicial
                authorities; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_313" name="j" temporalId="sch0_j"><num class="align_left" value="j">(j)</num><content>Training in national and international regulations and in languages. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109460_314" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>States Parties shall, according to their capacity, consider affording one
                another the widest measure of technical assistance, especially for the benefit of
                developing countries, in their respective plans and programmes to combat corruption,
                including material support and training in the areas referred to in paragraph 1 of
                this article, and training and assistance and the mutual exchange of relevant
                experience and specialized knowledge, which will facilitate international
                cooperation between States Parties in the areas of extradition and mutual legal
                assistance.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_315" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>States Parties shall strengthen, to the extent necessary, efforts to maximize
                operational and training activities in international and regional organizations and
                in the framework of relevant bilateral and multilateral agreements or
                arrangements.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_316" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>States Parties shall consider assisting one another, upon request, in
                conducting evaluations, studies and research relating to the types, causes, effects
                and costs of corruption in their respective countries, with a view to developing,
                with the participation of competent authorities and society, strategies and action
                plans to combat corruption.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_317" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>In order to facilitate the recovery of proceeds of offences established in
                accordance with this Convention, States Parties may cooperate in providing each
                other with the names of experts who could assist in achieving that
                objective.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_318" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>States Parties shall consider using subregional, regional and international
                conferences and seminars to promote cooperation and technical assistance and to
                stimulate discussion on problems of mutual concern, including the special problems
                and needs of developing countries and countries with economies in
                transition.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_319" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">7.</num><content>States Parties shall consider establishing voluntary mechanisms with a view to
                contributing financially to the efforts of developing countries and countries with
                economies in transition to apply this Convention through technical assistance
                programmes and projects.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_320" name="8" temporalId="sch0_8"><num class="align_left" value="8">8.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider making voluntary contributions to the United
                Nations Office on Drugs and Crime for the purpose of fostering, through the Office,
                programmes and projects in developing countries with a view to implementing this
                Convention.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                61</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Collection, exchange and analysis of information</i><br></br><i>on
                    corruption</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_321" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider analysing, in consultation with experts, trends
                in corruption in its territory, as well as the circumstances in which corruption
                offences are committed.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_322" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>States Parties shall consider developing and sharing with each other and
                through international and regional organizations statistics, analytical expertise
                concerning corruption and information with a view to developing, insofar as
                possible, common definitions, standards and methodologies, as well as information on
                best practices to prevent and combat corruption.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_323" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party shall consider monitoring its policies and actual measures to
                combat corruption and making assessments of their effectiveness and
                efficiency.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                62</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Other measures: implementation of the
                    Convention</i><br></br><i>through economic development and</i><br></br><i>technical
                    assistance</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_324" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>States Parties shall take measures conducive to the optimal implementation of
                this Convention to the extent possible, through international cooperation, taking
                into account the negative effects of corruption on society in general, in particular
                on sustainable development.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_325" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>States Parties shall make concrete efforts to the extent possible and in
                coordination with each other, as well as with international and regional
                organizations:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_326" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>To enhance their cooperation at various levels with developing countries, with
                a view to strengthening the capacity of the latter to prevent and combat
                corruption;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_327" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>To enhance financial and material assistance to support the efforts of
                developing countries to prevent and fight corruption effectively and to help them
                implement this Convention successfully;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_328" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>To provide technical assistance to developing countries and countries with
                economies in transition to assist them in meeting their needs for the implementation
                of this Convention. To that end, States Parties shall endeavour to make adequate and
                regular voluntary contributions to an account specifically designated for that
                purpose in a United Nations funding mechanism. States Parties may also give special
                consideration, in accordance with their domestic law and the provisions of this
                Convention, to contributing to that account a percentage of the money or of the
                corresponding value of proceeds of crime or property confiscated in accordance with
                the provisions of this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_329" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>To encourage and persuade other States and financial institutions as
                appropriate to join them in efforts in accordance with this article, in particular
                by providing more training programmes and modern equipment to developing countries
                in order to assist them in achieving the objectives of this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_330" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>To the extent possible, these measures shall be without prejudice to existing
                foreign assistance commitments or to other financial cooperation arrangements at the
                bilateral, regional or international level.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_331" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>States Parties may conclude bilateral or multilateral agreements or
                arrangements on material and logistical assistance, taking into consideration the
                financial arrangements necessary for the means of international cooperation provided
                for by this Convention to be effective and for the<inline class="width_3"> </inline>prevention, detection and control of
                corruption.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>Chapter
            VII<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Mechanisms
            for
            implementation</crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                63</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Conference of the States Parties to the
            Convention</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_332" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>A Conference of the States Parties to the Convention is hereby established to
                improve the capacity of and cooperation between States Parties to achieve the
                objectives set forth in this Convention and to promote and review its
                implementation.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109476_333" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>The Secretary-General of the United Nations shall convene the Conference of the
                States Parties not later than one year following the entry into force of this
                Convention. Thereafter, regular meetings of the Conference of the States Parties
                shall be held in accordance with the rules of procedure adopted by the
                Conference.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_334" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>The Conference of the States Parties shall adopt rules of procedure and rules
                governing the functioning of the activities set forth in this article, including
                rules concerning the admission and participation of observers, and the payment of
                expenses incurred in carrying out those activities. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_335" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>The Conference of the States Parties shall agree upon activities, procedures
                and methods of work to achieve the objectives set forth in paragraph 1 of this
                article, including:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_336" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Facilitating activities by States Parties under articles 60 and 62 and chapters
                II to V of this Convention, including by encouraging the mobilization of voluntary
                contributions;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_337" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Facilitating the exchange of information among States Parties on patterns and
                trends in corruption and on successful practices for preventing and combating it and
                for the return of proceeds of crime, through, inter alia, the publication of
                relevant information as mentioned in this article;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_338" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Cooperating with relevant international and regional organizations and
                mechanisms and non-governmental organizations;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_339" name="d" temporalId="sch0_d"><num class="align_left" value="d">(d)</num><content>Making appropriate use of relevant information produced by other international
                and regional mechanisms for combating and preventing corruption in order to avoid
                unnecessary duplication of work;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_340" name="e" temporalId="sch0_e"><num class="align_left" value="e">(e)</num><content>Reviewing periodically the implementation of this Convention by its States
                Parties;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_341" name="f" temporalId="sch0_f"><num class="align_left" value="f">(f)</num><content>Making recommendations to improve this Convention and its
                implementation;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_342" name="g" temporalId="sch0_g"><num class="align_left" value="g">(g)</num><content>Taking note of the technical assistance requirements of States Parties with
                regard to the implementation of this Convention and recommending any action it may
                deem necessary in that respect.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_343" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>For the purpose of paragraph 4 of this article, the Conference of the States
                Parties shall acquire the necessary knowledge of the measures taken by States
                Parties in implementing this Convention and the difficulties encountered by them in
                doing so through information provided by them and through such supplemental review
                mechanisms as may be established by the Conference of the States Parties.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_344" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">6.</num><content>Each State Party shall provide the Conference of the States Parties with
                information on its programmes, plans and practices, as well as on legislative and
                administrative measures to implement this Convention, as required by the Conference
                of the States Parties. The Conference of the States Parties shall examine the most
                effective way of receiving and acting upon information, including, inter alia,
                information received from States Parties and from competent international
                organizations. Inputs received from relevant non-governmental organizations duly
                accredited in accordance with procedures to be decided upon by the Conference of the
                States Parties may also be considered.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_345" name="7" temporalId="sch0_7"><num class="align_left" value="7">7.</num><content>Pursuant to paragraphs 4 to 6 of this article, the Conference of the States
                Parties shall establish, if it deems it necessary, any appropriate mechanism or body
                to assist in the effective implementation of the Convention.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                64</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Secretariat</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_346" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>The Secretary-General of the United Nations shall provide the necessary
                secretariat services to the Conference of the States Parties to the
                Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_347" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>The secretariat shall:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_348" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num class="align_left" value="a">(a)</num><content>Assist the Conference of the States Parties in carrying out the activities set
                forth in article 63 of this Convention and make arrangements and provide the
                necessary services for the sessions of the Conference of the States
                Parties;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_349" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num class="align_left" value="b">(b)</num><content>Upon request, assist States Parties in providing information to the Conference
                of the States Parties as envisaged in article 63, paragraphs 5 and 6, of this
                Convention; and</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_350" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num class="align_left" value="c">(c)</num><content>Ensure the necessary coordination with the secretariats of relevant
                international and regional organizations.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading>Chapter
            VIII<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Final
            provisions</crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                65</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Implementation of the
            Convention</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_351" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>Each State Party shall take the necessary measures, including legislative and
                administrative measures, in accordance with fundamental principles of its domestic
                law, to ensure the implementation of its obligations under this
                Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109492_352" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Each State Party may adopt more strict or severe measures than those provided
                for by this Convention for preventing and combating corruption.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                66</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Settlement of
            disputes</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_353" name="50" temporalId="sch0_50"><num class="align_left" value="50">l.</num><content>States Parties shall endeavour to settle disputes concerning the interpretation
                or application of this Convention through negotiation.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_354" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Any dispute between two or more States Parties concerning the interpretation or
                application of this Convention that cannot be settled through negotiation within a
                reasonable time shall, at the request of one of those States Parties, be submitted
                to arbitration. If, six months after the date of the request for arbitration, those
                States Parties are unable to agree on the organization of the arbitration, any one
                of those States Parties may refer the dispute to the International Court of Justice
                by request in accordance with the Statute of the Court.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_355" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>Each State Party may, at the time of signature, ratification, acceptance or
                approval of or accession to this Convention, declare that it does not consider
                itself bound by paragraph 2 of this article. The other States Parties shall not be
                bound by paragraph 2 of this article with respect to any State Party that has made
                such a reservation.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_356" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>Any State Party that has made a reservation in accordance with paragraph 3 of
                this article may at any time withdraw that reservation by notification to the
                Secretary-General of the United Nations.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold "><i>Article
                67</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Signature, ratification,
                    acceptance,
                    approval and
                    accession</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_357" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>This Convention shall be open to all States for signature from 9 to 11 December
                2003 in Merida, Mexico, and thereafter at United Nations Headquarters in New York
                until 9 December 2005.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_358" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>This Convention shall also be open for signature by regional economic
                integration organizations provided that at least one member State of such
                organization has signed this Convention in accordance with paragraph 1 of this
                article.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_359" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>This Convention is subject to ratification, acceptance or approval. Instruments
                of ratification, acceptance or approval shall be deposited with the
                Secretary-General of the United Nations. A regional economic integration
                organization may deposit its instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval if
                at least one of its member States has done likewise. In that instrument of
                ratification, acceptance or approval, such organization shall declare the extent of
                its competence with respect to the matters governed by this Convention. Such
                organization shall also inform the depositary of any relevant modification in the
                extent of its competence.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_360" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>This Convention is open for accession by any State or any regional economic
                integration organization of which at least one member State is a Party to this
                Convention. Instruments of accession shall be deposited with the Secretary-General
                of the United Nations. At the time of its accession, a regional economic integration
                organization shall declare the extent of its competence with respect to matters
                governed by this Convention. Such organization shall also inform the depositary of
                any relevant modification in the extent of its competence.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                68</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Entry into
            force</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_361" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>This Convention shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of
                deposit of the thirtieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or
                accession. For the purpose of this paragraph, any instrument deposited by a regional
                economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those
                deposited by member States of such organization.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_362" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>For each State or regional economic integration organization ratifying,
                accepting, approving or acceding to this Convention after the deposit of the
                thirtieth instrument of such action, this Convention shall enter into force on the
                thirtieth day after the date of deposit by such State or organization of the
                relevant instrument or on the date this Convention enters into force pursuant to
                paragraph 1 of this article, whichever is later.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                69</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Amendment</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_363" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>After the expiry of five years from the entry into force of this Convention, a
                State Party may propose an amendment and transmit it to the Secretary-General of the
                United Nations, who shall thereupon communicate the proposed amendment to the States
                Parties and to the Conference of the States Parties to the Convention for the
                purpose of considering and deciding on the proposal. The Conference of the States
                Parties shall make every effort to achieve consensus on each amendment. If all
                efforts at consensus have been exhausted and no agreement has been reached, the
                amendment shall, as a last resort, require for its adoption a two-thirds majority
                vote of the States Parties present and voting at the meeting of the Conference of
                the States Parties.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_364" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>Regional economic integration organizations, in matters within their
                competence, shall exercise their right to vote under this article with a number of
                votes equal to the number of their member States that are Parties to this
                Convention. Such organizations shall not exercise their right to vote if their
                member States exercise theirs and vice versa.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_365" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">3.</num><content>An amendment adopted in accordance with paragraph 1 of this article is subject
                to ratification, acceptance or approval by States Parties. </content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_366" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">4.</num><content>An amendment adopted in accordance with paragraph 1 of this article shall enter
                into force in respect of a State Party ninety days after the date of the deposit
                with the Secretary-General of the United Nations of an instrument of ratification,
                acceptance or approval of such amendment.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_367" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">5.</num><content>When an amendment enters into force, it shall be binding on those States
                Parties which have expressed their consent to be bound by it. Other States Parties
                shall still be bound by the provisions of this Convention and any earlier amendments
                that they have ratified, accepted or approved.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                70</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Denunciation</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_368" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>A State Party may denounce this Convention by written notification to the
                Secretary-General of the United Nations. Such denunciation shall become effective
                one year after the date of receipt of the notification by the
                Secretary-General.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_369" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>A regional economic integration organization shall cease to be a Party to this
                Convention when all of its member States have denounced it. </content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><i>Article
                71</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><inline class="not_bold"><i>Depositary and
            languages</i></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_370" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">1.</num><content>The Secretary-General of the United Nations is designated depositary of this
                Convention.</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1610441109507_371" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">2.</num><content>The original of this Convention, of which the Arabic, Chinese, English, French,
                Russian and Spanish texts are equally authentic, shall be deposited with the
                Secretary-General of the United Nations. </content></subsection><text class="first_line_indent_24">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the undersigned plenipotentiaries,
            being duly authorized thereto by their respective Governments, have signed this
            Convention.</text></schedule></main></subLeg>