<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 503 sub. leg. AA</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>503AA</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap503AA!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-04-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403283782_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-04-08">Fugitive Offenders (Suppression of the Financing of Terrorism)
            Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap503/s3">Cap. 503, section
                3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[31 August 2007]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2007/ln171">L.N. 171 of 2007</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403283782_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403283798_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Procedures in Ordinance to apply between Hong Kong and certain places outside Hong Kong</heading><content>In relation to the arrangements for the surrender of fugitive offenders the terms of which are recited in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, it is directed that the procedures in the Ordinance shall apply as between Hong Kong and the places outside Hong Kong to which the arrangements relate subject to the limitations, restrictions, exceptions and qualifications contained in the terms of the arrangements.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403283813_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-04-08" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap503AA/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>International
            Convention for the Suppression of the Financing of
            Terrorism<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><b>Preamble</b><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>The States Parties to this
                Convention,</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Bearing in mind</i> the purposes and
            principles of the Charter of the United Nations concerning the maintenance of
            international peace and security and the promotion of good-neighbourliness and friendly
            relations and cooperation among
            States,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Deeply concerned</i> about the worldwide
            escalation of acts of terrorism in all its forms and
            manifestations,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Recalling</i> the Declaration on the
            Occasion of the Fiftieth Anniversary of the United Nations, contained in General
            Assembly resolution 50/6 of 24 October
            1995,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Recalling also</i> all the relevant
            General Assembly resolutions on the matter, including resolution 49/60 of 9 December
            1994 and its annex on the Declaration on Measures to Eliminate International Terrorism,
            in which the States Members of the United Nations solemnly reaffirmed their unequivocal
            condemnation of all acts, methods and practices of terrorism as criminal and
            unjustifiable, wherever and by whomever committed, including those which jeopardize the
            friendly relations among States and peoples and threaten the territorial integrity and
            security of
            States,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Noting</i> that the Declaration on
            Measures to Eliminate International Terrorism also encouraged States to review urgently
            the scope of the existing international legal provisions on the prevention, repression
            and elimination of terrorism in all its forms and manifestations, with the aim of
            ensuring that there is a comprehensive legal framework covering all aspects of the
            matter,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Recalling</i> General Assembly
            resolution 51/210 of 17 December 1996, <ref>paragraph 3</ref>, subparagraph
            (f),
            in which the Assembly called upon all States to take steps to prevent and counteract,
            through appropriate domestic measures, the financing of terrorists and terrorist
            organizations, whether such financing is direct or indirect through organizations which
            also have or claim to have charitable, social or cultural goals or which are also
            engaged in unlawful activities such as illicit arms trafficking, drug dealing and
            racketeering, including the exploitation of persons for purposes of funding terrorist
            activities, and in particular to consider, where appropriate, adopting regulatory
            measures to prevent and counteract movements of funds suspected to be intended for
            terrorist purposes without impeding in any way the freedom of legitimate capital
            movements and to intensify the exchange of information concerning international
            movements of such
            funds,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Recalling also</i> General Assembly
            resolution 52/165 of 15 December 1997, in which the Assembly called upon States to
            consider, in particular, the implementation of the measures set out in <ref>paragraphs
                3(a)
                </ref> to
            (f)
            of its resolution 51/210 of 17 December
            1996,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Recalling further</i> General Assembly
            resolution 53/108 of 8 December 1998, in which the Assembly decided that the Ad Hoc
            Committee established by General Assembly resolution 51/210 of 17 December 1996 should
            elaborate a draft international convention for the suppression of terrorist financing to
            supplement related existing international
            instruments,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Considering</i> that the financing of
            terrorism is a matter of grave concern to the international community as a
            whole,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Noting</i> that the number and
            seriousness of acts of international terrorism depend on the financing that terrorists
            may
            obtain,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Noting also</i> that existing
            multilateral legal instruments do not expressly address such
            financing,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Being convinced</i> of the urgent need
            to enhance international cooperation among States in devising and adopting effective
            measures for the prevention of the financing of terrorism, as well as for its
            suppression through the prosecution and punishment of its
            perpetrators,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Have agreed as
            follows</i>:</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 1</crossHeading><text class="left_indent_24">For the purposes of this Convention:</text><text id="ID_1438412809842_060" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Funds</term>” means assets of every kind,
            whether tangible or intangible, movable or immovable, however acquired, and legal
            documents or instruments in any form, including electronic or digital, evidencing title
            to, or interest in, such assets, including, but not limited to, bank credits, travellers
            cheques, bank cheques, money orders, shares, securities, bonds, drafts and letters of
            credit. </text><text id="ID_1438412809842_068" name="2" temporalId="sch0_1_2">2. <fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">State or government facility</term>” means any
            permanent or temporary facility or conveyance that is used or occupied by
            representatives of a State, members of Government, the legislature or the judiciary or
            by officials or employees of a State or any other public authority or entity or by
            employees or officials of an intergovernmental organization in connection with their
            official duties. </text><text id="ID_1438412809858_012" name="3" temporalId="sch0_1_3">3. <fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Proceeds</term>” means any funds derived from
            or obtained, directly or indirectly, through the commission of an offence set forth in
            article 2. </text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 2</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412809858_028" name="1" temporalId="sch0_2_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Any person commits an offence within the meaning of this Convention if that
            person by any means, directly or indirectly, unlawfully and wilfully, provides or
            collects funds with the intention that they should be used or in the knowledge that they
            are to be used, in full or in part, in order to carry out:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056365_001" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>An act which constitutes an offence within the scope of and as defined in
                    one of the treaties listed in the annex; or</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056365_002" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>Any other act intended to cause death or serious bodily injury to a
                    civilian, or to any other person not taking an active part in the hostilities in
                    a situation of armed conflict, when the purpose of such act, by its nature or
                    context, is to intimidate a population, or to compel a government or an
                    international organization to do or to abstain from doing any act.</content></paragraph>
        </text><text id="ID_1438412809873_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>(a)<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn>On depositing its instrument of
            ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, a State Party which is not a party to a
            treaty listed in the annex may declare that, in the application of this Convention to
            the State Party, the treaty shall be deemed not to be included in the annex referred to
            in <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, subparagraph (a). The declaration shall cease to have effect
            as soon as the treaty enters into force for the State Party, which shall notify the
            depositary of this fact; </text><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056381_003" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>When a State Party ceases to be a party to a treaty listed in the annex, it may
                make a declaration as provided for in this article, with respect to that
                treaty.</content></paragraph><text id="ID_1438412809873_021" name="3" temporalId="sch0_2_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>For an act to constitute an offence set forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, it
            shall not be necessary that the funds were actually used to carry out an offence
            referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, subparagraphs (a) or (b). </text><text id="ID_1438412809889_004" name="4" temporalId="sch0_2_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Any person also commits an offence if that person attempts to commit an
            offence as set forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article. </text><text id="ID_1438412809889_012" name="5" temporalId="sch0_2_5">5.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Any person also commits an offence if that person:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056381_004" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>Participates as an accomplice in an offence as set forth in <ref>paragraph
                        1</ref> or <ref>4</ref> of this article;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056381_005" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>Organizes or directs others to commit an offence as set forth in
                        <ref>paragraph 1</ref> or <ref>4</ref> of this article;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056381_006" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><leadIn>Contributes to the commission of one or more offences as set forth in
                        <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> or <ref>4</ref> of this article by a group of
                    persons acting with a common purpose. Such contribution shall be intentional and
                    shall either:</leadIn><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(i)<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Be made with the aim of furthering the criminal
                    activity or criminal purpose of the group, where such activity or purpose
                    involves the commission of an offence as set forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of
                    this article; or</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(ii)<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn>Be made in the knowledge of the intention of the
                    group to commit an offence as set forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this
                    article.</text></paragraph>
        </text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 3</crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">This Convention shall not apply where the
            offence is committed within a single State, the alleged offender is a national of that
            State and is present in the territory of that State and no other State has a basis under
            article 7, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, or article 7, <ref>paragraph 2</ref>, to exercise
            jurisdiction, except that the provisions of articles 12 to 18 shall, as appropriate,
            apply in those
            cases.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 4</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall adopt such measures as may be
            necessary:</text><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_007" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>establish as criminal offences under its domestic law the offences set forth in
                article 2;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_008" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>To make those offences punishable by appropriate penalties which take into
                account the grave nature of the offences.</content></paragraph><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 5</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412809920_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_5_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each
            State Party, in accordance with its domestic legal principles, shall take the necessary
            measures to enable a legal entity located in its territory or organized under its laws
            to be held liable when a person responsible for the management or control of that legal
            entity has, in that capacity, committed an offence set forth in article 2. Such
            liability may be criminal, civil or
            administrative.</text><text id="ID_1438412809936_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_5_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Such
            liability is incurred without prejudice to the criminal liability of individuals who
            have committed the
            offences.</text><text id="ID_1438412809936_012" name="3" temporalId="sch0_5_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each
            State Party shall ensure, in particular, that legal entities liable in accordance with
                <ref>paragraph 1</ref> above are subject to effective, proportionate and dissuasive
            criminal, civil or administrative sanctions. Such sanctions may include monetary
            sanctions.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 6</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall adopt such measures as may be
            necessary, including, where appropriate, domestic legislation, to ensure that criminal
            acts within the scope of this Convention are under no circumstances justifiable by
            considerations of a political, philosophical, ideological, racial, ethnic, religious or
            other similar
            nature.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 7</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412809967_004" name="1" temporalId="sch0_7_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary to establish
            its jurisdiction over the offences set forth in article 2 when:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_009" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>The offence is committed in the territory of that State;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_010" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>The offence is committed on board a vessel flying the flag of that State or
                    an aircraft registered under the laws of that State at the time the offence is
                    committed;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_011" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content>The offence is committed by a national of that State.</content></paragraph></text><text id="ID_1438412809982_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_7_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>A State Party may also establish its jurisdiction over any such offence
                when:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>The offence was directed towards or resulted in the carrying out of an
                    offence referred to in article 2, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, subparagraph (a) or
                    (b), in the territory of or against a national of that State;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_013" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>The offence was directed towards or resulted in the carrying out of an
                    offence referred to in article 2, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, subparagraph (a) or
                    (b), against a State or government facility of that State abroad, including
                    diplomatic or consular premises of that State;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_014" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content>The offence was directed towards or resulted in an offence referred to in
                    article 2, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, subparagraph (a) or (b), committed in an
                    attempt to compel that State to do or abstain from doing any act;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_015" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(d)</num><content>The offence is committed by a stateless person who has his or her habitual
                    residence in the territory of that State;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056396_016" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(e)</num><content>The offence is committed on board an aircraft which is operated by the
                    Government of that State.</content></paragraph></text><text id="ID_1438412810014_012" name="3" temporalId="sch0_7_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Upon ratifying, accepting, approving or acceding to this Convention, each
            State Party shall notify the Secretary-General of the United Nations of the jurisdiction
            it has established in accordance with <ref>paragraph 2</ref>. Should any change take
            place, the State Party concerned shall immediately notify the Secretary-General.</text><text id="ID_1438412810029_004" name="4" temporalId="sch0_7_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall likewise take such measures as may be necessary to
            establish its jurisdiction over the offences set forth in article 2 in cases where the
            alleged offender is present in its territory and it does not extradite that person to
            any of the States Parties that have established their jurisdiction in accordance with
                <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> or <ref>2</ref>.</text><text id="ID_1438412810029_012" name="5" temporalId="sch0_7_5">5.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>When more than one State Party claims jurisdiction over the offences set
            forth in article 2, the relevant States Parties shall strive to coordinate their actions
            appropriately, in particular concerning the conditions for prosecution and the
            modalities for mutual legal assistance.</text><text id="ID_1438412810045_004" name="6" temporalId="sch0_7_6">6.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Without prejudice to the norms of general international law, this Convention
            does not exclude the exercise of any criminal jurisdiction established by a State Party
            in accordance with its domestic law.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 8</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810045_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_8_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take appropriate measures, in accordance with its
            domestic legal principles, for the identification, detection and freezing or seizure of
            any funds used or allocated for the purpose of committing the offences set forth in
            article 2 as well as the proceeds derived from such offences, for purposes of possible
            forfeiture.</text><text id="ID_1438412810060_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_8_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take appropriate measures, in accordance with its
            domestic legal principles, for the forfeiture of funds used or allocated for the purpose
            of committing the offences set forth in article 2 and the proceeds derived from such
            offences.</text><text id="ID_1438412810076_004" name="3" temporalId="sch0_8_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State Party concerned may give consideration to concluding agreements on
            the sharing with other States Parties, on a regular or case-by-case basis, of the funds
            derived from the forfeitures referred to in this article.</text><text id="ID_1438412810076_012" name="4" temporalId="sch0_8_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider establishing mechanisms whereby the funds
            derived from the forfeitures referred to in this article are utilized to compensate the
            victims of offences referred to in article 2, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, subparagraph (a)
            or (b), or their families.</text><text id="ID_1438412810092_004" name="5" temporalId="sch0_8_5">5.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The provisions of this article shall be implemented without prejudice to the
            rights of third parties acting in good faith.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 9</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810092_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_9_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Upon receiving information that a person who has committed or who is alleged
            to have committed an offence set forth in article 2 may be present in its territory, the
            State Party concerned shall take such measures as may be necessary under its domestic
            law to investigate the facts contained in the information.</text><text id="ID_1438412810107_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_9_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Upon being satisfied that the circumstances so warrant, the State Party in
            whose territory the offender or alleged offender is present shall take the appropriate
            measures under its domestic law so as to ensure that person’s presence for the purpose
            of prosecution or extradition.</text><text id="ID_1438412810107_012" name="3" temporalId="sch0_9_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Any person regarding whom the measures referred to in <ref>paragraph 2</ref>
            are being taken shall be entitled to:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056412_017" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>Communicate without delay with the nearest appropriate representative of
                    the State of which that person is a national or which is otherwise entitled to
                    protect that person’s rights or, if that person is a stateless person, the State
                    in the territory of which that person habitually resides;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056412_018" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>Be visited by a representative of that State;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056412_019" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content>Be informed of that person’s rights under subparagraphs (a) and
                    (b).</content></paragraph></text><text id="ID_1438412810138_004" name="4" temporalId="sch0_9_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The rights referred to in <ref>paragraph 3</ref> shall be exercised in
            conformity with the laws and regulations of the State in the territory of which the
            offender or alleged offender is present, subject to the provision that the said laws and
            regulations must enable full effect to be given to the purposes for which the rights
            accorded under <ref>paragraph 3</ref> are intended.</text><text id="ID_1438412810138_012" name="5" temporalId="sch0_9_5">5.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The provisions of <ref>paragraphs 3</ref> and <ref>4</ref> shall be without
            prejudice to the right of any State Party having a claim to jurisdiction in accordance
            with article 7, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, subparagraph (c), or <ref>paragraph 2</ref>,
            subparagraph (d), to invite the International Committee of the Red Cross to communicate
            with and visit the alleged offender.</text><text id="ID_1438412810154_004" name="6" temporalId="sch0_9_6">6.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>When a State Party, pursuant to the present article, has taken a person into
            custody, it shall immediately notify, directly or through the Secretary-General of the
            United Nations, the States Parties which have established jurisdiction in accordance
            with article 7, <ref>paragraph 1</ref> or <ref>2</ref>, and, if it considers it
            advisable, any other interested States Parties, of the fact that such person is in
            custody and of the circumstances which warrant that person’s detention. The State which
            makes the investigation contemplated in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> shall promptly inform the
            said States Parties of its findings and shall indicate whether it intends to exercise
            jurisdiction.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 10</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810185_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_10_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The State Party in the territory of which the alleged offender is present
            shall, in cases to which article 7 applies, if it does not extradite that person, be
            obliged, without exception whatsoever and whether or not the offence was committed in
            its territory, to submit the case without undue delay to its competent authorities for
            the purpose of prosecution, through proceedings in accordance with the laws of that
            State. Those authorities shall take their decision in the same manner as in the case of
            any other offence of a grave nature under the law of that State.</text><text id="ID_1438412810201_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_10_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Whenever a State Party is permitted under its domestic law to extradite or
            otherwise surrender one of its nationals only upon the condition that the person will be
            returned to that State to serve the sentence imposed as a result of the trial or
            proceeding for which the extradition or surrender of the person was sought, and this
            State and the State seeking the extradition of the person agree with this option and
            other terms they may deem appropriate, such a conditional extradition or surrender shall
            be sufficient to discharge the obligation set forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref>.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 11</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810232_004" name="1" temporalId="sch0_11_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The offences set forth in article 2 shall be deemed to be included as
            extraditable offences in any extradition treaty existing between any of the States
            Parties before the entry into force of this Convention. States Parties undertake to
            include such offences as extraditable offences in every extradition treaty to be
            subsequently concluded between them.</text><text id="ID_1438412810232_012" name="2" temporalId="sch0_11_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>When a State Party which makes extradition conditional on the existence of a
            treaty receives a request for extradition from another State Party with which it has no
            extradition treaty, the requested State Party may, at its option, consider this
            Convention as a legal basis for extradition in respect of the offences set forth in
            article 2. Extradition shall be subject to the other conditions provided by the law of
            the requested State.</text><text id="ID_1438412810248_004" name="3" temporalId="sch0_11_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>States Parties which do not make extradition conditional on the existence of
            a treaty shall recognize the offences set forth in article 2 as extraditable offences
            between themselves, subject to the conditions provided by the law of the requested
            State.</text><text id="ID_1438412810248_012" name="4" temporalId="sch0_11_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>If necessary, the offences set forth in article 2 shall be treated, for the
            purposes of extradition between States Parties, as if they had been committed not only
            in the place in which they occurred but also in the territory of the States that have
            established jurisdiction in accordance with article 7, <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and
                <ref>2</ref>.</text><text id="ID_1438412810263_004" name="5" temporalId="sch0_11_5">5.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The provisions of all extradition treaties and arrangements between States
            Parties with regard to offences set forth in article 2 shall be deemed to be modified as
            between States Parties to the extent that they are incompatible with this
            Convention.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 12</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810279_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_12_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>States Parties shall afford one another the greatest measure of assistance in
            connection with criminal investigations or criminal or extradition proceedings in
            respect of the offences set forth in article 2, including assistance in obtaining
            evidence in their possession necessary for the proceedings.</text><text id="ID_1438412810279_020" name="2" temporalId="sch0_12_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>States Parties may not refuse a request for mutual legal assistance on the
            ground of bank secrecy.</text><text id="ID_1438412810294_004" name="3" temporalId="sch0_12_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The requesting Party shall not transmit or use information or evidence
            furnished by the requested Party for investigations, prosecutions or proceedings other
            than those stated in the request without the prior consent of the requested
            Party.</text><text id="ID_1438412810294_012" name="4" temporalId="sch0_12_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State Party may give consideration to establishing mechanisms to share
            with other States Parties information or evidence needed to establish criminal, civil or
            administrative liability pursuant to article 5.</text><text id="ID_1438412810294_020" name="5" temporalId="sch0_12_5">5.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>States Parties shall carry out their obligations under <ref>paragraphs
                1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> in conformity with any treaties or other arrangements on
            mutual legal assistance or information exchange that may exist between them. In the
            absence of such treaties or arrangements, States Parties shall afford one another
            assistance in accordance with their domestic law.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 13</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">None of the offences set forth in article 2 shall be
            regarded, for the purposes of extradition or mutual legal assistance, as a fiscal
            offence. Accordingly, States Parties may not refuse a request for extradition or for
            mutual legal assistance on the sole ground that it concerns a fiscal
            offence.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 14</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">None of the offences set forth in article 2 shall be
            regarded for the purposes of extradition or mutual legal assistance as a political
            offence or as an offence connected with a political offence or as an offence inspired by
            political motives. Accordingly, a request for extradition or for mutual legal assistance
            based on such an offence may not be refused on the sole ground that it concerns a
            political offence or an offence connected with a political offence or an offence
            inspired by political
            motives.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 15</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Nothing in this Convention shall be interpreted as
            imposing an obligation to extradite or to afford mutual legal assistance, if the
            requested State Party has substantial grounds for believing that the request for
            extradition for offences set forth in article 2 or for mutual legal assistance with
            respect to such offences has been made for the purpose of prosecuting or punishing a
            person on account of that person’s race, religion, nationality, ethnic origin or
            political opinion or that compliance with the request would cause prejudice to that
            person’s position for any of these
            reasons.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 16</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810357_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_16_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>A person who is being detained or is serving a sentence in the territory of
            one State Party whose presence in another State Party is requested for purposes of
            identification, testimony or otherwise providing assistance in obtaining evidence for
            the investigation or prosecution of offences set forth in article 2 may be transferred
            if the following conditions are met:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_020" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>The person freely gives his or her informed consent;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_021" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>The competent authorities of both States agree, subject to such conditions
                    as those States may deem appropriate.</content></paragraph></text><text id="ID_1438412810372_012" name="2" temporalId="sch0_16_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>For the purposes of the present article:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_022" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>The State to which the person is transferred shall have the authority and
                    obligation to keep the person transferred in custody, unless otherwise requested
                    or authorized by the State from which the person was transferred;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_023" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>The State to which the person is transferred shall without delay implement
                    its obligation to return the person to the custody of the State from which the
                    person was transferred as agreed beforehand, or as otherwise agreed, by the
                    competent authorities of both States;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_024" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content>The State to which the person is transferred shall not require the State
                    from which the person was transferred to initiate extradition proceedings for
                    the return of the person;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_025" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(d)</num><content>The person transferred shall receive credit for service of the sentence
                    being served in the State from which he or she was transferred for time spent in
                    the custody of the State to which he or she was transferred.</content></paragraph></text><text id="ID_1438412810404_004" name="3" temporalId="sch0_16_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Unless the State Party from which a person is to be transferred in accordance
            with the present article so agrees, that person, whatever his or her nationality, shall
            not be prosecuted or detained or subjected to any other restriction of his or her
            personal liberty in the territory of the State to which that person is transferred in
            respect of acts or convictions anterior to his or her departure from the territory of
            the State from which such person was transferred.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 17</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Any person who is taken into custody or regarding whom
            any other measures are taken or proceedings are carried out pursuant to this Convention
            shall be guaranteed fair treatment, including enjoyment of all rights and guarantees in
            conformity with the law of the State in the territory of which that person is present
            and applicable provisions of international law, including international human rights
            law.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 18</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810435_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_18_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>States Parties shall cooperate in the prevention of the offences set forth in
            article 2 by taking all practicable measures, <i>inter alia</i>, by adapting their
            domestic legislation, if necessary, to prevent and counter preparations in their
            respective territories for the commission of those offences within or outside their
            territories, including:<paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_026" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>Measures to prohibit in their territories illegal activities of persons and
                    organizations that knowingly encourage, instigate, organize or engage in the
                    commission of offences set forth in article 2;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_027" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><leadIn>Measures requiring financial institutions and other professions involved in
                    financial transactions to utilize the most efficient measures available for the
                    identification of their usual or occasional customers, as well as customers in
                    whose interest accounts are opened, and to pay special attention to unusual or
                    suspicious transactions and report transactions suspected of stemming from a
                    criminal activity. For this purpose, States Parties shall consider:</leadIn><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(i)<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Adopting regulations prohibiting the opening of
                    accounts the holders or beneficiaries of which are unidentified or
                    unidentifiable, and measures to ensure that such institutions verify the
                    identity of the real owners of such transactions;</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(ii)<fillIn class="width_13"> </fillIn>With respect to the identification of legal
                    entities, requiring financial institutions, when necessary, to take measures to
                    verify the legal existence and the structure of the customer by obtaining,
                    either from a public register or from the customer or both, proof of
                    incorporation, including information concerning the customer’s name, legal form,
                    address, directors and provisions regulating the power to bind the
                    entity;</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(iii)<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn>Adopting regulations imposing on financial
                    institutions the obligation to report promptly to the competent authorities all
                    complex, unusual large transactions and unusual patterns of transactions, which
                    have no apparent economic or obviously lawful purpose, without fear of assuming
                    criminal or civil liability for breach of any restriction on disclosure of
                    information if they report their suspicions in good faith;</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(iv)<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn>Requiring financial institutions to maintain, for
                    at least five years, all necessary records on transactions, both domestic and
                    international.</text></paragraph></text><text id="ID_1438412810482_012" name="2" temporalId="sch0_18_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>States Parties shall further cooperate in the prevention of offences set
            forth in article 2 by considering:</text><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_028" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>Measures for the supervision, including, for example, the licensing, of all
                money-transmission agencies;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_029" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>Feasible measures to detect or monitor the physical cross-border transportation
                of cash and bearer negotiable instruments, subject to strict safeguards to ensure
                proper use of information and without impeding in any way the freedom of capital
                movements.</content></paragraph><text id="ID_1438412810497_020" name="3" temporalId="sch0_18_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>States Parties shall further cooperate in the prevention of the offences set
            forth in article 2 by exchanging accurate and verified information in accordance with
            their domestic law and coordinating administrative and other measures taken, as
            appropriate, to prevent the commission of offences set forth in article 2, in particular
            by:</text><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_030" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>Establishing and maintaining channels of communication between their competent
                agencies and services to facilitate the secure and rapid exchange of information
                concerning all aspects of offences set forth in article 2;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_031" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><leadIn>Cooperating with one another in conducting inquiries, with respect to the
                offences set forth in article 2, concerning:</leadIn><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(i)<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The identity, whereabouts and activities of persons
                in respect of whom reasonable suspicion exists that they are involved in such
                offences;</text><text class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0 align_justified">(ii)<fillIn class="width_13"> </fillIn>The movement of funds relating to the commission of
                such offences.</text></paragraph><text id="ID_1438412810528_012" name="4" temporalId="sch0_18_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15">
                </fillIn>States
            Parties may exchange information through the International Criminal Police Organization
            (Interpol).</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 19</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">The State Party where the alleged offender is prosecuted
            shall, in accordance with its domestic law or applicable procedures, communicate the
            final outcome of the proceedings to the Secretary-General of the United Nations, who
            shall transmit the information to the other States
            Parties.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 20</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">The States Parties shall carry out their obligations
            under this Convention in a manner consistent with the principles of sovereign equality
            and territorial integrity of States and that of non-intervention in the domestic affairs
            of other
            States.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 21</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Nothing in this Convention shall affect other rights,
            obligations and responsibilities of States and individuals under international law, in
            particular the purposes of the Charter of the United Nations, international humanitarian
            law and other relevant
            conventions.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 22</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">Nothing in this Convention entitles a State Party to
            undertake in the territory of another State Party the exercise of jurisdiction or
            performance of functions which are exclusively reserved for the authorities of that
            other State Party by its domestic
            law.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 23</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810575_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_23_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The annex may be amended by the addition of relevant treaties that:</text><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_032" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content>Are open to the participation of all States;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_033" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content>Have entered into force;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified" id="ID_1609224056427_034" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content>Have been ratified, accepted, approved or acceded to by at least twenty-two
                States Parties to the present Convention.</content></paragraph><text id="ID_1438412810591_020" name="2" temporalId="sch0_23_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>After the entry into force of this Convention, any State Party may propose
            such an amendment. Any proposal for an amendment shall be communicated to the depositary
            in written form. The depositary shall notify proposals that meet the requirements of
                <ref>paragraph 1</ref> to all States Parties and seek their views on whether the
            proposed amendment should be adopted.</text><text id="ID_1438412810606_004" name="3" temporalId="sch0_23_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The proposed amendment shall be deemed adopted unless one third of the States
            Parties object to it by a written notification not later than 180 days after its
            circulation.</text><text id="ID_1438412810606_012" name="4" temporalId="sch0_23_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>The adopted amendment to the annex shall enter into force 30 days after the
            deposit of the twenty-second instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval of such
            amendment for all those States Parties having deposited such an instrument. For each
            State Party ratifying, accepting or approving the amendment after the deposit of the
            twenty-second instrument, the amendment shall enter into force on the thirtieth day
            after deposit by such State Party of its instrument of ratification, acceptance or
            approval.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 24</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810622_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_24_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Any dispute between two or more States Parties concerning the interpretation
            or application of this Convention which cannot be settled through negotiation within a
            reasonable time shall, at the request of one of them, be submitted to arbitration. If,
            within six months from the date of the request for arbitration, the parties are unable
            to agree on the organization of the arbitration, any one of those parties may refer the
            dispute to the International Court of Justice, by application, in conformity with the
            Statute of the Court.</text><text id="ID_1438412810638_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_24_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Each State may at the time of signature, ratification, acceptance or approval
            of this Convention or accession thereto declare that it does not consider itself bound
            by <ref>paragraph 1</ref>. The other States Parties shall not be bound by <ref>paragraph
                1</ref> with respect to any State Party which has made such a reservation.</text><text id="ID_1438412810653_004" name="3" temporalId="sch0_24_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Any State which has made a reservation in accordance with
                <ref>paragraph 2</ref> may at any time withdraw that reservation by notification to
            the Secretary-General of the United
            Nations.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 25</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810669_004" name="1" temporalId="sch0_25_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>This Convention shall be open for signature by all States from 10 January
            2000 to 31 December 2001 at United Nations Headquarters in New York.</text><text id="ID_1438412810669_012" name="2" temporalId="sch0_25_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>This Convention is subject to ratification, acceptance or approval. The
            instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval shall be deposited with the
            Secretary-General of the United Nations.</text><text id="ID_1438412810669_020" name="3" temporalId="sch0_25_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>This Convention shall be open to accession by any State. The instruments of
            accession shall be deposited with the Secretary-General of the United Nations.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 26</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810684_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_26_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>This Convention shall enter into force on the thirtieth day following the
            date of the deposit of the twenty-second instrument of ratification, acceptance,
            approval or accession with the Secretary-General of the United Nations.</text><text id="ID_1438412810684_020" name="2" temporalId="sch0_26_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>For each State ratifying, accepting, approving or acceding to the Convention
            after the deposit of the twenty-second instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval
            or accession, the Convention shall enter into force on the thirtieth day after deposit
            by such State of its instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or
            accession.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 27</crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810700_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_27_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Any State Party may denounce this Convention by written notification to the
            Secretary-General of the United Nations.</text><text id="ID_1438412810700_020" name="2" temporalId="sch0_27_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Denunciation shall take effect one year following the date on which
            notification is received by the Secretary-General of the United Nations.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Article 28</crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24">The original of this Convention, of which the Arabic,
            Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish texts are equally authentic, shall be
            deposited with the Secretary-General of the United Nations who shall send certified
            copies thereof to all States.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="first_line_indent_24">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the undersigned, being duly
            authorized thereto by their respective Governments, have signed this Convention, opened
            for signature at United Nations Headquarters in New York on 10 January 2000.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Annex<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text id="ID_1438412810731_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_28_1">1.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Seizure of Aircraft, done at The
            Hague on 16 December 1970.</text><text id="ID_1438412810731_020" name="2" temporalId="sch0_28_2">2.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Civil
            Aviation, done at Montreal on 23 September 1971.</text><text id="ID_1438412810731_028" name="3" temporalId="sch0_28_3">3.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of Crimes against Internationally
            Protected Persons, including Diplomatic Agents, adopted by the General Assembly of the
            United Nations on 14 December 1973.</text><text id="ID_1438412810747_004" name="4" temporalId="sch0_28_4">4.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>International Convention against the Taking of Hostages, adopted by the
            General Assembly of the United Nations on 17 December 1979.</text><text id="ID_1438412810747_012" name="5" temporalId="sch0_28_5">5.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Convention on the Physical Protection of Nuclear Material, adopted at Vienna
            on 3 March 1980.</text><text id="ID_1438412810747_020" name="6" temporalId="sch0_28_6">6.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Protocol for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts of Violence at Airports Serving
            International Civil Aviation, supplementary to the Convention for the Suppression of
            Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Civil Aviation, done at Montreal on 24 February
            1988.</text><text id="ID_1438412810762_004" name="7" temporalId="sch0_28_7">7.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Convention for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of
            Maritime Navigation, done at Rome on 10 March 1988.</text><text id="ID_1438412810762_012" name="8" temporalId="sch0_28_8">8.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>Protocol for the Suppression of Unlawful Acts against the Safety of Fixed
            Platforms located on the Continental Shelf, done at Rome on 10 March
            1988.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text id="ID_1438412810778_004" name="9" temporalId="sch0_28_9">9.<fillIn class="width_15"> </fillIn>International Convention for the Suppression of Terrorist Bombings, adopted
            by the General Assembly of the United Nations on 15 December 1997.</text></schedule></main></subLeg>