<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 478 sub. leg. M</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>478M</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap478M!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-03-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403240445_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-03-19">Merchant
            Shipping (Seafarers) (Code of Safe Working Practices)
            Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap478/s96">Cap.
                478,
                sections
                96</ref>
            and <ref href="/hk/cap478/s134">134</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[2 September
                1996]<inline class="width_3"></inline><sourceNote><ref href="hk/1996/ln342">L.N. 342 of 1996</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403240461_002" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403240476_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412636822_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Code"><term>Code</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">守則</term>) means the United Kingdom Department of
                Transport publication entitled “Code of Safe Working Practices for Merchant Seamen”,
                published in 1991 by Her Majesty’s Stationery Office, as in force from time to
                time;</def><def name="Employer"><term>employer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">僱主</term>) means the person for the time being
                employing the master;</def><def name="Seagoing"><term>seagoing</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">海域航行</term>), in relation to a ship, means any ship
                other than one which is navigated exclusively within inland waters or in areas where
                port regulations apply;</def><def name="Ship"><term>ship</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船</term>、<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船舶</term>)
                means a Hong Kong ship.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412636822_039" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires, any requirement in respect of the Code shall include a like requirement in respect of the Chinese language translation thereof published in such manner as the Authority thinks fit; and the Authority shall, upon payment of the prescribed fee, provide a copy of that Chinese language translation to any person who applies to him in that behalf.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403240476_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412636853_018" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Regulation applies to all seagoing ships except any such ship which is a fishing vessel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412636853_026" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Authority may grant exemptions from all or any of the provisions of this Regulation for classes of cases or individual cases on such conditions, if any, as he thinks fit and may, subject to giving reasonable notice, alter or cancel any such exemption.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403240492_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Ships to carry copies of the Code</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412636884_026" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In a ship in which are employed the master and not more than 14 other seafarers, there shall be carried not less than 2 copies of the Code, of which one copy shall be kept in the custody of the master, and one copy in a place readily accessible to seafarers in the ordinary course of their duties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412636900_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In a ship in which are employed the master and more than 14 other seafarers, there shall be carried not less than one copy of the Code in the custody of each of the following seafarers—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412636900_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the master;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412636900_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the chief officer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412636900_029" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the chief engineer officer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412636900_037" name="d" temporalId="s4_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>either the purser or the catering officer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412636900_045" name="e" temporalId="s4_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the safety officer appointed pursuant to <ref>section 4</ref> of the
                    Merchant Shipping (Seafarers) (Safety Officials and Reporting of
                    Accidents,
                    Dangerous Occurrences and Occupational Diseases) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap478R">Cap. 478 sub. leg. R</ref>);
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2016/ln79">L.N. 79 of
                    2016</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412636900_053" name="f" temporalId="s4_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>where a safety representative has been appointed pursuant to <ref>section
                        4</ref> of the Merchant Shipping (Seafarers) (Safety Officials and Reporting
                    of
                    Accidents,
                    Dangerous Occurrences and Occupational Diseases) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap478R">Cap. 478 sub. leg.
                    R</ref>),
                    that safety representative; and
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2016/ln79">L.N. 79 of
                    2016</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412636900_061" name="g" temporalId="s4_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>where a safety committee has been appointed pursuant to <ref>section
                        4</ref> of the Merchant Shipping (Seafarers) (Safety Officials and Reporting
                    of
                    Accidents,
                    Dangerous Occurrences and Occupational Diseases) Regulation (<ref href="/hk/cap478R">Cap. 478 sub. leg.
                    R</ref>),
                    each member of that committee who requests a copy,
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2016/ln79">L.N. 79 of
                    2016</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>and in addition there shall be carried in different places (including the ship’s library,
                if any) readily accessible to seafarers in the ordinary course of their duties, not
                less than one copy of the Code (hereinafter referred to as the
                        <b><i>reference
                        copy</i></b>)
                for every 25 seafarers employed in the ship.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412636916_011" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>On being so requested by any seafarer employed in the ship, the master or any of the persons referred to in subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref> to (f), as the case may be, shall make temporarily available to that seafarer a copy of the Code.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403240508_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Notices of location of reference copies of the Code</heading><content>Where reference copies of the Code are required by this Regulation to be carried in a ship, the master shall cause to be displayed in different places in the ship, being places to which each seafarer has access in the ordinary course of his duties, not fewer than 3 clearly legible notices in the English and Chinese languages specifying the places where the reference copies are kept.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403240508_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Ship to carry sufficient copies of the Code</heading><content>The employer shall ensure in respect of a ship that the ship carries sufficient copies of
            the Code for the requirements of <ref>section 4</ref> to be
            complied
            with, including one copy for each member of the committee referred to in <ref>section
                4(2)(g)</ref>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403240523_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Copies of Regulation to be kept on board</heading><content>The master of a ship shall keep on board a copy of this Regulation and make such copy temporarily available to any seafarer who so requests, and the employer shall ensure that such ship carries a copy of this Regulation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403240523_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412637009_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A seafarer who is required by <ref>section 4(3)</ref> to make a copy of the
                Code available to any
                other
                seafarer who so requests and who fails without reasonable excuse
                to do so, commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level
                3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412637009_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The master of a ship who fails without reasonable excuse to comply with <ref>section 5</ref> or <ref>7</ref> commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 1.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412637009_020" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An employer who contravenes <ref>section 6</ref> commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 3 unless he shows that he has taken all reasonable steps to ensure that sufficient copies of the Code are carried on the ship.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412637009_028" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An employer who without reasonable excuse contravenes <ref>section 7</ref> commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412637025_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person who, without the consent of the employer or master, knowingly removes from a ship a copy of the Code carried in compliance with this Regulation commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 1.</content></subsection></section></main></subLeg>