<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 331 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>331C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap331C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-12-02</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403017630_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-09-10">
                                    Immigration Service (Treatment of Detained Persons) Order
                                    </docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap331/s13A">Cap.
                                                331, section
                                    13A</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er5">E.R. 5 of
                                                2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[14 November 1997]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er5">E.R. 5 of
                                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403017646_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ArrestdetentionSheet"><term>arrest/detention
                sheet</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">逮捕／羈留紀錄表</term>) means the sheet or record maintained
            in respect of a detainee under <ref>section 6</ref>;</def><def name="Detainee"><term>detainee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">被羈留者</term>) means a person detained at an office of
            the Service under <ref>section 13A(2)(a)</ref> of the Ordinance or pursuant to the order
            of a magistrate under <ref>section 20(3)</ref> or <ref>79(1)</ref> of the Magistrates
            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap227">Cap. 227</ref>);</def><def name="DetentionCentre"><term>Detention
                Centre</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">羈留中心</term>) means the detention facilities maintained
            by the Immigration Department specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>;</def><def name="GuardingOfficer"><term>guarding
                officer</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">看管人員</term>) means a member of the Service appointed to
            be a guarding officer under <ref>section 5(1)</ref> and, in relation to any detainee,
            means the guarding officer for the time being in charge of the Detention Centre.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403017646_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Detainee to be taken to Detention Centre</heading><content>A member of the Service of the rank of Chief Immigration Officer or above who detains or authorizes the detention of a detainee shall cause the detainee to be taken to the Detention Centre and placed in the custody of the guarding officer.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403017661_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Notification to relatives, etc.</heading><leadIn>Immediately after the detention of a detainee, or so soon thereafter as may be practicable, the member of the Service who authorized the detention shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411965522_026" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the request of the detainee, cause a close relative of the detainee, or any other person named by the detainee for that purpose, to be notified of his whereabouts; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411965537_006" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the detainee is a public officer, cause the head of the department in which he holds office to be notified of the detention orally and in writing.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403017661_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Communication with legal advisers, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965553_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A detainee shall be afforded reasonable opportunity to communicate with a legal adviser and to consult with him in the presence, but out of the hearing, of a member of the Service unless such communication or consultation would cause unreasonable hindrance or delay to the investigation of the suspected offence or the administration of justice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965553_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purpose of preparing his defence a detainee detained pursuant to the order of a magistrate shall be allowed—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411965553_020" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a supply of writing material and to have letters to his legal adviser, relatives and friends posted or delivered with the least possible delay;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411965553_028" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to speak on the telephone to his legal adviser, relatives and friends, unless such communication is reasonably likely to cause hindrance to the investigation of the suspected offence or the administration of justice.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017677_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Appointment and duties of guarding officers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965584_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may appoint members of the Service to be guarding officers for the purposes of this Order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965584_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A guarding officer shall, while a detainee is in his custody, be responsible for the safe custody and welfare of the detainee and for discharging such other duties as are imposed on him by this Order in relation to the detainee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965584_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notwithstanding anything in <ref>section 2</ref> or in this section, the guarding officer may temporarily place a detainee in the custody of another member of the Service for the purpose of furthering an investigation, in which case that other member of the Service shall, until he returns the detainee to the custody of the guarding officer at the Detention Centre, have the responsibilities and duties of a guarding officer referred to in subsection (2) in relation to the detainee.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017692_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Individual detention record to be kept</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965615_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>There shall be kept in respect of each detainee a record to be known as the arrest/detention sheet, in which shall be recorded—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411965615_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>immediately on the detention of a detainee, the reasons for the detention;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411965615_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all movements and interviews of, requests made by, and meals, articles and any facilities provided to, the detainee; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411965615_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>such other matters as are by this Order required to be so recorded.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965615_035" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In addition to the matters required to be recorded under subsection (1), there may be recorded by the guarding officer upon an arrest/detention sheet such other matters as he considers desirable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965615_043" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Except where in this Order it is otherwise provided, the guarding officer shall be responsible for recording in an arrest/detention sheet all matters required to be so recorded which occur while the detainee is in his custody.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017692_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Search of detainee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965646_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Upon the detention of a detainee, he shall, before being placed in any detention room, be searched thoroughly.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965646_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The searching of a detainee shall be conducted with due regard to decency and self-respect, and in as seemly a manner as is consistent with the necessity of discovering any concealed articles.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965646_020" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No detainee shall be searched other than by a member of the Service of the same sex.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965646_028" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A detainee removed from his detention room shall be searched before being returned to that, or being placed in another, detention room.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017880_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Articles found in detainee’s possession</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965662_035" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Any article found in the detainee’s possession which may be used by the detainee to injure himself or to escape from custody shall be taken from him and placed in the custody of a member of the Service, who shall make an inventory thereof and provide the detainee with a copy:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s8_1_proviso">Provided that if the detainee so requests, he may be permitted by a member of the Service to have the article in his possession or to use it for such period and subject to such conditions as the officer deems fit.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965662_049" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsection (1), a detainee shall, except for reasons which the guarding officer shall cause to be recorded in the arrest/detention sheet, be permitted to retain any head-dress he is by custom or religion required to wear, essential clothing and a hearing-aid.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017911_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Comfort of detainees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965693_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Reasonable arrangements shall be made for the comfort of detainees.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965693_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Whenever practicable both a detainee being questioned or making a statement and the member of the Service asking the questions or recording the statement shall be seated.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965693_020" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A detainee shall be permitted to receive from outside such items of clothing as may be necessary, subject to their inspection by a member of the Service.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965693_028" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A detainee who has to spend a night or a substantial part hereof at an office of the Service shall be provided with a bed and reasonable bedding.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017942_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Food and drink</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965709_035" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Reasonable arrangements shall be made by the guarding officer for the refreshment of a detainee, including the provision of adequate food, without charge to the detainee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965709_043" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to subsection (1) a detainee may be permitted by the guarding officer to obtain other food at his own expense subject to such food being inspected by an officer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965724_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Drinking water shall be supplied to a detainee on request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965724_013" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Details of all refreshment and food supplied to or received by a detainee shall be recorded in the arrest/detention sheet.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017973_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Toilet facilities and exercise</heading><content>Subject to such supervision and other measures as may be necessary to ensure that he does not escape or injure himself, a detainee shall be provided with adequate facilities and opportunity to wash, shower, shave, relieve himself and take a reasonable amount of exercise.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403017973_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Sickness or injury</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965771_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsections (2) and (3), if a detainee complains of or appears to be suffering from sickness or injury, he shall be provided with adequate medical attention at an office of the Service.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965771_012" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a medical practitioner so advises, or the services of a medical practitioner cannot be procured at an office of the Service, the detainee shall be escorted elsewhere to receive medical attention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965771_020" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the detainee is admitted to a hospital, he shall at all times be guarded by a member of the Service until lawfully released on bail or otherwise.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403017989_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Complaints by detainees</heading><content>Every complaint made by a detainee about the conditions under which he is detained or the conduct of any member of the Service shall, if not made in writing, be reduced to writing by the member of the Service to whom it is made, and as soon as possible brought to the attention of a member of the Service not below the rank of Assistant Principal Immigration Officer and recorded in the detainee’s arrest/detention sheet.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018004_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Female detainees</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965802_011" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Female detainees shall ordinarily be kept separate from male detainees.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965802_019" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A female detainee shall be guarded by a female member of the Service and, except in an emergency, no male member of the Service shall enter a detention room in which a female detainee is detained otherwise than in the company of a female member of the Service.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018004_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Safety of detainees in emergency</heading><content>In the event of fire or other emergency at an office of the Service, the safety of any detainees detained there shall be paramount and if their safety is threatened, the guarding officer or members of the Service shall escort the detainees to the nearest police station or other suitable place.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018020_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Use of handcuffs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965834_011" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Handcuffs shall only be used to restrain a detainee when necessary for his own safety or the safety of others or to prevent his escape.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965834_019" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any use of handcuffs shall be recorded on the arrest/detention sheet by the member of the Service causing them to be used.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018036_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Notice to detainees</heading><content>There shall be displayed in a conspicuous position in every room used for the
            detention of a detainee and in other conspicuous places at the offices of the Service
            where it can readily be seen by detainees, a notice in the following
            terms—</content><content>
            <crossHeading> </crossHeading>
        </content><quotedStructure>
            <content class="align_center">“Notice to Persons
                Detained<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
            <section><num value="1">1.</num><content>You may request that your relatives or a friend be informed of your
                    detention.</content></section>
            <section><num value="2">2.</num><content>Provided that no unreasonable delay or hindrance is caused to the processes
                    of investigation or the administration of justice you may communicate and
                    consult with a legal
                    adviser.</content></section>
            <section><num value="3">3.</num><leadIn>For the purpose of preparing your defence you will, if you have been
                    detained on the order of a magistrate, be allowed—</leadIn><paragraph class="left_indent_84 first_line_indent_-54"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a supply of writing material, and to have your letters posted or
                        delivered without delay;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_84 first_line_indent_-54"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to make telephone calls, provided no hindrance is caused to the
                        processes of investigation or the administration of
                        justice.</content></paragraph></section>
            <section><num value="4">4.</num><content>You may ask to be released on
                    bail.</content></section>
            <section><num value="5">5.</num><content>If you feel ill, ask for medical
                    attention.</content></section>
            <section><num value="6">6.</num><content>Adequate food and refreshment will be supplied free. You are not entitled
                    to receive from outside anything except the basic necessities of clothing.
                    However you may, if you request, be permitted at your own expense to have food
                    from outside to be brought to you subject to
                    inspection.</content></section>
            <section><num value="7">7.</num><content>Drinking water will be supplied on
                    request.</content></section>
            
        </quotedStructure><content>
            <crossHeading> </crossHeading>
        </content><quotedStructure>
            <content class="align_center">被羈留者請注意<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
            <section><num value="1">1.</num><content>你可要求通知你的親屬或一位朋友你已被羈留。</content></section>
            <section><num value="2">2.</num><content>在不會對進行調查或對執法構成不合理延遲或阻礙的前提下，你可與一名法律顧問通訊和商議。</content></section>
            <section><num value="3">3.</num><leadIn>你如根據裁判官的命令被羈留，為準備你的辯護，你會 ——</leadIn><paragraph class="left_indent_84 first_line_indent_-54"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>獲供應書寫用品，而你的書信會在沒有延遲的情況下郵寄或遞送；</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_84 first_line_indent_-54"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>在不會對進行調查或對執法構成阻礙的前提下，獲准打電話給他人。</content></paragraph></section>
            <section><num value="4">4.</num><content>你可要求保釋外出。</content></section>
            <section><num value="5">5.</num><content>你如感到不適，請要求醫療護理。</content></section>
            <section><num value="6">6.</num><content>你會獲得免費供應足夠的食物和茶點。除屬基本需要的衣物外，你不得接受從外間送來的任何其他東西。但如你提出要求，則可獲准自費得到外間送來的食物，但這些食物須經過檢查。</content></section>
            <section><num value="7">7.</num><content>飲用水會應你的要求供應。”.</content></section>
        </quotedStructure></section><section id="ID_1438403018051_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-09-10" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Visits by justices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411965943_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Service shall provide facilities to justices of the peace appointed by the
                Chief Executive for that purpose (in this section referred to as
                    <term>visiting
                    justices</term>) to enable them to visit detainees and satisfy themselves that
                detainees are held in accordance with this Order and any other law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965958_005" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (1) visiting justices shall be permitted to visit detainees at all reasonable times and for reasonable periods.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965958_013" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A record of such a visit shall be made in the arrest/detention sheet of every detainee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965958_021" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>There shall be kept at the offices of the Service a book to be known as the
                “Visiting Justices Report Book” in English and known as “太平紳士探訪紀錄簿” in Chinese, in
                which visiting justices shall record their visits and their observations and comments.
                <marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411965958_029" name="5" temporalId="s18_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any adverse observation or comment recorded in the Visiting Justices Report Book shall as soon as practicable be brought to the attention of the Director or Deputy Director.</content></subsection></section><schedule id="ID_1438403018051_003" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap331C/s1">s.
                1</ref>]</note><heading>Detention
            Facilities<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><section name="s17" temporalId="sch0_s17" class="no_header" id="ID_1712545323198_001"><num value="17"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="hk/2024/ln41">L.N. 41 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></section><crossHeading> </crossHeading><section name="s17" temporalId="sch0_s17" class="no_header" id="ID_1712545323199_002"><num value="17">2.</num><content>The detention centre at 2nd floor of the Enforcement Tower of the Immigration
                Headquarters, 61 Po Yap Road, Tseung Kwan O.</content></section><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/ln41">L.N. 41 of
        2024</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></subLeg>