<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 438</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>438</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap438!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403200057_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-09-30">
            <content>An Ordinance to provide for the creation of easements and other rights over
                land in favour of the Government for the purpose of the construction, maintenance
                and operation of sewage tunnels; and for connected matters.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
            84</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[5 November 1993]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                        2021</ref>)<marker></marker><marker></marker></sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><section id="ID_1438403200057_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Sewage Tunnels (Statutory Easements) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403200072_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Land"><term>land</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地</term>) means leased land within the meaning of the
            Land (Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap28">Cap. 28</ref>) or
            unleased land which is occupied in accordance with Part II of that Ordinance and
            includes land covered by water;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 85</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="LandRegistry"><term>Land
                Registry</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地註冊處</term>) means the
            Land
            Registry established under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap.
                128</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2002/20">20 of 2002 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Secretary"><term>Secretary</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">局長</term>) means the Secretary for Environment and
            Ecology; <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/ln330">L.N. 330 of 1999</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N.
                    106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="SewageTunnel,Tunnel"><term>sewage
                tunnel</term>
            and
                <term>tunnel</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">污水隧道</term>) mean an underground tunnel and associated
            underground structures for the transfer of sewage;</def><def name="TunnelWorks"><term>tunnel
                works</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">污水隧道工程</term>) means the construction, operation,
            maintenance, repair or replacement of any sewage tunnel or any part of such tunnel, or
            the investigation or examination of such tunnel or of any land required for such
            tunnel.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403200088_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Plans relating to sewage tunnels</heading><leadIn>Where the Government proposes to construct any sewage tunnel, the Secretary shall cause to be prepared a plan—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412519853_047" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>showing the route of the proposed tunnel; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412519853_055" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>identifying the land situated on the route of the proposed tunnel.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403200088_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Publication of plans</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412519869_054" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Upon completion of the preparation of a plan under <ref>section 3</ref>, the
                Secretary shall cause to be published in the Gazette in both the Chinese and English
                languages a notice of the plan containing the particulars specified in subsection
                (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412519884_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A notice of a plan shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412519884_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>either be published together with a copy of the plan to which it relates,
                    or state where and at what times the plan may be inspected;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412519884_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>describe the land situated on the route of the proposed tunnel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412519884_029" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>state the proposed minimum depth below the surface of the land at which the
                    tunnel will lie;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412519884_037" name="d" temporalId="s4_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>contain a statement to the effect that any person having an estate or
                    interest evidenced in an instrument registered in the Land Registry in any land
                    situated on the route of the proposed tunnel may object to the proposal under
                        <ref>section 5</ref> by lodging a notice in writing of his objection with
                    the Director of Drainage Services within a period specified in the notice of the
                    plan, being a period of not less than 2 months beginning on the date of
                    publication of the notice of the plan;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412519900_006" name="e" temporalId="s4_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>indicate that certain easements and other rights may be created in favour
                    of the Government over such land on the expiry of the period specified for the
                    purpose of paragraph (d) if no objection has been lodged before that
                        expiry.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403200103_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Objections</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412519915_065" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to this section, any person who has an estate or interest evidenced in an instrument registered in the Land Registry in any land situated on the route of a proposed tunnel may object to the route or depth or both of the proposed tunnel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412519931_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An objection under this section shall be made by notice in writing delivered to the Director of Drainage Services at any time during the period beginning on the publication of the notice of the plan of the proposed tunnel and ending with the expiry of the time specified in that notice for the purpose of <ref>section 4(2)(d)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412519931_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A notice of objection shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412519931_021" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>describe the estate or interest of the objector in the land; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412519931_029" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>state the reasons for his objection.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412519931_036" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A notice of objection delivered pursuant to subsection (2) may be amended or withdrawn in writing at any time before an order is made under <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref>, and if withdrawn shall be treated for the purposes of those sections as not having been delivered.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403200103_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Procedure if no objection made</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412519962_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the time for the making of an objection under <ref>section 5</ref> has expired and no objection has been delivered to the Director of Drainage Services, the Secretary may order that <ref>section 10</ref> shall apply in respect of any land identified in a plan prepared for the purposes of <ref>section 3</ref> and described in the notice of the plan published under <ref>section 4</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412519962_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Secretary shall publish in the Gazette notice of any order made by him under this section, and such notice shall describe the land to which the order applies.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403200119_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Procedure if objection made</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412519993_011" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where at the expiry of the time for the making of an objection under
                    <ref>section 5</ref> an objection has been delivered under that section, the
                Chief Executive in Council shall consider such objection and may if he thinks fit
                order that <ref>section 10</ref> shall apply in respect of any land identified in a
                plan prepared for the purposes of <ref>section 3</ref> and described in the notice
                of the plan published under <ref>section 4</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412519993_019" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an order is made under subsection (1), the plan relating to the proposed
                tunnel shall be subject to such amendment as the Chief Executive in Council thinks
                fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520009_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notice of an order made by the Chief Executive in Council under this section
                shall be published in the Gazette and shall describe the land to which the order
                applies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520009_013" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a plan is amended by the Chief Executive in Council pursuant to
                subsection (2) such that the route of the proposed tunnel passes through land not
                previously identified in the plan as land situated on the route of the proposed
                tunnel, <ref>sections 3 to 6</ref> and this section shall apply in respect of such
                amended part of the plan.<inline class="width_3"> </inline></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403200135_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Orders under <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438412520040_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Notice of an order made under <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref> and published in the Gazette pursuant to those sections shall include a statement to the effect that claims for compensation under <ref>section 12</ref> for loss or damage resulting from the creation or exercise of rights under this Ordinance may be submitted in writing to the Director of Lands within the period specified in that section and, if the Director of Lands rejects such claims in whole or in part, to the Lands Tribunal for final determination.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520056_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An order made under <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref> and of which notice has been published in the Gazette pursuant to those sections shall take effect on the expiration of 14 days after the date of such publication.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520056_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of <ref>section 2</ref> of the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>), an order made under <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref> and applying in respect of any land shall be deemed to be an instrument by which such land may be affected, and shall be capable of being entered and registered as such in the Land Registry.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403200135_004" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Deposit of plan and registration of order</heading><leadIn>Following the making of an order under <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref>, the Secretary shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520071_042" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>deposit in the Land Registry a copy of the plan to which the order refers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520087_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>as soon as practicable, and in any event not later than 14 days after the making of the order, deliver the order or a certified copy of the order to the Land Registry for registration under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>).</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403200150_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Statutory easements</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412520103_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to this Ordinance, the Government may exercise from time to time all or
                any of the following rights over any land identified in an order made under
                    <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref>, that is to say the right—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520103_019" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to place and keep any sewage tunnel under such land and to transfer sewage
                    through such tunnel; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520103_027" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to carry out tunnel works required for the purposes of paragraph
                    (a).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520103_034" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Rights shall only be exercisable under subsection (1) where there is a cover to
                the sewage tunnel or tunnel works, as the case may be, of not less than 30 metres of
                bedrock.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520103_042" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The rights conferred by this section on the Government may be exercised by any
                employee, servant or agent of the Government authorized for the purpose or by any
                other person authorized on the Government’s behalf for the purpose.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403200166_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Rectification of plan</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412520134_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive may, at the request in writing of the Secretary, direct
                that any plan referred to in an order made under <ref>section 6</ref> or
                    <ref>7</ref> shall be rectified so as to accord with the route of a tunnel as
                constructed, and any such direction together with any document or material
                containing the rectification shall be deposited in the Land Registry and annexed to
                the copy of the plan deposited under <ref>section 9</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520149_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any document or material evidencing the rectification of a plan is
                deposited in the Land Registry under subsection (1), the Secretary may by notice
                published in the Gazette order that any reference in this Ordinance or any order
                under this Ordinance to a plan shall be construed as including a reference to a plan
                as so rectified.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520149_013" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Section 9</ref> shall apply in relation to the delivery for registration
                of an order made under subsection (2) as it applies in relation to the delivery for
                registration of an order made under <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520149_021" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a direction made by the Chief Executive under subsection (1) for the
                rectification of any plan identifies land situated on the route of a tunnel as
                constructed, being land not previously identified in the plan for the purposes of
                    <ref>section 3</ref>, the Secretary may by notice published in the Gazette order
                that any reference in this Ordinance to land identified in an order made under
                    <ref>section 6</ref> or <ref>7</ref> shall be construed as including a reference
                to land so identified in the direction.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520165_005" name="5" temporalId="s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 12</ref>, where an order has been made under subsection
                (4), no action shall lie in respect of any act done by the Government prior to the
                making of the order in the purported exercise of rights conferred under <ref>section
                    10</ref> which would, if done subsequent to the making of the order, be lawfully
                and validly done.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403200181_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Compensation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412520196_049" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to this section, the Government shall be liable to pay compensation to
                any person who has suffered loss or damage to land (including any diminution in the
                value of the land) or property situated on land as a result of the creation of
                rights, or the exercise of rights created, under this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of
                        1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520212_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="LossOrDamageAsAResultOfTheCreationOfRightsUnderThisOrdinance">For the
                avoidance of doubt,
                    <term>loss
                    or damage as a result of the creation of rights under this
                Ordinance</term>
                in subsection (1) includes, where such rights have been created, any loss or damage
                as a result of a decision of the Building Authority under <ref>section 17A</ref> of
                the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>).</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520212_012" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A claim for compensation under this section shall be made by delivering notice
                of the claim in writing to the Director of Lands within the following period, that
                is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520212_020" name="a" temporalId="s12_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the claim is for compensation for diminution in the value of the land
                    arising from the creation of an easement or right, within 12 months after the
                    date on which the easement or right is created;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520212_028" name="b" temporalId="s12_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the claim is for loss sustained on account of any decision by the
                    Building Authority under <ref>section 17A</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>), being loss not foreseen and not
                    reasonably foreseeable at the expiry of the period referred to in paragraph (a),
                    within 12 months after the date of the decision;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/ln210">L.N. 210 of
                            1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520227_006" name="c" temporalId="s12_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in any other case, within 12 months after the date on which the loss or
                    damage is discovered.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520227_013" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>No compensation shall be payable for any loss as is referred to in subsection
                    <ref>(3)(b)</ref> in respect of any land—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520227_021" name="a" temporalId="s12_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where compensation has previously been paid under this section for any loss
                    as is referred in subsection <ref>(3)(b)</ref> in respect of such land;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520227_029" name="b" temporalId="s12_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>after the expiration of 10 years from completion of the construction of the
                    tunnel under such land.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520227_036" name="5" temporalId="s12_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>A notice of a claim for compensation under this section shall contain
                particulars of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520227_044" name="a" temporalId="s12_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the loss or damage sustained;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520243_006" name="b" temporalId="s12_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the amount of the claim; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520243_014" name="c" temporalId="s12_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>how the amount claimed is calculated.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520243_021" name="6" temporalId="s12_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Director of Lands may request any person claiming compensation under this
                section to furnish further particulars of and in support of his claim or any item of
                his claim, and if any such particulars are not furnished to the Director within a
                period of 1 month from the date of the notice, or within such further period as the
                Director may in writing allow, the claim or the item of the claim concerning which
                the particulars are requested shall be deemed to be rejected and subsection (7)
                shall not apply to such claim or item of the claim.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520259_005" name="7" temporalId="s12_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>The Director of Lands shall, within 3 months of the service of a claim on him
                or, if he has requested further particulars under subsection (6) within 3 months of
                the day on which the particulars are furnished in accordance with that subsection,
                notify the claimant in writing that he—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520259_013" name="a" temporalId="s12_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>admits the entire claim; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520259_021" name="b" temporalId="s12_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>rejects the entire claim; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520259_029" name="c" temporalId="s12_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>admits a specified part of the claim and rejects the remainder,</content></paragraph><continued>and shall briefly state his reasons for rejection.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520259_042" name="8" temporalId="s12_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>Where the Director of Lands has rejected a claim or any part of a claim under
                subsection (7), or where a claim or any part of a claim is deemed to have been
                rejected under subsection (6), the Director may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520259_050" name="a" temporalId="s12_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by notice in writing offer to the claimant such sum, including costs as
                    agreed, as the Government is willing to pay in full and final settlement of the
                    claim or any part of the claim;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520259_058" name="b" temporalId="s12_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>commence proceedings in the Lands Tribunal, to have the claim or any part
                    of the claim in respect of which no offer is made heard and determined by it in
                    accordance with this Ordinance; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520259_066" name="c" temporalId="s12_8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>commence such proceedings in the Lands Tribunal where any offer under
                    paragraph (a) is not accepted by the claimant within 1 month of the date of the
                    offer.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520274_005" name="9" temporalId="s12_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>If, after the expiry of 6 months from the receipt of a claim by the Director of
                Lands, the claim has not been settled by agreement, either the claimant or the
                Director may commence proceedings in the Lands Tribunal to have the claim, or so
                much of the claim as is still then in dispute, heard and determined by it under this
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520274_013" name="10" temporalId="s12_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>If any claimant is not satisfied with the decision of the Director of Lands to
                reject the claim or any part of the claim, he may, not later than 1 month after the
                Director has notified him of his decision, submit the claim to the Lands Tribunal
                for determination in accordance with this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520274_021" name="11" temporalId="s12_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><leadIn>Interest shall be payable on any amount of compensation payable under this
                Ordinance in respect of loss or damage as is referred to in subsection
                    <ref>(3)(b)</ref> or (c), and such interest shall be payable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412520290_005" name="a" temporalId="s12_11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for the period from the date on which a claim is made under this Ordinance
                    to the date of payment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412520290_013" name="b" temporalId="s12_11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at the rate payable on judgment debts pursuant to <ref>section 49</ref> of
                    the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of
                            1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520290_020" name="12" temporalId="s12_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>All sums of money agreed or determined as compensation, and any interest
                payable, under this Ordinance shall be a charge on the general revenue.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520290_028" name="13" temporalId="s12_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>No action, claim or proceedings shall lie or be brought against the Government
                or any other person to recover damages or compensation for loss or damage to land or
                any property situated on land as a result of the creation of rights, or the exercise
                of rights created, under this Ordinance except in pursuance of the rights to
                compensation provided for in this section.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403200213_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Claims out of time</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412520368_011" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), if notice of a claim is not delivered to the
                Director of Lands before the expiration of the period specified in <ref>section
                    12(3)</ref> in respect of that matter, the right to claim compensation for that
                matter shall be barred.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520368_019" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The period referred to in subsection (1) may, upon application made to the
                Lands Tribunal either before or after the expiry of that period, be extended in
                accordance with this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520368_027" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notice of an application under subsection (2) shall be given to the Director of
                Lands by the applicant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520383_005" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Lands Tribunal may extend the period within which notice of a claim must be
                delivered to the Director of Lands if it considers that the delay in delivering
                notice of the claim was occasioned by mistake of fact or mistake of any matter of
                law (other than the relevant provision in <ref>section 12(3)</ref>) or by any other
                reasonable cause or that the Government is not materially prejudiced in the conduct
                of its case or otherwise by the delay.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520383_013" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>An extension may be granted by the Lands Tribunal under subsection (4) with or
                without conditions for such period as it thinks fit but not in any case exceeding 5
                years from the expiration of the period referred to in subsection (1).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403200228_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Offence to obstruct exercise of right of Government</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412520415_011" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who, having been given notice by the Government of its intention to
                exercise rights created under <ref>section 10</ref> in respect of any land, wilfully
                obstructs or interferes with the lawful exercise of those rights at any time
                specified in the notice commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at level
                3
                and to imprisonment for 6 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520415_019" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Notice">
                <leadIn>For the purpose of subsection (1)
                        <term>notice</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">通知</term>) means written notice given—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412520415_027" name="a" temporalId="s14_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>not less than 1 day before the earliest time specified in the
                        notice;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412520430_006" name="b" temporalId="s14_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to the defendant personally.</content></paragraph>
            </def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412520430_013" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as imposing on the Government an
                obligation to give notice under this section prior to the exercise of any of the
                rights created under <ref>section 10</ref>.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403200228_003" name="s15" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="omitted" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403200244_002" name="s16" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-09-30" status="omitted" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>