<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 493 sub. leg. B</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>493B</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap493B!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403269477_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-02-25">Non-local Higher
            and
            Professional
            Education
            (Regulation)
            Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap493/s40">Cap.
                493,
                section
            40</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2021</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[20 June 1997]
            <sourceNote><ref href="/hk/1997/ln353">L.N. 353 of
            1997</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403269492_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403269492_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these Rules, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Publish"><term>publish</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">發表</term>) includes broadcast and otherwise
            disseminate;</def><def name="PurelyDistanceLearningCourse"><term>purely
                distance learning
            course</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">純遙距學習課程</term>) means a course of education which, but
            for the operation of <ref>section 2(5)</ref> or (6) of the Ordinance, would have fallen
            within the definition of
                <term>regulated
                course</term>
            in <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Ordinance by virtue of <ref>section 2(4)</ref> of the
            Ordinance.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403269508_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Publication of advertisements</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412732107_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person shall publish, or cause to be published, for distribution to or general reception by the public in Hong Kong any advertisement with respect to a registered course or an exempted course, or any part thereof, unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412732107_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>there is stated clearly in the advertisement—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732107_020" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of a registered course or any part thereof, the registration number (if any) of the course as set out in the certificate of registration issued in respect of the course under <ref>section 10(9)</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732107_028" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of an exempted course or any part thereof, that the course is an exempted course; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732107_035" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the advertisement contains—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732107_043" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the advertisement is in the English language only, a statement which reads “It is a matter of discretion for individual employers to recognize any qualification to which this course may lead”;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732123_007" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the advertisement is in the Chinese language only, a statement which reads “個別僱主可酌情決定是否承認本課程可令學員獲取的任何資格”;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732123_015" name="iii" temporalId="s3_1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>in any other case, both of the statements set out in subparagraphs (i) and (ii).</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732123_021" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>No person shall publish, or cause to be published, for distribution to or general reception by the public in Hong Kong with respect to a regulated course or a purely distance learning course, or any part thereof, any advertisement which contains any statement or representation which is false or misleading in a material particular as to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412732123_029" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>whether or not the course is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732123_037" name="i" temporalId="s3_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a regulated course;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732123_045" name="ii" temporalId="s3_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a registered course;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732123_053" name="iii" temporalId="s3_2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>an exempted course;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732123_061" name="iv" temporalId="s3_2_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>a purely distance learning course;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732123_068" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any recognition in respect of any qualification to which the course or any part thereof may or is claimed to lead;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732123_076" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any employment or remuneration opportunities which may be or are claimed to be open to persons studying or completing the course or any part thereof.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732138_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (4), a person who contravenes subsection (1) or (2) commits an offence and is liable on conviction—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412732138_013" name="a" temporalId="s3_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of contravention of subsection (1), to a fine at level 3;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732138_021" name="b" temporalId="s3_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of contravention of subsection (2), to a fine at level 4 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732138_028" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where a person is charged for contravention of subsection (3) in respect of an advertisement, it shall be a defence for such person to prove—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412732138_036" name="a" temporalId="s3_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that he carried on the business of publishing or arranging for the publication of advertisements, that he received the advertisement for publication in the ordinary course of business, and that at the time he published the advertisement he had no reason to believe that the contravention would occur by reason of the publication of the advertisement; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732138_044" name="b" temporalId="s3_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that he took all reasonable steps and exercised all due diligence to avoid the contravention.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403269524_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Refund of fees and charges collected</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412732185_065" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where any fees and charges, however described, have been collected in respect of
                a registered course or an exempted course, there shall be refunded—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412732201_005" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a registered course, within 1 month of the registration of
                    the course being cancelled under <ref>section 14</ref> of the Ordinance, such of
                    the fees and charges that have been collected in respect of any part of the
                    course falling to be conducted on or after the
                        date<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> on which the
                    cancellation comes into effect under <ref>section 16</ref> of the
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732201_013" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of an exempted course, within 1 month of the course being
                    removed from the register of exempted courses within the meaning of <ref>section
                        7(1)</ref> of the Ordinance upon its ceasing to be an exempted course within
                    the meaning of <ref>section 8</ref> of the Ordinance, such of the fees and
                    charges that have been collected in respect of any part of the course falling to
                    be conducted on or after the date of the course ceasing to be such an exempted
                    course;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732216_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>within 1 month of the premature cessation of any such course, such of the
                    fees and charges that have been collected in respect of any part of the course
                    falling to be conducted on or after the date of the cessation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732216_013" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any fees or charges collected in respect of any part of a registered
                course or an exempted course are not refunded in accordance with subsection (1), the
                operator of the course commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at
                level 4 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1604996547516_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 December
                1997.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403269524_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-09-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Premises in which registered course or exempted course is conducted</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412732247_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An operator of a registered course or an exempted course shall furnish to the
                Registrar, in such form as the Registrar may specify, such particulars as the
                Registrar may specify in respect of any premises in Hong Kong in which the course or
                any part thereof is to be conducted, not later than 3 months before the course or
                the part thereof, as the case may be, is to be so conducted, or such later date (if
                any) as the Registrar may allow.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732263_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438412732263_009" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>An operator of a registered course or an exempted course shall furnish to
                    the Registrar a certificate complying with the requirements of paragraph (b) in
                    respect of any premises (other than exempted premises) in Hong Kong in which the
                    course or any part thereof is to be conducted, not later than 1 month before the
                    course or the part thereof, as the case may be, is to be so conducted, or such
                    later date (if any) as the Registrar may allow.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732263_015" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>The certificate required to be furnished under paragraph (a) in respect of
                    any premises in which a registered course or an exempted course, or any part
                    thereof, is to be conducted—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732263_023" name="i" temporalId="s5_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>is a certificate issued by the Director of Fire Services pursuant to
                            <ref>regulation 2(c)</ref> of the Fire Services Department (Reports and
                        Certificates) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap95C">Cap. 95 sub. leg.
                        C</ref>); and
                                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/er1">E.R.
                                1
                                of
                                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732279_007" name="ii" temporalId="s5_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>shall certify that the use of the premises for the conduct of the
                        course or the part thereof, as the case may be, will not expose any person
                        in the premises to any undue risk of fire.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732279_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438412732279_017" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>A registered course or an exempted course, or any part thereof, shall not
                    be conducted in any premises (other than exempted premises) in Hong Kong,
                    without the approval of the Registrar granted under paragraph (c).</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732279_023" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>An operator of a registered course or an exempted course may at any time
                    not later than 3 months before the course or any part thereof is conducted in
                    any premises in Hong Kong, or such later date (if any) as the Registrar may
                    allow, apply to the Registrar, in such form as the Registrar may specify, for
                    the grant of an approval for the purposes of paragraph (a).</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732294_006" name="c" temporalId="s5_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>On
                    an application to the Registrar under paragraph (b) for an
                    approval in respect of any premises in which a registered course or an exempted
                    course, or
                    any
                    part of the course, is to be conducted, the Registrar may
                    grant the approval if
                    the
                    Registrar is satisfied, on the information provided for the
                    purposes of the application or on any other information available to
                    the
                    Registrar,
                        that—<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2023/25">25 of 2023 s.
                            118</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732294_014" name="i" temporalId="s5_3_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the operator has furnished to the Registrar particulars in respect of
                        the premises in accordance with subsection (1);</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732294_022" name="ii" temporalId="s5_3_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the operator has furnished to the Registrar a certificate in respect of
                        the premises in accordance with subsection <ref>(2)(a)</ref>;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732294_030" name="iii" temporalId="s5_3_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the conduct of the course or the part thereof, as the case may be, in
                        the premises will not expose any person in the premises to any undue risk of
                        fire; </content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732294_038" name="iv" temporalId="s5_3_c_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>the means of escape in case of fire available to persons in the
                        premises at any time when the course or the part thereof, as the case may
                        be, is to be conducted will be adequate;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732294_046" name="v" temporalId="s5_3_c_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the premises will be structurally suitable for the conduct of the
                        course or the part thereof, as the case may be;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="vi" temporalId="s5_3_c_vi" id="ID_1692062590566_001"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><leadIn>the conduct of the course or the part of the course, as the case
                        requires, will not result in a contravention of—</leadIn><subparagraph name="i" temporalId="s5_3_c_vi_i" id="ID_1692062590567_002"><num value="i">(A)</num><content>an approved plan or partly approved plan under the Town Planning
                            Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap131">Cap. 131</ref>) or a draft plan
                            prepared under that Ordinance; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph name="ii" temporalId="s5_3_c_vi_ii" id="ID_1692062590569_003"><num value="ii">(B)</num><content>any terms or conditions of the Government lease of the land in
                            which the premises are comprised; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                                    105</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2023/25">25 of 2023 s.
                                118</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732310_007" name="vii" temporalId="s5_3_c_vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content>the premises will not be unsuitable for any other reason for the
                        conduct of the course or the part thereof, as the case may be.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732310_013" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438412732310_017" name="a" temporalId="s5_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>An operator of a registered course or an exempted course who fails to
                    comply with subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a
                    fine at level 4.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732310_023" name="b" temporalId="s5_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Where a registered course or an exempted course, or any part thereof, is
                    conducted in any premises in contravention of subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref>, the
                    person by whom the course or the part thereof, as the case may be, is conducted
                    commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 4 and to
                    imprisonment for 6 months.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732325_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section, a reference to exempted premises is a
                reference to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412732325_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any premises specified in a certificate of registration within the meaning
                    of the Education Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap279">Cap. 279</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732325_021" name="b" temporalId="s5_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any premises specified in a certificate of provisional registration within
                    the meaning of that Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732325_029" name="c" temporalId="s5_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any premises owned or leased by a local institution of higher education for
                    educational purposes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732325_037" name="d" temporalId="s5_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any premises which are specified to the effect that they are designed and
                    constructed for educational purposes on a plan approved for the purposes of
                        <ref>section 14(1)</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412732325_045" name="e" temporalId="s5_5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><leadIn>any premises which are—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732325_053" name="i" temporalId="s5_5_e_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>comprised in premises for which a hotel licence as defined by section
                        2(1) of the Hotel and Guesthouse Accommodation Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap349">Cap. 349</ref>) is for the time being in force; and
                                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2020/6">6 of 2020 s.
                            51</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412732325_061" name="ii" temporalId="s5_5_e_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>specified as “function room” on a plan approved for the purposes of
                            <ref>section 14(1)</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>).</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403269539_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Receipts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412732388_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Upon the payment of any fees or charges, however described, in respect of a registered course or an exempted course, or any part thereof, being received from any person by or on behalf of the operator of the course, the operator shall cause the payment to be acknowledged within 30 days of the payment being so received, by the issue to the person of a receipt in writing setting out the date of the receipt and the amount and purpose of the payment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412732403_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An operator of a registered course or an exempted course who fails to comply with subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 3.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403269555_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Prescribed fees</heading><content>The fee specified in column 3 of the <ref>Schedule</ref> is prescribed in respect of the matter described opposite thereto in column 2 of the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403269570_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap493B/s7">s. 7</ref>]</note><heading>Prescribed
            Fees<marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="align_justified">
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="70%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td class="align_center">Column 1</td>
                    <td class="align_center">Column 2</td>
                    <td class="align_center">Column
                        3<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="align_left cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">Item</td>
                    <td class="align_center">Description</td>
                    <td class="align_center">Fee<br></br>$<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="align_left cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">1.</td>
                    <td>For the issue of a certified copy of an entry in the register under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 7(5)</ref> of the
                        Ordinance<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    <td class="align_center">140</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="align_left cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">2.</td>
                    <td>For tender as the prescribed fee accompanying a certificate referred to in
                            <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            8(1)(a)</ref> or (b)(ii) of the
                        Ordinance<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    <td class="align_center">115</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="align_left cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">3.</td>
                    <td>For an application for the registration of a purely distance learning course
                        or a regulated course under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 10(1)</ref> of
                        the
                        Ordinance<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    <td class="align_center">605</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="align_left cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">4.</td>
                    <td>For a registered course—</td>
                    <td class="align_center"></td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td class="align_center"></td>
                    <td class="left_indent_24">
                        
                        <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" id="ID_1578281514550_001" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in respect of each period of 12 months as referred to in
                                    <ref>section 18(1)(a)</ref> of the Ordinance</content></paragraph>
                    </td>
                    <td class="align_center">605</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td class="left_indent_24">
                        
                        <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" id="ID_1578281514550_002" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in respect of part of such a period as referred to in
                                    <ref>section 18(1)(b)</ref> of the Ordinance</content></paragraph>
                    </td>
                    <td class="align_center">605</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            
            
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>