<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 496</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>496</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap496!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-08-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403271676_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-08-11">
            <content>An
                Ordinance
                to
                enable effect to be given to the International Convention for the Regulation of
                Whaling signed at Washington on 2 December 1946; to prohibit the taking, towing or
                treating of whales within the waters of Hong Kong; to prohibit the taking, towing or
                treating of whales by any Hong Kong ship or Hong Kong aircraft outside the waters of
                Hong Kong without a licence or permit; to provide measures for the conservation and
                utilisation of whales elsewhere; and for purposes connected with such
                matters.</content>
            
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[20 December 1996]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><section id="ID_1438403271692_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Whaling Industry (Regulation) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403271708_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Aircraft"><term>aircraft</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">飛機</term>) includes any machine which can derive
            support in the atmosphere from the reactions of the air and is intended for aerial
            navigation;</def><def name="Commander"><term>commander</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機長</term>) in relation to an aircraft, means the member
            of the flight crew so designated by the operator thereof or, if no such person is
            designated, the person who is the pilot in command;</def><def name="HongKongAircraft"><term>Hong
                Kong
            aircraft</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">香港飛機</term>) means an aircraft registered in Hong
            Kong;</def><def name="HongKongShip"><term>Hong
                Kong
            ship</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">香港船舶</term>) means a ship registered in Hong
            Kong;</def><def name="Licence"><term>licence</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">牌照</term>) means a licence issued under <ref>section
                7(1)</ref>;</def><def name="LicensingAuthority"><term>licensing
                authority</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">發牌當局</term>) means the
            Secretary
            for Environment and Ecology;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N.
                    130 of
                2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Master"><term>master</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船長</term>) in relation to any ship, includes the person
            for the time being in command or charge of the ship and, in relation to a ship used for
            treating whales, includes the person for the time being in charge of the operations on
            board the ship in connection with such treatment;</def><def name="Ship"><term>ship</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船舶</term>) has the same meaning as in the Merchant
            Shipping (Registration) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap415">Cap. 415</ref>);</def><def name="Treating"><term>treating</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">加工處理</term>) a whale includes storage for the purpose
            of treatment;</def><def name="WhaleProducts"><term>whale
                products</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">鯨類產品</term>) includes any unprocessed part of a whale
            and blubber, meat, bones, whale oil, sperm oil, spermaceti, meal, baleen and other items
            derived from whales.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403271708_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Prohibition of catching or treating whales within the waters of Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738175_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The master of any ship which is used within the waters of Hong Kong for taking, towing or treating whales, commits an offence and is liable on conviction on indictment to a fine not exceeding $500,000.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738175_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The commander of an aircraft which is used over the waters of Hong Kong for taking or towing whales, commits an offence and is liable on conviction on indictment to a fine not exceeding $500,000.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403271739_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Protection for certain categories of whales</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738207_026" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If any person on board or belonging to a Hong Kong ship or Hong Kong aircraft,
                while outside the waters of Hong Kong, kills or takes—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738207_034" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a right whale or a grey whale;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738207_042" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an immature whale; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738207_050" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a female whale which is accompanied by a calf,</content></paragraph><continued>that person, and the master of the ship or the commander of the aircraft, as
                the case may be, and the owner and the charterer (if any) of the ship or aircraft,
                each commit an offence and are liable—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438412738222_012" name="i" temporalId="s4_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>on conviction on indictment to a fine not exceeding $500,000; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738222_020" name="ii" temporalId="s4_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to an additional fine not exceeding the value of any whale products
                    obtained or obtainable from the whale in question.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738222_027" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this section a whale of any description shall be deemed to
                be immature if it is less than such length as may be prescribed in relation to
                whales of that description.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738222_035" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The length prescribed for the purposes of this section in relation to blue
                whales shall not be less than 18.3 metres, and the length so prescribed in relation
                to fin whales shall not be less than 15.2 metres.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738222_043" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="BlueWhales"><term>blue whales</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">白長鬚鯨</term>) means whales known by any of the names set out in Part II of the
                    <ref>Schedule</ref>;</def><def name="Calf"><term>calf</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">幼鯨</term>) includes a
                suckling whale;</def><def name="FinWhales"><term>fin whales</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">長鬚鯨</term>)
                means whales known by any of the names set out in Part III of the
                    <ref>Schedule</ref>;</def><def name="GreyWhale"><term>grey whale</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">黑鯨</term>)
                means a whale known by any of the names set out in Part IV of the
                    <ref>Schedule</ref>; <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="RightWhale"><term>right whale</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">脊美鯨</term>)
                means a whale known by any of the names set out in Part I of the
                <ref>Schedule</ref>.  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738238_018" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The
                Secretary
                for Environment and Ecology may by notice published in the Gazette
                amend the <ref>Schedule</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403271754_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Description of whales to which <ref>sections 6 to 8</ref> apply</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738285_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In their application to a ship or aircraft registered in Hong Kong, or a
                factory situated in Hong Kong, <ref>sections 6 to 8</ref> shall have effect as if
                references to whales were references only to whales known as whalebone whales (or
                baleen whales), sperm whales, spermaceti whales, cachalots or pot whales, but the
                Secretary
                for Environment and Ecology may by order published in the Gazette
                direct that those references shall include any description of whale specified in the
                order, other than a description of whale referred to in <ref>section 4</ref>.<inline class="width_6"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of
                        1999 s. 7</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738300_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An order under subsection (1) may provide that in its application by virtue of
                the order, this Ordinance shall have effect with such exceptions, adaptations or
                modifications as may be specified in the order.</content><referenceNote class="align_right">[1934 c. 49 s. 1 U.K. as substituted by 1981 c. 29 s.
                35(2) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403271770_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Whaling ships, aircraft and factories to be licensed</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738316_026" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to <ref>section 9</ref> and without prejudice to <ref>section 4</ref>, it shall be an offence—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738316_034" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>outside the waters of Hong Kong for any Hong Kong ship or Hong Kong aircraft to be used to take, tow or treat whales; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738316_042" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for any factory situated in Hong Kong to be used for treating whales,</content></paragraph><continued>unless the owner or charterer of the ship or aircraft, or the occupier of the factory, as the case may be, is the holder of a licence granted under <ref>section 7(1)</ref> authorizing the ship, aircraft or factory to be used for such activity.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738331_011" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In the event of any contravention of this section—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738331_019" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in respect of a Hong Kong ship, the master, the owner and the charterer (if any);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738331_027" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in respect of a Hong Kong aircraft, the commander, the owner and the charterer (if any); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738331_035" name="c" temporalId="s6_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in respect of a factory, the manager and the occupier,</content></paragraph><continued>each commit an offence and are liable on conviction on indictment, for each whale taken, towed or treated in contravention of this section—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438412738331_049" name="i" temporalId="s6_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to a fine not exceeding $500,000; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738331_057" name="ii" temporalId="s6_2_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to an additional fine not exceeding the value of any whale products obtained or obtainable from the whale.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738331_064" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In the event of a conviction under this section the court may order the forfeiture of any whale carcass or whale products the subject of the contravention. Where the court makes an order of forfeiture, it may, if it thinks fit, give directions for the destruction or disposal of any such forfeited items by the Director of Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/ln331">L.N. 331 of 1999</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1934 c. 49 s. 4 U.K. as amended by 1981 c. 29 s. 35(3) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403271786_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Grant of licences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738363_071" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On application made in such manner as the licensing authority may determine by the owner or charterer of any Hong Kong ship, or by the owner or charterer of any Hong Kong aircraft, or by the occupier of any factory situated in Hong Kong, and on payment of the applicable fee, the authority may grant to the applicant a licence in such form and subject to such conditions as the licensing authority may determine authorizing that ship, aircraft or factory to be used for the purpose of taking, towing or treating whales, as the case may require.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738378_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A licence shall also contain such conditions as may be specified in regulations under <ref>section 13</ref>, and such regulations may specify different conditions for different classes of licence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738394_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A licence granted under this section shall, unless previously cancelled on the grounds of contravention of the conditions of the licence, continue in force for 1 year from the day specified therein as the day on which it takes effect, or for such shorter period beginning on that day as may be specified in the licence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738394_013" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The licensing authority shall refuse to grant a licence under this section if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738394_021" name="a" temporalId="s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the applicant has been convicted of an offence under this Ordinance; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738394_029" name="b" temporalId="s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the opinion of the licensing authority a refusal is necessary in order to meet the obligations of the International Convention for the Regulation of Whaling signed at Washington on 2 December 1946.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1934 c. 49 s. 5 U.K. &amp; 1938 c. 30 s. 44 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403271786_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Breach of conditions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738425_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If any condition attached to a licence under this Ordinance, except the condition referred to in subsection (2), is contravened, then in the case of a licence granted in respect of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738425_012" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a Hong Kong ship, the master, and the owner and the charterer (if any);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738425_020" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a Hong Kong aircraft, the commander, and the owner and the charterer (if any); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738425_028" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a factory, the manager and the occupier,</content></paragraph><continued>are each liable on conviction to a fine at level 5, and the court by whom the offender is convicted may, if it thinks fit, cancel any licence granted to the offender under this Ordinance, being a licence which is for the time being in force in respect of the ship, aircraft or factory, as the case may be.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738425_041" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who fails to keep any record in accordance with the conditions
                attached to a licence or knowingly makes, in any record which he is required by such
                conditions to keep, a statement false in any material particular, commits an offence
                and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 3.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1934 c. 49 s. 6 U.K. &amp; 1938 c. 30 s. 45 U.K.
                as amended by 1981 c. 29 s. 35(4) &amp; (5) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403271801_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Permits to take and treat whales for scientific purposes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738456_021" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Notwithstanding anything in this Ordinance, the relevant authority in the
                Central People’s Government may grant to any person a permit authorizing that person
                to kill, take and treat whales for the purposes of scientific research or for other
                exceptional purposes, subject to such restrictions as to the number, and subject to
                such other conditions, as the relevant authority in the Central People’s Government
                thinks fit, and the killing, taking or treating of whales in accordance with a
                permit in force under this section shall be exempt from the operation of the
                previous provisions of this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/65">65 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1934
                    c. 49 s. 7 U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738472_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="RelevantAuthorityInTheCentralPeoplesGovernment">In subsection (1),
                    <term>relevant
                    authority in the Central People’s
                Government</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">中央人民政府有關當局</term>) means the organ in the Central
                People’s Government from time to time responsible for whaling matters.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1999/65">65 of 1999
                        s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403271848_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Powers of whale fishery inspectors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738503_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of enforcing the provisions of this Ordinance a whale fishery inspector, on producing on demand evidence of the fact that he is such an inspector may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738503_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>board or enter any ship, aircraft or factory which he has reason to believe has been or is being used in contravention of this Ordinance, and inspect the ship, aircraft or factory and its plant and equipment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738503_020" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in respect of such a ship or aircraft require the master, the commander and the crew or any of them, and in respect of such a factory the occupier or manager and the employees therein or any of them, to produce all such licences, records and other documents as the inspector considers it necessary to inspect, and to answer all such inquiries as he considers it necessary to make; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738519_006" name="c" temporalId="s10_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>take copies of, or extracts from, any documents produced to him.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738519_013" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any whale fishery inspector specially authorized in writing in that behalf by the Director of Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation may go on board any Hong Kong ship or Hong Kong aircraft which is used for treating whales, and shall, during the period specified in his authority, be entitled to remain on board the ship or the aircraft, and to be present at all operations in connection with the treating of whales on board the ship or the aircraft, and to be provided with subsistence and accommodation on board the ship.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738519_021" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director of Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation shall, in respect of each day during which subsistence and accommodation on board a ship is provided in pursuance of subsection (2), pay to the master of the ship such sum as may be prescribed by regulations made by the licensing authority.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738534_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Every person who without reasonable excuse refuses to produce to a whale fishery inspector any document which he is required under this section to produce, without reasonable excuse refuses to answer, or answers falsely, any inquiry duly made of him by such an inspector, or otherwise wilfully obstructs, or without reasonable excuse refuses facilities to, such an inspector in the discharge of his functions under this section, commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738550_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="WhaleFisheryInspector">In this section
                    <term>whale
                    fishery
                inspector</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">鯨業監察員</term>) means any person appointed by the
                Director of Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation to be such an inspector.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/ln331">L.N. 331 of 1999</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1934 c. 49 s. 8 U.K. as amended by 1981 c. 29 s. 35(6) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403271864_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Improper use of documents</heading><leadIn>A person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738581_012" name="a" temporalId="s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>with intent to deceive, uses, or allows another person to use, a licence or permit granted under this Ordinance; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738581_020" name="b" temporalId="s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>makes or has in his possession any document so closely resembling a licence or permit authorized by this Ordinance as to be calculated to deceive,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 3.</continued><referenceNote>[cf. 1934 c. 49 s. 9 U.K. as amended by 1981 c. 29 s. 35(5) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403271879_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Defence available to certain owners, charterers and occupiers</heading><content>In any proceedings taken under this Ordinance against the master, owner or charterer of any ship, or against the commander, owner or charterer of any aircraft, or against the manager or occupier of any factory in respect of any act or omission on the part of another person, it shall be a defence for such person, as the case may be, to prove that the act or omission took place without his knowledge or connivance and was not facilitated by any negligence on his part.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403271895_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations for carrying out the purposes
            and provisions of this Ordinance including, without limiting the generality of the
            foregoing, regulations concerning—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/65">65 of
                    1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412738659_005" name="a" temporalId="s13_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>lengths of whales;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738659_013" name="b" temporalId="s13_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the manner in which lengths are to be measured;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738659_021" name="c" temporalId="s13_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the procedure for applying for a licence under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738659_029" name="d" temporalId="s13_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>fees in connection with an application for a licence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412738659_037" name="e" temporalId="s13_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the conditions to be attached to licences.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1934 c. 49 s. 18 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403271895_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Repeal and savings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412738690_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The provisions of the Whaling Industry (Regulation) Acts as applied in or
                extended to Hong Kong immediately before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance are repealed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738690_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The provisions of the Whaling Industry (Regulation) Act (Newfoundland,
                Colonies, Protectorates and Mandated Territories) Order 1936 (App. III, p. Z1) and
                the Whaling Industry (Regulation) Act (Newfoundland, Colonies, Protectorates and
                Mandated Territories) Order 1941 (App. III, p. AI1), in so far as they form part of
                the law of Hong Kong, are repealed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738690_020" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Sections 23 to 25</ref> of the Interpretation and General Clauses
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>) shall apply in relation to the repeal
                of a provision of an United Kingdom enactment effected by this section as they apply
                in relation to the repeal of a provision of an Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412738706_005" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="WhalingIndustryRegulationActs">In this section
                    <term>Whaling
                    Industry (Regulation)
                Acts</term>
                    (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">捕鯨業(規管)法令</term>》) means the Whaling Industry
                (Regulation) Acts 1934 and 1938 (1934 c. 49 U.K. &amp; 1938 c. 30 U.K.) and any
                subsidiary legislation made thereunder.</def></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1641973520509_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 20 December
                1996.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438403271910_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-11" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap496/s4">s. 4</ref>]</note><heading>Names of
            Whales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><part id="ID_1438412738721_032" name="PI" temporalId="sch0_PI"><num value="I">Part
                I</num><heading>Right
                Whales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading></part><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%">
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Arctic right
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">North Atlantic
                            right whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Atlantic right
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">North Cape
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Biscayan right
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Pacific right
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bowhead</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Pigmy right
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Greenland right
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Southern pigmy
                            right whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Greenland
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Southern right
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Nordkaper</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            
        </text><part id="ID_1438412738721_048" name="PII" temporalId="sch0_PII"><num value="II">Part
                II</num><heading>Blue
                Whales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading></part><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%">
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Blue whales</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Sulphur
                            bottom</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Sibbald’s
                            rorqual</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            
        </text><part id="ID_1438412738721_064" name="PIII" temporalId="sch0_PIII"><num value="III">Part
                III</num><heading>Fin
                Whales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading></part><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%">
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Common
                            finback</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Fin whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Common
                            finner</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Herring
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Common rorqual</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Razorback</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Finback</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">True fin
                            whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            
        </text><part id="ID_1438412738721_080" name="PIV" temporalId="sch0_PIV"><num value="IV">Part
                IV</num><heading>Grey
                Whales<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading></part><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%">
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">California
                            grey</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Grey whale</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Devil fish</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Hard head</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Grey back</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Mussel
                            digger</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Rip sack</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </text></schedule></main></ordinance>