<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 470</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>470</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap470!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-02-25</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403226093_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-02-25">
            <content>An Ordinance to provide for the design, construction, installation and
                maintenance in safe working order of builders’ lifts and tower working platforms,
                for the examination and testing of such lifts and platforms, and to provide for
                related matters.</content>
            <content>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[20 July 1995]
            <sourceNote><ref href="/hk/1995/ln313">L.N. 313 of
            1995</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of
                        2013</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><part id="ID_1438403226093_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403226109_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438412593142_004" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Builders’ Lifts and Tower
                    Working Platforms (Safety) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593142_012" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2013</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226124_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593158_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AppealBoard"><term>appeal board</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">上訴委員會</term>) means an appeal board appointed under <ref>section
                38</ref>;</def><def name="BuildersLift">
                <leadIn><term>builder’s lift</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築工地升降機</term>)
                    means a lifting machine—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593158_033" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that has a cage;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593158_041" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the operating controls for which are located inside the cage;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593158_049" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the cage of which is raised and lowered by means of a rack and pinion
                        suspension system or rope suspension system;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593158_057" name="d" temporalId="s2_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the direction of movement of which is restricted by a guide or
                        guides,</content></paragraph>
                <continued> and is used for construction work, and includes the supports, liftway
                    and enclosures and the whole of the mechanical and electrical apparatus required
                    in connection with the operation and safety of the builder’s lift;</continued>
            </def><def name="BuildersLiftWork"><term>builder’s lift work</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築工地升降機工程</term>) means any kind of work, not being
                construction work, connected with the installation, commissioning, testing,
                maintenance, repair, alteration or demolition of a builder’s lift or of any
                machinery or equipment provided in or connected with a builder’s lift, and includes
                the supervision and certification of that work and the certification of design of
                that installation;</def><def name="CompetentOperator"><term>competent operator</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合資格的操作員</term>), in relation to a builder’s lift or tower
                working platform, means a person who has undergone basic training on the general
                construction and operating principles of a builder’s lift or tower working
                platform;</def><def name="CompetentWorker">
                <leadIn><term>competent worker</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合資格人員</term>), in
                    relation to builder’s lift work or tower working platform work, means a
                    person—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593173_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>who—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593173_034" name="i" temporalId="s2_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>is the holder of a certificate in mechanical engineering, marine
                            engineering or building services engineering issued by a person approved
                            by the Director; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593173_042" name="ii" temporalId="s2_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>has not less than 3 years’ experience in builder’s lift work or
                            tower working platform work or other relevant practical experience as
                            approved by the Director; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593189_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>who has been in the employment, for an aggregate period of not less
                        than 4 years, of one or more registered contractors and is considered by the
                        registered contractor by whom he is currently employed to carry out
                        builder’s lift work or tower working platform work, as the case may be, to
                        have had sufficient experience or training in such work to be capable of
                        carrying it out competently without supervision;</content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="ConstructionSite"><term>construction site</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築工地</term>) means a place where construction work is undertaken;</def><def name="ConstructionWork"><term>construction work</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築工程</term>) has the same meaning as in the Factories and Industrial
                Undertakings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap59">Cap. 59</ref>);</def><def name="Director"><term>Director</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">署長</term>) means
                the Director of Electrical and Mechanical Services;</def><def name="DrivingMachineBrake"><term>driving machine brake</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">驅動機制動器</term>) means the electro-mechanical brake of the
                driving machine;</def><def name="FinalLimitSwitch"><term>final limit switch</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">最後限位掣</term>) means an emergency switch arranged to stop a
                builder’s lift or tower working platform automatically in the event of the lift cage
                or platform travelling a predetermined distance beyond a terminal landing or
                level;</def><def name="LiftCage"><term>lift cage</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">升降機吊籠</term>)
                means the cage of a builder’s lift;</def><def name="LiftWork"><term>lift work</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">升降機工程</term>)
                means builder’s lift work and tower working platform work;</def><def name="Liftway"><term>liftway</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">升降通道</term>) means
                the total space within which the lift cage or platform travels;</def><def name="OverspeedGovernor"><term>overspeed governor</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">限速器</term>) means a device which, when a builder’s lift or
                tower working platform attains a predetermined speed, causes it to stop and, if
                necessary, causes the safety gear to be applied;</def><def name="Owner">
                <leadIn><term>owner</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>) means the owner
                    of a builder’s lift or tower working platform or, where it is leased, means the
                    lessee of it, and includes—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593204_040" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any agent or person in charge or having the control or management of
                        it; and</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593204_048" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the contractor who is responsible for the construction site at which it
                        is being used;</content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="Platform"><term>platform</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">平台</term>) means
                the platform of a tower working platform;</def><def name="RackAndPinionSuspensionSystem"><term>rack and pinion suspension system</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">齒輪齒條式懸掛系統</term>) means a suspension system which
                uses a toothed rack and pinion to suspend the lift cage or the platform on the
                mast;</def><def name="RatedLoad"><term>rated load</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">額定負載</term>)
                means the maximum load that a builder’s lift or tower working platform has been
                designed to carry in service;</def><def name="RatedSpeed"><term>rated speed</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">額定速度</term>) means the normal speed at which a lift cage or platform has been
                designed to be operated;</def><def name="RegisteredContractor"><term>registered contractor</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">註冊承建商</term>), in relation to lift work, means a person
                whose name is for the time being on the register of contractors kept under this
                Ordinance;</def><def name="RegisteredExaminer"><term>registered examiner</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">註冊檢驗員</term>), in relation to lift work, means a person
                whose name is for the time being on the register of examiners kept under this
                Ordinance;</def><def name="SafetyGear"><term>safety gear</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">安全鉗</term>)
                means a mechanical device for stopping, and maintaining stationary on the guide or
                guides, the lift cage or the platform in cases where it exceeds the rated speed in
                the downward direction;</def><def name="Secretary"><term>Secretary</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">局長</term>)
                means the Secretary for Development;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of
                        2002</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2007</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TowerWorkingPlatform">
                <leadIn><term>tower working platform</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">塔式工作平台</term>) means a fixed or mobile tower that contains a lifting
                    machine—<marker role="section-break"></marker></leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593220_033" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that has a platform, the dimensions and design of which permit the
                        conveyance of persons;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593220_041" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the operating controls of which lifting machine are located on the
                        platform; and</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412593220_049" name="c" temporalId="s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the direction of movement of which is restricted by a guide or
                        guides,</content></paragraph>
                <continued> and is used for construction work, and includes the supports, liftway
                    and enclosures, the platform and the whole of the mechanical and electrical
                    apparatus required in connection with the operation and safety of the tower
                    working platform;</continued>
            </def><def name="TowerWorkingPlatformWork"><term>tower working platform work</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">塔式工作平台工程</term>) means any kind of work, not being
                construction work, connected with the installation, commissioning, testing,
                maintenance, repair, alteration or demolition of a tower working platform or of any
                machinery or equipment provided in or connected with a tower working platform, and
                includes the supervision and certification of that work and the certification of the
                design of that installation.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593236_004" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="BuildersLift">For the avoidance of doubt,
                    <term>builder’s
                    lift</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築工地升降機</term>) does not include a lift to which
                the Lifts and Escalators Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap618">Cap. 618</ref>)
                    applies.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/8">8 of 2012 ss. 156</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/8">160</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226140_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Registered
            Examiners</heading><section id="ID_1438403226140_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Register of examiners</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593314_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director shall keep a register (hereinafter referred to as
                    <term>the
                    register of examiners</term>) of persons who are, in his opinion, qualified to
                carry out the duties and exercise the functions required by this Ordinance to be
                carried out and exercised by a registered examiner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593314_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (3), no person shall be registered as an examiner unless he—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593314_020" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is a registered professional engineer registered under the Engineers Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap409">Cap. 409</ref>) within the discipline of mechanical, building services or marine engineering; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593314_028" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has at least 1 year’s experience in connection with the installation, testing and examination of builders’ lifts and tower working platforms.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593314_035" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director may include in the register of examiners an individual who does not meet the requirements referred to in subsection (2) if he is satisfied that the individual, by reason of other qualifications and experience, is qualified to carry out the duties and exercise the functions required to be carried out and exercised by a registered examiner under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593329_005" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The register of examiners shall be kept in such form and shall contain such particulars as the Director thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593329_013" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A certified copy of an entry in the register of examiners, or a certificate to the effect that a named person is not included in the register, issued under the signature of the Director shall, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, be accepted as proof in any proceedings of the facts stated in the certificate.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226155_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Procedure on application for registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593360_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every application for inclusion in the register of examiners shall be made to the Director in the form specified by him and shall be accompanied by the prescribed fee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593360_019" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where, upon application, the Director is of the opinion that the applicant is qualified in accordance with <ref>section 3</ref>, he shall, within 3 months of his receipt of the application, include the name of the applicant in the register of examiners, and shall issue to him a certificate of registration in the specified form.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593376_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where, upon application, the Director is of the opinion that the applicant is not qualified in accordance with <ref>section 3</ref>, he shall refuse the application and shall, within 3<inline class="width_3"> </inline>months of his receipt of the application, notify the applicant in writing of his refusal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593376_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person whose application for inclusion in the register of examiners is refused may, within 1 month of the date of notification to him of the refusal, appeal to an appeal board by submitting the appeal to the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593376_021" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Registration under this section shall be effective for a period of 3 years and, where a person wishes to continue to be registered, he shall, at least 3 months before his registration would otherwise cease, apply for re-registration in the form specified by the Director and pay the prescribed fee.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226171_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Removal from register</heading><leadIn>The Director may remove from the register of examiners the name of any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593470_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>dies; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593470_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>ceases, for any reason, to be an examiner.</content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226171_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Registered
            Contractors</heading><section id="ID_1438403226187_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Register of contractors</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593501_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director shall keep a register (hereinafter referred to as
                    <term>the
                    register of contractors</term>) of persons who are, in his opinion, qualified to
                carry out lift work.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593501_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The register of contractors shall be kept in such form and shall contain such particulars as the Director thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593501_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A certified copy of an entry in the register of contractors, or a certificate to the effect that a named person is not included in the register, issued under the signature of the Director shall, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, be accepted as proof in any proceedings of the facts stated in the certificate.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226187_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Procedure on application for registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593516_034" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every application for inclusion in the register of contractors shall be made to the Director in the form specified by him and shall be accompanied by the prescribed fee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593516_042" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Director shall not include a person in the register of contractors unless he is satisfied that, in the case of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593532_005" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an individual, he is a competent worker or else employs at least one competent worker;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593532_013" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a company, it employs at least one competent worker;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593532_021" name="c" temporalId="s7_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a partnership, at least one partner is a competent worker or the partnership employs at least one competent worker.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593532_028" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In considering an application under subsection (1), the Director may require the applicant to submit such further particulars as the Director may require and shall have regard to the qualifications and experience of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593532_036" name="a" temporalId="s7_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the applicant, if an individual who, or partnership which, does not employ a competent worker; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593532_044" name="b" temporalId="s7_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>competent workers employed by the applicant to supervise and carry out the lift work.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593532_051" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The Director shall, within 3 months of his receipt of an application under subsection (1) or such further particulars as he may require under subsection (3)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593532_059" name="a" temporalId="s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where he is of the opinion that the applicant, if applicable, and any persons employed by the applicant are qualified and experienced in accordance with subsection (2), include the name of the applicant in the register of contractors and shall issue to the applicant a certificate in the specified form; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593548_006" name="b" temporalId="s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where he is of the opinion that the applicant, if applicable, and any persons employed by the applicant are not qualified and experienced in accordance with subsection (2), refuse the application and notify the applicant in writing of his refusal.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593548_013" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person whose application for inclusion in the register of contractors is refused may, within 1 month of the date of notification to him of the refusal, appeal to an appeal board by submitting the appeal to the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593548_021" name="6" temporalId="s7_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Registration under this section shall be effective for a period of 3 years and, where a person wishes to continue to be registered, he shall, at least 3 months before the registration would otherwise cease, apply for re-registration in the form specified by the Director and pay the prescribed fee.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226202_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Removal from register</heading><leadIn>The Director may remove from the register of contractors the name of any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593579_057" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>dies;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593579_065" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>ceases, for any reason, to be a contractor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593594_006" name="c" temporalId="s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>ceases to be qualified for inclusion under <ref>section 7</ref> in such register; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593594_014" name="d" temporalId="s8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>ceases to employ at least one competent worker, unless the registered contractor is an individual who is a competent worker or a partnership one of the partners of whom is a competent worker.</content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226218_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Safety
            and
            Design
            Requirements</heading><section id="ID_1438403226218_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Duties of registered contractor and registered examiner</heading><leadIn>A registered contractor and a registered examiner in carrying out his
            responsibilities under this Ordinance shall ensure that the following requirements are
            complied with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593626_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>that a builder’s lift or tower working platform—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593626_020" name="i" temporalId="s9_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>is of good design and construction;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593626_028" name="ii" temporalId="s9_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>has adequate mechanical strength for the purpose for which it is intended
                    to be used;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593626_036" name="iii" temporalId="s9_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>is properly installed, adequately supported and securely
                    anchored;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593626_043" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>that a builder’s lift has a gate of robust construction—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593626_051" name="i" temporalId="s9_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>for the lift cage; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593626_059" name="ii" temporalId="s9_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>at every point at which there is access to the liftway,</content></subparagraph><continued>and that all gates are kept in good working condition and a proper state of
                repair;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593626_072" name="c" temporalId="s9_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that a builder’s lift has both electrically and mechanically operated locking
                devices on all gates referred to in paragraph (b) and that all such locking devices
                are kept in good working condition and a proper state of repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593641_005" name="d" temporalId="s9_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that a platform has a fence around its perimeter of robust construction with a
                minimum height of 1 metre, and that the fence is kept in a proper state of
                repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593641_013" name="e" temporalId="s9_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><leadIn>that the lift cage or platform, as the case may be, has an overload sensing
                device which, when activated—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593641_021" name="i" temporalId="s9_e_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>renders the builder’s lift or tower working platform inoperative;
                    and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593641_029" name="ii" temporalId="s9_e_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>sounds an audible alarm,</content></subparagraph><continued>and that the overload sensing device is kept in good working condition and a
                proper state of repair;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593641_042" name="f" temporalId="s9_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>that the lift cage is of robust design and capable of safeguarding passengers
                against shearing and crushing by objects outside the lift cage, and that the lift
                cage is kept in a proper state of repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593641_050" name="g" temporalId="s9_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>that the suspension device of a builder’s lift or tower working platform,
                including the rack and pinion suspension system or rope suspension system and, where
                applicable, the suspension system for the counterweight, is kept in good working
                condition and a proper state of repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593657_006" name="h" temporalId="s9_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><leadIn>that the driving machine of a builder’s lift or tower working platform is
                equipped with an effective driving machine brake that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593657_014" name="i" temporalId="s9_h_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>operates immediately to arrest the lift cage or platform, as the case may
                    be, when the electrical circuit of any safety device is interrupted;
                    and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593657_022" name="ii" temporalId="s9_h_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>is capable of bringing the lift cage or platform, as the case may be, to
                    rest under maximum load and at maximum speed and maintaining it in a stationary
                    position,</content></subparagraph><continued>and that the driving machine brake is kept in good working order and a proper
                state of repair;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593657_035" name="i" temporalId="s9_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>subject to paragraph (j), that a builder’s lift or tower working platform is
                equipped with effective safety gear and an effective overspeed governor, and that
                the safety gear and overspeed governor are kept in good working condition and a
                proper state of repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593657_043" name="j" temporalId="s9_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>where a tower working platform is not equipped with safety gear and an
                overspeed governor as required by paragraph (i), that it is equipped with an
                additional braking system which is capable of regulating its downward speed, and
                that the additional braking system is kept in good working condition and a proper
                state of repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593672_006" name="k" temporalId="s9_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>that all safety switches used on a builder’s lift or tower working platform are
                of a positive mechanically operated type and are kept in good working order and a
                proper state of repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593672_014" name="l" temporalId="s9_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>that the travel of a lift cage or platform and, where applicable, the
                counterweight, shall be limited at the bottom by an effective buffer
                system;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593672_022" name="m" temporalId="s9_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>that effective guards are provided for all moving parts of a builder’s lift or
                tower working platform to prevent accidental human contact;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593672_030" name="n" temporalId="s9_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content>that all electrical components of a builder’s lift or tower working platform
                are kept in a proper state of repair and are examined in accordance with the
                requirements of any laws relating to such components;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593688_006" name="o" temporalId="s9_o"><num value="o">(o)</num><leadIn>that a builder’s lift or tower working platform is equipped with an audible
                emergency alarm that is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593688_014" name="i" temporalId="s9_o_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>activated from inside the lift cage or on the platform, as the case may be;
                    and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593688_022" name="ii" temporalId="s9_o_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>sufficiently loud to attract assistance from other persons on the
                    construction site on which it is situated,</content></subparagraph><continued>and that the alarm is kept in good working condition and a proper state of
                repair;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593688_035" name="p" temporalId="s9_p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content>that all structural and mechanical components of a builder’s lift or tower
                working platform are kept in a proper state of repair.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403226233_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Duties of owner</heading><leadIn>The owner of a builder’s lift or tower working platform shall ensure that the
            following requirements are complied with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593735_034" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the builder’s lift or tower working platform is properly maintained,
                adequately supported and securely anchored;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593735_042" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>that a notice in both English and Chinese with letters and characters not less
                than 30 millimetres in height is prominently displayed in the lift cage or on the
                platform stating—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593750_006" name="i" temporalId="s10_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the maximum number of persons; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593750_014" name="ii" temporalId="s10_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the maximum weight,</content></subparagraph><continued>permitted to be carried, and that the notice is kept legible at all
                times;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593750_027" name="c" temporalId="s10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that the lift cage and every landing is sufficiently well lit, whether by
                natural light or artificial light, to permit its safe use when the builder’s lift is
                in operation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593750_035" name="d" temporalId="s10_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that the platform is sufficiently well lit, whether by natural light or
                artificial light, to permit its safe use when the tower working platform is in
                operation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593750_043" name="e" temporalId="s10_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>that any part of the liftway that is accessible to persons is properly enclosed
                so as to prevent a person from being struck by the lift cage or platform;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593750_051" name="f" temporalId="s10_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><leadIn>that a builder’s lift has a gate of robust construction—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593750_059" name="i" temporalId="s10_f_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>for the lift cage; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593750_067" name="ii" temporalId="s10_f_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>at every point at which there is access to the liftway,</content></subparagraph><continued>and that all gates are kept in good working condition and a proper state of
                repair;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593766_005" name="g" temporalId="s10_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>that a platform has a fence around its perimeter of robust construction with a
                minimum height of 1 metre, and that the fence is kept in a proper state of
                repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593766_013" name="h" temporalId="s10_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>that the lift cage is of robust design and capable of safeguarding passengers
                against shearing and crushing by objects outside the lift cage, and that the lift
                cage is kept in a proper state of repair;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593766_021" name="i" temporalId="s10_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>that effective guards are provided for all moving parts of a builder’s lift or
                tower working platform to prevent accidental human contact;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593766_029" name="j" temporalId="s10_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><leadIn>that a builder’s lift or tower working platform is equipped with an audible
                emergency alarm that is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593766_037" name="i" temporalId="s10_j_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>activated from inside the lift cage or on the platform, as the case may be;
                    and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593766_045" name="ii" temporalId="s10_j_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>sufficiently loud to attract assistance from other persons on the
                    construction site,</content></subparagraph><continued>and that the alarm is kept in good working condition and a proper state of
                repair.</continued></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226249_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Codes
            of
            Practice</heading><section id="ID_1438403226265_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Codes of practice</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593813_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may establish codes of practice for lift work.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593813_019" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Director establishes a code of practice or amends a code of practice already established, he shall publish a notice in the Gazette identifying the code that is established or amended, specifying the date on which it is to take effect and advising the place at which a copy of the code or amendment may be examined.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226265_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Lift work to be carried out to satisfaction of Director</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593844_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All lift work shall be carried out to the satisfaction of the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593844_012" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a registered examiner or registered contractor carries out lift work in accordance with the relevant portions of codes of practice established under this Part, he shall be deemed to have carried them out to the satisfaction of the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593844_020" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a person referred to in subsection (2) carries out lift work that is not in accordance with the relevant portions of codes of practice, he shall, before carrying it out, submit details of the proposed lift work to the Director and obtain the approval in writing of the Director that the proposed work, if carried out, will be to his satisfaction.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226280_001" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            VI</num><heading>Lift
            Work</heading><section id="ID_1438403226280_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Duty of owner</heading><content>The owner of a builder’s lift or tower working platform shall, at all times, retain the services of a registered contractor and shall ensure that no lift work is carried out except by or under the supervision of such registered contractor or a registered examiner employed by such registered contractor.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403226296_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Prohibition of carrying out lift work by unauthorized person</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593891_018" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (2), no person shall carry out lift work other
                than—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593891_026" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a registered examiner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593891_034" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>an individual who is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593891_042" name="i" temporalId="s14_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a registered contractor; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593891_050" name="ii" temporalId="s14_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a member of a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>partnership that is a
                        registered contractor,</content></subparagraph><continued>and is a competent worker;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593906_012" name="c" temporalId="s14_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a competent worker employed by a registered contractor; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593906_020" name="d" temporalId="s14_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a worker directly supervised, at the site where the lift work is being
                    carried out, by a person referred to in paragraph (a), (b) or (c).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593906_027" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director may in any particular case permit in writing a person other than a person referred to in subsection (1) to carry out lift work, subject to such conditions as the Director may impose.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226296_004" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Approval of Director before first installation</heading><leadIn>Before a builder’s lift or tower working platform is installed for the first time in Hong Kong, the registered contractor responsible for the installation shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593922_073" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>submit the following to the Director—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593922_081" name="i" temporalId="s15_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>basic design details and technical data as specified by the Director;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593938_007" name="ii" temporalId="s15_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a copy of the maintenance manual;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412593938_015" name="iii" temporalId="s15_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>test certificates in respect of the driving machine brake, overspeed governor, safety gear and rack and pinion suspension system issued by an institution which is acceptable to the Director; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593938_022" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>obtain the written approval of the Director.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403226311_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Notification of Director of installation</heading><content>Before installing a builder’s lift or tower working platform at any construction site, a registered contractor shall notify the Director of the location at which it will be installed.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403226327_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Director to be notified of major alterations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412593969_032" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Before carrying out lift work that involves a major alteration of a builder’s lift or tower working platform, a registered contractor shall notify the Director of his intention to do so in writing and in a form and with the information specified by the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412593984_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="MajorAlteration"><leadIn>For the purposes of this Part,
                        <term>major
                        alteration</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主要更改</term>) means any of the
                    following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412593984_013" name="a" temporalId="s17_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>modification resulting in any increase or decrease in the rated load or rated speed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593984_021" name="b" temporalId="s17_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>modification resulting in any increase or decrease in the dead weight of the lift cage or platform, as the case may be;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593984_029" name="c" temporalId="s17_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>modification resulting in any change in the system of operation or control;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593984_037" name="d" temporalId="s17_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>modification resulting in any change in the suspension system including the rack and pinion suspension system or rope suspension system;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593984_045" name="e" temporalId="s17_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>modification resulting in any change in the size or type of the guide or guides;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593984_053" name="f" temporalId="s17_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>modification resulting in any change in the type of electro-mechanical interlocking devices;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412593984_061" name="g" temporalId="s17_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>modification resulting in any change in the operating method of the cage door or the landing doors of a builder’s lift;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594000_006" name="h" temporalId="s17_2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the replacement of, or any change in type, model, make or design of, the safety gear;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594000_014" name="i" temporalId="s17_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the replacement of, or any change in type, model, make or design of, the overspeed governor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594000_022" name="j" temporalId="s17_2_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>the replacement of the driving machine;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594000_030" name="k" temporalId="s17_2_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>the replacement of the controller;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594000_038" name="l" temporalId="s17_2_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>the replacement of the driving machine brake;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594000_046" name="m" temporalId="s17_2_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>the replacement of the rack or the driving pinion of the rack and pinion suspension system.</content></paragraph></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226327_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Test and examination by registered examiner after installation or major alteration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594031_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a registered contractor—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594031_012" name="a" temporalId="s18_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>installs a builder’s lift or tower working platform at a construction site;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594031_020" name="b" temporalId="s18_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>dismantles and re-erects a builder’s lift or tower working platform at a different location on the same construction site; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594031_028" name="c" temporalId="s18_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>carries out lift work that involves a major alteration,</content></paragraph><continued>he shall, before allowing it to be used, employ a registered examiner to carry out a test and examination of it.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594031_041" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="TestAndExamination"><leadIn>In this section and <ref>section 19</ref>,
                        <term>test
                        and
                    examination</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">測試及檢驗</term>) means carrying out the following
                    safety checks—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594031_049" name="a" temporalId="s18_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>examination of all machinery and equipment to ensure it is in good working condition;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594031_057" name="b" temporalId="s18_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>functional tests at rated speed and at rated load;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594031_065" name="c" temporalId="s18_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>testing of driving machine brake, and additional braking system, if any, at 125% of rated load and at rated speed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594031_073" name="d" temporalId="s18_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>testing of overload sensing device at not more than 110% of rated load;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594047_006" name="e" temporalId="s18_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>testing of safety gear at rated load and at tripping speed of the overspeed governor.</content></paragraph></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226343_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Report and certificate of registered examiner after installation or major alteration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594062_035" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a registered examiner, after carrying out the test and examination, is satisfied that a builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, complies with the relevant requirements set out in <ref>section 9</ref> and is in safe working order, he shall forthwith deliver to the registered contractor, in the form and containing the information specified by the Director—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594062_043" name="a" temporalId="s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a report on the test and examination; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594078_006" name="b" temporalId="s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a certificate of test and examination in duplicate.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594078_013" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The registered contractor shall forthwith countersign the certificate and deliver it and the report to the owner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594078_021" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The owner shall deliver the report and certificate to the Director together with the prescribed fee, and the Director shall, if he is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594078_029" name="a" temporalId="s19_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>satisfied with the report and certificate, endorse the original of the certificate and return it to the owner; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594078_037" name="b" temporalId="s19_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not satisfied with the report and certificate, notify the owner in writing that the use of the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is prohibited, and the Director shall give his reasons for prohibiting its use.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594078_044" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the registered examiner is not satisfied that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, complies with the relevant requirements set out in <ref>section 9</ref> or is not in safe working order, he shall immediately report that fact to the Director and the registered contractor, and the registered contractor shall take the necessary steps to correct the problem.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594094_005" name="5" temporalId="s19_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>When the registered contractor has taken the necessary steps to correct the problem, the registered examiner shall carry out a further test and examination under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594094_013" name="6" temporalId="s19_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The owner shall ensure that a builder’s lift or tower working platform to which this section applies is not used until he receives the endorsed original of the certificate from the Director under subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226358_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Report of registered examiner after alteration of height of travel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594125_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a registered contractor carries out lift work that alters the height of travel of a lift cage or platform, he shall, before allowing it to be used, employ a registered examiner to carry out a test and examination of the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594125_012" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="TestAndExamination"><leadIn>In this section,
                        <term>test
                        and
                    examination</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">測試及檢驗</term>) means carrying out the following
                    safety checks—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594125_020" name="a" temporalId="s20_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>examination of all machinery and equipment to ensure it is in good working condition;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594125_028" name="b" temporalId="s20_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>checking the condition of the mast extension and its anchorage to adjacent structure;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594125_036" name="c" temporalId="s20_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>checking the condition of the suspension system including the rack and pinion suspension system or rope suspension system;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594140_006" name="d" temporalId="s20_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>checking the operation of the safety gear;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594140_014" name="e" temporalId="s20_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>checking the operation of other safety devices including final limit switches and the electro-mechanical interlocking devices;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594140_022" name="f" temporalId="s20_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>testing the running of the lift cage or platform, as the case may be, over the full range of normal operating travel.</content></paragraph></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594140_029" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the registered examiner, after carrying out the test and examination, is satisfied that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, complies with the relevant requirements set out in <ref>section 9</ref> and is in safe working order, he shall forthwith deliver to the registered contractor a report on the test and examination in the form and containing the information specified by the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594156_004" name="4" temporalId="s20_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The registered contractor shall attach the report to the log book required to be kept under <ref>section 21</ref> and shall make the report available to the Director on request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594156_012" name="5" temporalId="s20_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where the registered examiner is not satisfied that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, complies with the relevant requirements set out in <ref>section 9</ref> or is not in safe working order, he shall immediately report that fact to the Director and the registered contractor, and the registered contractor shall take the necessary steps to correct the problem.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594156_020" name="6" temporalId="s20_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>When the registered contractor has taken the necessary steps to correct the problem, the registered examiner shall carry out a further test and examination under this section and, if satisfied, shall advise the Director of that fact.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594156_028" name="7" temporalId="s20_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The owner shall ensure that a builder’s lift or tower working platform to which this section applies is not used until he is advised by the registered contractor that the report has been received from the registered examiner.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226358_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Routine maintenance by registered contractor</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594203_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered contractor shall, at intervals not exceeding 7 days, inspect, clean, oil and adjust all machinery and equipment to ensure that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is in safe working order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594203_012" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A registered contractor shall maintain a log book, in the form and containing information specified by the Director, either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594203_020" name="a" temporalId="s21_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the construction site where the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is located; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594203_028" name="b" temporalId="s21_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at his principal office if the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is not located at a construction site.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594203_035" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A registered contractor shall, at all reasonable times, make the log book available for inspection by the Director.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226374_002" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Periodic test and examination of safety equipment by registered examiner</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594234_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered contractor whose services have been retained by the owner of a builder’s lift or tower working platform under <ref>section 13</ref> shall employ a registered examiner to carry out a test and examination of such builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, at intervals not exceeding 6 months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594234_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="TestAndExamination"><leadIn>In this section,
                        <term>test
                        and
                    examination</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">測試及檢驗</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594234_020" name="a" temporalId="s22_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>examination of all machinery and equipment to ensure it is in good working condition;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594234_028" name="b" temporalId="s22_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>functional tests at rated speed and at rated load;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594234_036" name="c" temporalId="s22_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>testing of driving machine brake, and additional braking system, if any, at 125% of rated load and at rated speed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594250_006" name="d" temporalId="s22_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>testing of overload sensing device at not more than 110% of rated load;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594250_014" name="e" temporalId="s22_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>testing of safety gear at rated load and at tripping speed of the overspeed governor.</content></paragraph></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594250_021" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the registered examiner, after carrying out the test and examination, is satisfied that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, complies with the relevant requirements set out in <ref>section 9</ref> and is in safe working order, he shall forthwith deliver to the registered contractor, in the form and containing the information specified by the Director, a certificate of test and examination in duplicate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594250_029" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The registered contractor shall forthwith countersign the certificate and deliver it to the owner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594250_037" name="5" temporalId="s22_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>The owner shall, within 7 days of receiving the certificate, deliver it to the Director together with the prescribed fee, and the Director shall, if he is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594265_005" name="a" temporalId="s22_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>satisfied with the certificate, endorse the original and return it to the owner; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594265_013" name="b" temporalId="s22_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not satisfied with the certificate, notify the owner in writing that the use of the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is prohibited, and the Director shall give his reasons for prohibiting its use.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594265_020" name="6" temporalId="s22_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where the registered examiner is not satisfied that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, complies with the relevant requirements set out in <ref>section 9</ref> or is not in safe working order, he shall immediately report that fact to the Director and the registered contractor, and the registered contractor shall take the necessary steps to correct the problem.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594265_028" name="7" temporalId="s22_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>When the registered contractor has taken the necessary steps to correct the problem, the registered examiner shall carry out a further test and examination under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594281_005" name="8" temporalId="s22_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Where the registered contractor is advised under subsection (6) that the builder’s lift or tower working platform has not passed the test and examination, he shall immediately ensure that it is not used until such time as he receives a certificate from the registered examiner stating that it has passed such test and examination.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594281_013" name="9" temporalId="s22_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Where the owner receives a notice from the Director under subsection <ref>(5)(b)</ref>, he shall ensure that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is not used until such time as he is notified in writing by the Director that its use is no longer prohibited.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594281_021" name="10" temporalId="s22_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>For the purpose of determining the
                6-month
                period under subsection (1), the fact that a test and examination has been carried
                out under <ref>section 18</ref> shall be taken into consideration.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226389_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Failure to notify Director of periodic test and examination</heading><content>Where, within 4 weeks after the expiration of any period in which a test and examination is required under <ref>section 22</ref>, the Director has not received a certificate required to be delivered to him under that section, he may order the owner to arrange for such a test and examination to be carried out and to deliver the certificate to the Director within 21 days of receiving the order.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226405_001" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part
            VII</num><heading>Additional Powers
            and
            Duties</heading><section id="ID_1438403226405_003" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Director may prohibit use of builder’s lift or tower working platform</heading><leadIn>In addition to such other powers as are provided by this Ordinance, the Director may, by order in writing, prohibit an owner from using a builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, in any of the following circumstances—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594359_019" name="a" temporalId="s24_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>after inspection of the log book, the Director believes that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, has not been properly maintained in accordance with <ref>section 21</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594359_027" name="b" temporalId="s24_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Director has not received a certificate within the
                21-day
                period referred to in <ref>section 23</ref>;
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594359_035" name="c" temporalId="s24_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Director is not satisfied with a report or certificate submitted to him;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594359_043" name="d" temporalId="s24_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a registered examiner, after performing a test and examination, notifies the Director that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is not in safe working order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594374_006" name="e" temporalId="s24_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>after carrying out an inspection, the Director believes that the builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is not in safe working order.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403226421_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Additional powers of Director</heading><leadIn>The Director may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594390_027" name="a" temporalId="s25_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enter a construction site and inspect and carry out such tests as he considers necessary in respect of a builder’s lift or tower working platform;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594390_035" name="b" temporalId="s25_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>order an owner of a builder’s lift or tower working platform, in respect of which he has issued an order prohibiting its use, to disconnect the electricity supply to it;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594390_043" name="c" temporalId="s25_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>require an owner to submit a report, which has been prepared by a registered examiner and is in the form and contains the information specified by the Director, in respect of any accident involving a builder’s lift or tower working platform;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594406_006" name="d" temporalId="s25_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>enter premises adjacent to a construction site where such entry is necessary in investigating an accident involving a builder’s lift or tower working platform that occurred on the construction site;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594406_014" name="e" temporalId="s25_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>impound any part of a builder’s lift or tower working platform that has been involved in an accident where the Director believes the impounding is necessary for determining the cause of such accident;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594406_022" name="f" temporalId="s25_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><leadIn>order a registered contractor or registered examiner, as the case may be, to stop carrying out lift work where, in the Director’s opinion, such work is being carried out—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594406_030" name="i" temporalId="s25_f_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in contravention of a provision of this Ordinance; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594406_038" name="ii" temporalId="s25_f_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in a manner that is likely to cause injury to a person or damage to property.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403226436_001" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Additional duties of owner</heading><leadIn>In addition to such other duties as are imposed on him by this Ordinance, an owner shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594437_012" name="a" temporalId="s26_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>ensure that a builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is at all times operated by a competent operator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594437_020" name="b" temporalId="s26_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>prominently display the most recent certificate of test and examination inside the lift cage or on the platform;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594437_028" name="c" temporalId="s26_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>immediately notify in writing the Director and the registered contractor whose services have been retained under <ref>section 13</ref> where—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594437_036" name="i" temporalId="s26_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any accident occurs, whether or not there is personal injury or property damage associated with it; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594437_044" name="ii" temporalId="s26_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><leadIn>there is a failure of any of the following—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594437_051" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s26_c_ii_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>the driving machine brake;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594437_059" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s26_c_ii_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>the overspeed governor;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594437_067" name="C" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s26_c_ii_C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content>the safety gear;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594437_075" name="D" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s26_c_ii_D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content>the overload sensing device;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594437_083" name="E" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s26_c_ii_E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content>the suspension system including the rack and pinion suspension system or rope suspension system;</content></subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594452_007" name="d" temporalId="s26_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>ensure that a builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, is not used where he is advised by a registered contractor or registered examiner that it is not in safe working order.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403226436_003" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Additional duties of registered contractor</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594468_073" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In addition to such other duties as are imposed on him by this Ordinance, a registered contractor shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594484_005" name="a" temporalId="s27_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>ensure that no lift work for which he is responsible is carried out by a person contrary to the requirements of <ref>section 14</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594484_013" name="b" temporalId="s27_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immediately notify the owner and the Director if he finds that a builder’s lift or tower working platform, as the case may be, does not comply with any of the relevant requirements set out in <ref>section 9</ref> or is otherwise not in safe working order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594484_021" name="c" temporalId="s27_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>when notified by an owner of an accident or failure under <ref>section 26(c)</ref>, submit, within 7 days of being so notified, a report to the Director in the form and containing the information specified by the Director;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594484_029" name="d" temporalId="s27_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>on the request of the Director, assist in the investigation of an accident in respect of a builder’s lift or tower working platform for which he has been responsible for carrying out the lift work;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594484_037" name="e" temporalId="s27_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>provide to the Director the name and relevant qualifications of each competent worker employed by him and notify the Director of subsequent changes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594484_045" name="f" temporalId="s27_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><leadIn>notify the Director, within 14 days—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594499_006" name="i" temporalId="s27_1_f_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>when he ceases to be retained by an owner to carry out the lift work required under this Ordinance; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594499_014" name="ii" temporalId="s27_1_f_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>of any change in his business address.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594499_020" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref>, where the Director is of the opinion that a full report cannot reasonably be completed within 7 days of the registered contractor being notified by the owner of an accident or failure, the Director may notify the contractor in writing that the contractor may, instead of complying with the 7 days requirement in subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594499_028" name="a" temporalId="s27_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>submit a preliminary report to the Director within 72 hours of being notified of the accident or failure; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594499_036" name="b" temporalId="s27_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>submit a report in accordance with subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref> within 14 days of being notified of the accident or failure or within such longer period as the Director may specify in the notice.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226452_002" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Additional duties of registered examiner</heading><leadIn>In addition to such other duties as are imposed on him by this Ordinance, a registered examiner shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594530_065" name="a" temporalId="s28_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on the request of the Director, assist in the investigation of an accident in respect of a builder’s lift or tower working platform on which he carried out the most recent test and examination;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594546_006" name="b" temporalId="s28_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>notify the Director, within 14 days, of any change of his business or residential address.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403226467_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Duties of competent operator</heading><leadIn>A competent operator shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594562_012" name="a" temporalId="s29_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>ensure that the number of passengers in the lift cage or on the platform does not exceed the maximum number specified in the notice required under <ref>section 10(b)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594562_020" name="b" temporalId="s29_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not interfere with any safety devices while operating the builder’s lift or tower working platform;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594562_028" name="c" temporalId="s29_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>operate the builder’s lift or tower working platform in accordance with the proper operating procedures laid down by the manufacturer.</content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226467_003" name="P8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part
            VIII</num><heading>Discipline
            of
            Registered Contractors
            and
            Registered
            Examiners</heading><section id="ID_1438403226483_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Director may discipline or refer to disciplinary tribunal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594593_004" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where the Director considers that there is evidence that a registered contractor or a registered examiner has failed to comply with this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594593_012" name="a" temporalId="s30_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he may refer the matter to the Secretary for hearing by a disciplinary tribunal; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594593_020" name="b" temporalId="s30_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in accordance with <ref>section 31</ref>, he may do either or both of the following—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594593_028" name="i" temporalId="s30_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>reprimand the registered contractor or registered examiner;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412594593_036" name="ii" temporalId="s30_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>impose a penalty up to $10,000 on a registered contractor or up to $1,000 on a registered examiner.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594593_042" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In accordance with <ref>section 31</ref>, the Director may cancel a registration if he considers that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594593_050" name="a" temporalId="s30_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the person obtained registration by fraud or on the basis of misleading or inaccurate information;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594593_058" name="b" temporalId="s30_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the registration was made in error; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594593_066" name="c" temporalId="s30_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the person is no longer qualified under this Ordinance to be registered.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594608_005" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a person without reasonable excuse fails to pay a monetary penalty imposed on him under subsection (1) or <ref>section 35</ref> on or before the time stipulated for payment, the Director may, in accordance with <ref>section 31</ref>, suspend his registration until the monetary penalty is paid.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594608_013" name="4" temporalId="s30_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A monetary penalty imposed under this section is recoverable as a civil debt.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226499_001" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Discipline procedure</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594640_004" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the Director considers that there are grounds for taking action under <ref>section 30(1)(b)</ref>, (2) or (3) the Director shall notify the registered contractor or registered examiner specifying the grounds and advising him that he is entitled to a hearing or to submit a written representation and that if he intends to request a hearing or submit a representation he must do so within 4 weeks after the date of the Director’s notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594640_012" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Director, in his notice under subsection (1) in respect of a proposed action under <ref>section 30(1)(b)</ref>, states that the alleged failure, if proved or admitted, will not attract a penalty greater than that set out in the notice, the Director shall not impose a greater penalty.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594655_005" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the Director does not, within 4 weeks after the date of the notice sent under subsection (1), receive from the person a request for a hearing, he may, after considering any written representation from him, impose the appropriate penalty under <ref>section 30</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594655_013" name="4" temporalId="s31_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the Director, within 4 weeks after the date of the notice sent under subsection (1), receives a request for a hearing, he shall afford the person a reasonable opportunity to be heard.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594655_021" name="5" temporalId="s31_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>After the hearing or, where the person fails without reasonable excuse to attend at the time set by the Director for the hearing, the Director may exonerate the person or impose the appropriate penalty under <ref>section 30</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594655_029" name="6" temporalId="s31_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Director shall notify the person of his decision and the reasons for it.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226514_001" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Disciplinary tribunal panel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594686_027" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Secretary shall appoint members to a disciplinary tribunal panel based on the following numbers and categories—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594686_035" name="a" temporalId="s32_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>not more than 5 persons who are corporate members of the Hong Kong Institution of Engineers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594686_043" name="b" temporalId="s32_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of registered contractors;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594686_051" name="c" temporalId="s32_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of registered examiners;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594686_059" name="d" temporalId="s32_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of owners of builders’ lifts or tower working platforms; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594702_006" name="e" temporalId="s32_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of construction workers.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594702_013" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A public officer is not eligible for appointment to the disciplinary tribunal panel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594702_021" name="3" temporalId="s32_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A member shall be appointed for a term of 3 years and may be reappointed at the end of a term.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226514_003" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Disciplinary tribunal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594718_061" name="1" temporalId="s33_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Within 21 days after receipt of notice of a matter from the Director under <ref>section 30(1)</ref>, the Secretary shall appoint a disciplinary tribunal to hear the matter and the tribunal shall consist of 1 member from each category of the disciplinary tribunal panel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594733_005" name="2" temporalId="s33_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The members shall elect a chairman from among themselves.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594733_013" name="3" temporalId="s33_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Each member shall be remunerated out of money provided by the Legislative Council for the purpose at a rate that the Financial Secretary may determine.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226530_002" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Proceedings before the disciplinary tribunal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594749_034" name="1" temporalId="s34_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The chairman of the disciplinary tribunal shall notify the registered contractor or registered examiner and the Director of the time and place of its hearing into the matter.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594749_042" name="2" temporalId="s34_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The registered contractor or registered examiner and the Director may each be represented by an agent or legal representative at a proceeding before the disciplinary tribunal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594749_050" name="3" temporalId="s34_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A legal adviser may be present at proceedings of the disciplinary tribunal to advise the chairman on any legal matter.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226545_001" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Disciplinary tribunal powers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594780_004" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The disciplinary tribunal may, by notice under the signature of the chairman—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594780_012" name="a" temporalId="s35_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>order a person to attend before the tribunal and give evidence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594780_020" name="b" temporalId="s35_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>order a person to produce documents; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594780_028" name="c" temporalId="s35_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>authorize a person to inspect a builder’s lift or tower working platform or any lift work in connection with it.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594780_035" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>After concluding its hearing, the disciplinary tribunal may exonerate the registered contractor or registered examiner or may do one or more of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594780_043" name="a" temporalId="s35_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>reprimand the registered contractor or registered examiner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594780_051" name="b" temporalId="s35_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>impose a penalty up to $50,000 on a registered contractor or up to $10,000 on a registered examiner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594780_059" name="c" temporalId="s35_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>suspend or cancel the registration of the registered contractor or registered examiner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594780_067" name="d" temporalId="s35_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>suspend the registered contractor’s or registered examiner’s registration for a specified period of time.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594780_074" name="3" temporalId="s35_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The disciplinary tribunal may make any order it thinks fit with regard to the payment of costs of the proceedings under this section and the costs of the Director or of the registered contractor or registered examiner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594796_005" name="4" temporalId="s35_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The disciplinary tribunal shall notify the registered contractor or registered examiner of its decision and the reasons for it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594796_013" name="5" temporalId="s35_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where no notice of appeal has been delivered to the Director within the time required under <ref>section 36(2)</ref>, the decision of the disciplinary tribunal takes effect at the expiration of that time.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594796_021" name="6" temporalId="s35_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where a notice of appeal has been delivered to the Director within the time required under <ref>section 36(2)</ref>, but the appellant abandons his appeal before the commencement of the hearing before the appeal board, the decision of the disciplinary tribunal takes effect on the day after the Director receives notice of the abandonment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594796_029" name="7" temporalId="s35_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A monetary penalty imposed under this section and costs awarded or imposed under this section are recoverable as a civil debt.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226545_003" name="P9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P9"><num value="9">Part
            IX</num><heading>Appeals</heading><section id="ID_1438403226561_002" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Appeal to appeal board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594842_011" name="1" temporalId="s36_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who is aggrieved by a decision or action of the Director or a decision of a disciplinary tribunal under this Ordinance may appeal to the appeal board appointed under <ref>section 38</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594842_019" name="2" temporalId="s36_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Within 4 weeks after the decision or action of the Director or the decision of the disciplinary tribunal, the appellant shall deliver to the Director a notice of appeal stating the substance of the matter and reasons for the appeal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594858_005" name="3" temporalId="s36_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>After receiving the notice of appeal the Director shall forward it to the Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594858_013" name="4" temporalId="s36_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An appeal under this section against a decision of the Director does not suspend the Director’s decision unless he decides otherwise.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226577_001" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Appeal board panel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594874_027" name="1" temporalId="s37_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Secretary shall appoint members to an appeal board panel based on the following numbers and categories—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594874_035" name="a" temporalId="s37_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>not more than 5 persons who are corporate members of the Hong Kong Institution of Engineers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594874_043" name="b" temporalId="s37_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from tertiary educational institutions;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594874_051" name="c" temporalId="s37_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of registered contractors;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594874_059" name="d" temporalId="s37_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of registered examiners;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594889_006" name="e" temporalId="s37_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of owners of builders’ lifts or tower working platforms; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594889_014" name="f" temporalId="s37_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>not more than 5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of construction workers.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594889_021" name="2" temporalId="s37_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A public officer is not eligible for appointment to the appeal board panel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594889_029" name="3" temporalId="s37_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A member shall be appointed for a term of 3 years and may be reappointed at the end of a term.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226577_003" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Appeal board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594905_081" name="1" temporalId="s38_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Within 21 days after receipt of a notice of appeal from the Director under <ref>section 36(3)</ref>, the Secretary shall appoint an appeal board to hear the appeal and the board shall consist of 1 member from each category of the appeal board panel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594920_005" name="2" temporalId="s38_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In respect of an appeal from a decision of a disciplinary tribunal, the Secretary shall not appoint to the appeal board a person who was on the disciplinary tribunal whose decision is being appealed against.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594920_013" name="3" temporalId="s38_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The members shall elect a chairman from among themselves.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594920_021" name="4" temporalId="s38_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The quorum of an appeal board is 5 members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594920_029" name="5" temporalId="s38_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Each member shall be remunerated out of money provided by the Legislative Council for the purpose at a rate that the Financial Secretary may determine.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226592_002" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Proceedings before the appeal board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594936_057" name="1" temporalId="s39_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The chairman of the appeal board shall notify the appellant and the Director of the time and place of its hearing of the appeal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594952_005" name="2" temporalId="s39_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The appellant and the Director may be represented by an agent or legal representative at a proceeding before the appeal board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594952_013" name="3" temporalId="s39_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The appellant and the Director may adduce evidence at an appeal from a decision of the Director.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594952_021" name="4" temporalId="s39_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The appellant and the Director may appear and make representations at an appeal from a decision of the disciplinary tribunal but they shall not adduce evidence unless the appeal board consents.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594952_029" name="5" temporalId="s39_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A legal adviser may be present at proceedings of an appeal board to advise the chairman on any legal matter.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226592_004" name="s40" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s40"><num value="40">40.</num><heading>Appeal board powers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412594967_050" name="1" temporalId="s40_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The appeal board may, by notice under the signature of the chairman—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594967_058" name="a" temporalId="s40_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>order a person to attend before the board and give evidence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594967_066" name="b" temporalId="s40_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>order a person to produce documents; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594983_006" name="c" temporalId="s40_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>authorize a person to inspect a builder’s lift or tower working platform or any lift work in connection with it.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594983_013" name="2" temporalId="s40_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The appeal board may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412594983_021" name="a" temporalId="s40_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>confirm or revoke the decision or action of the Director or decision of the disciplinary tribunal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594983_029" name="b" temporalId="s40_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>make any decision that the Director or the disciplinary tribunal could have made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594983_037" name="c" temporalId="s40_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>order the Director to take any action within his powers; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412594983_045" name="d" temporalId="s40_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in an appeal from a decision of the Director to reprimand or impose a monetary penalty under <ref>section 30(1)</ref>, do anything that the disciplinary tribunal may do under <ref>section 35(2)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594983_052" name="3" temporalId="s40_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The appeal board may make any order it thinks fit with regard to the payment of costs of the proceedings under this section and the costs of the Director or of any person in respect of whom the proceedings are brought.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594983_060" name="4" temporalId="s40_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The appeal board shall notify the appellant and the Director of its decision and the reasons for it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412594983_068" name="5" temporalId="s40_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A monetary penalty imposed under this section and costs awarded or imposed under this section are recoverable as a civil debt.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403226608_002" name="P10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="P10"><num value="10">Part
            X</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403226623_001" name="s41" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s41"><num value="41">41.</num><heading>Submission of location plan</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595030_011" name="1" temporalId="s41_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Each time a builder’s lift or tower working platform is installed at a construction site or dismantled and re-erected at a different location on the same site, the owner shall, when submitting the certificate of test and examination required under <ref>section 18(1)(a)</ref> or (b), submit a plan of the construction site showing its location on the site.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595030_019" name="2" temporalId="s41_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where more than one builder’s lift or tower working platform is installed at a construction site, each one shall be marked with a number and the number shall be shown on the construction site plan.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595045_005" name="3" temporalId="s41_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Director shall not accept a certificate of test and examination under <ref>section 18(1)(a)</ref> or (b) unless the plan required under this section is submitted with it.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226623_003" name="s42" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s42"><num value="42">42.</num><heading>Authorized officers</heading><content>The Director may authorize in writing any public officer to exercise any powers and perform any duties conferred or imposed on the Director by this Ordinance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403226639_001" name="s43" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s43"><num value="43">43.</num><heading>Service of notices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595076_004" name="1" temporalId="s43_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A notice or order required to be served under this Ordinance shall be properly served if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412595076_012" name="a" temporalId="s43_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the case of an individual, it is delivered to him or, where it cannot conveniently be so delivered, it is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412595076_020" name="i" temporalId="s43_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>left at the address at which he ordinarily resides or carries on business or, if such an address is unknown, at his last known address; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412595076_028" name="ii" temporalId="s43_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>sent by post to him at any such address;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595076_035" name="b" temporalId="s43_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a company, it is delivered to an officer of the company or, where it cannot conveniently be so delivered, it is left at, or sent by post to, the company’s registered office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595076_043" name="c" temporalId="s43_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of a partnership, it is delivered to any partner or, where it cannot conveniently be so delivered, it is left at, or sent by post to, the address at which the partnership carries on business;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595092_006" name="d" temporalId="s43_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in the case of a body corporate other than a company or in the case of an unincorporated body of persons other than a partnership, it is delivered to an officer of the body or, where it cannot conveniently be so delivered, it is left at, or sent by post to, the address at which the body carries on business.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595092_013" name="2" temporalId="s43_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (1), every body corporate other than a company and every unincorporated body of persons not being a partnership shall be deemed to carry on business at its principal office or place of business.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595092_021" name="3" temporalId="s43_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where a notice or order is served—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412595092_029" name="a" temporalId="s43_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by sending it by post, it shall, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, be deemed to have been served on the 7th day after the day on which it was sent; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595092_037" name="b" temporalId="s43_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by leaving it at an address referred to in subsection <ref>(1)(a)(i)</ref>, (b), (c) or (d), as the case may be, it shall, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, be deemed to have been served on the 7th day after it was so left.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226655_001" name="s44" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s44"><num value="44">44.</num><heading>Limitation of public liability</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595123_058" name="1" temporalId="s44_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No liability shall rest upon the Government or upon any public officer solely by reason of the fact that any builder’s lift or tower working platform is subject to examination or to inspecting, cleaning, oiling and adjusting under the provisions of this Ordinance, or solely by reason of the fact that the safety equipment provided for any builder’s lift or tower working platform is subject to testing under the provisions of this Ordinance, or solely by reason of the carrying out of any such examination or test or the inspecting, cleaning, oiling or adjusting of any builder’s lift or tower working platform in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance or the carrying out of any other work pursuant to the provisions of this Ordinance, or solely by reason of the carrying out by the Director of an examination of a builder’s lift or tower working platform or a test of the safety equipment provided for a builder’s lift or tower working platform, or both, or solely by reason of any other matter or thing done or any certificate or report given or made under the provisions of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595186_005" name="2" temporalId="s44_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No matter or thing done by the Director or by any officer of the Electrical and Mechanical Services Department to whom the Director has, pursuant to <ref>section 42</ref>, delegated any of his powers or duties or by any public officer acting under the direction of the Director shall, if it was done bona fide for the purpose of executing the provisions of this Ordinance, subject him personally to any action, liability, claim or demand whatsoever.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226655_003" name="s45" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s45"><num value="45">45.</num><heading>Minor offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595217_004" name="1" temporalId="s45_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who contravenes <ref>section 15</ref>, <ref>16</ref>, <ref>17(1)</ref>, <ref>19(2)</ref>, <ref>20(7)</ref>, <ref>21(2)</ref> or (3), 22(4), 27, 28 or 29 commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595232_005" name="2" temporalId="s45_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who contravenes <ref>section 12(3)</ref> or, having obtained the approval of the Director under that subsection, fails to perform lift work in accordance with the details submitted to the Director, commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595232_013" name="3" temporalId="s45_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who commits an offence under this section is liable on conviction to a fine at level 3.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226670_002" name="s46" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s46"><num value="46">46.</num><heading>Serious offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595248_019" name="1" temporalId="s46_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who contravenes <ref>section 13</ref>, <ref>14(1)</ref>, <ref>19(1)</ref> or (4), 20(1), 22(3) or (6) or 26 commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595248_027" name="2" temporalId="s46_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who obstructs the Director in the exercise of any of the powers conferred on him by this Ordinance, or obstructs a public officer authorized by the Director to exercise any such powers, commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595248_035" name="3" temporalId="s46_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who fails to comply with an order or requirement of the Director given under <ref>section 25(b)</ref>, (c) or (f) commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595248_043" name="4" temporalId="s46_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person who employs or permits a person to carry out lift work in contravention of <ref>section 14(1)</ref> commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595264_005" name="5" temporalId="s46_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person who wilfully misuses or interferes with a builder’s lift or tower working platform, or any part thereof, commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595264_013" name="6" temporalId="s46_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>A person who, without reasonable excuse, fails to obey an order of the disciplinary tribunal or appeal board to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412595264_021" name="a" temporalId="s46_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>attend before it and give evidence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595264_029" name="b" temporalId="s46_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>produce documents,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595264_042" name="7" temporalId="s46_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A person who commits an offence under this section is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226670_004" name="s47" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s47"><num value="47">47.</num><heading>Very serious offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595295_004" name="1" temporalId="s47_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who contravenes <ref>section 9</ref>, <ref>10</ref>, <ref>18(1)</ref>, <ref>19(6)</ref> or <ref>22(8)</ref> or (9) commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595295_012" name="2" temporalId="s47_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who reconnects the electricity supply to a builder’s lift or tower working platform, which supply has been disconnected on the order of the Director under <ref>section 25(b)</ref>, without first obtaining the written permission of the Director to do so, commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595295_020" name="3" temporalId="s47_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who obstructs a person authorized by the disciplinary tribunal or appeal board under <ref>section 35(1)(c)</ref> or <ref>40(1)(c)</ref> to inspect a builder’s lift or tower working platform or to inspect lift work commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595295_028" name="4" temporalId="s47_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412595295_036" name="a" temporalId="s47_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>forges a certificate of test and examination;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595295_044" name="b" temporalId="s47_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>signs a certificate of test and examination knowing it is false in a material particular;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595310_006" name="c" temporalId="s47_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>makes use of a certificate of test and examination which he knows or ought reasonably to have known was forged or false in a material particular;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595310_014" name="d" temporalId="s47_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>knowingly utters or makes use of any certificate which in fact does not apply to a builder’s lift or tower working platform, as if it is a certificate required under this Ordinance,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595310_027" name="5" temporalId="s47_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person who makes a statement which he knows or ought reasonably to have known was false in a material particular when applying for registration as a registered contractor or registered examiner commits an offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595310_035" name="6" temporalId="s47_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A person who commits an offence under this section is liable on conviction to a fine of $200,000 and to imprisonment for 12 months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595310_043" name="7" temporalId="s47_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where a person has been convicted of an offence under subsection (1) for contravening <ref>section 18(1)</ref>, <ref>19(6)</ref> or <ref>22(8)</ref> or (9), he shall, in addition to the penalty provided therefor, be liable to a fine of $1,000 for each day during which it is proved to the satisfaction of the court that there has been a further contravention of the same subsection unless he shows that such further contravention occurred without his consent or connivance and that he had taken all reasonable steps to prevent the use and operation of the builder’s lift or tower working platform.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226686_002" name="s48" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s48"><num value="48">48.</num><heading>Liability of person other than principal offender</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595357_041" name="1" temporalId="s48_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a body corporate is guilty of an offence under this Ordinance in respect of any act or default which is shown to have been committed with the consent or connivance of, or to be attributable to any neglect on the part of, any director, manager, secretary or other similar officer of the body corporate or any person who was purporting to act in any such capacity he, as well as the body corporate, shall be guilty of that offence and shall be liable to be proceeded against.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595373_005" name="2" temporalId="s48_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the affairs of a body corporate are managed by its members, subsection (1) applies in relation to the acts and defaults of a member in connection with his functions of management as if he were a director of the body corporate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595373_013" name="3" temporalId="s48_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the person who is guilty of an offence under this Ordinance is a firm and it is proved that the offence was committed with the consent or connivance of, or was attributable to any neglect on the part of, any partner in the firm or any person concerned in the management of the firm, the partner or the person concerned in the management of the firm shall be guilty of the like offence.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226701_002" name="s49" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s49"><num value="49">49.</num><heading>Limitation period for prosecution</heading><content>Any prosecution under this Ordinance shall not be commenced more than 6 months after the commission of the offence or more than 6 months after the offence is discovered by or comes to the notice of the Director, whichever is the later.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403226717_001" name="s50" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s50"><num value="50">50.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595420_025" name="1" temporalId="s50_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations including regulations for
                all or any of the following matters—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/57">57 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412595420_033" name="a" temporalId="s50_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>additional procedures, qualifications and requirements for the registration
                    of contractors and examiners and the regulation of the activities of such
                    registered contractors and registered examiners;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595420_041" name="b" temporalId="s50_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>prescribing requirements for the design, installation, inspection, test,
                    examination, maintenance, operation and use of builder’s lifts and tower working
                    platforms;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595435_006" name="c" temporalId="s50_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the carrying out of lift work and other work in relation thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595435_014" name="d" temporalId="s50_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the submission of technical data, operation and maintenance manuals, plans,
                    notices and certificates to the Director as required by this
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412595435_022" name="e" temporalId="s50_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the procedures to be followed with respect to proceedings of the
                    disciplinary tribunal and the appeal board.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595435_029" name="2" temporalId="s50_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Regulations made under subsection (1) may provide for a penalty not exceeding a
                fine at level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595435_037" name="3" temporalId="s50_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Financial Secretary may make regulations prescribing the amount of fees
                required to be paid under this Ordinance.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403226811_001" name="s51" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-02-25" status="operational" temporalId="s51"><num value="51">51.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412595466_004" name="1" temporalId="s51_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where, on the day <ref>section 18</ref> comes into
                    operation<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>, lift work referred to in
                    <ref>section 18(1)(a)</ref>, (b) or (c) is being carried out but has not yet
                been completed, <ref>section 18</ref> shall apply to such lift work.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595466_012" name="2" temporalId="s51_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where, on the day <ref>section 22</ref> comes into
                    operation<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>, a builder’s lift or tower
                working platform is already installed at a construction site, the registered
                contractor whose services have been retained by the owner shall employ a registered
                examiner to carry out a test and examination under that section within 90 days of
                that section coming into operation unless, within that
                90-day
                period, a test and examination has been carried out under <ref>section
                18</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412595482_005" name="3" temporalId="s51_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where, on the day <ref>section 41</ref> comes into
                    operation<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>, a builder’s lift or tower
                working platform is already installed at a construction site, the owner shall,
                within 90 days of that section coming into operation, submit a plan of the
                construction site showing its location on the site unless, within that
                90-day
                period, a test and examination has been carried out under <ref>section
                    18(1)(a)</ref> or
                (b).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er1">E.R. 1 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1611299546679_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Operation date: 30 December
                1995.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></part></main></ordinance>