<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 503 sub. leg. X</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>503X</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap503X!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-12-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403285919_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-12-29">Fugitive
                                    Offenders
                                    (Germany)
                                    Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap503/s3">Cap.
                                                503, section
                                    3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of
                                                2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[11 April 2009]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2009/ln61">L.N. 61 0f
                                                  2009</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of
                                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403285935_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403285935_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Procedures in Ordinance to apply between Hong Kong and Germany</heading><content>In relation to the arrangements for the surrender of fugitive offenders the terms of which are recited in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, it is directed that the procedures in the Ordinance shall apply as between Hong Kong and the Federal Republic of Germany subject to the limitations, restrictions, exceptions and qualifications contained in the terms of the arrangements.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403285950_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap503X/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Agreement
            between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s
            Republic of China and the Government of the Federal Republic of Germany for the
            Surrender of Fugitive
                Offenders<ref idref="ID_1600825892834_001"><inline class="not_bold"><sup>#</sup></inline></ref><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text>The
            Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the
            People’s
            Republic of China,
            having
            been duly authorised by the Central People’s Government of the
            People’s
            Republic of China and
            the
            Government of the Federal Republic of
            Germany,<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><leadIn class="first_line_indent_0">Desiring to make provision for the reciprocal surrender
            of fugitive
            offenders—<marker role="blank-line"></marker>Have
            agreed as
            follows:</leadIn><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            1</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Obligation to
            Surrender</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938012_001" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>The Parties agree to surrender to each other, subject to the provisions laid
                down in this Agreement, any person who is found in the jurisdiction of the Requested
                Party and who is wanted by the Requesting Party for prosecution or for the
                imposition or enforcement of a sentence in respect of an offence under Article
                2.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938012_002" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this Agreement, “sentence” includes a detention order
                involving deprivation of liberty made following conviction by a criminal court in
                addition to or instead of a prison sentence.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            2</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Offences</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938012_003" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>Surrender of fugitive offenders shall be granted for offences which are,
                according to the laws of both Parties, punishable by imprisonment or other form of
                detention for a maximum period of at least one year, or by a more severe penalty,
                and which come within any of the descriptions in the Appendix to this Agreement. The
                Appendix shall form part of this Agreement.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938012_004" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>Where surrender of a fugitive offender is requested for the purpose of carrying
                out a sentence, a further requirement shall be that at least six months of the
                sentence remain to be served.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938012_005" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>In determining whether an offence is an offence punishable under the laws of
                both Parties, it shall not matter whether, under the laws of the Parties, the
                constituent elements of the offence differ, it being understood that the totality of
                the acts or omissions as presented by the Requesting Party shall be taken into
                account.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_006" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">(4)</num><content>Where surrender of a fugitive offender is requested for the purpose of carrying
                out a sentence on the grounds that the person sought has been convicted of an
                offence for which surrender may be granted under this Agreement, the Requested Party
                may refuse to return or to keep such person in custody for such a purpose if it
                appears that the conviction was obtained in his
                absence.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            3</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Surrender
                of
            Nationals</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_007" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region reserves the
                right to refuse the surrender of nationals of the People’s Republic of China and the
                Government of the Federal Republic of Germany reserves the right to refuse the
                surrender of its nationals.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_008" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Requested Party exercises this right, it shall, if asked to do so by
                the Requesting Party, take all possible measures in accordance with its own law to
                prosecute the person. The Requesting Party shall be informed of the result of its
                request.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            4</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Death
                Penalty</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 align_justified">If the offence for which surrender of a fugitive
            offender is requested under this Agreement is punishable according to the law of the
            Requesting Party with the death penalty, and if in respect of such an offence the death
            penalty is not provided for by the law of the Requested Party or is not normally carried
            out, surrender may be refused unless the Requesting Party gives such assurances as the
            Requested Party considers sufficient that this penalty will not be imposed or if imposed
            will not be carried
            out.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            5</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Mandatory
                Refusal to
            Surrender</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_009" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>A fugitive offender shall not be surrendered if the Requested Party considers
                that the offence of which that person is accused or was convicted is a political
                offence or an offence of a political character.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_010" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A fugitive offender shall not be surrendered if the Requested Party has
                substantial grounds for believing:</leadIn></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938028_011" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>that the request for his surrender (though purporting to be made on account
                    of an offence for which surrender may be granted) is in fact made for the
                    purpose of prosecuting or punishing him on account of his race, religion,
                    nationality, sex, ethnic origin or political opinions; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_013" name="2" temporalId="sch0_0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>that he might, if surrendered, be prejudiced at his trial or punished,
                    detained or restricted in his personal liberty by reason of his race, religion,
                    nationality, sex, ethnic origin or political opinions.</content></paragraph></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            6</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Non
                bis in
            idem</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_justified left_indent_0">Surrender shall not be granted if the person
            whose surrender is requested has been finally acquitted or convicted, or has been
            pardoned, by either Party for the offence for which surrender is
            requested.<marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            7</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Discretionary
                Refusal to
            Surrender</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_014" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>The Requested Party may refuse to surrender a fugitive offender for an offence
                which is regarded by its law as having been committed within the jurisdiction of its
                courts. If the Requested Party so refuses, it shall if asked to do so by the
                Requesting Party, take all possible measures in accordance with its own law to
                prosecute the person.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_015" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>The surrender of a fugitive offender may also be refused if the Requested Party
                considers that:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938028_016" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_017" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>in the circumstances of the case, the surrender of the fugitive offender
                    would be incompatible with humanitarian considerations in view of age, health or
                    other personal circumstances; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_018" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>the surrender would prejudice essential interests of the Requested Party;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_019" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">3.</num><content>the surrender of the fugitive offender may place that Party in breach of
                    its obligations under international treaties.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_020" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>Before refusing a request for surrender under this Article the Requested Party
                shall consider whether surrender may be granted subject to conditions. If the
                Requesting Party accepts surrender subject to those conditions, it shall comply with
                them.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            8</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">The
                Request and Supporting
            Documents</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_021" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>Requests under this Agreement and responses thereto shall be transmitted
                through the Department of Justice of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of
                the People’s Republic of China and the Federal Ministry of Justice of the Federal
                Republic of Germany.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_022" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>The request shall be accompanied by:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938028_023" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_024" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>as accurate a description as possible of the fugitive offender, together
                    with any other information which would help to establish his identity,
                    nationality and, if known, his whereabouts;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_025" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>a statement and particulars of the offence for which the surrender is
                    requested unless the facts of the case are apparent from the warrant of arrest
                    or the judgment of conviction;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_026" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">3.</num><content>the legal provisions creating the offence, a statement of the punishment
                    which can be imposed therefore and, where applicable, a specification of the
                    time bar that is imposed on the prosecution or on the enforcement of any
                    sentence in respect of that offence.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_027" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>A request for the surrender of a person for the purpose of prosecution shall be
                accompanied, in addition to the documents provided for in paragraph (2), by a copy
                of the warrant of arrest issued by a judge or other competent authority of the
                Requesting Party, and by such evidence as, according to the law of the Requested
                Party, would justify his committal for trial if the offence had been committed
                within the jurisdiction of the Requested Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938028_028" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">(4)</num><content>If the request relates to a person already convicted or sentenced, in addition
                to the documents provided for in paragraph (2), it shall also be accompanied
                by:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938028_029" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938028_030" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>a copy of the certificate of the conviction or sentence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938043_031" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>if the person was convicted but not sentenced, a statement to that effect
                    by the appropriate court and a copy of the warrant of arrest; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938043_032" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">3.</num><content>if the person was sentenced, a statement that the sentence is enforceable
                    and indicating how much of the sentence has still to be served.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_033" name="5" temporalId="sch0_5"><num class="align_left" value="5">(5)</num><content>If the information communicated by the Requesting Party is found to be
                insufficient to allow the Requested Party to make a decision in pursuance of this
                Agreement, the latter Party shall request the necessary supplementary information
                and may fix a time-limit for receipt thereof.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_034" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num class="align_left" value="6">(6)</num><content>The request and, if so required by the Requested Party, all documents submitted
                in support of the request shall be translated into an official language of the
                Requested
                Party.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            9</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Authentication</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="align_justified left_indent_0">Documents accompanying a request for surrender
            shall be admitted in evidence if authenticated. A document is authenticated if it has
            been:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938043_035" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938043_036" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>signed or certified by a judge, magistrate or an official of the Requesting
                    Party; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938043_037" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>sealed with the official seal of the competent authority of the Requesting
                    Party.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            10</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Provisional
                Arrest</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_038" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>In urgent cases the person sought may, in accordance with the law of the
                Requested Party, be provisionally arrested on the application of the competent
                authorities of the Requesting Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_039" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>The application shall contain a description of the person sought, an indication
                of intention to request his surrender, a statement of the existence and terms of a
                warrant of arrest or a judgment of conviction against the person, a statement of the
                maximum punishment that can be imposed or the sentence that has been imposed for the
                offence, and a statement of the acts or omissions (including time and place) alleged
                to constitute the offence.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_040" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>The application for provisional arrest shall be in writing and may be forwarded
                through the same channels as a request for surrender or through the International
                Criminal Police Organisation (Interpol).</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_041" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">(4)</num><content>The provisional arrest of the person sought shall be terminated upon the
                expiration of sixty days from the date of his arrest if the request for his
                surrender, supported by the documents referred to in paragraphs (2) to (4) of
                Article 8 of this Agreement, has not been received. This provision shall not prevent
                his re-arrest or surrender if the request for his surrender is received
                subsequently.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            11</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Conflicting
                Requests</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 align_justified">A Party which has received conflicting requests
            for the surrender or, in the case of the Government of the Federal Republic of Germany,
            extradition of the same person, either in respect of the same offence or of different
            offences, shall make its decision having regard to all the circumstances, including the
            relative seriousness and place of commission of the offence, the respective dates of the
            requests, the nationality of the person sought and any applicable international
            obligations as well as, in particular, the possibility of subsequent re-surrender or, in
            the case of the Government of the Federal Republic of Germany, re-extradition of that
            person.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            12</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Representation
                and
            Costs</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_042" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>The Requested Party shall, by all legal means within its power, assist the
                Requesting Party before the judicial and other competent authorities of the
                Requested Party.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_043" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>The Requested Party shall bear the expenses of the arrest of the person whose
                surrender is requested, of the maintenance in custody of the person until he is
                handed over to a person nominated by the Requesting Party and in relation to any
                legal proceedings before the judicial authorities of the Requested Party arising out
                of the request for surrender.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_044" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>The Requesting Party shall bear the expenses incurred in conveying the person
                from the jurisdiction of the Requested
                Party.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            13</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Arrangements
                for
            Handover</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_045" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>The Requested Party shall promptly communicate its decision on the request for
                surrender to the Requesting Party. Reasons shall be given for any complete or
                partial refusal of the request.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_046" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>If the surrender of the fugitive offender has been granted, he shall be taken
                by the authorities of the Requested Party on a date agreed with the Requesting Party
                to a mutually convenient place of departure within the jurisdiction of the Requested
                Party. The Requested Party shall inform the Requesting Party of the length of time
                for which the fugitive offender was detained in connection with the request for his
                surrender.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_047" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of paragraph (4) of this Article, if the Requesting
                Party does not take custody of the person on the date agreed by the two Parties, he
                shall be released on the expiry of thirty days thereafter or such lesser period as
                is provided by the law of the Requested Party. The Requested Party may subsequently
                refuse to surrender him for the same offence.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_048" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num class="align_left" value="4">(4)</num><content>If circumstances beyond its control prevent a Party from handing over or taking
                over the person as agreed, it shall notify the other Party. In that case, the two
                Parties shall agree on a new date for the handover, and the provisions of paragraph
                (3) of this Article shall apply.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            14</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Deferred
                or Temporary
            Surrender</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_049" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>If the fugitive offender is being proceeded against or is under punishment in
                the jurisdiction of the Requested Party for any offence other than the offence for
                which surrender is requested, his surrender may be deferred until the conclusion of
                the proceedings and the execution of any punishment awarded to him.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938043_050" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>Alternatively, the Requested Party may temporarily surrender the person sought
                to the Requesting Party for the purpose of prosecution. The person so surrendered
                shall be kept in custody by the Requesting Party and shall be returned to the
                Requested Party after conclusion of the proceedings against that person, in
                accordance with conditions to be determined by mutual agreement of the
                Parties.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            15</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Handing
                Over of
            Property</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_051" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>When a request for surrender of a fugitive offender is granted the Requested
                Party shall, at the request of the Requesting Party and in so far as its law allows,
                hand over to the Requesting Party all articles, including sums of money, found
                within its jurisdiction:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938059_052" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_053" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>which may serve as proof of the offence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_054" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>which have been acquired by the fugitive offender as a result of the
                    offence and are in his possession or discovered subsequently.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_055" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>If the articles in question are liable to seizure or confiscation within the
                jurisdiction of the Requested Party the latter may, in connection with pending
                criminal proceedings, temporarily retain them or hand them over on condition that
                they are returned.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_056" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>These provisions shall not prejudice the rights of the Requested Party or of
                any person other than the person sought. When such rights exist the articles shall,
                on request, be returned to the Requested Party without charge as soon as possible
                after the end of the
                proceedings.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            16</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Rule
                of
            Specialty</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_057" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>A fugitive offender who has been surrendered shall not be proceeded against,
                sentenced, detained or subjected to any other restriction of personal liberty by the
                Requesting Party for any offence committed prior to his handover other
                than:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938059_058" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_059" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>the offence or offences in respect of which his surrender was
                    granted;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_060" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>an offence, however described, based on substantially the same facts as
                    that in respect of which his surrender was granted, provided such offence is one
                    for which he could be surrendered under this Agreement, and provided further
                    such offence is punishable by a penalty no more severe than the penalty for the
                    offence for which he was surrendered;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_061" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">3.</num><content>any other offence for which surrender may be granted under this Agreement
                    and in respect of which the Requested Party consents to his being dealt
                    with;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_062" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><continued>unless he has first had an opportunity to exercise his right to leave the
                jurisdiction of the Party to which he has been surrendered and he has not done so
                within forty days or has voluntarily returned to that jurisdiction having left
                it.</continued></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_063" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>A Party whose consent is requested under paragraph (1) number 3 of this Article
                may require the submission of any document or statement referred to in Article 8 of
                this Agreement, and a statement made by the surrendered person on the
                matter.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            17</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Re-Surrender
                or
            Re-Extradition</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_064" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>A fugitive offender who has been surrendered shall not be re-surrendered or, in
                the case of the Government of the Federal Republic of Germany, re-extradited to
                another jurisdiction for an offence committed prior to his handover
                unless:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938059_065" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_066" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>the Requested Party consents to such re-surrender or re-extradition;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_067" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>he has first had an opportunity to exercise his right to leave the
                    jurisdiction of the Party to which he has been surrendered and has not done so
                    within forty days or has voluntarily returned to that jurisdiction having left
                    it.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_068" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>A Party whose consent is requested under paragraph (1) number 1 of this Article
                may require the submission of any document or statement referred to in Article 8 of
                this Agreement, and a statement made by the surrendered person on the
                matter.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            18</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Transit</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_justified left_indent_0">To the extent permitted by its law, transit
            through the jurisdiction of a Party may be granted on a request in writing. The Party
            through whose jurisdiction transit will occur may request the information referred to in
            paragraph (2) of Article 10 of this Agreement. The Party requesting transit shall bear
            the expenses
            thereof.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            19</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Result
                of Criminal
            Proceedings</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_justified lleft_indent_0">The Requesting Party shall, upon request,
            inform the Requested Party of the result of the criminal proceedings against the person
            surrendered and shall send a copy of the final and binding decision to that
            Party.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            20</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Surrender
                by
            Consent</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_069" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>If the person consents voluntarily and in writing to surrender to the
                Requesting Party, the Requested Party may, subject to its law, surrender the person
                as expeditiously as possible without further formal proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_070" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>The provisions of Articles 16 and 17 shall apply to a person surrendered
                pursuant to this Article.</content></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            21</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Personal
                Data</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_071" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>In this Article “personal data” means any information about an identified or
                identifiable natural person.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_072" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>Personal data transmitted on the basis of this Agreement shall be used for the
                purposes for which the data were transmitted and subject to such conditions as the
                transmitting Party determines. In addition such data may be used by the Party which
                has received it for the purpose of warding off substantial dangers to its security.
                Use of the data for other purposes requires the prior consent of the Party
                transmitting the data.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938059_073" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to the respective law of each Party, the following provisions shall
                apply to the transmission and use of personal data transmitted for the purpose of a
                request for surrender under this Agreement:</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_32" id="ID_1599548938059_074" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><paragraph id="ID_1599548938059_075" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">1.</num><content>only data that relates to the request shall be transmitted;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938074_076" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">2.</num><content>upon request, the Party which has received the data shall identify the data
                    received and inform the transmitting Party of the use made of the data and the
                    results achieved therefrom;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938074_077" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">3.</num><content>if it appears to the transmitting Party that incorrect data have been
                    transmitted or that data have been transmitted that should not have been, the
                    transmitting Party shall notify without delay the Party that has received the
                    data; the Party that has received the data shall without delay rectify any
                    errors or destroy the data;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938074_078" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">4.</num><content>the Parties shall keep records in a readily retrievable form concerning the
                    transmission and receipt of data;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1599548938074_079" name="b" temporalId="sch0_0_b"><num value="b">5.</num><content>the Parties shall protect personal data against unauthorised access,
                    unauthorised alteration and unauthorised publication.</content></paragraph></subsection><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            22</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Settlement
                of
            Disputes</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_justified left_indent_0">Any dispute arising out of the interpretation,
            application or implementation of this Agreement shall be resolved through diplomatic
            channels if the Parties are themselves unable to reach agreement.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
            23</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">Entry
                into Force, Suspension and
            Termination</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938074_080" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num class="align_left" value="1">(1)</num><content>This Agreement shall enter into force thirty days after the date on which the
                Parties have notified each other that their respective requirements for the entry
                into force of this Agreement have been complied with. The date of receipt of the
                second notification shall be decisive.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938074_081" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num class="align_left" value="2">(2)</num><content>The provisions of this Agreement shall apply to requests made after its entry
                into force regardless of the date of the commission of the offence or offences set
                out in the request.</content></subsection><subsection class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0" id="ID_1599548938074_082" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num class="align_left" value="3">(3)</num><content>This Agreement shall be of unlimited duration. Each of the Parties may suspend
                or terminate this Agreement at any time by giving notification to the other.
                Suspension shall take effect on receipt of the relevant notification. In the event
                of termination the Agreement shall cease to have effect six months after the receipt
                of the relevant notification.</content></subsection><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36">Done at Hong Kong, this
            26th day of May 2006 in two originals in the Chinese, English and German languages, each
            text being equally
            authentic.</text><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text class="align_center">Appendix to the Agreement between the Government<br></br>of the Hong
            Kong Special Administrative Region<br></br>of the People’s Republic of China and
            the<br></br>Government of the Federal Republic of<br></br>Germany for the Surrender
            of<br></br>Fugitive Offenders</text><crossHeading> </crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1525423852831_067" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="left_indent_32"><leadIn class="left_indent_36">Description of offences referred to in Article 2
                paragraph (1)</leadIn><paragraph name="1" temporalId="sch0_0_1" id="ID_1525423852831_068"><num value="1">1.</num><content>murder or manslaughter, including criminal negligence causing death,
                    culpable homicide, assault with intent to commit murder</content></paragraph><paragraph name="2" temporalId="sch0_0_2" id="ID_1525423852847_069"><num value="2">2.</num><content>malicious wounding, maiming, inflicting grievous or actual bodily harm,
                    assault occasioning actual bodily harm, threats to kill, intentional or reckless
                    endangering of life whether by means of a weapon, a dangerous substance or
                    otherwise, offences relating to unlawful wounding or injuring</content></paragraph><paragraph name="3" temporalId="sch0_0_3" id="ID_1525423852847_070"><num value="3">3.</num><content>offences of a sexual nature including rape, sexual assault, indecent
                    assault, unlawful sexual acts on children, statutory sexual offences</content></paragraph><paragraph name="4" temporalId="sch0_0_4" id="ID_1525423852847_071"><num value="4">4.</num><content>gross indecency with a child, a mental defective or an unconscious
                    person</content></paragraph><paragraph name="5" temporalId="sch0_0_5" id="ID_1525423852847_072"><num value="5">5.</num><content>kidnapping, abduction, false imprisonment, unlawful confinement, dealing or
                    trafficking in slaves or other persons, taking a hostage </content></paragraph><paragraph name="6" temporalId="sch0_0_6" id="ID_1525423852847_073"><num value="6">6.</num><content>criminal
                    intimidation<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph name="7" temporalId="sch0_0_7" id="ID_1525423852847_074"><num value="7">7.</num><content>offences against the law relating to dangerous drugs including narcotics,
                    psychotropic substances, precursors and essential chemicals used in the illegal
                    manufacture of narcotics and psychotropic substances, offences relating to the
                    proceeds of drug trafficking</content></paragraph><paragraph name="8" temporalId="sch0_0_8" id="ID_1525423852847_075"><num value="8">8.</num><content>obtaining property or pecuniary advantage by deception, theft, robbery,
                    burglary (including breaking and entering), embezzlement, blackmail, extortion,
                    unlawful handling or receiving of property, false accounting, any other offence
                    in respect of property or fiscal matters involving fraud, any offence against
                    the law relating to unlawful deprivation of property</content></paragraph><paragraph name="9" temporalId="sch0_0_9" id="ID_1525423852847_076"><num value="9">9.</num><content>offences against bankruptcy law or insolvency law</content></paragraph><paragraph name="10" temporalId="sch0_0_10" id="ID_1525423852847_077"><num value="10">10.</num><content>offences against the law relating to companies including offences committed
                    by officers, directors and promoters</content></paragraph><paragraph name="11" temporalId="sch0_0_11" id="ID_1525423852847_078"><num value="11">11.</num><content>offences relating to securities and futures trading</content></paragraph><paragraph name="12" temporalId="sch0_0_12" id="ID_1525423852847_079"><num value="12">12.</num><content>offences relating to counterfeiting, offences against the law relating to
                    forgery or uttering what is forged</content></paragraph><paragraph name="13" temporalId="sch0_0_13" id="ID_1525423852847_080"><num value="13">13.</num><content>offences against the law relating to protection of intellectual property,
                    copyrights, patents or
                    trademarks</content></paragraph><paragraph name="14" temporalId="sch0_0_14" id="ID_1525423852847_081"><num value="14">14.</num><content>offences against the law relating to bribery, corruption, secret
                    commissions and breach of trust</content></paragraph><paragraph name="15" temporalId="sch0_0_15" id="ID_1525423852862_082"><num value="15">15.</num><content>perjury and subornation of perjury</content></paragraph><paragraph name="16" temporalId="sch0_0_16" id="ID_1525423852862_083"><num value="16">16.</num><content>offence relating to the perversion or obstruction of the course of
                    justice</content></paragraph><paragraph name="17" temporalId="sch0_0_17" id="ID_1525423852862_084"><num value="17">17.</num><content>arson, criminal damage or mischief including mischief in relation to
                    computer data</content></paragraph><paragraph name="18" temporalId="sch0_0_18" id="ID_1525423852862_085"><num value="18">18.</num><content>offences against the law relating to firearms </content></paragraph><paragraph name="19" temporalId="sch0_0_19" id="ID_1525423852862_086"><num value="19">19.</num><content>offences against the law relating to
                    explosives<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph name="20" temporalId="sch0_0_20" id="ID_1525423852862_087"><num value="20">20.</num><content>offences against the law relating to environmental pollution or protection
                    of public health</content></paragraph><paragraph name="21" temporalId="sch0_0_21" id="ID_1525423852862_088"><num value="21">21.</num><content>mutiny or any mutinous act committed on board a vessel at sea</content></paragraph><paragraph name="22" temporalId="sch0_0_22" id="ID_1525423852862_089"><num value="22">22.</num><content>piracy involving ships or aircraft</content></paragraph><paragraph name="23" temporalId="sch0_0_23" id="ID_1525423852862_090"><num value="23">23.</num><content>unlawful seizure or exercise of control of an aircraft or other means of
                    transportation </content></paragraph><paragraph name="24" temporalId="sch0_0_24" id="ID_1525423852862_091"><num value="24">24.</num><content>genocide or direct and public incitement to commit genocide </content></paragraph><paragraph name="25" temporalId="sch0_0_25" id="ID_1525423852862_092"><num value="25">25.</num><content>facilitating or permitting the escape of a person from custody </content></paragraph><paragraph name="26" temporalId="sch0_0_26" id="ID_1525423852862_093"><num value="26">26.</num><content>offences against the law relating to the control of exportation or
                    importation of goods of any type, or the international transfer of
                    funds</content></paragraph><paragraph name="27" temporalId="sch0_0_27" id="ID_1525423852862_094"><num value="27">27.</num><content>smuggling, offences against the law relating to import and export of
                    prohibited items, including historical and archaeological items</content></paragraph><paragraph name="28" temporalId="sch0_0_28" id="ID_1525423852862_095"><num value="28">28.</num><content>immigration offences including fraudulent acquisition or use of a passport
                    or visa</content></paragraph><paragraph name="29" temporalId="sch0_0_29" id="ID_1525423852878_096"><num value="29">29.</num><content>arranging or facilitating for financial gain, the illegal entry of persons
                    into the jurisdiction of the Requesting Party</content></paragraph><paragraph name="30" temporalId="sch0_0_30" id="ID_1525423852878_097"><num value="30">30.</num><content>offences relating to gambling or
                    lotteries</content></paragraph><paragraph name="31" temporalId="sch0_0_31" id="ID_1525423852878_098"><num value="31">31.</num><content>offences relating to the unlawful termination of pregnancy </content></paragraph><paragraph name="32" temporalId="sch0_0_32" id="ID_1525423852878_099"><num value="32">32.</num><content>stealing, abandoning, exposing or unlawfully detaining a child, any other
                    offences involving the exploitation of children</content></paragraph><paragraph name="33" temporalId="sch0_0_33" id="ID_1525423852878_100"><num value="33">33.</num><content>offences against the law relating to prostitution and premises kept for the
                    purposes of
                    prostitution</content></paragraph><paragraph name="34" temporalId="sch0_0_34" id="ID_1525423852878_101"><num value="34">34.</num><content>offences involving the unlawful use of
                    computers<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph name="35" temporalId="sch0_0_35" id="ID_1525423852878_102"><num value="35">35.</num><content>offences relating to fiscal matters, taxes or duties, notwithstanding that
                    the law of the Requested Party does not impose the same kind of tax or duty or
                    does not contain a tax duty or customs regulation of the same kind as that of
                    the Requesting Party</content></paragraph><paragraph name="36" temporalId="sch0_0_36" id="ID_1525423852878_103"><num value="36">36.</num><content>offences relating to unlawful escape from custody, mutiny in prison
                </content></paragraph><paragraph name="37" temporalId="sch0_0_37" id="ID_1525423852878_104"><num value="37">37.</num><content>bigamy</content></paragraph><paragraph name="38" temporalId="sch0_0_38" id="ID_1525423852878_105"><num value="38">38.</num><content>offences relating to women and girls</content></paragraph><paragraph name="39" temporalId="sch0_0_39" id="ID_1525423852878_106"><num value="39">39.</num><content>offences against the law relating to false or misleading trade
                    descriptions</content></paragraph><paragraph name="40" temporalId="sch0_0_40" id="ID_1525423852878_107"><num value="40">40.</num><content>offences relating to the possession or laundering of proceeds obtained from
                    the commission of any offence for which surrender may be granted under this
                    Agreement</content></paragraph><paragraph name="41" temporalId="sch0_0_41" id="ID_1525423852878_108"><num value="41">41.</num><content>impeding the arrest or prosecution of a person who has or is believed to
                    have committed an offence for which surrender may be granted under this
                    Agreement</content></paragraph><paragraph name="42" temporalId="sch0_0_42" id="ID_1525423852878_109"><num value="42">42.</num><content>offences for which persons may be surrendered under multilateral
                    international conventions binding on the Parties, offences created as a result
                    of decisions of international organizations which are binding on the
                    Parties</content></paragraph><paragraph name="43" temporalId="sch0_0_43" id="ID_1525423852878_110"><num value="43">43.</num><content>conspiracy to commit fraud or to
                    defraud</content></paragraph><paragraph name="44" temporalId="sch0_0_44" id="ID_1525423852894_111"><num value="44">44.</num><content>conspiracy to commit, or any type of association to commit, any offence for
                    which surrender may be granted under this
                    Agreement</content></paragraph><paragraph name="45" temporalId="sch0_0_45" id="ID_1525423852894_112"><num value="45">45.</num><content>aiding, abetting, counselling or procuring the commission of, inciting,
                    being an accessory before or after the fact to, or attempting to commit any
                    offence for which surrender may be granted under this
                    Agreement<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph name="46" temporalId="sch0_0_46" id="ID_1525423852894_113"><num value="46">46.</num><content>any other offence for which surrender may be granted in accordance with the
                    laws of both Parties</content></paragraph></subsection><statutoryNote id="ID_1600825892834_001" type="footnote">
            <content>
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="font_size_9" width="446">
                    <colgroup>
                        <col width="9%"></col>
                        <col width="91%"></col>
                    </colgroup>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td align="left">
                                
                                
                                <p>Note:
                                        <sup xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">#</sup></p>
                                
                            </td>
                            <td class="align_justified">
                                
                                
                                <p>The
                                    Agreement between the Government of the Hong Kong Special
                                    Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China and the
                                    Government of the Federal Republic of Germany for the Surrender
                                    of Fugitive Offenders was done in the Chinese, English and
                                    German languages, each text being equally authentic. The German
                                    text of the Agreement is available for inspection at the
                                    Security Bureau of the Government of the
                                    HKSAR.</p>
                                
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </content>
        </statutoryNote></schedule></main></subLeg>