<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 548 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>548A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap548A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-12-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403418407_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2022-12-08">Merchant
                                    Shipping
                                    (Local
                                    Vessels)
                                    (Dwelling
                                    Vessels)
                                    Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap548/s89">Cap.
                                                548, section
                                    89</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted— <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                                                2022</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[2
                                    January 2007]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2006/ln282">L.N. 282 of
                                                2006</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes— <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403418407_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent— <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403418423_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ClosedArea"><term>closed
                area</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">禁區</term>) means an area of the waters of Hong Kong
            specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>;</def><def name="Licence">
            <leadIn><term>licence</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">牌照</term>) means—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438413227450_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a licence issued under the repealed Regulations and in force immediately
                    before the
                        commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Regulation;
                    or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438413227450_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a licence issued under this Regulation;</content></paragraph>
        </def><def name="LicensedDwellingVessel,UnlicensedDwellingVessel"><term>licensed
                dwelling
            vessel</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已領牌住家船隻</term>) means a dwelling vessel in respect of
            which a licence has been issued and is for the time being in force, and
                <term>unlicensed
                dwelling
            vessel</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">未領牌住家船隻</term>) shall be construed accordingly;</def><def name="Licensee">
            <leadIn><term>licensee</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">持牌人</term>) means—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438413227450_055" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a person to whom a licence for the time being in force is issued;
                    or</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438413227465_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a person to whom a licence for the time being in force is transferred under
                        <ref>section 7</ref>;</content></paragraph>
        </def><def name="PeriodOfValidity"><term>period
                of
            validity</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有效期</term>), in relation to a licence, means the period
            from the date of issue of the licence up to and including the date of expiry of the
            licence, both dates as specified in the licence;</def><def name="PrescribedArea"><term>prescribed
                area</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訂明範圍</term>) means an area of the waters of Hong Kong
            specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>;</def><def name="RepealedRegulations"><term>repealed
                Regulations</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已廢除規例</term>) means the Shipping and Port Control
            (Dwelling Vessels) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap313C">Cap. 313 sub. leg.
            C</ref>).</def><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1660813204916_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline><inline> </inline>Commencement date:
                2 January 2007.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403418438_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Licensing of dwelling vessels</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413227497_012" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A licence issued under the repealed Regulations and in force immediately before
                the
                    commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Regulation shall,
                subject to the provisions of this Regulation, continue in force until the expiry of
                its period of validity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227512_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>No person shall use a vessel as a dwelling vessel in a prescribed area, or cause
                or permit a dwelling vessel to enter or remain in a prescribed area,
                unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227512_013" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a licence has been issued in respect of the vessel and is for the time
                    being in force; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227512_021" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the provisions of this Regulation and the conditions specified in the
                    licence are complied with.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227512_028" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, contravenes subsection (2) commits an
                offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6
                months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227512_036" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If an unlicensed dwelling vessel enters or remains in a prescribed area, or if
                a licensed dwelling vessel enters or remains in a prescribed area in contravention
                of any provision of this Regulation or any condition specified in the licence issued
                in respect of the vessel for the time being in force, the person in control of the
                vessel commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to
                imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227528_005" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Director may, on the issue of a licence under <ref>section 4(3)(a)</ref>
                pursuant to an application for renewal or under <ref>section 7(6)(a)</ref> pursuant
                to an application for transfer, specify in the licence such conditions as he
                considers necessary or desirable in the interests of safety or discipline.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227543_005" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Director may, at any time while a licence is in force, make such amendments
                or additions to the conditions specified in the licence as he considers necessary or
                desirable in the interests of safety or discipline and request that the licence be
                delivered to him for amendments or additions to be made under this
                subsection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227543_013" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with a request made by
                the Director under subsection (6) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to
                a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1660813218836_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline><inline> </inline>Commencement date:
                2 January 2007.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403418438_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Renewal of licences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413227590_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The licensee of a licensed dwelling vessel may, at any time during the period of 3 months immediately before the expiry of the period of validity of the licence issued in respect of the vessel, apply for the licence to be renewed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227590_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An application for the renewal of a licence shall be made to the Director in a form specified by him, and shall give such particulars regarding the applicant, the owner of the vessel in respect of which the licence is issued, and every person normally dwelling on the vessel at the time of the making of the application, as the Director may require.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227606_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Director may determine an application for the renewal of a licence made under subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227606_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by issuing a licence to the applicant in accordance with subsection (5); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227606_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by refusing to renew the licence.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227606_028" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If an application for the renewal of a licence is made under subsection (1) and the period of validity of the licence expires before the determination of the application, the licence shall continue in force until the determination of the application, the withdrawal of the application or the cancellation of the licence under <ref>section 8</ref>, whichever occurs first.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227621_005" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>A licence issued under subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227621_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall be in a form determined by the Director;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227621_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall be subject to such conditions as the Director may specify under <ref>section 3(5)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227621_029" name="c" temporalId="s4_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>subject to the provisions of this Regulation, shall be in force for its period of validity, which shall expire on the first anniversary of the expiry of the period of validity of the licence sought to be renewed.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227621_036" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>No fee shall be payable in respect of the renewal of a licence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227621_044" name="7" temporalId="s4_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>The licensee of a licensed dwelling vessel shall surrender the licence issued in respect of the vessel to the Director—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227621_052" name="a" temporalId="s4_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>upon the renewal of the licence under this section;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227637_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>upon the expiry of the period of validity of the licence or, where the licence continues in force by virtue of subsection (4) or <ref>section 7(5)</ref>, upon the licence ceasing to be in force; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227637_014" name="c" temporalId="s4_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>upon the cancellation of the licence under <ref>section 8</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever occurs first.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227637_027" name="8" temporalId="s4_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>A licensee who contravenes subsection (7) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418454_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Owner to notify Director of change in ownership</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413227684_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If, at any time while a licence is in force, a change occurs in the ownership of the dwelling vessel in respect of which the licence is issued, the new owner of the vessel shall, within 72 hours after the occurrence of the change, notify the Director of the change in a form specified by the Director and deliver the licence to the Director for amendment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227684_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On receipt of a notification of a change in ownership given under subsection (1), the Director shall cause the particulars of the change to be noted, free of charge, on the licence issued in respect of the vessel concerned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227699_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, contravenes subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418469_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Painting of licence number and other particulars on vessel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413227715_027" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The licensee of a licensed dwelling vessel shall, at all times while the licence issued in respect of the vessel is in force, ensure—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227731_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the licence number specified in the licence and such other particulars of the licence as the Director may specify are painted on the vessel; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227731_013" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the painting of the licence number and other particulars on the vessel under paragraph (a) is done and maintained in such manner as the Director may specify.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227731_020" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A licensee who contravenes subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227731_028" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, damages, obliterates or defaces the licence number or any of the particulars painted on a licensed dwelling vessel in accordance with subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418469_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Licence to be transferred only in certain circumstances</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413227762_020" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A licence shall not be transferred, except as provided in this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227762_028" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the licensee of a licensed dwelling vessel dies at any time during the period of validity of the licence issued in respect of the vessel, the surviving spouse, parent, parent-in-law, or eldest child over the age of 16 years, of the deceased licensee, in that order, may apply to the Director for the licence to be transferred to him until the expiry of its period of validity, if he was dwelling on the vessel at the time when a licence was first issued in respect of the vessel under the repealed Regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227777_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the persons dwelling on a licensed dwelling vessel comprise members of more than one family and the licensee of the vessel and members of his family cease to dwell on the vessel at any time during the period of validity of the licence issued in respect of the vessel, a person, other than the licensee or a member of his family, may apply to the Director for the licence to be transferred to him until the expiry of its period of validity, if he is nominated by the family or families continuing to dwell on the vessel so to apply and if he was dwelling on the vessel at the time when a licence was first issued in respect of the vessel under the repealed Regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227809_005" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (6), the Director may determine an application for the transfer of a licence made under subsection (2) or (3)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227809_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by transferring the licence to the applicant until the expiry of its period of validity; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227809_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by refusing to transfer the licence.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227809_028" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If an application for the transfer of a licence is made under subsection (2) or (3) and the period of validity of the licence expires before the determination of the application, the licence shall continue in force until the determination of the application, the withdrawal of the application or the cancellation of the licence under <ref>section 8</ref>, whichever occurs first.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227824_005" name="6" temporalId="s7_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>If an application for the transfer of a licence is made under subsection (2) or (3) and the period of validity of the licence expires before the determination of the application, the Director may determine the application—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227824_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by issuing a licence to the applicant in accordance with subsection (7), in which case the Director shall be deemed to have determined the application in the manner provided in subsection <ref>(4)(a)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227824_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by refusing to issue such a licence, in which case the Director shall be deemed to have determined the application in the manner provided in subsection <ref>(4)(b)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227840_005" name="7" temporalId="s7_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>A licence issued under subsection <ref>(6)(a)</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227840_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall be in a form determined by the Director;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227840_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall be subject to such conditions as the Director may specify under <ref>section 3(5)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227840_029" name="c" temporalId="s7_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>subject to the provisions of this Regulation, shall be in force for its period of validity, which shall be of the same length as the portion of the period of validity of the licence sought to be transferred that remained unexpired at the time of the making of the application for transfer.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227840_036" name="8" temporalId="s7_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>If, in the circumstances described in subsection (2) or (3), there is no person who may apply for the transfer of the licence in question under the relevant subsection, the licence in question shall lapse and the Director may require any person in possession of that licence to surrender it.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418485_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Discretion to cancel licence</heading><content>Without prejudice to <ref>section 12</ref>, the Director may, at any time while a licence is in force, cancel the licence for contravention of any condition specified in the licence or of any provision under this Regulation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403418501_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Licence to be kept on board and produced for inspection</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413227918_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A licence shall, at all times while it is in force, be kept on board the dwelling vessel in respect of which it is issued and be produced on demand to any authorized officer by the licensee or any person normally dwelling on the vessel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413227918_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, fails to produce a licence when called upon to do so by an authorized officer commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418501_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Issue of duplicate licence if original destroyed, etc.</heading><content>Where a licence for the time being in force is destroyed, defaced or lost, the Director may, if he is satisfied as to the destruction, defacement or loss, issue a duplicate licence free of charge, and the duplicate licence shall have the same force and effect as the original licence and shall be regarded for all purposes of this Regulation as if it were the original licence.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403418532_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Penalty for fraudulent alteration or use of licence</heading><content>A person who fraudulently alters or uses a licence, or permits a licence to be fraudulently altered or used, commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 3 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403418532_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Contravention of condition of licence</heading><content>If the licensee of a licensed dwelling vessel contravenes, without reasonable excuse, any condition specified in the licence issued in respect of the vessel for the time being in force, he commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403418547_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Replacement of unsafe vessels</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413227996_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director may permit the licensee of a licensed dwelling vessel to replace the vessel with another vessel if the Director is satisfied—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413227996_012" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the vessel to be replaced is unsafe and will be surrendered to the Director for destruction or disposal under subsection (3);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227996_020" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the replacement vessel is safe;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227996_028" name="c" temporalId="s13_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that the dimensions of the replacement vessel are no larger than those of the vessel to be replaced; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413227996_036" name="d" temporalId="s13_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that the licensee and the persons normally dwelling on the vessel to be replaced provide a service to other vessels in the vicinity.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228011_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director may require a replacement vessel to be examined, free of charge to the licensee, by a person authorized by him to ensure that it complies with paragraphs (b) and (c) of subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228011_013" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the Director permits the replacement of a vessel under this section, the vessel shall be surrendered by the licensee to the Director for destruction or disposal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228011_021" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A licensee who fails to surrender a vessel in accordance with subsection (3) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418563_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Director may require information</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413228074_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may, from time to time, request the licensee of a licensed dwelling vessel to inform him of the name, age and identity card number of any person normally dwelling on the vessel at the time of the making of the request, and of the relationship of such person to the licensee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228074_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A licensee who, having been requested to give information under subsection (1), fails to do so or gives information which he knows or reasonably ought to know to be false in a material particular, commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418563_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Closed areas</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413228105_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall cause or permit a dwelling vessel to enter or remain in a closed area.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228105_012" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who contravenes subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418579_001" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Dwelling vessels in closed area or unlicensed dwelling vessels in prescribed
            area</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413228121_019" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may by notice order that a dwelling vessel in a closed area be
                removed from the closed area or that an unlicensed dwelling vessel in a prescribed
                area be removed from the prescribed area.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228136_005" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A notice given under subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413228136_013" name="a" temporalId="s16_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall be addressed to the owner or licensee of the vessel or generally to
                    all persons normally dwelling on the vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228136_021" name="b" temporalId="s16_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall be served by affixing it to the mast or any other prominent part of
                    the vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228136_029" name="c" temporalId="s16_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>shall order the person or persons to whom the notice is addressed to remove
                    the vessel or cause it to be removed from the closed area or the prescribed
                    area, as the case may be, within such time (being not less than 14 days) as is
                    specified in the notice; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228136_037" name="d" temporalId="s16_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>shall give a brief description of the powers exercisable by the Director
                    under this Regulation if the vessel is not removed as ordered by the
                    notice.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228136_044" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with a notice given
                under subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at
                level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228152_005" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>If a vessel is not removed as ordered by a notice given under subsection (1),
                the Director may do any or all of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413228152_013" name="a" temporalId="s16_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>seize the vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228152_021" name="b" temporalId="s16_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>remove the vessel or cause it to be removed from the closed area or the
                    prescribed area, as the case may be;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228152_029" name="c" temporalId="s16_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>detain the vessel.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228152_036" name="5" temporalId="s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a vessel has been seized and detained under subsection (4), and
                regardless of whether the vessel has been removed under that subsection, the
                Director may remove any person or property found on the vessel and may take
                possession of any property found on the vessel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228167_005" name="6" temporalId="s16_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>As soon as practicable after seizing and detaining a vessel under subsection
                (4), and regardless of whether the vessel has been removed under that subsection,
                the Director shall serve a notice of the seizure and detention on the persons whom
                the Director believes to be the owner and the licensee of the vessel, and on every
                person whom the Director believes to be the owner or otherwise entitled to the
                possession of any property on board the vessel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228167_013" name="7" temporalId="s16_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>A notice served under subsection (6) shall be deemed to have been duly served on
                the person on whom it is to be served—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413228167_021" name="a" temporalId="s16_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the notice is delivered to the person concerned;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228183_006" name="b" temporalId="s16_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the notice is sent by registered post addressed to that person at the
                    place of residence or business of that person, if any, last known to the
                    Director; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228183_014" name="c" temporalId="s16_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>(where it cannot be served in accordance with paragraph (a) or (b)) if the
                    notice is published in the Gazette.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228183_021" name="8" temporalId="s16_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>A notice served under subsection (6) shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413228183_029" name="a" temporalId="s16_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>state the names (if known to the Director) of the persons whom the Director
                    believes to be the owner and the licensee of the vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228183_037" name="b" temporalId="s16_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>state the name (if known to the Director) of every person whom the Director
                    believes to be the owner or otherwise entitled to the possession of any property
                    on board the vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228183_045" name="c" temporalId="s16_8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>describe the vessel and the place at which it was seized;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228183_053" name="d" temporalId="s16_8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>describe the property on board the vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228183_061" name="e" temporalId="s16_8_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>give the reason for the seizure and detention of the vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228199_006" name="f" temporalId="s16_8_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>specify the position where the vessel is secured, anchored or moored during
                    its detention;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228199_014" name="g" temporalId="s16_8_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>specify the action (if any) required to secure the release of the vessel or
                    any property on board the vessel; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228199_022" name="h" temporalId="s16_8_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>specify the period (being not less than 14 days) within which a claim may
                    be submitted to the Director for the release of the vessel or any property on
                    board the vessel, and the place at which such a claim may be
                    submitted.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228199_029" name="9" temporalId="s16_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>The Director may, for the purposes of subsection <ref>(8)(g)</ref>, specify any
                action required to secure the release of a vessel or any property on board the
                vessel, and any such action may include the payment of any expense incurred as a
                result of or in connection with any action taken or caused to be taken by the
                Director under this section in respect of the vessel or the property in question, as
                the case may
                be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1603421328390_001" name="10" temporalId="s16_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>A person who obstructs the Director in the exercise of any of the powers
                conferred by subsection (4) or (5) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to
                a fine at level 2 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418579_003" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Release of detained vessels, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413228277_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A claim for the release of a vessel that is the subject of a notice served under <ref>section 16(6)</ref>, or for the release of any property on board the vessel, may be submitted to the Director, subject to compliance with the following requirements—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413228277_012" name="a" temporalId="s17_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the claim shall be submitted, in the case of a claim for the release of the vessel, by the owner or licensee of the vessel and, in the case of a claim for the release of any property on board the vessel, by the person who is the owner or otherwise entitled to the possession of the property in question; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228292_006" name="b" temporalId="s17_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the claim shall be submitted within the period and at the place specified in the notice.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228292_013" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If a claim is submitted to the Director for the release of a vessel that is the subject of a notice served under <ref>section 16(6)</ref> or for the release of any property on board the vessel, and if the Director is satisfied that the claim is submitted in accordance with the requirements set out in subsection (1) and that the action specified in the notice under <ref>section 16(8)(g)</ref> in respect of the vessel or the property in question, as the case may be, has been carried out, then the Director shall release the vessel or the property in question, as the case may be, to the claimant.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418610_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Sale of detained vessels, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413228339_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a vessel that is the subject of a notice served under <ref>section 16(6)</ref> is not released pursuant to <ref>section 17(2)</ref>, the Director may sell the vessel by public auction or otherwise as he thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228339_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The proceeds of sale of a vessel sold under subsection (1), after deducting all expenses incurred as a result of or in connection with the seizure, removal, detention and sale of the vessel, shall be paid to the owner of the vessel if he claims them within 1 year after the date of the sale, or forfeited to the Government if the owner of the vessel does not claim them within that period.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228355_005" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A vessel that the Director is unable to sell under subsection (1) may be destroyed or otherwise disposed of as the Director thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228355_013" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If any property on board a vessel that is the subject of a notice served under <ref>section 16(6)</ref> is not released pursuant to <ref>section 17(2)</ref>, such property shall become the property of the Government free from the rights of any person and may be disposed of by the Director as he thinks fit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418625_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Appeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413228386_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any person aggrieved by a decision of the Director—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413228386_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to specify any condition in a licence under <ref>section 3(5)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228386_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to make any amendment or addition to the conditions specified in a licence under <ref>section 3(6)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228386_028" name="c" temporalId="s19_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to refuse to renew a licence under <ref>section 4(3)(b)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228386_036" name="d" temporalId="s19_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to refuse to transfer a licence under <ref>section 7(4)(b)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228401_006" name="e" temporalId="s19_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to cancel a licence under <ref>section 8</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228401_014" name="f" temporalId="s19_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to refuse to permit the replacement of a vessel under <ref>section 13</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228401_022" name="g" temporalId="s19_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>to specify any action required to secure the release of a vessel or any property on board the vessel under <ref>section 16(9)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228401_030" name="h" temporalId="s19_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>to refuse to release a vessel or any property on board the vessel under <ref>section 17(2)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>may, within 14 days after the day on which he is informed of the decision, appeal to the Administrative Appeals Board against the decision.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228401_043" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If a decision referred to in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e) or (f) of subsection (1) is appealed against under that subsection, the decision concerned shall be suspended in its operation from the day on which notice of the appeal is lodged until the appeal is disposed of, withdrawn or abandoned, unless such suspension would, in the opinion of the Director, be contrary to the public interest and the notice of that decision contains a statement to that effect.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228417_005" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If a decision referred to in paragraph (g) of subsection (1) is appealed against under that subsection, then, as against the person making the appeal—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413228417_013" name="a" temporalId="s19_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the period within which a claim may be submitted to the Director for the release of the vessel concerned or any property on board that vessel, specified in the notice served in respect of that vessel under <ref>section 16(6)</ref>, shall not begin to run until the appeal is disposed of, withdrawn or abandoned; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413228433_006" name="b" temporalId="s19_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the notice shall otherwise have effect subject to the outcome of the appeal.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413228433_013" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If a decision referred to in paragraph (h) of subsection (1) is appealed against under that subsection, the decision concerned shall be suspended in its operation from the day on which notice of the appeal is lodged until the appeal is disposed of, withdrawn or abandoned.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403418625_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Amendment of <ref>Schedules</ref></heading><content>The Director may, by notice published in the Gazette, amend either or both of the <ref>Schedules</ref>.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403418641_002" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap548A/s2">ss. 2</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap548A/s20">20</ref>]</note><heading>Closed
            Areas<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text class="align_justified">All waters of Hong Kong except Causeway Bay Typhoon Shelter
            and Cheung Chau Typhoon Shelter.</text></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403418641_004" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-12-08" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
                                    2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap548A/s2">ss. 2</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap548A/s20">20</ref>]</note><heading>Prescribed
                                    Areas<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text class="first_line_indent_0">Causeway Bay Typhoon Shelter<br></br>Cheung Chau Typhoon Shelter</text></schedule></main></subLeg>