<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 357</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>357</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap357!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-09-16</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403047020_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-09-16">
            <content>To provide for the creation of easements in and over land in favour of certain
                undertakings which generate, transmit or distribute electricity; and for matters
                incidental thereto and connected therewith.</content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[11 July 1980]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403047036_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Electricity Networks (Statutory Easements) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403047036_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ApprovedScheme"><term class="old_format"><b><i>approved
                        scheme</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">獲准計劃</term>) means a scheme approved by the Secretary
            for Development for the purposes of <ref>section 3</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/ln245">L.N. 245 of 1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln244">L.N. 244 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/ln330">L.N. 330 of 1999</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ElectricLine"><term class="old_format"><b><i>electric
                        line</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電力線</term>) means a wire, cable, conductor or other
            means of transmitting or distributing electricity from one location to another above or
            below ground, and any casing, coating, covering, tube, pipe, insulator, pole, mast or
            pylon enclosing, surrounding or supporting the same or any part thereof or any apparatus
            or ancillary facilities connected therewith;</def><def name="ElectricityNetwork"><term class="old_format"><b><i>electricity
                        network</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">供電網絡</term>) means a system for the transmission or
            distribution of electrical energy consisting of one or more electric lines, but does not
            include any such system which is in operation at the
            commencement*
            of this Ordinance;</def><def name="Owner">
            <leadIn><term class="old_format"><b><i>owner</i></b></term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>), in relation to any land,
                means—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412056844_019" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a person registered or entitled to be registered as owner of such land in
                    the Land Registry;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412056844_027" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a person having any estate or interest in such land, or in lawful
                    occupation thereof, under an instrument registered in the Land Registry;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of
                            1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
        </def><def name="PowerCompany"><term class="old_format"><b><i>power
                        company</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電力公司</term>) means a person or any body of persons,
            corporate or unincorporate, by whom electricity is generated or transmitted or
            distributed;</def><def name="Route"><term class="old_format"><b><i>route</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">線路</term>) means the alignment of the electric lines of
            an electricity network as specified by the terms of the approved scheme relating to such
            electricity network;</def><def name="Terms"><term class="old_format"><b><i>terms</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">條款</term>), in relation to an approved scheme, includes
            the conditions, specifications, restrictions and other stipulations contained therein,
            and any plans, maps, drawings or other documents forming part thereof or referred to
            therein;</def><def name="Works"><term class="old_format"><b><i>works</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">工程</term>) means the construction, operation,
            maintenance, repair or replacement of an electricity network or any part thereof, or the
            investigation or examination thereof or of any land situated on the route thereof.</def><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1626923520366_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 11 July
                1980.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403047052_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Provisions of Ordinance to apply to power company by order of Chief Executive in
            Council</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412056891_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the Chief Executive in Council is satisfied that a power company is
                carrying out or is about to carry out any works relating to an electricity network
                across any land in Hong Kong in accordance with the terms of a scheme approved by
                the Secretary for Development for the purposes of this section, the Chief Executive
                in Council may, at the request of the company made in writing to the Secretary for
                Development, order that the provisions of this Ordinance shall apply to the company
                for the purpose of enabling the company to carry out such works in accordance with
                the approved scheme.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/ln245">L.N. 245 of 1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln244">L.N. 244 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/ln330">L.N. 330 of 1999</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412056907_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Before an order is made under this section in respect of an electricity
                network, the approved scheme relating thereto shall be deposited in the Land
                    Registry.<inline class="width_3"></inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993
                    s.2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412056907_013" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>It shall be sufficient for the purposes of an order made under this section to
                refer therein to an approved scheme by the description and date assigned thereto in
                the Land Registry for the purposes of subsection
                    (2).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993
                        s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047067_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Statutory easements</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412056953_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to this Ordinance, a power company specified in an order made under
                    <ref>section 3</ref> may, in accordance with the terms of the approved scheme
                relating to the electricity network in respect of which the order is made, exercise
                from time to time all or any of the following rights in or over land situated on the
                route of such electricity network—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412056953_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the right to place and retain any electric line above or below ground
                    across such land; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412056953_027" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the right to carry out any works required for the purposes of paragraph (a)
                    on such land, including the right to excavate, drain, remove or cover over any
                    part of the soil of such land, and to lop, cut or remove any trees, shrubs,
                    growing crops or vegetation of any kind on such land which obstruct or interfere
                    with any electric line; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412056953_035" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the right to enter on and pass over or under such land with such persons,
                    animals, vehicles and equipment and to do all such acts thereon as may be
                    necessary for or incidental to the exercise of any right conferred by this
                    section,</content></paragraph><continued>but nothing in this section shall authorize the power company to place,
                construct, erect or retain any permanent structure, pole, mast or pylon on such
                land.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412056969_011" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Land">In this section
                    <term class="old_format"><b><i>land</i></b></term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地</term>) does not include unleased land within
                the meaning of the Land (Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap28">Cap. 28</ref>) which is not occupied under Part II of that Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of
                        1998 s. 70</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047067_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Easements not to have effect until order registered</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412056985_041" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The rights conferred by <ref>section 4</ref> shall not be exercisable in or over any land by virtue of an order made under <ref>section 3</ref> unless the order is registered under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057000_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>It shall be the duty of the power company specified in an order made under <ref>section 3</ref> to register the order under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>) not later than 14 days after the date of publication of the order in the Gazette.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047083_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Registration of order to be advertised in press</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412057016_010" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Where an order made under <ref>section 3</ref> is registered under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>), the power company specified in the order shall, once in each of 2 consecutive weeks, publish in 2 Chinese language newspapers and an English language newspaper an advertisement containing the matters specified in subsection (2) in respect of such order:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_1_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412057016_025" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>such period of 2 consecutive weeks shall, for the purposes of this section, be deemed to commence on the date of publication of the first such advertisement;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057016_033" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the first such advertisement shall be so published not later than 14 days after the date of registration of such order.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057031_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>An advertisement published under this section shall contain—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412057031_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a statement of the fact that an order made under <ref>section 3</ref> has been registered under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057031_021" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the number and date of the order, the date of registration and the number of the memorial thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057031_029" name="c" temporalId="s6_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>particulars of the land affected by the order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057031_037" name="d" temporalId="s6_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a statement of the rights exercisable in or over such land under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057031_045" name="e" temporalId="s6_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the name and business address of the power company specified in the order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057031_053" name="f" temporalId="s6_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>a statement that claims for compensation under <ref>section 10</ref> may be submitted in writing to the company at that address not later than 12 months after the date of registration of the order and, if the parties fail to agree, to the Lands Tribunal for final determination.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047083_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Rectification etc. of approved scheme</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412057172_011" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive may, at the request in writing (addressed to the Secretary
                for Development) of a power company specified in an order made under <ref>section
                    3</ref>, direct that the terms of the approved scheme in respect of which the
                order is made shall be rectified, modified or varied in such manner and to such
                extent as may be agreed in writing by the company and the Secretary for Development,
                and any such agreement shall be deposited in the Land Registry and annexed to the
                copy of the scheme deposited therein under <ref>section 3(2)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/ln245">L.N.
                        245 of 1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln244">L.N. 244 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999
                        s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/ln330">L.N. 330 of 1999</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057219_004" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an agreement for the rectification, modification or variation of the
                terms of an approved scheme is deposited in the Land Registry under subsection (1),
                the Chief Executive may by order declare that, subject to subsection (3), the
                approved scheme shall have effect subject to such rectification, modification or
                variation, as the case may be; and any reference in this Ordinance or any order
                thereunder to an approved scheme shall be construed as including a reference to an
                approved scheme as so rectified, modified or varied.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057219_012" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where the terms of an approved scheme are rectified, modified or varied by an
                order made under subsection (2) in such manner or to such extent that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412057234_005" name="a" temporalId="s7_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any part of the route of the electricity network comprised in the scheme is
                    altered; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057234_013" name="b" temporalId="s7_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any reference therein to land is added or substituted,</content></paragraph><continued>the rights conferred by <ref>section 4</ref> shall not be exercisable in or
                over any land affected by the part of the route which is so altered or in respect of
                which such reference is so added or substituted unless the order is registered under
                the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>).</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057234_026" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><ref>Sections 5(2)</ref> and <ref>6</ref> shall apply in relation to the
                registration of an order made under subsection (2) as they apply in relation to the
                registration of an order made under <ref>section 3</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047098_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Right of access over other land</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412057265_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to this Ordinance, where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412057265_019" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a power company specified in an order made under <ref>section 3</ref>
                    intends to carry out any works relating to the electricity network in respect of
                    which the order is made; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057265_027" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it is necessary for that purpose for the company’s officers, servants or
                    agents or other persons authorized by the company to enter on and cross over any
                    land in order to gain access to the site of such works,</content></paragraph><continued>the company, its officers, servants or agents or other persons authorized by
                the company in that behalf may enter on and cross over such land to and from such
                site with such persons, animals, vehicles and equipment as may be necessary for or
                incidental to the carrying out of such works.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057281_004" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall apply to unleased land within the meaning of the
                Land (Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap28">Cap. 28</ref>)
                which is not occupied under Part II of that Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                    70</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047114_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Restrictions on exercise of rights under <ref>section 4</ref> or
            <ref>8</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438412057312_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to this section, a power company shall, before exercising any right
                conferred by <ref>section 4</ref> or <ref>8</ref> in respect of any land, serve
                notice of its intention to do so on the owner of the land; and for the purposes of
                this section notice shall be deemed to have been duly served on the owner of land
                if, but only if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412057328_005" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it is delivered to him; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057328_013" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it is sent by registered post addressed to him at his last postal address
                    known to the power company; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057328_021" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>where the owner is not known or cannot be found or for any reason it is not
                    practicable to serve the notice in accordance with paragraph (a) or (b), it is
                    published—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412057328_029" name="i" temporalId="s9_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the Gazette; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412057328_037" name="ii" temporalId="s9_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in 2 Chinese language newspapers and an English language
                        newspaper,</content></subparagraph></paragraph><continued>not less than 30 days prior to the exercise of such right:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_1_proviso">Provided that in the case of
                emergency, a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>power company intending to exercise
                any such right in respect of any land may notify the owner of such land of its
                intention in such manner as the power company may deem practicable in the
                circumstances of the case, and subsections (2), (3) and (4) shall not apply to such
                case.</proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057343_004" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the owner of any land on whom notice is served by a power company under
                subsection (1) wishes to object to the exercise by the power company of any rights
                to which the notice refers, he shall, before the expiration of the period of such
                notice, notify the power company in writing of his objection and the grounds
                thereof, and the power company shall, unless the objection is sooner withdrawn or
                resolved, deliver particulars in writing thereof to the Secretary for Development
                not later than 14 days after the expiration of such period.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057359_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where particulars of any objection are delivered to the Secretary for
                Development under subsection (2), he may direct a public officer to attend, within a
                period of not more than 30 days after the date of delivery of such particulars, on
                the owner by whom the objection is made and the power company, respectively, and to
                receive and record any representations as to the matters in dispute put forward by
                the owner or the power company, as the case may be, and to submit a report in
                respect thereof for the consideration of the Secretary for Development.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057375_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Secretary for Development shall consider any objection of which particulars
                are delivered to him under subsection (2) and any report directed to be submitted to
                him under subsection (3) in respect thereof, and shall give such directions to the
                power company relating to the exercise by the power company of any rights to which
                the objection relates as he may deem proper having regard to the public interest and
                shall give notice of such directions to the owner concerned; and it shall be the
                duty of the power company and the owner to comply with such directions.</content><sourceNote class="align_right">(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/ln245">L.N. 245 of
                    1981</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1989/ln244">L.N. 244 of 1989</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/ln330">L.N. 330 of 1999</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N.
                    106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                2007</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047130_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Compensation for diminution of value of land</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412057421_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an order made under this Ordinance affecting any land is registered by a
                power company under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap.
                    128</ref>), the company shall be liable to pay compensation to the person who,
                at the date of registration of the order, is the owner of the land in respect of any
                diminution of the value of his estate or interest therein attributable to the
                registration of the order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057437_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person claiming to be entitled to be paid compensation by a power company
                under this section in respect of any land may, not later than 12 months after the
                date of registration of an order made under this Ordinance affecting such land,
                deliver particulars of the claim in writing to the company.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057437_013" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If, within a period of 28 days after the delivery of the particulars of any
                claim to a power company under this section, the claimant and the company fail to
                reach agreement in respect of the company’s liability, if any, under this section,
                the claimant may, not later than 60 days after the expiration of that period, submit
                the claim to the Lands Tribunal for determination.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057453_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Lands Tribunal shall have jurisdiction to determine the amount of
                compensation, if any, payable in the case of any claim submitted to the Tribunal
                under this section; and in the application of the Lands Tribunal Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap17">Cap. 17</ref>) to any such determination, <ref>section
                    11(1)</ref> of that Ordinance shall have effect as if for paragraphs (a) and (b)
                thereof there were substituted the words “the amount of compensation payable in the
                case of any claim submitted to it under <ref>section 10</ref> of the Electricity
                Networks (Statutory Easements) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap357">Cap.
                357</ref>)”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057468_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>In the determination of the amount of compensation, if any, payable under this
                section, no compensation shall be given in respect of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412057468_013" name="a" temporalId="s10_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any expectancy or probability of the grant or renewal or continuance by the
                    Government or any person of any licence, permission, lease or permit
                    whatsoever;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057468_021" name="b" temporalId="s10_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any use of the land which is not in accordance with the terms of the
                    Government lease under which the land is held.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                            71</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057468_028" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><def name="Value">For the purposes of this section,
                    <term class="old_format"><b><i>value</i></b></term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">值</term>), in relation to any land affected by an
                order made under this Ordinance, means the open market value of the land assessed as
                at the date of registration of the order.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047145_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Liability for loss or damage</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412057499_027" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to this section, nothing in this Ordinance shall affect the liability of any person in respect of any loss or damage caused by or arising out of the exercise of any rights under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057499_035" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where by reason of the exercise by a power company of any rights under this Ordinance in or over any land—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412057499_043" name="a" temporalId="s11_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any fixtures, growing crops, farm produce or plants on such land are damaged; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412057515_006" name="b" temporalId="s11_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of land which is used exclusively for the purpose of tillage, the use of such land for that purpose is temporarily prevented or restricted to such extent as to cause any loss,</content></paragraph><continued>the company shall be liable for such loss or damage notwithstanding that the company acted with reasonable care or that the loss or damage could not have been avoided without preventing or hindering the exercise of such rights:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s11_2_proviso">Provided that if the company proves that the loss or damage resulted wholly or partially either from an act or omission done with intent to cause any loss or damage by the person who suffered the loss or damage or from the negligence of that person, the company shall be exonerated wholly or partially from its liability to such person.</proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412057515_026" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>This section shall not apply in relation to any claim for compensation in respect of the diminution of the value of any estate or interest in land.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403047145_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Offence to obstruct power company</heading><content>Any person who wilfully obstructs or interferes with the lawful
                                    exercise by any power company or its officers or servants or
                                    agents, or persons authorized by the company in that
                                    behalf,
                                    of any rights exercisable by the company under this Ordinance in
                                    respect of any land commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                                    at
                                    level 2 and to imprisonment for 6
                                    months.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                                    2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></ordinance>