<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 525 sub. leg. W</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>525W</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap525W!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-04-23</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403326074_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-04-23">Mutual
            Legal Assistance in Criminal Matters (Corruption) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap525/s4">Cap. 525, section
                4</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote class="align_right">(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3
                of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[22 February 2008]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2007/ln235">L.N. 235 of 2007</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote class="align_right">(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403326074_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403326089_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Ordinance to apply between Hong Kong and certain places outside Hong Kong</heading><content>In relation to the arrangements for mutual legal assistance the terms of which are recited in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>, it is directed that the Ordinance shall, subject to the modifications specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>, apply as between Hong Kong and the places outside Hong Kong to which the arrangements relate.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403326136_001" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap525W/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>United
            Nations Convention against Corruption</heading><crossHeading class="align_center ">PREAMBLE</crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>The States Parties to this Convention,</i></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Concerned</i> about the seriousness of problems and threats posed by corruption to the stability and security of societies, undermining the institutions and values of democracy, ethical values and justice and jeopardizing sustainable development and the rule of law,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Concerned also</i> about the links between corruption and other forms of crime, in particular organized crime and economic crime, including money-laundering,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Concerned further</i> about cases of corruption that involve vast quantities of assets, which may constitute a substantial proportion of the resources of States, and that threaten the political stability and sustainable development of those States,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced</i> that corruption is no longer a local matter but a transnational phenomenon that affects all societies and economies, making international cooperation to prevent and control it essential,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced</i>
            <i>also</i> that a comprehensive and multidisciplinary approach is required to prevent and combat corruption effectively,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced further</i> that the availability of technical assistance can play an important role in enhancing the ability of States, including by strengthening capacity and by institution-building, to prevent and combat corruption effectively,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Convinced</i> that the illicit acquisition of personal wealth can be particularly damaging to democratic institutions, national economies and the rule of law,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Determined</i> to prevent, detect and deter in a more effective manner international transfers of illicitly acquired assets and to strengthen international cooperation in asset recovery,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Acknowledging</i> the fundamental principles of due process of law in criminal proceedings and in civil or administrative proceedings to adjudicate property rights,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Bearing in mind</i> that the prevention and eradication of corruption is a responsibility of all States and that they must cooperate with one another, with the support and involvement of individuals and groups outside the public sector, such as civil society, non-governmental organizations and community-based organizations, if their efforts in this area are to be effective,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Bearing also in mind</i> the principles of proper management of public affairs and public property, fairness, responsibility and equality before the law and the need to safeguard integrity and to foster a culture of rejection of corruption,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Commending</i> the work of the Commission on Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice and the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime in preventing and combating corruption,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Recalling</i> the work carried out by other international and regional organizations in this field, including the activities of the African Union, the Council of Europe, the Customs Cooperation Council (also known as the World Customs Organization), the European Union, the League of Arab States, the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development and the Organization of American States,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Taking note with appreciation</i> of multilateral instruments to prevent and combat corruption, including, inter alia, the Inter-American Convention against Corruption, adopted by the Organization of American States on 29 March 1996, the Convention on the Fight against Corruption involving Officials of the European Communities or Officials of Member States of the European Union, adopted by the Council of the European Union on 26 May 1997, the Convention on Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials in International Business Transactions, adopted by the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development on 21 November 1997, the Criminal Law Convention on Corruption, adopted by the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe on 27 January 1999, the Civil Law Convention on Corruption, adopted by the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe on 4 November 1999, and the African Union Convention on Preventing and
            Combating Corruption, adopted by the Heads of State and Government of the African Union on 12 July 2003,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Welcoming</i> the entry into force on 29 September 2003 of the United Nations Convention against Transnational Organized Crime,</text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><i>Have agreed as follows</i>:</text><crossHeading>Chapter I</crossHeading><crossHeading>General provisions</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438412999919_033" name="P1" temporalId="sch1_P1" class="no_header"><crossHeading class="align_center"><i><inline class="not_bold">Article
                1</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Statement of
                purpose</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704899_001" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><paragraph id="ID_1521794704899_002" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0"><leadIn class="left_indent_24">The purposes of this Convention are:</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999919_062" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To promote and
                            strengthen measures to prevent and combat corruption more efficiently
                            and effectively;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999919_071" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To promote, facilitate
                            and support international cooperation and technical assistance in the
                            prevention of and fight against corruption, including in asset
                            recovery;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999919_080" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To promote integrity,
                            accountability and proper management of public affairs and public
                            property.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subparagraph></paragraph></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438412999919_083" name="P2" temporalId="sch1_P2" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 2</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Use of
                terms</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704899_003" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><paragraph id="ID_1521794704899_004" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0"><leadIn class="left_indent_24">For the purposes of this Convention:</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999919_112" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Public official</term>” shall mean: (i) any person holding a
                            legislative, executive, administrative or judicial office of a State
                            Party, whether appointed or elected, whether permanent or temporary,
                            whether paid or unpaid, irrespective of that person’s seniority; (ii)
                            any other person who performs a public function, including for a public
                            agency or public enterprise, or provides a public service, as defined in
                            the domestic law of the State Party and as applied in the pertinent area
                            of law of that State Party; (iii) any other person defined as a “public
                            official” in the domestic law of a State Party. However, for the purpose
                            of some specific measures contained in chapter II of this Convention,
                            “public official” may mean any person who performs a public function or
                            provides a public service as defined in the domestic law of the State
                            Party and as applied in the pertinent area of law of that State
                            Party;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999950_006" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content name="ForeignPublicOfficial" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Foreign public official</term>”
                            shall mean any person holding a legislative, executive, administrative
                            or judicial office of a foreign country, whether appointed or elected;
                            and any person exercising a public function for a foreign country,
                            including for a public agency or public enterprise;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999950_014" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-2"><content name="OfficialOfAPublicInternationalOrganization" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Official of a public
                                international organization</term>” shall mean an international civil
                            servant or any person who is authorized by such an organization to act
                            on behalf of that organization;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999950_022" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-3"><content name="Property" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Property</term>” shall mean assets of every kind, whether corporeal
                            or incorporeal, movable or immovable, tangible or intangible, and legal
                            documents or instruments evidencing title to or interest in such
                            assets;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999965_006" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-4"><content class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Proceeds of
                                crime</term>” shall mean any property derived from or obtained,
                            directly or indirectly, through the commission of an offence;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999965_014" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-5"><content name="Freezing,Seizure" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Freezing</term>” or “<term class="old_format">seizure</term>” shall
                            mean temporarily prohibiting the transfer, conversion, disposition or
                            movement of property or temporarily assuming custody or control of
                            property on the basis of an order issued by a court or other competent
                            authority;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999965_022" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-6"><content name="Confiscation" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(g)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Confiscation</term>”, which includes forfeiture where applicable,
                            shall mean the permanent deprivation of property by order of a court or
                            other competent authority;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999965_030" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-7"><content name="PredicateOffence" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(h)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Predicate offence</term>” shall mean any offence as a result of
                            which proceeds have been generated that may become the subject of an
                            offence as defined in article 23 of this Convention;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412999965_038" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_s0_0_0-8"><content name="ControlledDelivery" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>“<term class="old_format">Controlled delivery</term>”
                            shall mean the technique of allowing illicit or suspect consignments to
                            pass out of, through or into the territory of one or more States, with
                            the knowledge and under the supervision of their competent authorities,
                            with a view to the investigation of an offence and the identification of
                            persons involved in the commission of the
                            offence.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438412999981_001" name="P3" temporalId="sch1_P3" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 3</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Scope of
                application</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_005" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438412999981_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header "><content class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Convention shall apply,
                        in accordance with its terms, to the prevention, investigation and
                        prosecution of corruption and to the freezing, seizure, confiscation and
                        return of the proceeds of offences established in accordance with this
                        Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412999981_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purposes of
                        implementing this Convention, it shall not be necessary, except as otherwise
                        stated herein, for the offences set forth in it to result in damage or harm
                        to state property.</content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438412999981_033" name="P4" temporalId="sch1_P4" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 4</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Protection of
                sovereignty</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_006" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438412999981_052" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall carry
                        out their obligations under this Convention in a manner consistent with the
                        principles of sovereign equality and territorial integrity of States and
                        that of non-intervention in the domestic affairs of other States.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412999981_060" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Nothing in this Convention
                        shall entitle a State Party to undertake in the territory of another State
                        the exercise of jurisdiction and performance of functions that are reserved
                        exclusively for the authorities of that other State by its domestic
                        law.</content></subsection></article></chapter><crossHeading>Chapter II</crossHeading><crossHeading>Preventive measures</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438412999997_017" name="P5" temporalId="sch1_P5" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 5</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Preventive anti-corruption policies and
                        practices</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_007" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438412999997_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, in
                        accordance with the fundamental principles of its legal system, develop and
                        implement or maintain effective, coordinated anti-corruption policies that
                        promote the participation of society and reflect the principles of the rule
                        of law, proper management of public affairs and public property, integrity,
                        transparency and accountability.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412999997_044" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall
                        endeavour to establish and promote effective practices aimed at the
                        prevention of corruption.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000012_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall
                        endeavour to periodically evaluate relevant legal instruments and
                        administrative measures with a view to determining their adequacy to prevent
                        and fight corruption.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000012_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall, as
                        appropriate and in accordance with the fundamental principles of their legal
                        system, collaborate with each other and with relevant international and
                        regional organizations in promoting and developing the measures referred to
                        in this article. That collaboration may include participation in
                        international programmes and projects aimed at the prevention of
                        corruption.</content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000012_017" name="P6" temporalId="sch1_P6" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 6</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Preventive anti-corruption body or
                        bodies</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_008" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438413000012_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, in
                        accordance with the fundamental principles of its legal system, ensure the
                        existence of a body or bodies, as appropriate, that prevent corruption by
                        such means as:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000028_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Implementing the policies
                        referred to in article 5 of this Convention and, where appropriate,
                        overseeing and coordinating the implementation of those policies;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000028_013" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Increasing and disseminating
                        knowledge about the prevention of corruption.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000028_021" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall grant
                        the body or bodies referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article the
                        necessary independence, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                        legal system, to enable the body or bodies to carry out its or their
                        functions effectively and free from any undue influence. The necessary
                        material resources and specialized staff, as well as the training that such
                        staff may require to carry out their functions, should be provided.
                    </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000043_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall
                        inform the Secretary-General of the United Nations of the name and address
                        of the authority or authorities that may assist other States Parties in
                        developing and implementing specific measures for the prevention of
                        corruption.</content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000043_009" name="P7" temporalId="sch1_P7" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 7</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Public
                sector</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_009" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438413000043_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall,
                        where appropriate and in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                        legal system, endeavour to adopt, maintain and strengthen systems for the
                        recruitment, hiring, retention, promotion and retirement of civil servants
                        and, where appropriate, other non-elected public officials:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000043_036" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>That are based on principles
                        of efficiency, transparency and objective criteria such as merit, equity and
                        aptitude;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000043_045" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>That include adequate
                        procedures for the selection and training of individuals for public
                        positions considered especially vulnerable to corruption and the rotation,
                        where appropriate, of such individuals to other positions;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000059_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>That promote adequate
                        remuneration and equitable pay scales, taking into account the level of
                        economic development of the State Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000059_013" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>That promote education and
                        training programmes to enable them to meet the requirements for the correct,
                        honourable and proper performance of public functions and that provide them
                        with specialized and appropriate training to enhance their awareness of the
                        risks of corruption inherent in the performance of their functions. Such
                        programmes may make reference to codes or standards of conduct in applicable
                        areas.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000059_021" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall also
                        consider adopting appropriate legislative and administrative measures,
                        consistent with the objectives of this Convention and in accordance with the
                        fundamental principles of its domestic law, to prescribe criteria concerning
                        candidature for and election to public office.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000075_004" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall also
                        consider taking appropriate legislative and administrative measures,
                        consistent with the objectives of this Convention and in accordance with the
                        fundamental principles of its domestic law, to enhance transparency in the
                        funding of candidatures for elected public office and, where applicable, the
                        funding of political parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000075_012" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, in
                        accordance with the fundamental principles of its domestic law, endeavour to
                        adopt, maintain and strengthen systems that promote transparency and prevent
                        conflicts of interest.</content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000075_017" name="P8" temporalId="sch1_P8" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 8</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Codes of conduct for public
                    officials</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_010" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438413000075_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In order to fight
                        corruption, each State Party shall promote, inter alia, integrity, honesty
                        and responsibility among its public officials, in accordance with the
                        fundamental principles of its legal system.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000090_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In particular, each State
                        Party shall endeavour to apply, within its own institutional and legal
                        systems, codes or standards of conduct for the correct, honourable and
                        proper performance of public functions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000090_012" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purposes of
                        implementing the provisions of this article, each State Party shall, where
                        appropriate and in accordance with the fundamental principles of its legal
                        system, take note of the relevant initiatives of regional, interregional and
                        multilateral organizations, such as the International Code of Conduct for
                        Public Officials contained in the annex to General Assembly resolution 51/59
                        of 12 December 1996.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000106_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall also
                        consider, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its domestic law,
                        establishing measures and systems to facilitate the reporting by public
                        officials of acts of corruption to appropriate authorities, when such acts
                        come to their notice in the performance of their functions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000106_012" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall
                        endeavour, where appropriate and in accordance with the fundamental
                        principles of its domestic law, to establish measures and systems requiring
                        public officials to make declarations to appropriate authorities regarding,
                        inter alia, their outside activities, employment, investments, assets and
                        substantial gifts or benefits from which a conflict of interest may result
                        with respect to their functions as public officials.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000121_004" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall
                        consider taking, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                        domestic law, disciplinary or other measures against public officials who
                        violate the codes or standards established in accordance with this
                        article.</content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000121_009" name="P9" temporalId="sch1_P9" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 9</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Public procurement and management
                        <br></br>of
                        public
                finances</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_011" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438413000121_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, in
                        accordance with the fundamental principles of its legal system, take the
                        necessary steps to establish appropriate systems of procurement, based on
                        transparency, competition and objective criteria in decision-making, that
                        are effective, inter alia, in preventing corruption. Such systems, which may
                        take into account appropriate threshold values in their application, shall
                        address, inter alia:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000121_044" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The public distribution of
                        information relating to procurement procedures and contracts, including
                        information on invitations to tender and relevant or pertinent information
                        on the award of contracts, allowing potential tenderers sufficient time to
                        prepare and submit their tenders;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000137_005" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The establishment, in
                        advance, of conditions for participation, including selection and award
                        criteria and tendering rules, and their publication;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000137_014" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The use of objective and
                        predetermined criteria for public procurement decisions, in order to
                        facilitate the subsequent verification of the correct application of the
                        rules or procedures;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000137_023" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>An effective system of
                        domestic review, including an effective system of appeal, to ensure legal
                        recourse and remedies in the event that the rules or procedures established
                        pursuant to this paragraph are not followed;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000137_032" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where appropriate, measures
                        to regulate matters regarding personnel responsible for procurement, such as
                        declaration of interest in particular public procurements, screening
                        procedures and training requirements.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000153_004" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, in
                        accordance with the fundamental principles of its legal system, take
                        appropriate measures to promote transparency and accountability in the
                        management of public finances. Such measures shall encompass, inter
                        alia:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000153_012" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Procedures for the adoption
                        of the national budget;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000153_021" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Timely reporting on revenue
                        and expenditure;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000153_030" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A system of accounting and
                        auditing standards and related oversight;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000153_039" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Effective and efficient
                        systems of risk management and internal control; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000153_048" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where appropriate,
                        corrective action in the case of failure to comply with the requirements
                        established in this paragraph.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000153_056" name="0-12" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-12" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take
                        such civil and administrative measures as may be necessary, in accordance
                        with the fundamental principles of its domestic law, to preserve the
                        integrity of accounting books, records, financial statements or other
                        documents related to public expenditure and revenue and to prevent the
                        falsification of such documents.</content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000168_001" name="P10" temporalId="sch1_P10" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 10</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Public
                reporting</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_012" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Taking into account the need to
                    combat corruption, each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental
                    principles of its domestic law, take such measures as may be necessary to
                    enhance transparency in its public administration, including with regard to its
                    organization, functioning and decision-making processes, where appropriate. Such
                    measures may include, inter alia:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413000168_030" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Adopting procedures or regulations
                        allowing members of the general public to obtain, where appropriate,
                        information on the organization, functioning and decision-making processes
                        of its public administration and, with due regard for the protection of
                        privacy and personal data, on decisions and legal acts that concern members
                        of the public;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000168_039" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Simplifying administrative
                        procedures, where appropriate, in order to facilitate public access to the
                        competent decision-making authorities; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000168_048" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Publishing information, which may
                        include periodic reports on the risks of corruption in its public
                        administration.</content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000168_051" name="P11" temporalId="sch1_P11" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 11</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Measures relating to the judiciary and
                        <br></br>prosecution
                        services</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704915_013" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438413000184_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Bearing in mind the
                        independence of the judiciary and its crucial role in combating corruption,
                        each State Party shall, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its
                        legal system and without prejudice to judicial independence, take measures
                        to strengthen integrity and to prevent opportunities for corruption among
                        members of the judiciary. Such measures may include rules with respect to
                        the conduct of members of the judiciary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000184_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Measures to the same effect
                        as those taken pursuant to <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article may be
                        introduced and applied within the prosecution service in those States
                        Parties where it does not form part of the judiciary but enjoys independence
                        similar to that of the judicial
                        service.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000199_001" name="P12" temporalId="sch1_P12" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 12</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Private
                sector</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><article id="ID_1521794704930_014" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><subsection id="ID_1438413000199_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_s0_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take
                        measures, in accordance with the fundamental principles of its domestic law,
                        to prevent corruption involving the private sector, enhance accounting and
                        auditing standards in the private sector and, where appropriate, provide
                        effective, proportionate and dissuasive civil, administrative or criminal
                        penalties for failure to comply with such measures.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000199_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Measures to achieve these
                        ends may include, inter alia:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000199_036" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Promoting cooperation
                        between law enforcement agencies and relevant private entities;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000199_045" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Promoting the development of
                        standards and procedures designed to safeguard the integrity of relevant
                        private entities, including codes of conduct for the correct, honourable and
                        proper performance of the activities of business and all relevant
                        professions and the prevention of conflicts of interest, and for the
                        promotion of the use of good commercial practices among businesses and in
                        the contractual relations of businesses with the State;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000215_005" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Promoting transparency among
                        private entities, including, where appropriate, measures regarding the
                        identity of legal and natural persons involved in the establishment and
                        management of corporate entities;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000215_014" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Preventing the misuse of
                        procedures regulating private entities, including procedures regarding
                        subsidies and licences granted by public authorities for commercial
                        activities;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000215_023" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Preventing conflicts of
                        interest by imposing restrictions, as appropriate and for a reasonable
                        period of time, on the professional activities of former public officials or
                        on the employment of public officials by the private sector after their
                        resignation or retirement, where such activities or employment relate
                        directly to the functions held or supervised by those public officials
                        during their tenure;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000231_005" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Ensuring that private
                        enterprises, taking into account their structure and size, have sufficient
                        internal auditing controls to assist in preventing and detecting acts of
                        corruption and that the accounts and required financial statements of such
                        private enterprises are subject to appropriate auditing and certification
                        procedures.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_004" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In order to prevent
                        corruption, each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary,
                        in accordance with its domestic laws and regulations regarding the
                        maintenance of books and records, financial statement disclosures and
                        accounting and auditing standards, to prohibit the following acts carried
                        out for the purpose of committing any of the offences established in
                        accordance with this Convention:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_012" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The establishment of
                        off-the-books accounts;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_021" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The making of off-the-books
                        or inadequately identified transactions;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_030" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The recording of
                        non-existent expenditure;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_039" name="0-12" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-12" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The entry of liabilities
                        with incorrect identification of their objects;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_048" name="0-13" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-13" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The use of false documents;
                        and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_057" name="0-14" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-14" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The intentional destruction
                        of bookkeeping documents earlier than foreseen by the law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000246_065" name="0-15" temporalId="sch1_s0_0-15" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall
                        disallow the tax deductibility of expenses that constitute bribes, the
                        latter being one of the constituent elements of the offences established in
                        accordance with articles 15 and 16 of this Convention and, where
                        appropriate, other expenses incurred in furtherance of corrupt
                        conduct.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></article></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000262_001" name="P13" temporalId="sch1_P13" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 13</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Participation of
                society</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000262_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take appropriate
                    measures, within its means and in accordance with fundamental principles of its
                    domestic law, to promote the active participation of individuals and groups
                    outside the public sector, such as civil society, non-governmental organizations
                    and community-based organizations, in the prevention of and the fight against
                    corruption and to raise public awareness regarding the existence, causes and
                    gravity of and the threat posed by corruption. This participation should be
                    strengthened by such measures as:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000262_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Enhancing the transparency of and
                    promoting the contribution of the public to decision-making processes;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000262_037" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Ensuring that the public has effective
                    access to information;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000262_046" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Undertaking public information
                    activities that contribute to non-tolerance of corruption, as well as public
                    education programmes, including school and university curricula;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000262_055" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Respecting, promoting and protecting
                    the freedom to seek, receive, publish and disseminate information concerning
                    corruption. That freedom may be subject to certain restrictions, but these shall
                    only be such as are provided for by law and are necessary:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000262_063" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0"><content>(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For respect of the rights or
                    reputations of others;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000262_072" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0"><content>(ii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the protection of national
                    security or ordre public or of public health or morals.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000277_004" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take appropriate
                    measures to ensure that the relevant anti-corruption bodies referred to in this
                    Convention are known to the public and shall provide access to such bodies,
                    where appropriate, for the reporting, including anonymously, of any incidents
                    that may be considered to constitute an offence established in accordance with
                    this Convention.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000277_009" name="P14" temporalId="sch1_P14" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 14</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Measures to prevent
                    money-laundering</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000277_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000277_036" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Institute a comprehensive domestic
                    regulatory and supervisory regime for banks and non-bank financial institutions,
                    including natural or legal persons that provide formal or informal services for
                    the transmission of money or value and, where appropriate, other bodies
                    particularly susceptible to money-laundering, within its competence, in order to
                    deter and detect all forms of money-laundering, which regime shall emphasize
                    requirements for customer and, where appropriate, beneficial owner
                    identification, record-keeping and the reporting of suspicious
                    transactions;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000293_005" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Without prejudice to article 46 of
                    this Convention, ensure that administrative, regulatory, law enforcement and
                    other authorities dedicated to combating money-laundering (including, where
                    appropriate under domestic law, judicial authorities) have the ability to
                    cooperate and exchange information at the national and international levels
                    within the conditions prescribed by its domestic law and, to that end, shall
                    consider the establishment of a financial intelligence unit to serve as a
                    national centre for the collection, analysis and dissemination of information
                    regarding potential money-laundering.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000324_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider
                    implementing feasible measures to detect and monitor the movement of cash and
                    appropriate negotiable instruments across their borders, subject to safeguards
                    to ensure proper use of information and without impeding in any way the movement
                    of legitimate capital. Such measures may include a requirement that individuals
                    and businesses report the cross-border transfer of substantial quantities of
                    cash and appropriate negotiable instruments.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000324_012" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider
                    implementing appropriate and feasible measures to require financial
                    institutions, including money remitters:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000324_020" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To include on forms for the electronic
                    transfer of funds and related messages accurate and meaningful information on
                    the originator;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000340_005" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To maintain such information
                    throughout the payment chain; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000340_014" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To apply enhanced scrutiny to
                    transfers of funds that do not contain complete information on the
                    originator.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000340_022" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In establishing a domestic regulatory
                    and supervisory regime under the terms of this article, and without prejudice to
                    any other article of this Convention, States Parties are called upon to use as a
                    guideline the relevant initiatives of regional, interregional and multilateral
                    organizations against money-laundering.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000340_030" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall endeavour to
                    develop and promote global, regional, subregional and bilateral cooperation
                    among judicial, law enforcement and financial regulatory authorities in order to
                    combat money-laundering.</content></subsection></chapter><crossHeading>Chapter III</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><crossHeading>Criminalization and law enforcement</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438413000340_051" name="P15" temporalId="sch1_P15" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 15</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Bribery of national public
                    officials</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall adopt such
                legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal
                offences, when committed intentionally:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413000355_021" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The promise, offering or giving, to a
                    public official, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage, for the official
                    himself or herself or another person or entity, in order that the official act
                    or refrain from acting in the exercise of his or her official duties;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000355_030" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The solicitation or acceptance by a
                    public official, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage, for the official
                    himself or herself or another person or entity, in order that the official act
                    or refrain from acting in the exercise of his or her official duties.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000355_033" name="P16" temporalId="sch1_P16" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 16</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Bribery of foreign public officials and
                        officials of
                        <br></br>public
                        international
                organizations</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000355_060" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall adopt such
                    legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal
                    offence, when committed intentionally, the promise, offering or giving to a
                    foreign public official or an official of a public international organization,
                    directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage, for the official himself or
                    herself or another person or entity, in order that the official act or refrain
                    from acting in the exercise of his or her official duties, in order to obtain or
                    retain business or other undue advantage in relation to the conduct of
                    international business.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000387_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider
                    adopting such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as
                    a criminal offence, when committed intentionally, the solicitation or acceptance
                    by a foreign public official or an official of a public international
                    organization, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage, for the official
                    himself or herself or another person or entity, in order that the official act
                    or refrain from acting in the exercise of his or her official duties.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000387_009" name="P17" temporalId="sch1_P17" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 17</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Embezzlement, misappropriation or other
                        diversion
                        <br></br>of
                        property by a public
                official</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall adopt such
                legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal
                offences, when committed intentionally, the embezzlement, misappropriation or other
                diversion by a public official for his or her benefit or for the benefit of another
                person or entity, of any property, public or private funds or securities or any
                other thing of value entrusted to the public official by virtue of his or her
                position.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000402_001" name="P18" temporalId="sch1_P18" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 18</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Trading in influence</inline></i></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider adopting such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal offences, when committed intentionally:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413000402_030" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The promise, offering or giving to a public official or any other person, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage in order that the public official or the person abuse his or her real or supposed influence with a view to obtaining from an administration or public authority of the State Party an undue advantage for the original instigator of the act or for any other person;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000418_007" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The solicitation or acceptance by a public official or any other person, directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage for himself or herself or for another person in order that the public official or the person abuse his or her real or supposed influence with a view to obtaining from an administration or public authority of the State Party an undue advantage.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000433_001" name="P19" temporalId="sch1_P19" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 19</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Abuse of
                functions</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider
                adopting such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a
                criminal offence, when committed intentionally, the abuse of functions or position,
                that is, the performance of or failure to perform an act, in violation of laws, by a
                public official in the discharge of his or her functions, for the purpose of
                obtaining an undue advantage for himself or herself or for another person or
                entity.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000433_025" name="P20" temporalId="sch1_P20" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 20</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Illicit
                enrichment</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Subject to its constitution and the
                fundamental principles of its legal system, each State Party shall consider adopting
                such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal
                offence, when committed intentionally, illicit enrichment, that is, a significant
                increase in the assets of a public official that he or she cannot reasonably explain
                in relation to his or her lawful income.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000449_001" name="P21" temporalId="sch1_P21" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 21</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Bribery in the private
                sector</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider
                adopting such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as
                criminal offences, when committed intentionally in the course of economic, financial
                or commercial activities:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413000449_030" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The promise, offering or giving,
                    directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage to any person who directs or
                    works, in any capacity, for a private sector entity, for the person himself or
                    herself or for another person, in order that he or she, in breach of his or her
                    duties, act or refrain from acting;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000465_007" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The solicitation or acceptance,
                    directly or indirectly, of an undue advantage by any person who directs or
                    works, in any capacity, for a private sector entity, for the person himself or
                    herself or for another person, in order that he or she, in breach of his or her
                    duties, act or refrain from acting.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000480_001" name="P22" temporalId="sch1_P22" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 22</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Embezzlement of property in the private
                        sector</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider
                adopting such legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a
                criminal offence, when committed intentionally in the course of economic, financial
                or commercial activities, embezzlement by a person who directs or works, in any
                capacity, in a private sector entity of any property, private funds or securities or
                any other thing of value entrusted to him or her by virtue of his or her
                position.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000480_025" name="P23" temporalId="sch1_P23" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 23</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Laundering of proceeds of
                crime</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000480_044" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall adopt, in
                    accordance with fundamental principles of its domestic law, such legislative and
                    other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal offences, when
                    committed intentionally:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000496_009" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The conversion or transfer of property, knowing that such property is
                    the proceeds of crime, for the purpose of concealing or disguising the illicit
                    origin of the property or of helping any person who is involved in the
                    commission of the predicate offence to evade the legal consequences of his or
                    her action;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1521794704930_015" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2"><content>(ii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The concealment or disguise of the
                    true nature, source, location, disposition, movement or ownership of or rights
                    with respect to property, knowing that such property is the proceeds of
                    crime;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000511_005" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Subject to the basic concepts of
                    its legal system:</leadIn><subsection class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1438413000511_015" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0-3_0"><content>(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The acquisition, possession
                        or use of property, knowing, at the time of receipt, that such property is
                        the proceeds of crime;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000527_007" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-3_0-1" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0"><content>(ii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Participation in,
                        association with or conspiracy to commit, attempts to commit and aiding,
                        abetting, facilitating and counselling the commission of any of the offences
                        established in accordance with this article.</content></subsection></subsection><subsection class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24" id="ID_1501139922721_001" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For purposes of implementing or
                    applying <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000527_021" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall seek to apply
                        <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article to the widest range of predicate
                    offences;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000543_005" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall include as
                    predicate offences at a minimum a comprehensive range of criminal offences
                    established in accordance with this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000543_014" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purposes of subparagraph (b)
                    above, predicate offences shall include offences committed both within and
                    outside the jurisdiction of the State Party in question. However, offences
                    committed outside the jurisdiction of a State Party shall constitute predicate
                    offences only when the relevant conduct is a criminal offence under the domestic
                    law of the State where it is committed and would be a criminal offence under the
                    domestic law of the State Party implementing or applying this article had it
                    been committed there;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000558_005" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall furnish copies
                    of its laws that give effect to this article and of any subsequent changes to
                    such laws or a description thereof to the Secretary-General of the United
                    Nations;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000574_005" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If required by fundamental principles
                    of the domestic law of a State Party, it may be provided that the offences set
                    forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article do not apply to the persons who
                    committed the predicate offence.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000574_010" name="P24" temporalId="sch1_P24" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 24</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Concealment</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Without prejudice to the provisions of
                article 23 of this Convention, each State Party shall consider adopting such
                legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal
                offence, when committed intentionally after the commission of any of the offences
                established in accordance with this Convention without having participated in such
                offences, the concealment or continued retention of property when the person
                involved knows that such property is the result of any of the offences established
                in accordance with this Convention.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000589_001" name="P25" temporalId="sch1_P25" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 25</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Obstruction of
                justice</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall adopt such
                legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as criminal
                offences, when committed intentionally:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413000589_030" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The use of physical force, threats or
                    intimidation or the promise, offering or giving of an undue advantage to induce
                    false testimony or to interfere in the giving of testimony or the production of
                    evidence in a proceeding in relation to the commission of offences established
                    in accordance with this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24" id="ID_1438413000605_007" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The use of physical force, threats or
                    intimidation to interfere with the exercise of official duties by a justice or
                    law enforcement official in relation to the commission of offences established
                    in accordance with this Convention. Nothing in this subparagraph shall prejudice
                    the right of States Parties to have legislation that protects other categories
                    of public official.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000621_001" name="P26" temporalId="sch1_P26" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 26</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Liability of legal
                persons</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000621_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall adopt such
                    measures as may be necessary, consistent with its legal principles, to establish
                    the liability of legal persons for participation in the offences established in
                    accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000621_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Subject to the legal principles of the
                    State Party, the liability of legal persons may be criminal, civil or
                    administrative.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000636_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Such liability shall be without
                    prejudice to the criminal liability of the natural persons who have committed
                    the offences.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000636_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, in particular,
                    ensure that legal persons held liable in accordance with this article are
                    subject to effective, proportionate and dissuasive criminal or non-criminal
                    sanctions, including monetary sanctions.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000652_001" name="P27" temporalId="sch1_P27" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 27</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Participation and
                attempt</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000652_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall adopt such
                    legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal
                    offence, in accordance with its domestic law, participation in any capacity such
                    as an accomplice, assistant or instigator in an offence established in
                    accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000652_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party may adopt such
                    legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal
                    offence, in accordance with its domestic law, any attempt to commit an offence
                    established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000667_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party may adopt such
                    legislative and other measures as may be necessary to establish as a criminal
                    offence, in accordance with its domestic law, the preparation for an offence
                    established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000667_009" name="P28" temporalId="sch1_P28" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 28</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Knowledge, intent and purpose as elements
                        <br></br>of
                        an
                offence</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Knowledge, intent or purpose required
                as an element of an offence established in accordance with this Convention may be
                inferred from objective factual circumstances.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000683_001" name="P29" temporalId="sch1_P29" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 29</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Statute of
                limitations</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall, where
                appropriate, establish under its domestic law a long statute of limitations period
                in which to commence proceedings for any offence established in accordance with this
                Convention and establish a longer statute of limitations period or provide for the
                suspension of the statute of limitations where the alleged offender has evaded the
                administration of justice.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000683_025" name="P30" temporalId="sch1_P30" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 30</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Prosecution, adjudication and
                        sanctions</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000683_044" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall make the commission of an offence established in accordance with this Convention liable to sanctions that take into account the gravity of that offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000699_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary to establish or maintain, in accordance with its legal system and constitutional principles, an appropriate balance between any immunities or jurisdictional privileges accorded to its public officials for the performance of their functions and the possibility, when necessary, of effectively investigating, prosecuting and adjudicating offences established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000714_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall endeavour to ensure that any discretionary legal powers under its domestic law relating to the prosecution of persons for offences established in accordance with this Convention are exercised to maximize the effectiveness of law enforcement measures in respect of those offences and with due regard to the need to deter the commission of such offences.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000730_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the case of offences established in accordance with this Convention, each State Party shall take appropriate measures, in accordance with its domestic law and with due regard to the rights of the defence, to seek to ensure that conditions imposed in connection with decisions on release pending trial or appeal take into consideration the need to ensure the presence of the defendant at subsequent criminal proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000745_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take into account the gravity of the offences concerned when considering the eventuality of early release or parole of persons convicted of such offences.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000745_012" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party, to the extent consistent with the fundamental principles of its legal system, shall consider establishing procedures through which a public official accused of an offence established in accordance with this Convention may, where appropriate, be removed, suspended or reassigned by the appropriate authority, bearing in mind respect for the principle of the presumption of innocence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000761_004" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>7.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where warranted by the gravity of the offence, each State Party, to the extent consistent with the fundamental principles of its legal system, shall consider establishing procedures for the disqualification, by court order or any other appropriate means, for a period of time determined by its domestic law, of persons convicted of offences established in accordance with this Convention from:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000761_012" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Holding public office; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000761_021" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Holding office in an enterprise owned in whole or in part by the State.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000777_004" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>8.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn><ref>Paragraph 1</ref> of this article shall be without prejudice to the exercise of disciplinary powers by the competent authorities against civil servants.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000777_012" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>9.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Nothing contained in this Convention shall affect the principle that the description of the offences established in accordance with this Convention and of the applicable legal defences or other legal principles controlling the lawfulness of conduct is reserved to the domestic law of a State Party and that such offences shall be prosecuted and punished in accordance with that law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000792_004" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>10.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall endeavour to promote the reintegration into society of persons convicted of offences established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000792_009" name="P31" temporalId="sch1_P31" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 31</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Freezing, seizure and
                    confiscation</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000792_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take, to the
                    greatest extent possible within its domestic legal system, such measures as may
                    be necessary to enable confiscation of:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000808_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Proceeds of crime derived from
                    offences established in accordance with this Convention or property the value of
                    which corresponds to that of such proceeds;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000808_013" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Property, equipment or other
                    instrumentalities used in or destined for use in offences established in
                    accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000823_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take such
                    measures as may be necessary to enable the identification, tracing, freezing or
                    seizure of any item referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article for
                    the purpose of eventual confiscation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000823_012" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall adopt, in
                    accordance with its domestic law, such legislative and other measures as may be
                    necessary to regulate the administration by the competent authorities of frozen,
                    seized or confiscated property covered in <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and
                        <ref>2</ref> of this article.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000839_004" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If such proceeds of crime have been
                    transformed or converted, in part or in full, into other property, such property
                    shall be liable to the measures referred to in this article instead of the
                    proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000839_012" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If such proceeds of crime have been
                    intermingled with property acquired from legitimate sources, such property
                    shall, without prejudice to any powers relating to freezing or seizure, be
                    liable to confiscation up to the assessed value of the intermingled
                    proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000855_004" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Income or other benefits derived from
                    such proceeds of crime, from property into which such proceeds of crime have
                    been transformed or converted or from property with which such proceeds of crime
                    have been intermingled shall also be liable to the measures referred to in this
                    article, in the same manner and to the same extent as proceeds of
                    crime.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000855_012" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>7.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purpose of this article and
                    article 55 of this Convention, each State Party shall empower its courts or
                    other competent authorities to order that bank, financial or commercial records
                    be made available or seized. A State Party shall not decline to act under the
                    provisions of this paragraph on the ground of bank secrecy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000870_004" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>8.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties may consider the
                    possibility of requiring that an offender demonstrate the lawful origin of such
                    alleged proceeds of crime or other property liable to confiscation, to the
                    extent that such a requirement is consistent with the fundamental principles of
                    their domestic law and with the nature of judicial and other
                    proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000886_004" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>9.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The provisions of this article shall
                    not be so construed as to prejudice the rights of bona fide third
                    parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000886_012" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>10.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Nothing contained in this article
                    shall affect the principle that the measures to which it refers shall be defined
                    and implemented in accordance with and subject to the provisions of the domestic
                    law of a State Party.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000901_001" name="P32" temporalId="sch1_P32" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 32</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Protection of witnesses, experts and
                        victims</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000901_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take appropriate measures in accordance with its domestic legal system and within its means to provide effective protection from potential retaliation or intimidation for witnesses and experts who give testimony concerning offences established in accordance with this Convention and, as appropriate, for their relatives and other persons close to them.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000901_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The measures envisaged in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article may include, inter alia, without prejudice to the rights of the defendant, including the right to due process:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000917_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Establishing procedures for the physical protection of such persons, such as, to the extent necessary and feasible, relocating them and permitting, where appropriate, non-disclosure or limitations on the disclosure of information concerning the identity and whereabouts of such persons;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000917_013" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Providing evidentiary rules to permit witnesses and experts to give testimony in a manner that ensures the safety of such persons, such as permitting testimony to be given through the use of communications technology such as video or other adequate means.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000933_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider entering into agreements or arrangements with other States for the relocation of persons referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000933_012" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The provisions of this article shall also apply to victims insofar as they are witnesses.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413000948_004" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, subject to its domestic law, enable the views and concerns of victims to be presented and considered at appropriate stages of criminal proceedings against offenders in a manner not prejudicial to the rights of the defence.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000948_009" name="P33" temporalId="sch1_P33" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 33</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Protection of reporting
                persons</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall consider
                incorporating into its domestic legal system appropriate measures to provide
                protection against any unjustified treatment for any person who reports in good
                faith and on reasonable grounds to the competent authorities any facts concerning
                offences established in accordance with this Convention.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000964_001" name="P34" temporalId="sch1_P34" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 34</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Consequences of acts of
                    corruption</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">With due regard to the rights of third
                parties acquired in good faith, each State Party shall take measures, in accordance
                with the fundamental principles of its domestic law, to address consequences of
                corruption. In this context, States Parties may consider corruption a relevant
                factor in legal proceedings to annul or rescind a contract, withdraw a concession or
                other similar instrument or take any other remedial action.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000964_025" name="P35" temporalId="sch1_P35" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 35</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Compensation for
                damage</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall take such
                measures as may be necessary, in accordance with principles of its domestic law, to
                ensure that entities or persons who have suffered damage as a result of an act of
                corruption have the right to initiate legal proceedings against those responsible
                for that damage in order to obtain compensation.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000979_001" name="P36" temporalId="sch1_P36" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 36</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Specialized
                authorities</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall, in accordance
                with the fundamental principles of its legal system, ensure the existence of a body
                or bodies or persons specialized in combating corruption through law enforcement.
                Such body or bodies or persons shall be granted the necessary independence, in
                accordance with the fundamental principles of the legal system of the State Party,
                to be able to carry out their functions effectively and without any undue influence.
                Such persons or staff of such body or bodies should have the appropriate training
                and resources to carry out their tasks.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413000995_001" name="P37" temporalId="sch1_P37" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 37</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Cooperation with law enforcement
                        authorities</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413000995_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take appropriate
                    measures to encourage persons who participate or who have participated in the
                    commission of an offence established in accordance with this Convention to
                    supply information useful to competent authorities for investigative and
                    evidentiary purposes and to provide factual, specific help to competent
                    authorities that may contribute to depriving offenders of the proceeds of crime
                    and to recovering such proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001011_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider
                    providing for the possibility, in appropriate cases, of mitigating punishment of
                    an accused person who provides substantial cooperation in the investigation or
                    prosecution of an offence established in accordance with this
                    Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001026_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider
                    providing for the possibility, in accordance with fundamental principles of its
                    domestic law, of granting immunity from prosecution to a person who provides
                    substantial cooperation in the investigation or prosecution of an offence
                    established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001026_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Protection of such persons shall be,
                    mutatis mutandis, as provided for in article 32 of this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001042_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where a person referred to in
                        <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article located in one State Party can
                    provide substantial cooperation to the competent authorities of another State
                    Party, the States Parties concerned may consider entering into agreements or
                    arrangements, in accordance with their domestic law, concerning the potential
                    provision by the other State Party of the treatment set forth in <ref>paragraphs
                        2</ref> and <ref>3</ref> of this article.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001057_001" name="P38" temporalId="sch1_P38" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 38</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Cooperation between national
                        authorities</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall take such
                measures as may be necessary to encourage, in accordance with its domestic law,
                cooperation between, on the one hand, its public authorities, as well as its public
                officials, and, on the other hand, its authorities responsible for investigating and
                prosecuting criminal offences. Such cooperation may include:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413001057_030" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Informing the latter authorities, on
                    their own initiative, where there are reasonable grounds to believe that any of
                    the offences established in accordance with articles 15, 21 and 23 of this
                    Convention has been committed; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001057_039" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Providing, upon request, to the latter
                    authorities all necessary information.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001073_001" name="P39" temporalId="sch1_P39" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 39</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Cooperation between national authorities
                        <br></br>and
                        the private
                sector</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413001073_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take such
                    measures as may be necessary to encourage, in accordance with its domestic law,
                    cooperation between national investigating and prosecuting authorities and
                    entities of the private sector, in particular financial institutions, relating
                    to matters involving the commission of offences established in accordance with
                    this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001089_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider
                    encouraging its nationals and other persons with a habitual residence in its
                    territory to report to the national investigating and prosecuting authorities
                    the commission of an offence established in accordance with this
                    Convention.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001089_009" name="P40" temporalId="sch1_P40" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 40</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Bank
                secrecy</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall ensure that, in
                the case of domestic criminal investigations of offences established in accordance
                with this Convention, there are appropriate mechanisms available within its domestic
                legal system to overcome obstacles that may arise out of the application of bank
                secrecy
                laws.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001104_001" name="P41" temporalId="sch1_P41" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 41</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Criminal
                record</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party may adopt such
                legislative or other measures as may be necessary to take into consideration, under
                such terms as and for the purpose that it deems appropriate, any previous conviction
                in another State of an alleged offender for the purpose of using such information in
                criminal proceedings relating to an offence established in accordance with this
                Convention.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001104_025" name="P42" temporalId="sch1_P42" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 42</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Jurisdiction</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413001104_044" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall adopt such
                    measures as may be necessary to establish its jurisdiction over the offences
                    established in accordance with this Convention when:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001120_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The offence is committed in the
                    territory of that State Party; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001120_013" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The offence is committed on board a
                    vessel that is flying the flag of that State Party or an aircraft that is
                    registered under the laws of that State Party at the time that the offence is
                    committed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001120_021" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Subject to article 4 of this
                    Convention, a State Party may also establish its jurisdiction over any such
                    offence when:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001135_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The offence is committed against a
                    national of that State Party; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001135_013" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The offence is committed by a national
                    of that State Party or a stateless person who has his or her habitual residence
                    in its territory; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001135_022" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The offence is one of those
                    established in accordance with article 23, <ref>paragraph 1
                        (b)
                        (ii)</ref>, of this Convention and is committed outside
                    its territory with a view to the commission of an offence established in
                    accordance with article 23, <ref>paragraph 1
                        (a)
                        (i)</ref> or (ii) or (b)
                    (i), of this Convention within its territory; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001151_005" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The offence is committed against the
                    State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001167_004" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purposes of article 44 of this
                    Convention, each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary to
                    establish its jurisdiction over the offences established in accordance with this
                    Convention when the alleged offender is present in its territory and it does not
                    extradite such person solely on the ground that he or she is one of its
                    nationals.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001167_012" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party may also take such
                    measures as may be necessary to establish its jurisdiction over the offences
                    established in accordance with this Convention when the alleged offender is
                    present in its territory and it does not extradite him or her.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001182_004" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If a State Party exercising its
                    jurisdiction under <ref>paragraph 1</ref> or <ref>2</ref> of this article has
                    been notified, or has otherwise learned, that any other States Parties are
                    conducting an investigation, prosecution or judicial proceeding in respect of
                    the same conduct, the competent authorities of those States Parties shall, as
                    appropriate, consult one another with a view to coordinating their
                    actions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001198_004" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Without prejudice to norms of general
                    international law, this Convention shall not exclude the exercise of any
                    criminal jurisdiction established by a State Party in accordance with its
                    domestic law.</content></subsection></chapter><crossHeading>Chapter IV</crossHeading><crossHeading>International cooperation</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438413001198_025" name="P43" temporalId="sch1_P43" class="no_header"><crossHeading><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 43</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">International
                cooperation</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413001198_044" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall cooperate in
                    criminal matters in accordance with articles 44 to 50 of this Convention. Where
                    appropriate and consistent with their domestic legal system, States Parties
                    shall consider assisting each other in investigations of and proceedings in
                    civil and administrative matters relating to corruption.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001213_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In matters of international
                    cooperation, whenever dual criminality is considered a requirement, it shall be
                    deemed fulfilled irrespective of whether the laws of the requested State Party
                    place the offence within the same category of offence or denominate the offence
                    by the same terminology as the requesting State Party, if the conduct underlying
                    the offence for which assistance is sought is a criminal offence under the laws
                    of both States Parties.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001229_001" name="P44" temporalId="sch1_P44" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 44</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Extradition</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413001229_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This article shall apply to the
                    offences established in accordance with this Convention where the person who is
                    the subject of the request for extradition is present in the territory of the
                    requested State Party, provided that the offence for which extradition is sought
                    is punishable under the domestic law of both the requesting State Party and the
                    requested State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001245_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Notwithstanding the provisions of
                        <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article, a State Party whose law so permits
                    may grant the extradition of a person for any of the offences covered by this
                    Convention that are not punishable under its own domestic law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001260_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If the request for extradition includes
                    several separate offences, at least one of which is extraditable under this
                    article and some of which are not extraditable by reason of their period of
                    imprisonment but are related to offences established in accordance with this
                    Convention, the requested State Party may apply this article also in respect of
                    those offences.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001260_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each of the offences to which this
                    article applies shall be deemed to be included as an extraditable offence in any
                    extradition treaty existing between States Parties. States Parties undertake to
                    include such offences as extraditable offences in every extradition treaty to be
                    concluded between them. A State Party whose law so permits, in case it uses this
                    Convention as the basis for extradition, shall not consider any of the offences
                    established in accordance with this Convention to be a political
                    offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001291_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If a State Party that makes extradition
                    conditional on the existence of a treaty receives a request for extradition from
                    another State Party with which it has no extradition treaty, it may consider
                    this Convention the legal basis for extradition in respect of any offence to
                    which this article applies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001291_012" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A State Party that makes extradition
                    conditional on the existence of a treaty shall:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001291_020" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>At the time of deposit of its
                    instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval of or accession to this
                    Convention, inform the Secretary-General of the United Nations whether it will
                    take this Convention as the legal basis for cooperation on extradition with
                    other States Parties to this Convention; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001307_005" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If it does not take this Convention as
                    the legal basis for cooperation on extradition, seek, where appropriate, to
                    conclude treaties on extradition with other States Parties to this Convention in
                    order to implement this article.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001323_004" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>7.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties that do not make
                    extradition conditional on the existence of a treaty shall recognize offences to
                    which this article applies as extraditable offences between
                    themselves.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001323_012" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>8.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Extradition shall be subject to the
                    conditions provided for by the domestic law of the requested State Party or by
                    applicable extradition treaties, including, inter alia, conditions in relation
                    to the minimum penalty requirement for extradition and the grounds upon which
                    the requested State Party may refuse extradition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001338_004" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>9.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall, subject to their
                    domestic law, endeavour to expedite extradition procedures and to simplify
                    evidentiary requirements relating thereto in respect of any offence to which
                    this article applies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001338_012" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>10.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Subject to the provisions of its
                    domestic law and its extradition treaties, the requested State Party may, upon
                    being satisfied that the circumstances so warrant and are urgent and at the
                    request of the requesting State Party, take a person whose extradition is sought
                    and who is present in its territory into custody or take other appropriate
                    measures to ensure his or her presence at extradition proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001354_004" name="0-12" temporalId="sch1_0-12" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>11.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A State Party in whose territory an
                    alleged offender is found, if it does not extradite such person in respect of an
                    offence to which this article applies solely on the ground that he or she is one
                    of its nationals, shall, at the request of the State Party seeking extradition,
                    be obliged to submit the case without undue delay to its competent authorities
                    for the purpose of prosecution. Those authorities shall take their decision and
                    conduct their proceedings in the same manner as in the case of any other offence
                    of a grave nature under the domestic law of that State Party. The States Parties
                    concerned shall cooperate with each other, in particular on procedural and
                    evidentiary aspects, to ensure the efficiency of such prosecution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001385_004" name="0-13" temporalId="sch1_0-13" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>12.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Whenever a State Party is permitted
                    under its domestic law to extradite or otherwise surrender one of its nationals
                    only upon the condition that the person will be returned to that State Party to
                    serve the sentence imposed as a result of the trial or proceedings for which the
                    extradition or surrender of the person was sought and that State Party and the
                    State Party seeking the extradition of the person agree with this option and
                    other terms that they may deem appropriate, such conditional extradition or
                    surrender shall be sufficient to discharge the obligation set forth in
                        <ref>paragraph 11</ref> of this article.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001401_004" name="0-14" temporalId="sch1_0-14" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>13.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If extradition, sought for purposes of
                    enforcing a sentence, is refused because the person sought is a national of the
                    requested State Party, the requested State Party shall, if its domestic law so
                    permits and in conformity with the requirements of such law, upon application of
                    the requesting State Party, consider the enforcement of the sentence imposed
                    under the domestic law of the requesting State Party or the remainder
                    thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001416_004" name="0-15" temporalId="sch1_0-15" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>14.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Any person regarding whom proceedings
                    are being carried out in connection with any of the offences to which this
                    article applies shall be guaranteed fair treatment at all stages of the
                    proceedings, including enjoyment of all the rights and guarantees provided by
                    the domestic law of the State Party in the territory of which that person is
                    present.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001432_004" name="0-16" temporalId="sch1_0-16" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>15.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Nothing in this Convention shall be
                    interpreted as imposing an obligation to extradite if the requested State Party
                    has substantial grounds for believing that the request has been made for the
                    purpose of prosecuting or punishing a person on account of that person’s sex,
                    race, religion, nationality, ethnic origin or political opinions or that
                    compliance with the request would cause prejudice to that person’s position for
                    any one of these reasons.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001447_004" name="0-17" temporalId="sch1_0-17" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>16.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties may not refuse a
                    request for extradition on the sole ground that the offence is also considered
                    to involve fiscal matters.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001447_012" name="0-18" temporalId="sch1_0-18" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>17.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Before refusing extradition, the
                    requested State Party shall, where appropriate, consult with the requesting
                    State Party to provide it with ample opportunity to present its opinions and to
                    provide information relevant to its allegation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001463_004" name="0-19" temporalId="sch1_0-19" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>18.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall seek to conclude
                    bilateral and multilateral agreements or arrangements to carry out or to enhance
                    the effectiveness of extradition.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001463_009" name="P45" temporalId="sch1_P45" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 45</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Transfer of sentenced
                persons</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">States Parties may consider entering
                into bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements on the transfer to their
                territory of persons sentenced to imprisonment or other forms of deprivation of
                liberty for offences established in accordance with this Convention in order that
                they may complete their sentences there.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413001479_001" name="P46" temporalId="sch1_P46" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 46</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Mutual legal
                assistance</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413001479_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall afford one another
                    the widest measure of mutual legal assistance in investigations, prosecutions
                    and judicial proceedings in relation to the offences covered by this
                    Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001479_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Mutual legal assistance shall be
                    afforded to the fullest extent possible under relevant laws, treaties,
                    agreements and arrangements of the requested State Party with respect to
                    investigations, prosecutions and judicial proceedings in relation to the
                    offences for which a legal person may be held liable in accordance with article
                    26 of this Convention in the requesting State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001494_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Mutual legal assistance to be afforded
                    in accordance with this article may be requested for any of the following
                    purposes:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001494_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Taking evidence or statements from
                    persons;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001510_005" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Effecting service of judicial
                    documents;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001510_014" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Executing searches and seizures, and
                    freezing;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001510_023" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Examining objects and sites;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001510_032" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Providing information, evidentiary
                    items and expert evaluations;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001525_005" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Providing originals or certified
                    copies of relevant documents and records, including government, bank, financial,
                    corporate or business records;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001525_014" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(g)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Identifying or tracing proceeds of
                    crime, property, instrumentalities or other things for evidentiary
                    purposes;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001525_023" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(h)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Facilitating the voluntary appearance
                    of persons in the requesting State Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001541_005" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Any other type of assistance
                    that is not contrary to the domestic law of the requested State Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001541_014" name="0-12" temporalId="sch1_0-12" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(j)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Identifying, freezing and
                    tracing proceeds of crime in accordance with the provisions of chapter V of this
                    Convention;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001541_023" name="0-13" temporalId="sch1_0-13" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(k)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The recovery of assets, in
                    accordance with the provisions of chapter V of this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001557_004" name="0-14" temporalId="sch1_0-14" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Without prejudice to domestic law, the
                    competent authorities of a State Party may, without prior request, transmit
                    information relating to criminal matters to a competent authority in another
                    State Party where they believe that such information could assist the authority
                    in undertaking or successfully concluding inquiries and criminal proceedings or
                    could result in a request formulated by the latter State Party pursuant to this
                    Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001572_004" name="0-15" temporalId="sch1_0-15" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The transmission of information
                    pursuant to <ref>paragraph 4</ref> of this article shall be without prejudice to
                    inquiries and criminal proceedings in the State of the competent authorities
                    providing the information. The competent authorities receiving the information
                    shall comply with a request that said information remain confidential, even
                    temporarily, or with restrictions on its use. However, this shall not prevent
                    the receiving State Party from disclosing in its proceedings information that is
                    exculpatory to an accused person. In such a case, the receiving State Party
                    shall notify the transmitting State Party prior to the disclosure and, if so
                    requested, consult with the transmitting State Party. If, in an exceptional
                    case, advance notice is not possible, the receiving State Party shall inform the
                    transmitting State Party of the disclosure without delay.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001603_004" name="0-16" temporalId="sch1_0-16" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The provisions of this article shall
                    not affect the obligations under any other treaty, bilateral or multilateral,
                    that governs or will govern, in whole or in part, mutual legal
                    assistance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001619_004" name="0-17" temporalId="sch1_0-17" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>7.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn><ref>Paragraphs 9 to 29</ref> of this
                    article shall apply to requests made pursuant to this article if the States
                    Parties in question are not bound by a treaty of mutual legal assistance. If
                    those States Parties are bound by such a treaty, the corresponding provisions of
                    that treaty shall apply unless the States Parties agree to apply <ref>paragraphs
                        9 to 29</ref> of this article in lieu thereof. States Parties are strongly
                    encouraged to apply those paragraphs if they facilitate cooperation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001635_004" name="0-18" temporalId="sch1_0-18" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>8.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall not decline to
                    render mutual legal assistance pursuant to this article on the ground of bank
                    secrecy.</content></subsection><subsection class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24" id="ID_1522742614555_001" name="0-19" temporalId="sch1_0-19"><content>9.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A
                    requested State Party, in responding to a request for assistance pursuant to
                    this article in the absence of dual criminality, shall take into account the
                    purposes of this Convention, as set forth in article 1;</content></subsection><subsection class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24" id="ID_1522742614555_002" name="0-20" temporalId="sch1_0-20"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties may decline to render
                    assistance pursuant to this article on the ground of absence of dual
                    criminality. However, a requested State Party shall, where consistent with the
                    basic concepts of its legal system, render assistance that does not involve
                    coercive action. Such assistance may be refused when requests involve matters of
                    a de minimis nature or matters for which the cooperation or assistance sought is
                    available under other provisions of this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24" id="ID_1522742614555_003" name="0-21" temporalId="sch1_0-21"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party may consider adopting
                    such measures as may be necessary to enable it to provide a wider scope of
                    assistance pursuant to this article in the absence of dual
                    criminality.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001666_013" name="0-22" temporalId="sch1_0-22" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>10.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A person who is being detained or is
                    serving a sentence in the territory of one State Party whose presence in another
                    State Party is requested for purposes of identification, testimony or otherwise
                    providing assistance in obtaining evidence for investigations, prosecutions or
                    judicial proceedings in relation to offences covered by this Convention may be
                    transferred if the following conditions are met:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001666_021" name="0-23" temporalId="sch1_0-23" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The person freely gives his or her
                    informed consent;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001681_005" name="0-24" temporalId="sch1_0-24" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The competent authorities of both
                    States Parties agree, subject to such conditions as those States Parties may
                    deem appropriate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001681_013" name="0-25" temporalId="sch1_0-25" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>11.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purposes of <ref>paragraph
                        10</ref> of this article:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001681_021" name="0-26" temporalId="sch1_0-26" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The State Party to which the person is
                    transferred shall have the authority and obligation to keep the person
                    transferred in custody, unless otherwise requested or authorized by the State
                    Party from which the person was transferred;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001697_005" name="0-27" temporalId="sch1_0-27" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The State Party to which the person is
                    transferred shall without delay implement its obligation to return the person to
                    the custody of the State Party from which the person was transferred as agreed
                    beforehand, or as otherwise agreed, by the competent authorities of both States
                    Parties;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001713_005" name="0-28" temporalId="sch1_0-28" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The State Party to which the person is
                    transferred shall not require the State Party from which the person was
                    transferred to initiate extradition proceedings for the return of the
                    person;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001713_014" name="0-29" temporalId="sch1_0-29" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The person transferred shall receive
                    credit for service of the sentence being served in the State from which he or
                    she was transferred for time spent in the custody of the State Party to which he
                    or she was transferred.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001713_022" name="0-30" temporalId="sch1_0-30" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>12.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Unless the State Party from which a
                    person is to be transferred in accordance with <ref>paragraphs 10</ref> and
                        <ref>11</ref> of this article so agrees, that person, whatever his or her
                    nationality, shall not be prosecuted, detained, punished or subjected to any
                    other restriction of his or her personal liberty in the territory of the State
                    to which that person is transferred in respect of acts, omissions or convictions
                    prior to his or her departure from the territory of the State from which he or
                    she was transferred.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001744_004" name="0-31" temporalId="sch1_0-31" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>13.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall designate a
                    central authority that shall have the responsibility and power to receive
                    requests for mutual legal assistance and either to execute them or to transmit
                    them to the competent authorities for execution. Where a State Party has a
                    special region or territory with a separate system of mutual legal assistance,
                    it may designate a distinct central authority that shall have the same function
                    for that region or territory. Central authorities shall ensure the speedy and
                    proper execution or transmission of the requests received. Where the central
                    authority transmits the request to a competent authority for execution, it shall
                    encourage the speedy and proper execution of the request by the competent
                    authority. The Secretary-General of the United Nations shall be notified of the
                    central authority designated for this purpose at the time each State Party
                    deposits its instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval of or accession
                    to this Convention. Requests for mutual legal assistance and any communication
                    related thereto shall be transmitted to the central authorities designated by
                    the States Parties. This requirement shall be without prejudice to the right of
                    a State Party to require that such requests and communications be addressed to
                    it through diplomatic channels and, in urgent circumstances, where the States
                    Parties agree, through the International Criminal Police Organization, if
                    possible.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001837_004" name="0-32" temporalId="sch1_0-32" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>14.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Requests shall be made in writing or,
                    where possible, by any means capable of producing a written record, in a
                    language acceptable to the requested State Party, under conditions allowing that
                    State Party to establish authenticity. The Secretary-General of the United
                    Nations shall be notified of the language or languages acceptable to each State
                    Party at the time it deposits its instrument of ratification, acceptance or
                    approval of or accession to this Convention. In urgent circumstances and where
                    agreed by the States Parties, requests may be made orally but shall be confirmed
                    in writing forthwith.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001853_004" name="0-33" temporalId="sch1_0-33" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>15.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A request for mutual legal assistance
                    shall contain:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001853_012" name="0-34" temporalId="sch1_0-34" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The identity of the authority making
                    the request;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001869_005" name="0-35" temporalId="sch1_0-35" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The subject matter and nature of the
                    investigation, prosecution or judicial proceeding to which the request relates
                    and the name and functions of the authority conducting the investigation,
                    prosecution or judicial proceeding;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001869_014" name="0-36" temporalId="sch1_0-36" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A summary of the relevant facts,
                    except in relation to requests for the purpose of service of judicial
                    documents;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001869_023" name="0-37" temporalId="sch1_0-37" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A description of the assistance sought
                    and details of any particular procedure that the requesting State Party wishes
                    to be followed;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001884_005" name="0-38" temporalId="sch1_0-38" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where possible, the identity, location
                    and nationality of any person concerned; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001884_014" name="0-39" temporalId="sch1_0-39" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The purpose for which the evidence,
                    information or action is sought.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001884_022" name="0-40" temporalId="sch1_0-40" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>16.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The requested State Party may request
                    additional information when it appears necessary for the execution of the
                    request in accordance with its domestic law or when it can facilitate such
                    execution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001900_004" name="0-41" temporalId="sch1_0-41" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>17.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A request shall be executed in
                    accordance with the domestic law of the requested State Party and, to the extent
                    not contrary to the domestic law of the requested State Party and where
                    possible, in accordance with the procedures specified in the request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001900_012" name="0-42" temporalId="sch1_0-42" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>18.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Wherever possible and consistent with
                    fundamental principles of domestic law, when an individual is in the territory
                    of a State Party and has to be heard as a witness or expert by the judicial
                    authorities of another State Party, the first State Party may, at the request of
                    the other, permit the hearing to take place by video conference if it is not
                    possible or desirable for the individual in question to appear in person in the
                    territory of the requesting State Party. States Parties may agree that the
                    hearing shall be conducted by a judicial authority of the requesting State Party
                    and attended by a judicial authority of the requested State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001931_004" name="0-43" temporalId="sch1_0-43" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>19.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The requesting State Party shall not
                    transmit or use information or evidence furnished by the requested State Party
                    for investigations, prosecutions or judicial proceedings other than those stated
                    in the request without the prior consent of the requested State Party. Nothing
                    in this paragraph shall prevent the requesting State Party from disclosing in
                    its proceedings information or evidence that is exculpatory to an accused
                    person. In the latter case, the requesting State Party shall notify the
                    requested State Party prior to the disclosure and, if so requested, consult with
                    the requested State Party. If, in an exceptional case, advance notice is not
                    possible, the requesting State Party shall inform the requested State Party of
                    the disclosure without delay.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001962_004" name="0-44" temporalId="sch1_0-44" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>20.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The requesting State Party may require
                    that the requested State Party keep confidential the fact and substance of the
                    request, except to the extent necessary to execute the request. If the requested
                    State Party cannot comply with the requirement of confidentiality, it shall
                    promptly inform the requesting State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001978_004" name="0-45" temporalId="sch1_0-45" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>21.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Mutual legal assistance may be
                    refused:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001978_012" name="0-46" temporalId="sch1_0-46" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If the request is not made in
                    conformity with the provisions of this article;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001978_021" name="0-47" temporalId="sch1_0-47" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If the requested State Party considers
                    that execution of the request is likely to prejudice its sovereignty, security,
                        <i>ordre public</i> or other essential interests;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001993_005" name="0-48" temporalId="sch1_0-48" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If the authorities of the requested
                    State Party would be prohibited by its domestic law from carrying out the action
                    requested with regard to any similar offence, had it been subject to
                    investigation, prosecution or judicial proceedings under their own
                    jurisdiction;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001993_014" name="0-49" temporalId="sch1_0-49" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If it would be contrary to the legal
                    system of the requested State Party relating to mutual legal assistance for the
                    request to be granted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413001993_022" name="0-50" temporalId="sch1_0-50" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>22.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties may not refuse a
                    request for mutual legal assistance on the sole ground that the offence is also
                    considered to involve fiscal matters.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002009_005" name="0-51" temporalId="sch1_0-51" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>23.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Reasons shall be given for any refusal
                    of mutual legal assistance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002009_013" name="0-52" temporalId="sch1_0-52" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>24.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The requested State Party shall
                    execute the request for mutual legal assistance as soon as possible and shall
                    take as full account as possible of any deadlines suggested by the requesting
                    State Party and for which reasons are given, preferably in the request. The
                    requesting State Party may make reasonable requests for information on the
                    status and progress of measures taken by the requested State Party to satisfy
                    its request. The requested State Party shall respond to reasonable requests by
                    the requesting State Party on the status, and progress in its handling, of the
                    request. The requesting State Party shall promptly inform the requested State
                    Party when the assistance sought is no longer required.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002040_004" name="0-53" temporalId="sch1_0-53" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>25.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Mutual legal assistance may be
                    postponed by the requested State Party on the ground that it interferes with an
                    ongoing investigation, prosecution or judicial proceeding.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002040_012" name="0-54" temporalId="sch1_0-54" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>26.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Before refusing a request pursuant to
                        <ref>paragraph 21</ref> of this article or postponing its execution pursuant
                    to <ref>paragraph 25</ref> of this article, the requested State Party shall
                    consult with the requesting State Party to consider whether assistance may be
                    granted subject to such terms and conditions as it deems necessary. If the
                    requesting State Party accepts assistance subject to those conditions, it shall
                    comply with the conditions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002056_004" name="0-55" temporalId="sch1_0-55" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>27.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Without prejudice to the application
                    of <ref>paragraph 12</ref> of this article, a witness, expert or other person
                    who, at the request of the requesting State Party, consents to give evidence in
                    a proceeding or to assist in an investigation, prosecution or judicial
                    proceeding in the territory of the requesting State Party shall not be
                    prosecuted, detained, punished or subjected to any other restriction of his or
                    her personal liberty in that territory in respect of acts, omissions or
                    convictions prior to his or her departure from the territory of the requested
                    State Party. Such safe conduct shall cease when the witness, expert or other
                    person having had, for a period of fifteen consecutive days or for any period
                    agreed upon by the States Parties from the date on which he or she has been
                    officially informed that his or her presence is no longer required by the
                    judicial authorities, an opportunity of leaving, has nevertheless remained
                    voluntarily in the territory of the requesting State Party or, having left it,
                    has returned of his or her own free will.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002118_004" name="0-56" temporalId="sch1_0-56" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>28.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The ordinary costs of executing a
                    request shall be borne by the requested State Party, unless otherwise agreed by
                    the States Parties concerned. If expenses of a substantial or extraordinary
                    nature are or will be required to fulfil the request, the States Parties shall
                    consult to determine the terms and conditions under which the request will be
                    executed, as well as the manner in which the costs shall be borne.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002134_004" name="0-57" temporalId="sch1_0-57" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>29.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The requested State Party:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002134_012" name="0-58" temporalId="sch1_0-58" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Shall provide to the requesting State
                    Party copies of government records, documents or information in its possession
                    that under its domestic law are available to the general public;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002134_021" name="0-59" temporalId="sch1_0-59" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>May, at its discretion, provide to the
                    requesting State Party in whole, in part or subject to such conditions as it
                    deems appropriate, copies of any government records, documents or information in
                    its possession that under its domestic law are not available to the general
                    public.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002149_004" name="0-60" temporalId="sch1_0-60" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>30.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider, as may
                    be necessary, the possibility of concluding bilateral or multilateral agreements
                    or arrangements that would serve the purposes of, give practical effect to or
                    enhance the provisions of this article.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002149_009" name="P47" temporalId="sch1_P47" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 47</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Transfer of criminal
                proceedings</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall consider the
                possibility of transferring to one another proceedings for the prosecution of an
                offence established in accordance with this Convention in cases where such transfer
                is considered to be in the interests of the proper administration of justice, in
                particular in cases where several jurisdictions are involved, with a view to
                concentrating the prosecution.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002165_017" name="P48" temporalId="sch1_P48" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 48</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Law enforcement
                cooperation</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413002165_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall cooperate closely
                    with one another, consistent with their respective domestic legal and
                    administrative systems, to enhance the effectiveness of law enforcement action
                    to combat the offences covered by this Convention. States Parties shall, in
                    particular, take effective measures:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002181_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To enhance and, where necessary, to
                    establish channels of communication between their competent authorities,
                    agencies and services in order to facilitate the secure and rapid exchange of
                    information concerning all aspects of the offences covered by this Convention,
                    including, if the States Parties concerned deem it appropriate, links with other
                    criminal activities;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002181_013" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To cooperate with other States
                    Parties in conducting inquiries with respect to offences covered by this
                    Convention concerning:</leadIn><paragraph class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1438413002196_006" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0-2_0"><content>(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The identity, whereabouts
                        and activities of persons suspected of involvement in such offences or the
                        location of other persons concerned;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413002196_015" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-2_0-1" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0"><content>(ii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The movement of proceeds of
                        crime or property derived from the commission of such offences;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413002196_024" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2_0-2" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_0"><content>(iii)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The movement of property,
                        equipment or other instrumentalities used or intended for use in the
                        commission of such offences;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002212_005" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To provide, where appropriate,
                    necessary items or quantities of substances for analytical or investigative
                    purposes;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002212_014" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To exchange, where appropriate,
                    information with other States Parties concerning specific means and methods used
                    to commit offences covered by this Convention, including the use of false
                    identities, forged, altered or false documents and other means of concealing
                    activities;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002227_005" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To facilitate effective coordination
                    between their competent authorities, agencies and services and to promote the
                    exchange of personnel and other experts, including, subject to bilateral
                    agreements or arrangements between the States Parties concerned, the posting of
                    liaison officers;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002227_014" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To exchange information and coordinate
                    administrative and other measures taken as appropriate for the purpose of early
                    identification of the offences covered by this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002243_004" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>With a view to giving effect to this
                    Convention, States Parties shall consider entering into bilateral or
                    multilateral agreements or arrangements on direct cooperation between their law
                    enforcement agencies and, where such agreements or arrangements already exist,
                    amending them. In the absence of such agreements or arrangements between the
                    States Parties concerned, the States Parties may consider this Convention to be
                    the basis for mutual law enforcement cooperation in respect of the offences
                    covered by this Convention. Whenever appropriate, States Parties shall make full
                    use of agreements or arrangements, including international or regional
                    organizations, to enhance the cooperation between their law enforcement
                    agencies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002259_004" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall endeavour to
                    cooperate within their means to respond to offences covered by this Convention
                    committed through the use of modern technology.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002274_002" name="P49" temporalId="sch1_P49" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 49</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Joint
                investigations</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall consider
                concluding bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements whereby, in relation
                to matters that are the subject of investigations, prosecutions or judicial
                proceedings in one or more States, the competent authorities concerned may establish
                joint investigative bodies. In the absence of such agreements or arrangements, joint
                investigations may be undertaken by agreement on a case-by-case basis. The States
                Parties involved shall ensure that the sovereignty of the State Party in whose
                territory such investigation is to take place is fully respected.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002290_001" name="P50" temporalId="sch1_P50" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 50</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Special investigative
                techniques</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413002290_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In order to combat corruption
                    effectively, each State Party shall, to the extent permitted by the basic
                    principles of its domestic legal system and in accordance with the conditions
                    prescribed by its domestic law, take such measures as may be necessary, within
                    its means, to allow for the appropriate use by its competent authorities of
                    controlled delivery and, where it deems appropriate, other special investigative
                    techniques, such as electronic or other forms of surveillance and undercover
                    operations, within its territory, and to allow for the admissibility in court of
                    evidence derived therefrom.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002305_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purpose of investigating the
                    offences covered by this Convention, States Parties are encouraged to conclude,
                    when necessary, appropriate bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements
                    for using such special investigative techniques in the context of cooperation at
                    the international level. Such agreements or arrangements shall be concluded and
                    implemented in full compliance with the principle of sovereign equality of
                    States and shall be carried out strictly in accordance with the terms of those
                    agreements or arrangements.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002337_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the absence of an agreement or
                    arrangement as set forth in <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of this article, decisions to
                    use such special investigative techniques at the international level shall be
                    made on a case-by-case basis and may, when necessary, take into consideration
                    financial arrangements and understandings with respect to the exercise of
                    jurisdiction by the States Parties concerned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002337_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Decisions to use controlled delivery at
                    the international level may, with the consent of the States Parties concerned,
                    include methods such as intercepting and allowing the goods or funds to continue
                    intact or be removed or replaced in whole or in
                    part.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></chapter><crossHeading>Chapter V</crossHeading><crossHeading>Asset recovery</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438413002352_017" name="P51" temporalId="sch1_P51" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 51</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">General
                provision</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">The return of assets pursuant to this
                chapter is a fundamental principle of this Convention, and States Parties shall
                afford one another the widest measure of cooperation and assistance in this
                regard.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002368_001" name="P52" temporalId="sch1_P52" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 52</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Prevention and detection of transfers of
                        proceeds of
                crime</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413002368_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Without prejudice to article 14 of this
                    Convention, each State Party shall take such measures as may be necessary, in
                    accordance with its domestic law, to require financial institutions within its
                    jurisdiction to verify the identity of customers, to take reasonable steps to
                    determine the identity of beneficial owners of funds deposited into high-value
                    accounts and to conduct enhanced scrutiny of accounts sought or maintained by or
                    on behalf of individuals who are, or have been, entrusted with prominent public
                    functions and their family members and close associates. Such enhanced scrutiny
                    shall be reasonably designed to detect suspicious transactions for the purpose
                    of reporting to competent authorities and should not be so construed as to
                    discourage or prohibit financial institutions from doing business with any
                    legitimate customer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002399_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In order to facilitate implementation
                    of the measures provided for in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article, each
                    State Party, in accordance with its domestic law and inspired by relevant
                    initiatives of regional, interregional and multilateral organizations against
                    money-laundering, shall:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002399_012" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Issue advisories regarding the types
                    of natural or legal person to whose accounts financial institutions within its
                    jurisdiction will be expected to apply enhanced scrutiny, the types of accounts
                    and transactions to which to pay particular attention and appropriate
                    account-opening, maintenance and record-keeping measures to take concerning such
                    accounts; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002415_005" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where appropriate, notify financial
                    institutions within its jurisdiction, at the request of another State Party or
                    on its own initiative, of the identity of particular natural or legal persons to
                    whose accounts such institutions will be expected to apply enhanced scrutiny, in
                    addition to those whom the financial institutions may otherwise
                    identify.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002430_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the context of <ref>paragraph 2
                        (a)</ref> of this article, each State Party shall
                    implement measures to ensure that its financial institutions maintain adequate
                    records, over an appropriate period of time, of accounts and transactions
                    involving the persons mentioned in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article, which
                    should, as a minimum, contain information relating to the identity of the
                    customer as well as, as far as possible, of the beneficial owner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002446_004" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>With the aim of preventing and
                    detecting transfers of proceeds of offences established in accordance with this
                    Convention, each State Party shall implement appropriate and effective measures
                    to prevent, with the help of its regulatory and oversight bodies, the
                    establishment of banks that have no physical presence and that are not
                    affiliated with a regulated financial group. Moreover, States Parties may
                    consider requiring their financial institutions to refuse to enter into or
                    continue a correspondent banking relationship with such institutions and to
                    guard against establishing relations with foreign financial institutions that
                    permit their accounts to be used by banks that have no physical presence and
                    that are not affiliated with a regulated financial group.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002477_004" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider
                    establishing, in accordance with its domestic law, effective financial
                    disclosure systems for appropriate public officials and shall provide for
                    appropriate sanctions for non-compliance. Each State Party shall also consider
                    taking such measures as may be necessary to permit its competent authorities to
                    share that information with the competent authorities in other States Parties
                    when necessary to investigate, claim and recover proceeds of offences
                    established in accordance with this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002493_004" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider taking
                    such measures as may be necessary, in accordance with its domestic law, to
                    require appropriate public officials having an interest in or signature or other
                    authority over a financial account in a foreign country to report that
                    relationship to appropriate authorities and to maintain appropriate records
                    related to such accounts. Such measures shall also provide for appropriate
                    sanctions for non-compliance.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002508_001" name="P53" temporalId="sch1_P53" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 53</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Measures for direct recovery of
                        property</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><leadIn class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Each State Party shall, in accordance
                with its domestic law:</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413002508_030" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Take such measures as may be necessary
                    to permit another State Party to initiate civil action in its courts to
                    establish title to or ownership of property acquired through the commission of
                    an offence established in accordance with this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002524_007" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Take such measures as may be necessary
                    to permit its courts to order those who have committed offences established in
                    accordance with this Convention to pay compensation or damages to another State
                    Party that has been harmed by such offences; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002524_016" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Take such measures as may be necessary
                    to permit its courts or competent authorities, when having to decide on
                    confiscation, to recognize another State Party’s claim as a legitimate owner of
                    property acquired through the commission of an offence established in accordance
                    with this Convention.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002539_001" name="P54" temporalId="sch1_P54" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 54</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Mechanisms for recovery of property through
                        <br></br>international
                        cooperation in
                confiscation</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413002539_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party, in order to provide
                    mutual legal assistance pursuant to article 55 of this Convention with respect
                    to property acquired through or involved in the commission of an offence
                    established in accordance with this Convention, shall, in accordance with its
                    domestic law:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002539_036" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Take such measures as may be necessary
                    to permit its competent authorities to give effect to an order of confiscation
                    issued by a court of another State Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002555_005" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Take such measures as may be necessary
                    to permit its competent authorities, where they have jurisdiction, to order the
                    confiscation of such property of foreign origin by adjudication of an offence of
                    money-laundering or such other offence as may be within its jurisdiction or by
                    other procedures authorized under its domestic law; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002571_005" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Consider taking such measures as may
                    be necessary to allow confiscation of such property without a criminal
                    conviction in cases in which the offender cannot be prosecuted by reason of
                    death, flight or absence or in other appropriate cases.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002571_013" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party, in order to provide
                    mutual legal assistance upon a request made pursuant to <ref>paragraph 2</ref>
                    of article 55 of this Convention, shall, in accordance with its domestic
                    law:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002571_021" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Take such measures as may be necessary
                    to permit its competent authorities to freeze or seize property upon a freezing
                    or seizure order issued by a court or competent authority of a requesting State
                    Party that provides a reasonable basis for the requested State Party to believe
                    that there are sufficient grounds for taking such actions and that the property
                    would eventually be subject to an order of confiscation for purposes of
                        <ref>paragraph 1(a)</ref> of this article;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002586_005" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Take such measures as may be necessary
                    to permit its competent authorities to freeze or seize property upon a request
                    that provides a reasonable basis for the requested State Party to believe that
                    there are sufficient grounds for taking such actions and that the property would
                    eventually be subject to an order of confiscation for purposes of <ref>paragraph
                        1(a)</ref> of this article; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002602_005" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Consider taking additional measures to
                    permit its competent authorities to preserve property for confiscation, such as
                    on the basis of a foreign arrest or criminal charge related to the acquisition
                    of such property.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002617_001" name="P55" temporalId="sch1_P55" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 55</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">International cooperation for purposes of
                        confiscation</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413002617_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A State Party that has received a
                    request from another State Party having jurisdiction over an offence established
                    in accordance with this Convention for confiscation of proceeds of crime,
                    property, equipment or other instrumentalities referred to in article 31,
                        <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, of this Convention situated in its territory shall,
                    to the greatest extent possible within its domestic legal system:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002617_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Submit the request to its competent
                    authorities for the purpose of obtaining an order of confiscation and, if such
                    an order is granted, give effect to it; or</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002633_005" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Submit to its competent authorities,
                    with a view to giving effect to it to the extent requested, an order of
                    confiscation issued by a court in the territory of the requesting State Party in
                    accordance with articles 31, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, and 54, <ref>paragraph 1
                        (a)</ref>, of this Convention insofar as it relates to
                    proceeds of crime, property, equipment or other instrumentalities referred to in
                    article 31, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, situated in the territory of the requested
                    State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002649_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Following a request made by another
                    State Party having jurisdiction over an offence established in accordance with
                    this Convention, the requested State Party shall take measures to identify,
                    trace and freeze or seize proceeds of crime, property, equipment or other
                    instrumentalities referred to in article 31, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, of this
                    Convention for the purpose of eventual confiscation to be ordered either by the
                    requesting State Party or, pursuant to a request under <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of
                    this article, by the requested State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002664_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The provisions of article 46 of this
                    Convention are applicable, mutatis mutandis, to this article. In addition to the
                    information specified in article 46, <ref>paragraph 15</ref>, requests made
                    pursuant to this article shall contain:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002664_012" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the case of a request pertaining to
                        <ref>paragraph 1
                        (a)</ref> of this article, a description of the property
                    to be confiscated, including, to the extent possible, the location and, where
                    relevant, the estimated value of the property and a statement of the facts
                    relied upon by the requesting State Party sufficient to enable the requested
                    State Party to seek the order under its domestic law;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002680_005" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the case of a request pertaining to
                        <ref>paragraph 1
                        (b)</ref> of this article, a legally admissible copy of an
                    order of confiscation upon which the request is based issued by the requesting
                    State Party, a statement of the facts and information as to the extent to which
                    execution of the order is requested, a statement specifying the measures taken
                    by the requesting State Party to provide adequate notification to bona fide
                    third parties and to ensure due process and a statement that the confiscation
                    order is final;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002695_005" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the case of a request pertaining to
                        <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of this article, a statement of the facts relied upon
                    by the requesting State Party and a description of the actions requested and,
                    where available, a legally admissible copy of an order on which the request is
                    based.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002711_004" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The decisions or actions provided for
                    in <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> of this article shall be taken by
                    the requested State Party in accordance with and subject to the provisions of
                    its domestic law and its procedural rules or any bilateral or multilateral
                    agreement or arrangement to which it may be bound in relation to the requesting
                    State Party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002727_004" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall furnish copies
                    of its laws and regulations that give effect to this article and of any
                    subsequent changes to such laws and regulations or a description thereof to the
                    Secretary-General of the United Nations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002727_012" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>If a State Party elects to make the
                    taking of the measures referred to in <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref>
                    of this article conditional on the existence of a relevant treaty, that State
                    Party shall consider this Convention the necessary and sufficient treaty
                    basis.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002742_004" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>7.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Cooperation under this article may also
                    be refused or provisional measures lifted if the requested State Party does not
                    receive sufficient and timely evidence or if the property is of a <i>de
                        minimis</i> value.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002742_012" name="0-12" temporalId="sch1_0-12" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>8.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Before lifting any provisional measure
                    taken pursuant to this article, the requested State Party shall, wherever
                    possible, give the requesting State Party an opportunity to present its reasons
                    in favour of continuing the measure.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002758_004" name="0-13" temporalId="sch1_0-13" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>9.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The provisions of this article shall
                    not be construed as prejudicing the rights of bona fide third
                    parties.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002758_009" name="P56" temporalId="sch1_P56" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 56</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Special
                cooperation</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Without prejudice to its domestic law,
                each State Party shall endeavour to take measures to permit it to forward, without
                prejudice to its own investigations, prosecutions or judicial proceedings,
                information on proceeds of offences established in accordance with this Convention
                to another State Party without prior request, when it considers that the disclosure
                of such information might assist the receiving State Party in initiating or carrying
                out investigations, prosecutions or judicial proceedings or might lead to a request
                by that State Party under this chapter of the Convention.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002773_001" name="P57" temporalId="sch1_P57" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 57</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Return and disposal of
                assets</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413002773_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Property confiscated by a State Party
                    pursuant to article 31 or 55 of this Convention shall be disposed of, including
                    by return to its prior legitimate owners, pursuant to <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of
                    this article, by that State Party in accordance with the provisions of this
                    Convention and its domestic law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002789_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall adopt such
                    legislative and other measures, in accordance with the fundamental principles of
                    its domestic law, as may be necessary to enable its competent authorities to
                    return confiscated property, when acting on the request made by another State
                    Party, in accordance with this Convention, taking into account the rights of
                    bona fide third parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002789_012" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In accordance with articles 46 and 55
                    of this Convention and <ref>paragraphs 1</ref> and <ref>2</ref> of this article,
                    the requested State Party shall:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002805_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the case of embezzlement of public
                    funds or of laundering of embezzled public funds as referred to in articles 17
                    and 23 of this Convention, when confiscation was executed in accordance with
                    article 55 and on the basis of a final judgement in the requesting State Party,
                    a requirement that can be waived by the requested State Party, return the
                    confiscated property to the requesting State Party;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002820_005" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In the case of proceeds of any other
                    offence covered by this Convention, when the confiscation was executed in
                    accordance with article 55 of this Convention and on the basis of a final
                    judgement in the requesting State Party, a requirement that can be waived by the
                    requested State Party, return the confiscated property to the requesting State
                    Party, when the requesting State Party reasonably establishes its prior
                    ownership of such confiscated property to the requested State Party or when the
                    requested State Party recognizes damage to the requesting State Party as a basis
                    for returning the confiscated property;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002836_005" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In all other cases, give priority
                    consideration to returning confiscated property to the requesting State Party,
                    returning such property to its prior legitimate owners or compensating the
                    victims of the crime.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002836_013" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where appropriate, unless States
                    Parties decide otherwise, the requested State Party may deduct reasonable
                    expenses incurred in investigations, prosecutions or judicial proceedings
                    leading to the return or disposition of confiscated property pursuant to this
                    article.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002851_004" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Where appropriate, States Parties may
                    also give special consideration to concluding agreements or mutually acceptable
                    arrangements, on a case-by-case basis, for the final disposal of confiscated
                    property.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002851_009" name="P58" temporalId="sch1_P58" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 58</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Financial intelligence
                unit</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall cooperate with one
                another for the purpose of preventing and combating the transfer of proceeds of
                offences established in accordance with this Convention and of promoting ways and
                means of recovering such proceeds and, to that end, shall consider establishing a
                financial intelligence unit to be responsible for receiving, analysing and
                disseminating to the competent authorities reports of suspicious financial
                transactions.</text></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413002867_017" name="P59" temporalId="sch1_P59" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 59</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Bilateral and multilateral agreements and
                        arrangements</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">States Parties shall consider
                concluding bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements to enhance the
                effectiveness of international cooperation undertaken pursuant to this chapter of
                the Convention.</text></chapter><crossHeading>Chapter VI</crossHeading><crossHeading>Technical assistance and information exchange</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438413002883_017" name="P60" temporalId="sch1_P60" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 60</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Training and technical
                assistance</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413002883_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall, to the extent
                    necessary, initiate, develop or improve specific training programmes for its
                    personnel responsible for preventing and combating corruption. Such training
                    programmes could deal, inter alia, with the following areas:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002883_044" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Effective measures to prevent, detect,
                    investigate, punish and control corruption, including the use of
                    evidence-gathering and investigative methods;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002898_005" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Building capacity in the development
                    and planning of strategic anti-corruption policy;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002898_014" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Training competent authorities in the
                    preparation of requests for mutual legal assistance that meet the requirements
                    of this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002898_023" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Evaluation and strengthening of
                    institutions, public service management and the management of public finances,
                    including public procurement, and the private sector;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002914_005" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Preventing and combating the transfer
                    of proceeds of offences established in accordance with this Convention and
                    recovering such proceeds;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002914_014" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Detecting and freezing of the transfer
                    of proceeds of offences established in accordance with this
                    Convention;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002914_023" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(g)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Surveillance of the movement of
                    proceeds of offences established in accordance with this Convention and of the
                    methods used to transfer, conceal or disguise such proceeds;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002929_005" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(h)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Appropriate and efficient legal and
                    administrative mechanisms and methods for facilitating the return of proceeds of
                    offences established in accordance with this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002929_014" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(i)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Methods used in protecting
                    victims and witnesses who cooperate with judicial authorities; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002929_023" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(j)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Training in national and
                    international regulations and in languages.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002945_004" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall, according to
                    their capacity, consider affording one another the widest measure of technical
                    assistance, especially for the benefit of developing countries, in their
                    respective plans and programmes to combat corruption, including material support
                    and training in the areas referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article,
                    and training and assistance and the mutual exchange of relevant experience and
                    specialized knowledge, which will facilitate international cooperation between
                    States Parties in the areas of extradition and mutual legal
                    assistance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002961_004" name="0-12" temporalId="sch1_0-12" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall strengthen, to the
                    extent necessary, efforts to maximize operational and training activities in
                    international and regional organizations and in the framework of relevant
                    bilateral and multilateral agreements or arrangements.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002976_004" name="0-13" temporalId="sch1_0-13" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider assisting
                    one another, upon request, in conducting evaluations, studies and research
                    relating to the types, causes, effects and costs of corruption in their
                    respective countries, with a view to developing, with the participation of
                    competent authorities and society, strategies and action plans to combat
                    corruption.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002976_012" name="0-14" temporalId="sch1_0-14" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>In order to facilitate the recovery of
                    proceeds of offences established in accordance with this Convention, States
                    Parties may cooperate in providing each other with the names of experts who
                    could assist in achieving that objective.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002992_004" name="0-15" temporalId="sch1_0-15" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider using
                    subregional, regional and international conferences and seminars to promote
                    cooperation and technical assistance and to stimulate discussion on problems of
                    mutual concern, including the special problems and needs of developing countries
                    and countries with economies in transition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413002992_012" name="0-16" temporalId="sch1_0-16" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>7.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider
                    establishing voluntary mechanisms with a view to contributing financially to the
                    efforts of developing countries and countries with economies in transition to
                    apply this Convention through technical assistance programmes and
                    projects.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003007_004" name="0-17" temporalId="sch1_0-17" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>8.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider making
                    voluntary contributions to the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime for the
                    purpose of fostering, through the Office, programmes and projects in developing
                    countries with a view to implementing this Convention.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003023_001" name="P61" temporalId="sch1_P61" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 61</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Collection, exchange and analysis of
                        <br></br>information
                        on
                corruption</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003023_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider
                    analysing, in consultation with experts, trends in corruption in its territory,
                    as well as the circumstances in which corruption offences are
                    committed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003023_036" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall consider
                    developing and sharing with each other and through international and regional
                    organizations statistics, analytical expertise concerning corruption and
                    information with a view to developing, insofar as possible, common definitions,
                    standards and methodologies, as well as information on best practices to prevent
                    and combat corruption.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003039_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall consider
                    monitoring its policies and actual measures to combat corruption and making
                    assessments of their effectiveness and efficiency.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003039_009" name="P62" temporalId="sch1_P62" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 62</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Other measures: implementation of the
                        Convention through
                        <br></br>economic
                        development and technical
                assistance</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003039_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall take measures
                    conducive to the optimal implementation of this Convention to the extent
                    possible, through international cooperation, taking into account the negative
                    effects of corruption on society in general, in particular on sustainable
                    development.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003054_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall make concrete
                    efforts to the extent possible and in coordination with each other, as well as
                    with international and regional organizations:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003054_012" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To enhance their cooperation at
                    various levels with developing countries, with a view to strengthening the
                    capacity of the latter to prevent and combat corruption;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003070_005" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To enhance financial and material
                    assistance to support the efforts of developing countries to prevent and fight
                    corruption effectively and to help them implement this Convention
                    successfully;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003070_014" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To provide technical assistance to
                    developing countries and countries with economies in transition to assist them
                    in meeting their needs for the implementation of this Convention. To that end,
                    States Parties shall endeavour to make adequate and regular voluntary
                    contributions to an account specifically designated for that purpose in a United
                    Nations funding mechanism. States Parties may also give special consideration,
                    in accordance with their domestic law and the provisions of this Convention, to
                    contributing to that account a percentage of the money or of the corresponding
                    value of proceeds of crime or property confiscated in accordance with the
                    provisions of this Convention;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003101_005" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To encourage and persuade other States
                    and financial institutions as appropriate to join them in efforts in accordance
                    with this article, in particular by providing more training programmes and
                    modern equipment to developing countries in order to assist them in achieving
                    the objectives of this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003101_013" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>To the extent possible, these measures
                    shall be without prejudice to existing foreign assistance commitments or to
                    other financial cooperation arrangements at the bilateral, regional or
                    international level.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003117_004" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties may conclude bilateral
                    or multilateral agreements or arrangements on material and logistical
                    assistance, taking into consideration the financial arrangements necessary for
                    the means of international cooperation provided for by this Convention to be
                    effective and for the prevention, detection and control of corruption.</content></subsection></chapter><crossHeading>Chapter VII</crossHeading><crossHeading>Mechanisms for implementation</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438413003132_008" name="P63" temporalId="sch1_P63" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 63</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Conference of the States Parties to the
                        Convention</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003132_027" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A Conference of the States Parties to
                    the Convention is hereby established to improve the capacity of and cooperation
                    between States Parties to achieve the objectives set forth in this Convention
                    and to promote and review its implementation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003132_035" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The Secretary-General of the United
                    Nations shall convene the Conference of the States Parties not later than one
                    year following the entry into force of this Convention. Thereafter, regular
                    meetings of the Conference of the States Parties shall be held in accordance
                    with the rules of procedure adopted by the Conference.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003148_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The Conference of the States Parties
                    shall adopt rules of procedure and rules governing the functioning of the
                    activities set forth in this article, including rules concerning the admission
                    and participation of observers, and the payment of expenses incurred in carrying
                    out those activities.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003148_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The Conference of the States Parties
                    shall agree upon activities, procedures and methods of work to achieve the
                    objectives set forth in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article,
                    including:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003163_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Facilitating activities by States
                    Parties under articles 60 and 62 and chapters II to V of this Convention,
                    including by encouraging the mobilization of voluntary contributions;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003163_013" name="0-5" temporalId="sch1_0-5" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Facilitating the exchange of
                    information among States Parties on patterns and trends in corruption and on
                    successful practices for preventing and combating it and for the return of
                    proceeds of crime, through, inter alia, the publication of relevant information
                    as mentioned in this article;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003179_005" name="0-6" temporalId="sch1_0-6" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Cooperating with relevant
                    international and regional organizations and mechanisms and non-governmental
                    organizations;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003179_014" name="0-7" temporalId="sch1_0-7" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(d)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Making appropriate use of relevant
                    information produced by other international and regional mechanisms for
                    combating and preventing corruption in order to avoid unnecessary duplication of
                    work;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003179_023" name="0-8" temporalId="sch1_0-8" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(e)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Reviewing periodically the
                    implementation of this Convention by its States Parties;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003195_005" name="0-9" temporalId="sch1_0-9" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(f)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Making recommendations to improve this
                    Convention and its implementation;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003195_014" name="0-10" temporalId="sch1_0-10" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(g)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Taking note of the technical
                    assistance requirements of States Parties with regard to the implementation of
                    this Convention and recommending any action it may deem necessary in that
                    respect.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003195_022" name="0-11" temporalId="sch1_0-11" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For the purpose of <ref>paragraph
                        4</ref> of this article, the Conference of the States Parties shall acquire
                    the necessary knowledge of the measures taken by States Parties in implementing
                    this Convention and the difficulties encountered by them in doing so through
                    information provided by them and through such supplemental review mechanisms as
                    may be established by the Conference of the States Parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003210_004" name="0-12" temporalId="sch1_0-12" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>6.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall provide the
                    Conference of the States Parties with information on its programmes, plans and
                    practices, as well as on legislative and administrative measures to implement
                    this Convention, as required by the Conference of the States Parties. The
                    Conference of the States Parties shall examine the most effective way of
                    receiving and acting upon information, including, inter alia, information
                    received from States Parties and from competent international organizations.
                    Inputs received from relevant non-governmental organizations duly accredited in
                    accordance with procedures to be decided upon by the Conference of the States
                    Parties may also be considered.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003241_004" name="0-13" temporalId="sch1_0-13" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>7.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Pursuant to <ref>paragraphs 4 to
                        6</ref> of this article, the Conference of the States Parties shall
                    establish, if it deems it necessary, any appropriate mechanism or body to assist
                    in the effective implementation of the Convention.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003257_001" name="P64" temporalId="sch1_P64" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 64</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Secretariat</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003257_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The Secretary-General of the United
                    Nations shall provide the necessary secretariat services to the Conference of
                    the States Parties to the Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003257_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The secretariat shall:</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003257_036" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(a)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Assist the Conference of the States
                    Parties in carrying out the activities set forth in article 63 of this
                    Convention and make arrangements and provide the necessary services for the
                    sessions of the Conference of the States Parties;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003273_005" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(b)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Upon request, assist States Parties in
                    providing information to the Conference of the States Parties as envisaged in
                    article 63, <ref>paragraphs 5</ref> and <ref>6</ref>, of this Convention;
                    and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003273_014" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>(c)<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Ensure the necessary coordination with
                    the secretariats of relevant international and regional organizations.</content></subsection></chapter><crossHeading>Chapter VIII</crossHeading><crossHeading>Final provisions</crossHeading><chapter id="ID_1438413003288_017" name="P65" temporalId="sch1_P65" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 65</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Implementation of the
                Convention</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003288_036" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party shall take the
                    necessary measures, including legislative and administrative measures, in
                    accordance with fundamental principles of its domestic law, to ensure the
                    implementation of its obligations under this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003288_044" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party may adopt more strict
                    or severe measures than those provided for by this Convention for preventing and
                    combating
                    corruption.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003304_001" name="P66" temporalId="sch1_P66" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 66</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Settlement of
                disputes</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subparagraph class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24" id="ID_1438413003304_023" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>States Parties shall endeavour
                    to settle disputes concerning the interpretation or application of this
                    Convention through negotiation.</content></subparagraph><subsection id="ID_1438413003304_028" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Any dispute between two or more States
                    Parties concerning the interpretation or application of this Convention that
                    cannot be settled through negotiation within a reasonable time shall, at the
                    request of one of those States Parties, be submitted to arbitration. If, six
                    months after the date of the request for arbitration, those States Parties are
                    unable to agree on the organization of the arbitration, any one of those States
                    Parties may refer the dispute to the International Court of Justice by request
                    in accordance with the Statute of the Court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003319_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Each State Party may, at the time of
                    signature, ratification, acceptance or approval of or accession to this
                    Convention, declare that it does not consider itself bound by <ref>paragraph
                        2</ref> of this article. The other States Parties shall not be bound by
                        <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of this article with respect to any State Party that
                    has made such a reservation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003335_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Any State Party that has made a
                    reservation in accordance with <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of this article may at any
                    time withdraw that reservation by notification to the Secretary-General of the
                    United Nations.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003335_009" name="P67" temporalId="sch1_P67" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 67</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Signature, ratification, acceptance,
                        <br></br>approval
                        and
                accession</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003351_004" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Convention shall be open to all
                    States for signature from 9 to 11 December 2003 in Merida, Mexico, and
                    thereafter at United Nations Headquarters in New York until 9 December
                    2005.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003351_012" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Convention shall also be open for
                    signature by regional economic integration organizations provided that at least
                    one member State of such organization has signed this Convention in accordance
                    with <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003351_020" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Convention is subject to
                    ratification, acceptance or approval. Instruments of ratification, acceptance or
                    approval shall be deposited with the Secretary-General of the United Nations. A
                    regional economic integration organization may deposit its instrument of
                    ratification, acceptance or approval if at least one of its member States has
                    done likewise. In that instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval, such
                    organization shall declare the extent of its competence with respect to the
                    matters governed by this Convention. Such organization shall also inform the
                    depositary of any relevant modification in the extent of its
                    competence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003382_004" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Convention is open for accession
                    by any State or any regional economic integration organization of which at least
                    one member State is a Party to this Convention. Instruments of accession shall
                    be deposited with the Secretary-General of the United Nations. At the time of
                    its accession, a regional economic integration organization shall declare the
                    extent of its competence with respect to matters governed by this Convention.
                    Such organization shall also inform the depositary of any relevant modification
                    in the extent of its competence.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003397_001" name="P68" temporalId="sch1_P68" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 68</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Entry into
                force</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003397_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>This Convention shall enter into force
                    on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit of the thirtieth instrument of
                    ratification, acceptance, approval or accession. For the purpose of this
                    paragraph, any instrument deposited by a regional economic integration
                    organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by member
                    States of such organization.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003413_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>For each State or regional economic
                    integration organization ratifying, accepting, approving or acceding to this
                    Convention after the deposit of the thirtieth instrument of such action, this
                    Convention shall enter into force on the thirtieth day after the date of deposit
                    by such State or organization of the relevant instrument or on the date this
                    Convention enters into force pursuant to <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article,
                    whichever is later.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003429_001" name="P69" temporalId="sch1_P69" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 69</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Amendment</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003429_020" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>After the expiry of five years from the
                    entry into force of this Convention, a State Party may propose an amendment and
                    transmit it to the Secretary-General of the United Nations, who shall thereupon
                    communicate the proposed amendment to the States Parties and to the Conference
                    of the States Parties to the Convention for the purpose of considering and
                    deciding on the proposal. The Conference of the States Parties shall make every
                    effort to achieve consensus on each amendment. If all efforts at consensus have
                    been exhausted and no agreement has been reached, the amendment shall, as a last
                    resort, require for its adoption a two-thirds majority vote of the States
                    Parties present and voting at the meeting of the Conference of the States
                    Parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003460_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>Regional economic integration
                    organizations, in matters within their competence, shall exercise their right to
                    vote under this article with a number of votes equal to the number of their
                    member States that are Parties to this Convention. Such organizations shall not
                    exercise their right to vote if their member States exercise theirs and vice
                    versa.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003475_004" name="0-2" temporalId="sch1_0-2" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>3.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>An amendment adopted in accordance with
                        <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article is subject to ratification,
                    acceptance or approval by States Parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003475_012" name="0-3" temporalId="sch1_0-3" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>4.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>An amendment adopted in accordance with
                        <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this article shall enter into force in respect of
                    a State Party ninety days after the date of the deposit with the
                    Secretary-General of the United Nations of an instrument of ratification,
                    acceptance or approval of such amendment. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003491_004" name="0-4" temporalId="sch1_0-4" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>5.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>When an amendment enters into force, it
                    shall be binding on those States Parties which have expressed their consent to
                    be bound by it. Other States Parties shall still be bound by the provisions of
                    this Convention and any earlier amendments that they have ratified, accepted or
                    approved.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003491_009" name="P70" temporalId="sch1_P70" class="no_header"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 70</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Denunciation</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003491_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A State Party may denounce this
                    Convention by written notification to the Secretary-General of the United
                    Nations. Such denunciation shall become effective one year after the date of
                    receipt of the notification by the Secretary-General.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003507_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>A regional economic integration
                    organization shall cease to be a Party to this Convention when all of its member
                    States have denounced it.</content></subsection></chapter><chapter id="ID_1438413003507_009" name="P71" temporalId="sch1_P71" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Article 71</inline></i></crossHeading><crossHeading><i><inline class="not_bold">Depositary and
                languages</inline></i><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438413003507_028" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>1.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The Secretary-General of the United
                    Nations is designated depositary of this Convention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413003522_004" name="0-1" temporalId="sch1_0-1" class="no_header left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24"><content>2.<fillIn class="width_9"> </fillIn>The original of this Convention, of
                    which the Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish texts are
                    equally authentic, shall be deposited with the Secretary-General of the United
                    Nations.</content></subsection><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the undersigned
                plenipotentiaries, being duly authorized thereto by their respective Governments,
                have signed this Convention.</text></chapter></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403326214_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
            2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap525W/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Modifications
            to the
            Ordinance</heading><section id="ID_1438413004677_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1"><inline class="not_bold">1.</inline></num><content><ref>Section
                    17(3)(b)</ref>
                of the Ordinance shall be modified to read as follows—</content><quotedStructure class="left_indent_36">
                
                <subsection class="left_indent_60 first_line_indent_-24"><num value="b">“(b)</num><leadIn>the person has had an opportunity of leaving Hong Kong and has remained
                        in Hong Kong <ins>for the specified period from the date of being officially
                            informed that his presence is no longer required for any of the
                            following purposes</ins>* <del>otherwise than for</del>**—</leadIn><paragraph><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the purpose to which the request relates; <del>or</del>**</content></paragraph><paragraph><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the purpose of giving assistance in relation to a criminal matter
                            in Hong Kong certified in writing by the Secretary for Justice to be a
                            criminal matter in relation to which it is desirable that the person
                            give assistance.”.</content></paragraph></subsection>
                
            </quotedStructure></section><section id="ID_1438413004677_045" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2"><inline class="not_bold">2.</inline></num><content><ref>Section 17</ref> of the Ordinance shall be modified by adding—</content><quotedStructure class="left_indent_36">
                
                <subsection class="left_indent_60 first_line_indent_-24"><num value="6">“(6)</num><leadIn><ins>In subsection
                                <ref>(3)(b)</ref>,
                                “<term class="old_format">specified period</term>” (</ins><ins><term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明期間</term></ins><ins>) means—</ins></leadIn><paragraph><num value="a" class="tab_underline"><inline class="underline">(a)</inline></num><content><inline class="underline">in the case where a period has been
                                agreed between Hong Kong and the place outside Hong Kong to which
                                the request relates, that period; and</inline></content></paragraph><paragraph><num value="b" class="tab_underline"><inline class="underline">(b)</inline></num><content><inline class="underline">in the case where no such period has been
                                agreed, a period of 15 consecutive days.</inline>*”.</content></paragraph></subsection>
                
            </quotedStructure></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1521791561448_001" name="s0" temporalId="sch2_s0"><num value="0">*</num><content class="align_justified">The words underlined are added. (The underlining is for
                ease of identifying the
                modification).</content></section><section class="no_header" id="ID_1521791561448_002" name="s0" temporalId="sch2_s0"><num value="0">**</num><content class="align_justified">The words crossed out are deleted. (The crossing out is
                for ease of identifying the modification).</content></section></schedule></main></subLeg>