<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 539 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>539A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap539A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-09-16</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403394243_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-09-16">
            
            
            <p>Hong Kong Special Administrative Region Passports (Appeal Board) Regulation</p>
            
        </docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap539/s10">Cap.
                539,
                section
            10(2)</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
            2021</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[7 September 1998]<sourceNote> <ref href="/hk/1998/ln305">L.N. 305 of
            1998</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403394258_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403394258_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Appellant"><term class="old_format"><b><i>appellant</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">上訴人</term>) means a person who initiates an appeal
            under <ref>section 10(1)</ref> of the Ordinance;</def><def name="Board"><term class="old_format"><b><i>Board</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">委員會</term>) means the Hong Kong Special Administrative
            Region Passports Appeal Board established by <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="BoardSecretary"><term class="old_format"><b><i>Board
                        Secretary</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">委員會秘書</term>) means the person appointed as Secretary
            to the Board under <ref>section 5(1)</ref>;</def><def name="Chairman"><term class="old_format"><b><i>Chairman</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the person appointed as Chairman of
            the Board under <ref>section 4(1)</ref>;</def><def name="DeputyChairman"><term class="old_format"><b><i>Deputy
                        Chairman</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">副主席</term>) means the person appointed as Deputy
            Chairman of the Board under <ref>section 4(1)</ref>;</def><def name="Respondent"><term class="old_format"><b><i>respondent</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">答辯人</term>) means the Director of Immigration whose
            decision has been appealed against and who may be represented by an immigration
            officer;</def><def name="Secretary"><term class="old_format"><b><i>Secretary</i></b></term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">局長</term>) means the Secretary for Security.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403394274_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Establishment of Hong Kong Special Administrative Region Passports Appeal Board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121120_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall be a board called the
                                “Hong
                                Kong Special Administrative Region Passports Appeal
                                        Board”.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                                        2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121120_019" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The functions of the Board are to consider, hear and determine any appeal made to the Board under <ref>section 10(1)</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121120_027" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purpose of considering, hearing and determining an appeal, the members of the Board shall comprise—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413121136_005" name="a" temporalId="s3_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a person who shall preside, either the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121136_013" name="b" temporalId="s3_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>2 of the persons from the panel referred to in <ref>section 4(2)</ref> as the Secretary may appoint for that purpose.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394289_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Chairman, Deputy Chairman and members</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121151_019" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Secretary shall appoint from among persons who are qualified for appointment as District Judges under <ref>section 5</ref> of the District Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap336">Cap. 336</ref>)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413121151_027" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a Chairman of the Board; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121151_035" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a Deputy Chairman of the Board.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121151_042" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Secretary shall appoint a panel of persons whom he considers suitable for appointment as members of the Board.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121167_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subsection (5), a person appointed as Chairman or Deputy Chairman or to the panel of persons, shall be appointed for a term of 3 years but may be reappointed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121167_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An appointment under this section shall be notified in the Gazette.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121167_021" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person appointed under this section may resign by notice in writing to the Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121167_029" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The remuneration and any subsequent revision, if any, of the Chairman, Deputy Chairman and other members of the Board considering, hearing and determining an appeal shall be determined by the Secretary and shall be payable out of the general revenue of Hong Kong.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394289_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Board Secretary</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121198_012" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>There shall be a Secretary to the Board who shall be appointed by the Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121198_020" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Secretary may give the Board Secretary such directions as he thinks fit for the purposes of this Regulation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121198_028" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Chairman may give to the Board Secretary such directions as he thinks fit with respect to the exercise of the Board Secretary’s functions under this Regulation, either generally or in any particular case.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121214_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Board Secretary shall, in the exercise or performance of any functions or duties under this Regulation, comply with any directions given by the Chairman under subsection (3) in addition to complying with directions given by the Secretary under subsection (2).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394305_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Provision where Chairman, Deputy Chairman or member absent</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121229_035" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If, for any period, the Chairman is precluded by absence from Hong Kong or any other cause from exercising his functions, the Deputy Chairman shall act on behalf of the Chairman and as such to exercise and perform all the functions of the Chairman during that period.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121245_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the term of appointment of the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman or of any person appointed by the Secretary under <ref>section 4(2)</ref> expires during the hearing of an appeal, the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman or such person may continue to hear the appeal until the appeal is determined.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394321_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Hearing of appeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121260_019" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Board shall hear an appeal regardless of whether—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413121276_005" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the appeal is lodged in or from outside Hong Kong; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121276_013" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the disputed decision was made with regard to an application submitted in or from outside Hong Kong.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121276_020" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where the Board, upon an examination of a written notice of appeal received under <ref>section 9(2)</ref> is satisfied that the facts or matters on which the appellant is seeking to rely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413121276_028" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>would not entitle the appellant to succeed in the appeal; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121276_036" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>are the same or substantially the same facts or matters on which the appellant sought to rely on in an unsuccessful appeal under <ref>section 2AD(1)</ref> or <ref>53A(1)(aa)</ref> of the Immigration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap115">Cap. 115</ref>) or <ref>section 3D(1)</ref> of the Registration of Persons Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap177">Cap. 177</ref>),</content></paragraph><continued>the Board may dismiss the appeal without a hearing and shall cause written notice of such dismissal to be given or sent by post to the appellant.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121292_011" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In determining whether an appeal is to be dismissed without a hearing under subsection (2), the opinions of the majority of members of the Board, including the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman if he is presiding, shall prevail.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121292_019" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The decision of the Board under subsection (2) shall be final.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394336_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Expediting appeals</heading><content>The Board shall deal with an appeal as expeditiously as is practicable, and for that purpose may sit at any time.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394336_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Applications to Board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121338_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An appeal to the Board shall be made by written notice setting forth the grounds of appeal and the facts relied on. The notice of appeal may be in such form as the Chairman may accept.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121338_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The appellant shall send or deliver the notice of appeal to the Board Secretary within 90 days after the date on which the disputed decision was given to or served upon the appellant or within such longer period as the Chairman, on application, may allow.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121354_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Board Secretary shall acknowledge the receipt of the notice of appeal and will inform the appellant or his representative of any further steps which the appellant shall take to enable the Board to decide the appeal.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394352_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Board Secretary to serve notice of appeal on respondent</heading><content>The Board Secretary shall serve a copy of a notice of appeal lodged with him under <ref>section 9</ref> on the respondent within 14 days after the notice of appeal is so lodged.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394367_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Respondent to prepare facts for Board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121385_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The respondent shall, as soon as practicable after notice of appeal is served under <ref>section 10</ref>, cause—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413121385_019" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a written summary of the facts of the case and of the reasons for the decision appealed against to be prepared and to be referred to the Board; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121385_027" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a copy thereof to be given to the appellant.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121401_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>It shall not be necessary for the respondent to comply with subsection (1) if he is of the opinion that it is not practicable to do so having regard to the time available before the hearing of the appeal, but in any such case an oral statement of the facts of the case and of the reasons for the decision appealed against shall be given at the hearing of the appeal.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394367_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Date, time and place of hearing</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121432_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where notice of appeal is lodged, the Board Secretary shall, subject to subsection (2), fix the date, time and place of the hearing of the appeal so as to enable the hearing to commence as soon as is reasonably practicable and shall, not less than 28 days before the date so fixed, serve on the appellant and the respondent notice of the date, time and place in such form as the Chairman may determine.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121448_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of an appeal, the Board may determine the appeal without an oral hearing on the basis of written submissions on oath or affirmation only.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394383_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Board not confined to grounds set out in notice of appeal</heading><content>The Board may consider any matter which appears to it to be relevant to grounds of any appeal permitted by the Ordinance notwithstanding the omission of any reference to such matter in the notice of appeal, and may receive and consider any evidence which appears to it to be relevant to the issues before it notwithstanding that the evidence would not be admissible in a court of law.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394383_004" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Representation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121494_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The appellant and the respondent may appear and be present at the hearing of the appeal and may make representations or be represented either by a barrister or a solicitor or, with the approval of the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman if he is presiding at the hearing, by any other person authorized by the appellant or the respondent in writing. The respondent may be represented by a legal officer within the meaning of the Legal Officers Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap87">Cap. 87</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121510_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Board shall consider any written representations on oath or affirmation submitted by the appellant.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394399_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Appellant a minor or under a disability</heading><content>Where the appellant is a minor, or is prevented by mental or physical infirmity from acting on his own behalf, the appeal may, subject to the conditions imposed by the Chairman, be brought by a parent or guardian, or by a person appointed by the Chairman.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394399_004" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Witnesses and evidence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121557_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Board may, on the application of an appellant or of the respondent, or on its own motion, require any person to attend as a witness at the hearing of an appeal at such time and place as may be specified, and at the hearing to answer any questions, to give evidence or produce any documents in that person’s possession, custody or power which may relate to any issue in the appeal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121557_012" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438413121557_016" name="a" temporalId="s16_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Notwithstanding subsection (1), no person shall be compelled to give any evidence or produce any document which he could not be compelled to give or produce in proceedings in a court of law.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121572_006" name="b" temporalId="s16_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Nothing in this subsection shall entitle any person to refuse to give any evidence or to produce any document on the ground only that such evidence or document would not be admissible in a court of law and that accordingly he could not be compelled to give or produce it.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121572_013" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Board may require any witness to give evidence on oath or affirmation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121572_021" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Board may receive and consider any evidence by way of written statements on oath or affirmation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121572_029" name="5" temporalId="s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438413121588_001" name="a" temporalId="s16_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>The Board may allow in respect of a witness who attends at the hearing of
                    an appeal to give evidence (including professional or expert evidence) a
                    professional witness allowance, expert witness allowance or loss allowance, as
                    the case may be, not exceeding the professional witness allowance, expert
                    witness allowance or loss allowance that a magistrate may allow under the
                    Criminal Procedure (Witnesses’ Allowances) Rules (<ref href="/hk/cap221B">Cap.
                        221 sub.
                        leg.
                        B</ref>) in respect of a witness who attends to give
                    evidence in criminal
                        proceedings.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/er4">E.R. 4 of
                            2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121588_007" name="b" temporalId="s16_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Any sum allowed under paragraph (a) shall cease to be payable unless
                    claimed within 3 months from the date on which it was allowed.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394414_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Hearings to be in private</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121635_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), an appeal shall be heard in private.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121635_012" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chairman, or the Deputy Chairman if he is presiding, may, if he thinks proper, permit any person to be present at the hearing.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394430_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Abandonment of appeal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121650_012" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The appellant may abandon the whole or any part of the appeal by notice in writing lodged with the Board Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121650_020" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>When lodging a notice under subsection (1), the appellant shall at the same time serve a copy of such notice on the respondent.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394430_003" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Failure of appellant to attend hearing</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121666_019" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If on the day and time fixed for the hearing of the appeal, the appellant fails to attend the hearing or fails to make representations either in person or by a barrister or a solicitor or by some other authorized person, the Board may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413121682_005" name="a" temporalId="s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if satisfied that the appellant’s failure to attend was due to sickness or any other reasonable cause, postpone or adjourn the hearing for such period as it thinks fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121682_013" name="b" temporalId="s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>proceed to hear the appeal; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121682_021" name="c" temporalId="s19_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by order dismiss the appeal.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121682_028" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the appeal is dismissed by the Board under subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref> the appellant may, within 28 days after the making of the order for dismissal, by notice in writing lodged with the Board Secretary, apply to the Board to review the order and the Board may, if satisfied that the appellant’s failure to attend the hearing was due to sickness or any other reasonable cause, set aside the order for dismissal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121697_005" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>When lodging a notice under subsection (2), the appellant shall at the same time serve a copy of such notice on the respondent.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394445_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Language</heading><content>The hearing of an appeal to the Board may be conducted in the English or Chinese language or both as the Board thinks fit.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394445_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Record of proceedings</heading><content>The Board shall keep a summary or record of proceedings in every appeal which comes before it in such form as the Chairman may determine.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394461_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Questions to be decided by majority</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121744_011" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every question before the Board, except a question of law, shall be determined by the opinions of the majority of members hearing the appeal, including the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman if he is presiding at the hearing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121760_005" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Question of law shall be determined by the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman if he is presiding at the hearing.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394461_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Decision of Board</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413121775_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Board hearing an appeal may by order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413121775_012" name="a" temporalId="s23_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>confirm the decision under appeal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121775_020" name="b" temporalId="s23_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>dismiss the appeal; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413121775_028" name="c" temporalId="s23_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>direct the respondent to reverse, vary or substitute the decision under appeal.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121775_035" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Board shall give reasons in writing for its decisions, and those reasons shall include its findings on material questions of fact and a summary of the evidence or other material on which those findings were based.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121791_005" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The decision of the Board on question of fact under this Regulation shall be final.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121791_013" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Board Secretary shall serve a copy of the Board’s decision and of the reasons for its decisions on the appellant and the respondent.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413121791_021" name="5" temporalId="s23_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A document purporting to be a copy of a decision or order of the Board and to be certified by the Chairman or the Deputy Chairman who presided at the hearing to be a true copy of the decision or order is admissible in any proceedings as evidence of the decision or order.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403394477_001" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Conduct of proceedings</heading><content>Subject to this Regulation, the Board may determine its own procedure for the purposes of considering, hearing and determining an appeal.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403394477_003" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-16" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><content>An appeal may be made under this Regulation with respect to any decision made by
            the Director of Immigration under <ref>section 3(1)</ref>, <ref>4(2)</ref>,
                <ref>5(1)</ref> or <ref>9</ref> of the Ordinance before the
            commencement*
            of this Regulation, provided that the appeal is lodged within 90 days from the
            commencement of this Regulation, or within such longer period as the Chairman, on
            application, may allow.</content><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1626923220496_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 7 September
                1998.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></main></subLeg>