<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 382</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>382</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap382!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2021-10-07</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403136346_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2021-09-17">
            <content>To declare and define certain powers, privileges and immunities of the
                Legislative Council and of the members and officers thereof and of the Chief
                Executive and public officers designated by him in relation to attendance at
                sittings of the Legislative Council and committees thereof; to secure freedom of
                speech in the Legislative Council; to make provision for regulating admittance to
                and conduct within the precincts of the Chamber of the Legislative Council;
                to make
                provision for disciplinary sanctions against the members of the Legislative Council
                in certain circumstances; to provide for the giving of evidence in
                proceedings before the Legislative Council or committees thereof, and for offences
                in respect of such proceedings and related matters; and for purposes incidental to
                or connected therewith.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/11">11 of 1994 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s.
            3</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[26 July 1985]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1985/ln215">L.N. 215 of 1985</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403136377_001" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403136377_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Legislative Council (Powers and Privileges) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403136409_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-17" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412343994_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, except where the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Chamber"><term>Chamber</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會議廳</term>) means the Chamber in which the
                proceedings of the Council are conducted, and any galleries and places therein
                provided for members of the public and representatives of the press, television and
                radio, and includes any lobbies, offices or precincts used exclusively in
                connexion
                with the proceedings of the Council;</def><def name="Clerk"><term>Clerk</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">秘書</term>) means the Clerk to the Legislative
                Council or any person acting as his deputy;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1994/11">11 of 1994 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Committee">
                <leadIn><term>committee</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">委員會</term>) means—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412343994_040" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a standing or select committee or any other committee of the
                        Council;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412343994_048" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a subcommittee of any committee referred to in paragraph (a);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1994/11">11 of 1994 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="Council"><term>Council</term>
                means the Legislative Council;</def><def name="Journals"><term>journals</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">議事錄</term>) means the minutes of the Council or the
                official record of the votes and proceedings thereof;</def><def name="Member"><term>member</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">議員</term>) means a member of the Council;</def><def name="OfficerOfTheCouncil"><term>officer
                    of the
                Council</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">立法會人員</term>) means the Clerk or any other officer
                or person acting within the precincts of the Chamber under the orders of the
                President and includes any police officer on duty within the precincts of the
                    Chamber;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="PrecinctsOfTheChamber"><term>precincts
                    of the
                Chamber</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">會議廳範圍</term>) means the Chamber and offices of the
                Council and any adjacent galleries and places provided for the use or accommodation
                of members of the public and representatives of the press, television and radio, and
                subject to any exceptions made by the President under subsection (2) includes,
                during the whole of any day the Council or a committee is sitting, the entire
                building in which the Chamber is situated and any forecourt, yard, garden, enclosure
                or open space adjoining or appertaining to such building and used or provided for
                the purposes of the Council;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/11">11 of 1994 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="President"><term>President</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the President of the Council, and
                includes any other member of the Council when presiding at a sitting of the
                Council;</def><def name="RulesOfProcedure"><term>Rules
                    of
                Procedure</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">議事規則</term>) means the Rules of Procedure of the
                Council for the time being in force.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344025_011" name="1A" temporalId="s2_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>For the purposes of the definition of <term>committee</term> in subsection (1)
                the reference to any other committee of the Council shall be construed as including
                a panel consisting only of members and paragraph (b) of that definition shall be
                construed and have effect accordingly.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/11">11 of 1994 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632187689909_001" name="1B" temporalId="s2_1B"><num value="1B">(1B)</num><leadIn>In relation to a sitting of the Council or a committee conducted remotely
                pursuant to an authorization under <ref>section 27</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1632187689912_002" name="a" temporalId="s2_1B_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the definitions of <b><i>Chamber</i></b> and <b><i>precincts of the
                            Chamber</i></b> in subsection (1) are to be construed as including the
                    place or places designated under <ref>section 27(</ref>2) for the sitting;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1632187689914_003" name="b" temporalId="s2_1B_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the definition of <b><i>precincts of the Chamber</i></b> in subsection (1)
                    is not to be construed as including the entire building in which the proceedings
                    of the Council or a committee are conducted, or the entire building in which the
                    place or places referred to in paragraph (a) is or are situated.
                        <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344025_019" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="PrecinctsOfTheChamber">The President may, by notice published in the Gazette,
                order that any part of a building, forecourt, yard, garden, enclosure or open space
                referred to in the definition in subsection (1) of <b><i>precincts of the
                        Chamber</i></b> shall be excluded from that definition, either generally or
                for a specific purpose and either temporarily or permanently.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403136424_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Privileges
            and
            Immunities</heading><section id="ID_1438403136440_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Freedom of speech and debate</heading><content>There shall be freedom of speech and debate in the Council or proceedings before a committee, and such freedom of speech and debate shall not be liable to be questioned in any court or place outside the Council.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403136440_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Immunity from legal proceedings</heading><content>No civil or criminal proceedings shall be instituted against any member for words spoken before, or written in a report to, the Council or a committee, or by reason of any matter brought by him therein by petition, Bill, resolution, motion or otherwise.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403136455_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Freedom from arrest</heading><leadIn>No member shall be liable to arrest—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344119_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for any civil debt (except a debt the contraction of which constitutes a criminal offence) whilst going to, attending at or returning from a sitting of the Council or a committee;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344119_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for any criminal offence whilst attending at a sitting of the Council or a committee.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403136471_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Service of civil process and exemptions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344134_033" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No process issued by any court in Hong Kong or elsewhere in the exercise of its
                civil jurisdiction shall be served or executed within the precincts of the Chamber
                while the Council is sitting, nor shall any such process be served or executed
                through the President or any officer of the Council unless it relates to a person
                employed within the precincts of the Chamber.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344134_041" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Except by leave of the Council obtained in accordance with the Rules of
                Procedure, a member, the Chief Executive or any public officer designated by the
                Chief Executive for the purpose of attending sittings of the Council, while so
                designated, shall not be required to attend as a witness in any civil proceedings on
                a day when the Council is sitting.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/11">11 of 1994 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344150_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A member shall be exempted from service as a juror in accordance with
                    <ref>section 5</ref> of the Jury Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap3">Cap.
                3</ref>).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136471_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Evidence of proceedings in the Council or any committee not to be given without
            leave</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344165_055" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No member or officer of the Council, and no person employed to take minutes or
                keep any record of evidence before the Council or a committee, shall give evidence
                elsewhere in respect of the contents of such minutes or record of evidence, or of
                the contents of any document laid before the Council or committee, as the case may
                be, or in respect of any proceedings or examination held before the Council or
                committee, as the case may be, without the special leave of the Council.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344181_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>During a recess or adjournment of the Council, the special leave referred to in
                subsection (1) may be given by the President or, if the President is unable to act
                owing to his absence from Hong Kong or incapacity, in accordance with the Rules of
                    Procedure.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136487_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Regulation of admittance to precincts of the Chamber</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344197_040" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to this section, sittings of the Council shall be open to the
                public.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344212_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The right of persons other than members or officers of the Council to enter or
                remain within the precincts of the Chamber shall be subject to the Rules of
                Procedure or any resolution of the Council limiting or prohibiting the enjoyment of
                such right.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344212_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The President may from time to time, for the purpose of maintaining the
                security of the precincts of the Chamber, ensuring the proper behaviour and decorum
                of persons therein and for other administrative purposes, issue such administrative
                instructions as he may deem necessary or expedient for regulating the admittance of
                persons (other than members or officers of the Council) to, and the conduct of such
                persons within, the Chamber and the precincts of the Chamber.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344228_005" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Copies of administrative instructions issued by the President under subsection
                (3) shall be duly authenticated by the Clerk and exhibited in a conspicuous position
                in the precincts of the Chamber; and such copies when so authenticated and exhibited
                shall be deemed to be sufficient notice to all persons affected thereby.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136502_001" name="s8A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s8A"><num value="8A">8A.</num><heading>Extension of privileges and immunities</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344243_041" name="1" temporalId="s8A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The persons specified in subsection (2) shall, in the relevant circumstances
                described in that subsection, enjoy the same privileges or immunities as those
                provided in or conferred on the members by <ref>section 3</ref>, <ref>4</ref> or
                    <ref>5</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344259_005" name="2" temporalId="s8A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The persons and circumstances referred to in subsection (1) are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344259_013" name="a" temporalId="s8A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Chief Executive when present at a sitting of the Council or a
                    committee; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344259_021" name="b" temporalId="s8A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any public officer designated by the Chief Executive for the purpose of
                    attending sittings of the Council or any committee, while so designated and
                    attending any such sitting.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s.
                            3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/11">11 of 1994 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403136502_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Evidence</heading><section id="ID_1438403136518_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Power to order attendance of witnesses</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344290_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Council or a standing committee thereof may, subject to <ref>sections 13</ref> and <ref>14</ref>, order any person to attend before the Council or before such committee and to give evidence or to produce any paper, book, record or document in the possession or under the control of such person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344290_012" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The powers conferred by subsection (1) on a standing committee may be exercised by any other committee which is specially authorized by a resolution of the Council to exercise such powers in respect of any matter or question specified in the resolution.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136518_004" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Attendance to be notified by summons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344306_033" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any person is lawfully ordered to attend to give evidence or to produce documents before the Council or a committee, he shall be notified by a summons issued under the hand of the Clerk by direction of the President.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344321_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In every summons issued to any person under subsection (1) there shall be stated the name of that person and the time when and the place where he is required to attend and the particular documents (if any) he is required to produce, and the summons shall be served on him either by delivering to him a copy thereof or by leaving a copy thereof at his usual or last known place of abode in Hong Kong with some adult person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344321_013" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A summons issued under this section may be served by an officer of the Council or by a police officer or any public officer.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136533_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Witnesses may be examined on oath</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344337_048" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Council or a committee may require that any facts, matters and things relating to the subject of inquiry before the Council or such committee be verified or otherwise ascertained by the oral examination of witnesses, and may cause any such witnesses to be examined upon oath.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344353_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An oath required to be taken under this section may be administered by the Clerk or by any other person appointed by the Council for that purpose or, in the case of a witness before a committee, by the chairman of the committee or by the member presiding in the absence of the chairman.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136549_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Power to issue warrant to compel attendance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344368_033" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a person to whom a summons is issued under <ref>section 10</ref> does not
                attend before the Council or the committee at the time and place stated therein, the
                President may, if satisfied that the summons has been duly served or that such
                person has wilfully avoided service, direct the Clerk to issue a warrant in the
                prescribed form to apprehend him and bring him, at a time and place stated in the
                warrant, before the Council or committee, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344384_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a warrant is issued under this section, the President may, by ordering an
                appropriate endorsement on the warrant, direct that the person named in the warrant
                be brought before a magistrate after arrest and released on entering into such
                recognizance for his appearance before the Council or committee as may be specified
                in the endorsement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344384_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A warrant issued under this section shall be executed by a police
                officer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344384_021" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A magistrate may, when a person is brought before him under subsection (2),
                release that person upon his entering into such recognizance as may be specified in
                the endorsement on the warrant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344399_005" name="5" temporalId="s12_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Every warrant and every endorsement on such warrant purporting to bear the
                signature of the Clerk under this section shall be deemed, unless the contrary is
                proved, to have been issued or made under the direction or order of the President
                under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344399_013" name="6" temporalId="s12_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Chief Executive may, by order in the Gazette, prescribe a form of warrant
                for the purposes of this section.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136549_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Objection to answer question or produce papers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344415_058" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 14</ref>, where any person lawfully ordered to attend to give evidence or to produce any paper, book, record or document before the Council refuses to answer any question that may be put to him or to produce any such paper, book, record or document on the ground that the same is of a private nature and does not affect the subject of inquiry, the President may (and shall if such question or the production of such paper, book, record or document is not relevant) excuse the answering of such question or the production of such paper, book, record or document, or may order the answering or production thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344446_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 14</ref>, where any person lawfully ordered to attend to give evidence or to produce any paper, book, record or document before any committee refuses to answer any question that may be put to him or to produce any such paper, book, record or document on the ground that the same is of a private nature and does not affect the subject of inquiry, the chairman of the committee may report such refusal to the President with the reasons therefor; and the President may (and shall if such question or the production of such paper, book, record or document is not relevant) thereupon excuse the answering of such question or the production of such paper, book, record or document or may order the answering or production thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136565_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Privileges of witnesses</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344493_018" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every person lawfully ordered to attend to give evidence or to produce any
                paper, book, record or document before the Council or a committee shall, subject to
                    <ref>section 16</ref>, be entitled, in respect of such evidence or the
                disclosure of any communication or the production of any such paper, book, record or
                document, to the same right or privilege as before a court of law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344493_026" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>No person, other than a public officer acting with the consent of the Chief
                Executive, shall before the Council or a committee—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344509_005" name="a" temporalId="s14_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>give any evidence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344509_013" name="b" temporalId="s14_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>produce any paper, book, record or document,</content></paragraph><continued>relating to the correspondence concerning—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438412344509_027" name="i" temporalId="s14_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any naval, military or air force matter or of any other matter relating to
                    the security of Hong Kong; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344509_035" name="ii" temporalId="s14_2_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the responsibilities of the Central People’s Government otherwise than with
                    respect to the administration of Hong Kong by its Government,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of
                            2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>nor shall secondary evidence be received by or produced before the Council or
                a committee of the contents of any such paper, book, record or document.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403136580_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Determination of questions relating to evidence and production of documents before the Council or committee</heading><leadIn>Where at any time any question arises in the Council or a committee in regard to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344524_085" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the right or power of the Council or a committee to hear, admit or receive oral evidence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344540_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the right or power of the Council or a committee to peruse or examine any paper, book, record or document or to order, direct or call upon any person to produce any paper, book, record or document before the Council or committee; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344540_014" name="c" temporalId="s15_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the right or privilege of any person (including a member of the Council or committee) to refuse to produce any paper, book, record or document or to lay any paper, book, record or document before the Council or committee,</content></paragraph><continued>that question may, subject to this Ordinance and except in so far as express provision is made therein for the determination of that question, be determined in accordance with the usage and practice of the Council which applied prior to the commencement of this Ordinance or applies thereafter by virtue of any resolution of the Council.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403136580_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Limitation on privilege against incrimination of self or spouse</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344555_062" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In any proceedings in the Council or a committee, any person lawfully ordered to attend to give evidence or to produce any paper, book, record or document before the Council or committee shall not, unless excused under <ref>section 13</ref>, be excused—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344571_005" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>from answering any relevant question put to that person in the proceedings or producing any such paper, book, record or document; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344571_013" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>from complying with any order made in or in
                    connexion
                    with the proceedings,</content></paragraph><continued>on the ground that to do so may tend to expose that person, or the wife or husband of that person, to proceedings for an offence or for the recovery of a penalty.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344571_026" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (3), no statement or admission made by a person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344571_034" name="a" temporalId="s16_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in answering a question put to him in any proceedings to which subsection (1) applies; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344571_042" name="b" temporalId="s16_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in complying with any order made in any such proceedings,</content></paragraph><continued>shall, in proceedings for any offence or for the recovery of any penalty, be admissible in evidence against that person or (unless they married after the making of the statement or admission) against the wife or husband of that person.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344571_055" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in subsection (2) shall render any statement or admission made by a person as there mentioned inadmissible in evidence against that person in proceedings for an offence under <ref>section 32</ref> (which relates to false statements on oath made otherwise than in a judicial proceeding) or <ref>section 36</ref> (which relates to false statutory declarations and other false statements without oath) of the Crimes Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap200">Cap. 200</ref>).</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403136596_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-17" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Offences and
            Disciplinary
            Sanctions</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403136611_001" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-07" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Contempts</heading><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344618_026" name="a" temporalId="s17_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>disobeys any lawful order made by the Council or a committee requiring him to
                attend or produce any papers, books, documents or records before the Council or
                committee, unless such attendance or production is excused under <ref>section
                    13</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344633_006" name="b" temporalId="s17_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>refuses to be examined before, or to answer any lawful and relevant question
                put by, the Council or a committee during the course of any examination, unless such
                refusal is excused under <ref>section 13</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344633_014" name="c" temporalId="s17_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>creates or joins in any disturbance which interrupts or is likely to interrupt
                the proceedings of the Council or a committee while the Council or such committee is
                sitting,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable to a fine
            at
            level 3 and to imprisonment for 12 months, and in the case of a
            continuing offence to a further fine of $2,000 for each day on which the offence
            continues.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403136611_003" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-07" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>False evidence and deception</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412344680_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any person who before the Council or a committee intentionally gives a false
                answer to any question material to the subject of inquiry which may be put to him
                during the course of any examination commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 5 and to imprisonment for 2 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412344680_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who presents to the Council or a committee any false, untrue,
                fabricated or falsified document with intent to deceive the Council or such
                committee, unless such presentation constitutes an offence under subsection (1),
                commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 3 and to imprisonment for 12 months.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403136627_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-07" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Interference with members, officers or witnesses</heading><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344883_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>assaults, obstructs or molests any member going to, being within or going from
                the precincts of the Chamber, or endeavours to compel any member by force or menace
                to declare himself in favour of or against any motion or matter pending before the
                Council or a committee; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344883_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>assaults, interferes with, molests, resists or obstructs any officer of the
                Council while in the execution of his duty; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344883_028" name="c" temporalId="s19_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>tampers with, deters, threatens, molests or in any way unduly influences any
                witness in regard to any evidence to be given by him before the Council or a
                committee; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344883_036" name="d" temporalId="s19_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>threatens, molests or in any way punishes or injures or attempts to punish or
                injure any person for having given evidence before the Council or a committee or on
                account of any evidence which he has given before the Council or a
                committee,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable to a fine
            at
            level 3 and to imprisonment for 12 months.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403136643_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-10-07" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Offences by persons entering or remaining in precincts of Chamber</heading><leadIn>Any person, other than a member or officer of the Council, who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412344945_019" name="a" temporalId="s20_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enters or attempts to enter the Chamber or the precincts of the Chamber in
                contravention of any of the Rules of Procedure or any resolution under <ref>section
                    8(2)</ref>; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412344961_006" name="b" temporalId="s20_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>contravenes any administrative instructions issued under <ref>section
                    8(3)</ref>, or any direction given thereunder, regulating the admittance of
                persons to or the conduct of persons within the Chamber or the precincts of the
                Chamber,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable to a fine
            at
            level 1 and to imprisonment for 3 months.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1631865565010_001" name="s20A" temporalId="s20A" startPeriod="2021-09-17" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="20A">20A.</num><heading>Members not
            entitled to remuneration and allowance during suspension</heading><subsection id="ID_1632187836595_001" name="1" temporalId="s20A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to a member who is suspended under the Rules of Procedure
                from the service of the Council for engaging in grossly disorderly
                conduct.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632187836596_002" name="2" temporalId="s20A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The member is not entitled to receive any remuneration or allowance to which
                the member is, apart from this section, entitled in respect of the period of
                suspension, but the member is entitled to be reimbursed the operating expenses
                incurred by the member in respect of that period.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1631865565166_002" name="s20B" temporalId="s20B" startPeriod="2021-09-17" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="20B">20B.</num><heading>Members liable
            to financial penalty if absence causes adjournment of
            Council</heading><subsection id="ID_1632188024311_001" name="1" temporalId="s20B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>This section applies in relation to a member if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1632188024312_002" name="a" temporalId="s20B_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the member is absent from a sitting of the Council;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1632188024313_003" name="b" temporalId="s20B_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Council is adjourned under the Rules of Procedure because a quorum is
                    not present at that sitting; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1632188024314_004" name="c" temporalId="s20B_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the President is not satisfied that there is a valid reason for the
                    member’s absence.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632188024315_005" name="2" temporalId="s20B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The member is liable to pay a financial penalty on each occasion that the
                Council is so adjourned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632188024316_006" name="3" temporalId="s20B_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The financial penalty is to be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1632188024318_007" name="a" temporalId="s20B_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>determined by the Council according to the Rules of Procedure;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1632188024319_008" name="b" temporalId="s20B_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>deducted from the member’s remuneration to which the member is
                    entitled.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632188024320_009" name="4" temporalId="s20B_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref>, it does not matter whether
                the Council adjourned is subsequently resumed for continuation of any unfinished
                business under the Rules of Procedure.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403136643_003" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part V</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403136658_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-09-17" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Journals
            to
            be admitted as evidence</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote><leadIn>Upon any inquiry touching the privileges, immunities and powers of the Council or of
            any member—
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1632188322166_001" name="a" temporalId="s21_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>any copy of the journals—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1632188322167_002" name="1" temporalId="s21_a_1"><num value="1">(i)</num><content>printed or purporting to be printed by the Director of Government
                    Logistics; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1632188322168_003" name="2" temporalId="s21_a_2"><num value="2">(ii)</num><content>printed or purporting to be printed by or under the authority of the
                    Council; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1632188322169_004" name="b" temporalId="s21_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any copy of the journals authenticated by the signature of the Clerk,</content></paragraph><continued>is to be admitted as evidence of such journals in all courts and places without
            further proof.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2003/ln164">L.N. 164 of
            2003</ref>; <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403136658_003" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Powers of President supplementary to powers under the Basic Law</heading><text>The powers of the President under this Ordinance shall be supplementary to any powers
            conferred on him by the Basic Law.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403136674_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Courts not to exercise jurisdiction in respect of acts of the Council, President or
            officers</heading><text>The Council, the President or any officer of the Council shall not be subject to the
            jurisdiction of any court in respect of the lawful exercise of any power conferred on or
            vested in the Council, the President or such officer by or under this Ordinance or the
            Rules of Procedure.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/71">71 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403136674_004" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Officers of the Council to have powers of police officer</heading><content>Within the precincts of the Chamber, every officer of the Council shall, for the purposes of this Ordinance and of the application of the criminal law, have all the powers and enjoy all the privileges of a police officer.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403136689_002" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>President may act when the Council is dissolved</heading><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, the President may exercise the powers conferred on him by this Ordinance even though the Council has been dissolved.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403136689_004" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Consent of Secretary for Justice to prosecute</heading><content>No prosecution for an offence under this Ordinance shall be instituted except with the consent of the Secretary for Justice.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1631867696824_001" name="s27" temporalId="s27" startPeriod="2021-09-17" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Sittings of
            Council or committee may be conducted remotely</heading><subsection id="ID_1632188629276_001" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Council may, by a resolution passed at a physical sitting of the Council,
                authorize that during a specified period, sittings of the Council or a committee may
                be conducted remotely in accordance with the Rules of Procedure by the virtual,
                digital or electronic means determined by the Council.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632188629277_002" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The President may designate a place or places for a sitting conducted remotely
                pursuant to an authorization under subsection (1) (<i><b>remote sitting</b></i>),
                including any virtual, digital or electronic location at which members or other
                persons attending the sitting may attend or participate by remote access.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632188629278_003" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In relation to a remote sitting—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1632188629279_004" name="a" temporalId="s27_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a reference to a sitting of the Council or a committee in this Ordinance is
                    not to be construed as limited to a sitting at which members or other persons
                    attending the sitting are present in the same place; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1632188629280_005" name="b" temporalId="s27_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>this Ordinance (other than <ref>section 8(4)</ref>) is to apply to the
                    remote sitting as if it were a physical sitting.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1632188629282_006" name="4" temporalId="s27_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="PhysicalSitting"><term>physical sitting</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">實體會議</term>) means a sitting of the Council or a committee at which no member
                or other person attending the sitting attends or participates by virtual, digital or
                electronic means;</def><def name="SpecifiedPeriod"><term>specified period</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指明期間</term>) means a period—<paragraph id="ID_1632188629283_007" name="a" temporalId="s27_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>during which the Council or a committee is precluded by an event or
                        occurrence (including an occasion of emergency or public danger) from
                        conducting a physical sitting; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1632188629284_008" name="b" temporalId="s27_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that is specified in a resolution passed at a physical sitting of the
                        Council.</content></paragraph></def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="hk/2021/27">27 of 2021 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part></main></ordinance>