<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 378</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>378</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap378!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2018-09-20</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403133351_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2018-09-20">
            <content>To make provision for criminal offenders to be required to perform unpaid work
                of benefit to the community in place of, or in addition to, other sentences, and for
                incidental matters.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[23 November 1984]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2018/er4">E.R. 4 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403133367_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>General</heading><section id="ID_1438403133382_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Community Service Orders Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403133382_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412338721_018" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="CommunityServiceOrder"><term>community
                    service
                order</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">社會服務令</term>) means an order made under
                    <ref>section
                4(1)</ref>;</def><def name="Court"><term>court</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院、法庭</term>) includes a
                magistrate;</def><def name="Offender"><term>offender</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">罪犯</term>) means a person in respect of whom a
                community service order is in force or a court is considering making such an
                order;</def><def name="PrincipalProbationOfficer"><term>principal
                    probation
                officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">首席感化主任</term>) means the person appointed to be the
                principal probation officer under <ref>section 9</ref> of the Probation of Offenders
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap298">Cap. 298</ref>);</def><def name="ProbationOfficer"><term>probation
                    officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">感化主任</term>) means a person appointed to be a
                probation officer under <ref>section 9</ref> of the Probation of Offenders Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap298">Cap. 298</ref>);</def><def name="SupervisingProbationOfficer"><term>supervising
                    probation
                officer</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">督導感化主任</term>) means the supervising probation
                officer referred to in <ref>section 5(3)</ref>.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338737_039" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An offence is to be treated as punishable with imprisonment for the purposes of this Ordinance notwithstanding any prohibition or restriction imposed by any Ordinance on the imprisonment of young offenders.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403133398_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><content>The power to make community service orders may be exercised by any court sitting at a particular place where that court is notified by the Director of Social Welfare that facilities for the administration of community service order are available in respect of orders made at that place.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403133398_004" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Community
            Service
            Orders</heading><section id="ID_1438403133413_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Power to make community service orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412338799_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a person of or over 14 years of age is convicted of an offence punishable with imprisonment, the court which sentences him for that offence may make an order requiring him to perform, during the life of the order, unpaid work in accordance with this Ordinance for such number of hours, not exceeding 240, as may be specified in the order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338799_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A community service order may be made against an offender—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338799_020" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in addition to any other sentence that the court imposes; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338799_028" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>instead of any other sentence that the court may impose, unless such other sentence is mandatory.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338799_035" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A court shall not make a community service order against an offender unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338799_043" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the offender consents to the making of such an order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338799_051" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the court is satisfied—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412338799_059" name="i" temporalId="s4_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>after considering a report by a probation officer about the offender and his circumstances and, if the court thinks it necessary, hearing a probation officer, that the offender is a suitable person to perform work under such an order; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412338815_007" name="ii" temporalId="s4_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that provision can be made for the offender to perform work under such an order.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338815_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>More than one community service order may be made by one or more courts in respect of the same offender so as to be in force at the same time provided that the total number of hours that remain to be spent by the offender in performing work under the orders does not at any time exceed 240.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338815_021" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Before making a community service order the court shall explain to the offender in ordinary language—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338815_029" name="a" temporalId="s4_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the purpose and effect of the order (and in particular the conditions and requirements that may be specified in it under <ref>section 5(1)</ref> and the requirements of <ref>section 6(1)</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338815_037" name="b" temporalId="s4_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the consequences which may follow under <ref>section 8</ref> if he fails to comply with any of those conditions and requirements or under <ref>section 9</ref> if he commits an offence during the period of the community service order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338830_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that the court has under <ref>section 10</ref> the power to review the order on application either of the offender or of the supervising probation officer.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403133429_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Contents and copies of community service orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412338861_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A court which makes a community service order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338861_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may specify in the order conditions to be complied with by the offender during the period that the order is in force;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338861_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall specify in the order a place at which or a person to whom, and a time when or within which, the offender shall present himself for the purpose of enabling the administration of the order to commence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338861_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>shall forthwith give a copy of the order to the offender and send a copy of it to the principal probation officer.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338861_035" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The principal probation officer shall ensure that a copy of any community service order which is sent to him under subsection <ref>(1)(c)</ref> is supplied to the offender’s supervising probation officer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338877_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>An offender’s supervising probation officer shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338877_013" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the probation officer appointed or assigned to the area in which the offender from time to time resides, or such other probation officer as the principal probation officer nominates; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338877_021" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 54</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403133445_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Obligations of offenders under community service orders, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412338893_035" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a community service order is in force against an offender, he shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338893_043" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>perform, for the number of hours specified in the order, such work and at such times as may be directed by his supervising probation officer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338893_051" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>perform that work in a satisfactory manner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338893_059" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>comply with any conditions and requirements specified in the order under <ref>section 5(1)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338893_067" name="d" temporalId="s6_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>comply with any reasonable direction of his supervising probation officer including any direction designed to enable that officer to provide rehabilitative counselling and guidance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338908_006" name="e" temporalId="s6_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>immediately notify his supervising probation officer of any change in his address.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338908_013" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The directions given by a supervising probation officer for the purposes of subsection (1) shall, so far as practicable, take account of the offender’s religious beliefs and the times, if any, when he normally works or attends a school or other educational establishment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338908_021" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The type of work that an offender may be required to perform under a community service order shall be that specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403133460_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Duration of community service orders</heading><leadIn>A community service order shall remain in force against an offender until—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338939_005" name="a" temporalId="s7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the offender has performed the work required under it for the number of hours specified in it;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338939_013" name="b" temporalId="s7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the expiration of a period of 12 months commencing on the date on which the order was made or, where that period is extended under <ref>section 10(1)</ref>, the expiration of that period as so extended; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338939_021" name="c" temporalId="s7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the order is revoked under <ref>section 8</ref>, <ref>9</ref> or <ref>10</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever first occurs.</continued></section></part><part id="ID_1438403133460_003" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Breaches
            and Variation
            of
            Community
            Service
            Orders</heading><section id="ID_1438403133476_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Breach of <ref>section 6</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438412338955_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An offender who fails to comply with <ref>section 6(1)</ref> (whether by reason
                of a failure satisfactorily to comply with the conditions or requirements of his
                community service order, or otherwise) may be dealt with in accordance with this
                section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338971_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If at any time while a community service order is in force in respect of an
                offender it appears on information to a magistrate that the offender has failed to
                comply with <ref>section 6(1)</ref>, the magistrate may issue a summons requiring
                the offender to appear before a magistrate at the time specified therein, or may, if
                the information is in writing and on oath, issue a warrant for his arrest.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338971_013" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If it is proved to the satisfaction of the magistrate before whom an offender
                appears or is brought under this section that he has failed without reasonable
                excuse to comply with <ref>section 6(1)</ref> the magistrate may, without prejudice
                to the continuance of the order, impose on him a fine not exceeding $1,000 or
                may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338986_005" name="a" temporalId="s8_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the community service order was made by a magistrate revoke the order
                    and deal with the offender, for the offence in respect of which the order was
                    made, in any manner in which the offender could have been dealt with for that
                    offence by the magistrate who made the order if the order had not been
                    made;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412338986_013" name="b" temporalId="s8_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the order was made by the Court of First Instance or District Court,
                    commit the offender to custody or release him on bail (with or without sureties)
                    until he can be brought or appear before the Court of First Instance or District
                    Court, as the case may be.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412338986_020" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where a magistrate deals with an offender’s case under subsection
                    <ref>(3)(b)</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412338986_028" name="a" temporalId="s8_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the magistrate shall send to the Court of First Instance or District Court
                    a certificate signed by the magistrate certifying that the offender has failed
                    to comply with <ref>section 6(1)</ref> in the respect specified in the
                    certificate, together with such other particulars of the case as are in the
                    opinion of the magistrate desirable, and a certificate purporting to be so
                    signed shall upon its production be admissible without further proof as evidence
                    before the Court of First Instance or District Court of the failure to comply;
                        and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339002_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>where the offender is brought or appears before the Court of First Instance
                    or District Court and that court is satisfied that he has failed to comply with
                        <ref>section 6(1)</ref>, that court may either—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412339002_014" name="i" temporalId="s8_4_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>without prejudice to the continuance of the order, impose on the
                        offender a fine not exceeding $1,000; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412339002_022" name="ii" temporalId="s8_4_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>revoke the order and deal with the offender, for the offence in respect
                        of which the order was made, in any manner in which the offender could have
                        been dealt with for that offence by the court which made the order if the
                        order had not been made.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339017_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A fine imposed under this section in respect of a failure to comply with
                    <ref>section 6(1)</ref> shall be deemed for the purposes of any enactment to be
                a sum adjudged to be paid by a conviction.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403133491_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Commission of further offences</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412339049_011" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An offender who commits an offence whilst a community service order is in force
                in respect of him (in this section referred to as
                    <term>a
                    subsequent
                offence</term>)
                may be dealt with in respect of the subsequent offence and of any offence for which
                the community service order was made (in this section referred to as
                    <term>an
                    original
                offence</term>)
                in accordance with this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339064_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>An offender who is convicted and sentenced by a court in respect of a
                    subsequent offence may in addition be sentenced by that court, if it considers
                    it expedient to do so, for an original offence in any manner in which the court
                    that made the community service order could have sentenced the offender if it
                    had just convicted him of the original offence:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_2_proviso">
                    <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412339064_020" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a magistrate or a juvenile court shall not by virtue of this
                            subsection sentence an offender for the original offence if the
                            community service order was made by the Court of First Instance or the
                            District Court; and</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412339064_028" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the District Court shall not by virtue of this subsection sentence
                            an offender for the original offence if the community service order was
                            made by the Court of First Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998
                                    s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                </proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339064_035" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a court sentences an offender under subsection (2) it may revoke, or vary
                the terms of, any community service order which is in force in respect of him, or
                make no order in respect of it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339064_043" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412339064_051" name="a" temporalId="s9_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a magistrate or a juvenile court convicts an offender of a subsequent
                    offence that was committed whilst a community service order made by the Court of
                    First Instance or the District Court was in force in respect of him;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339080_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the District Court convicts an offender of a subsequent offence that was
                    committed whilst a community service order made by the Court of First Instance
                    was in force in respect of him,</content></paragraph><continued>the court that convicts the offender may, if it thinks fit, without
                proceeding to sentence order that the offender appear or be brought before the court
                by which the community service order was made to be dealt with under subsection (7),
                and for this purpose may commit him to custody or release him on bail (with or
                without sureties); and a court that so orders shall send to the Court of First
                Instance or the District Court, as the case may be, a copy of the record of the
                conviction for the subsequent offence.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339080_019" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>If it appears—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412339080_027" name="a" temporalId="s9_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to a judge of a court by which a community service order was made;
                    or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339095_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a community service order made by a magistrate or a juvenile
                    court, to a magistrate,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>that an offender has been convicted by any court of a subsequent offence, and
                has been dealt with for that offence but not sentenced under this section for an
                original offence, the judge or magistrate may issue a summons requiring the offender
                to appear before the court that made the community service order, at the time
                specified in the summons, or may issue a warrant for his arrest requiring him to be
                brought before that court and dealt with under subsection (7):<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of
                        1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_5_proviso">Provided that a magistrate shall not
                issue a warrant except on information in writing and on oath.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/47">47 of 1997 s.
                    10</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339095_026" name="6" temporalId="s9_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If a warrant issued under this section directs an offender to be brought before
                the Court of First Instance or the District Court, and the offender cannot forthwith
                be brought before that court, the warrant shall have effect as if it directed him to
                be brought before a magistrate or a juvenile court and such magistrate or juvenile
                court shall commit him to custody or release him on bail with or without sureties
                until he can be brought before the Court of First Instance or District Court, as the
                case may be.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339111_005" name="7" temporalId="s9_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>Where it is proved to the satisfaction of the court before which an offender
                appears or is brought under subsection (4), (5) or (6) that the offender has been
                convicted of a subsequent offence, the court—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412339111_013" name="a" temporalId="s9_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may sentence him for an original offence in any manner in which the court
                    that made the community service order could have sentenced him if it had just
                    convicted him of the original offence, and may revoke, or vary the terms of, any
                    community service order that is in force in respect of him, or may make no order
                    in respect of it; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339111_021" name="b" temporalId="s9_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the offender appears or is brought before the court under subsection
                    (4), may also sentence him for the subsequent offence in any manner in which the
                    court that convicted him of the subsequent offence could have sentenced
                    him.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403133507_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Variation and revocation of community service orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412339158_026" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a community service order is in force in respect of an offender, a
                magistrate, on the application of the offender or his supervising probation
                officer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412339158_034" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>may, upon any of the grounds specified in subsection (2), if the community
                    service order was made by a magistrate—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412339158_042" name="i" temporalId="s10_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>extend in relation to the order the period of 12 months specified in
                            <ref>section 7(b)</ref>;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412339173_007" name="ii" temporalId="s10_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>reduce the number of hours that the offender is required by the order
                        to spend performing work; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412339173_015" name="iii" temporalId="s10_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>revoke the order, and deal with the offender for the offence in respect
                        of which the order was made in any manner in which he could have been dealt
                        with for that offence by the court which made the order if the order had not
                        been made;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339173_022" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may, if the community service order was made by the Court of First Instance
                    or District Court, commit the offender to custody or release him on bail until
                    he can be brought or appear before the Court of First Instance or District Court
                    as the case may be and if the magistrate does so, he shall send to that Court
                    such particulars of the case as in the opinion of the magistrate are
                        desirable.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339173_029" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The grounds upon which a magistrate may vary or revoke a community service order
                under this section are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412339189_005" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that there has been a change of circumstances since the order was imposed
                    that would justify the variation or revocation of the order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339189_013" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that it is no longer necessary in the interests of the community or the
                    offender that the order should continue;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339189_021" name="c" temporalId="s10_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that no or no more suitable service is available to be performed by the
                    offender for the purpose of the order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339189_029" name="d" temporalId="s10_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that because of incapacity or for humanitarian or other reasons considered
                    sufficient by the magistrate, it will be impossible for the offender to perform
                    the service before the order expires, or that it would be unreasonable to
                    require him to do so.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339189_036" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where in pursuance of subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> the offender is brought or
                appears before the Court of First Instance or District Court, the Court may, upon
                the grounds specified in subsection (2), deal with the offender in any manner
                specified in subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412339205_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a magistrate proposes to exercise his powers under this section otherwise
                than on the application of the offender he shall summon him to appear before the
                court and, if he does not appear in answer to the summons, may issue a warrant for
                his arrest.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403133523_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Court to give notice of revocation or variation of community service orders</heading><content>Where any court revokes, or extends, or otherwise varies, a community service order it shall forthwith give to the offender, and send to the offender’s supervising probation officer and to the principal probation officer, a copy of its order revoking, extending or otherwise varying the community service order.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403133523_004" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403133538_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Breach of community service order not for jury to decide</heading><text>In proceedings before the Court of First Instance under this Ordinance, any question
            whether an offender has failed to comply with <ref>section 6(1)</ref>, or has been
            convicted of an offence committed during the period that a community service order was
            in force, shall be determined by the court and not by the verdict of a jury.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403133554_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Power to amend <ref>Schedule</ref></heading><text>The Secretary for Labour and Welfare may by order amend the <ref>Schedule</ref> and in
            so doing may specify work by reference to the person for whom, or the place where, it is
            to be performed, or in any other way.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 23</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403133554_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Power to make regulations</heading><text>The Secretary for Labour and Welfare may make regulations for the better carrying out
            of the purpose and provisions of this Ordinance.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/80">80 of 1997 s. 24</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                2007</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403133569_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><content>A court may make a community service order against a person who is convicted of an offence before the date on which the court acquires the power to make such an order provided that he has not already been sentenced for the offence.</content></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403133585_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-09-20" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap378/s6">ss. 6(3)</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap378/s13">13</ref>]</note><heading>Type
            of
            Work</heading><paragraph id="ID_1438412339314_037" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Work at or for any hospital, or at or for any charitable, education, cultural,
                or recreational institution or
                organization.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339314_045" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Work at or for any other institution or organization for old, infirm or
                handicapped persons.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412339314_053" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Work on any land that is leased, occupied, administered, maintained or kept
                clean by the Government or any public body.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                    83</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></schedule></main></ordinance>