<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 558 sub. leg. D</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>558D</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap558D!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-02-06</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403442493_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-02-06">International
            Organizations (Privileges and Immunities) (Bank for International Settlements) Order
            </docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap558/s3">Cap. 558, section
                3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2020</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[18 July 2008]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403442509_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2020/er1">E.R. 1 of
                        2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403442509_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order—</leadIn><def name="Bank"><term>Bank</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">銀行</term>) means the Bank for International
            Settlements;</def><def name="BrusselsProtocol"><term>Brussels
                Protocol</term>
                (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">布魯塞爾議定書</term>》) means the Protocol regarding the
            immunities of the Bank for International Settlements, done at Brussels on 30 July
            1936;</def><def name="HostCountryAgreement"><term>Host
                Country
            Agreement</term>
                (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">東道國協定</term>》) means the Host Country Agreement
            Between the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Bank for International
            Settlements Relating to the Establishment and Status of a Representative Office of the
            Bank for International Settlements in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the
            People’s Republic of China*, done at Basle on 11 May 1998;</def><def name="RepresentativeOffice"><term>Representative
                Office</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">代表處</term>) means the Representative Office of the Bank
            in Hong
            Kong.<marker role="section-break"></marker></def><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1573106920467_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:<table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%" class="font_size_9">
                    <colgroup>
                        <col width="3%"></col>
                        <col width="97%"></col>
                    </colgroup>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="force_orig_font"><sup>*</sup></inline></td>
                            <td class="align_justified cellpadding_right_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">The
                                Host Country Agreement is published in
                                    <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="hk/2001/30/ss5/1">Special
                                    Supplement No. 5 to Gazette No.
                                30/2001</ref>
                                (from page E295).</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table></content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403442525_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Certain provisions of Host Country Agreement have force of law in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413323671_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It is declared that the provisions of the Host Country Agreement as specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> shall have the force of law in Hong Kong and shall for that purpose be construed in accordance with subsections (2), (3), (4), (5), (6) and (7).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323671_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="SeniorResidentRepresentative">In applying those provisions of the Host Country Agreement, “<term class="old_format">senior resident representative</term>” shall be construed as meaning the senior resident representative of the Representative Office referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 2 of the Host Country Agreement.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323671_019" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="HeadquartersAgreement">In applying <ref>paragraph 5</ref> of Article 5 of the Host Country Agreement, “<term class="old_format">Headquarters Agreement</term>” shall be construed as meaning the Agreement between the Swiss Federal Council and the Bank to determine the Bank’s legal status in Switzerland, done at Berne on 10 February 1987, as amended from time to time.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323686_004" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><def name="InternationalTelecommunicationConvention">In applying <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of Article 6 of the Host Country Agreement, “<term class="old_format">International Telecommunication Convention</term>” shall be construed as meaning the Convention of the International Telecommunication Union, done at Geneva on 22 December 1992 and as amended in 1994.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323686_011" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="FlagrantInstancesOfCriminalOffence">In applying Article 13 of the Host Country Agreement, the reference to “<term class="old_format">flagrant instances of criminal offence</term>” shall be construed as a reference to any offence punishable on a first conviction with imprisonment for a term of up to 5 years or with a more severe sentence.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323686_018" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><def name="SeniorOfficials">In applying Article 14 of the Host Country Agreement, “<term class="old_format">senior officials</term>” shall be construed as meaning the Deputy Chief Representative, the Head of Regional Treasury, Asia Pacific and any other officials of the Representative Office of a rank comparable to that of a senior official of any Specialized Agency of the United Nations in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323702_004" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><def name="Safeguard">In applying <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 21 of the Host Country Agreement, the reference to “<term class="old_format">safeguard</term>” shall be construed as including any safeguard that the Central People’s Government authorizes the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region to apply.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403442525_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Article 1 of Brussels Protocol has force of law in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413323764_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It is declared that Article 1 of the Brussels Protocol as specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> shall have the force of law in Hong Kong and shall for that purpose be construed in accordance with subsection (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413323764_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In applying Article 1 of the Brussels Protocol—</leadIn><def name="AgreementWithGermany"><term>Agreement
                    with
                Germany</term>
                    (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">與德國的協定</term>》) shall be construed as meaning the
                Agreement concerning the settlement of financial questions resulting from World War
                One that the government of Germany entered into with the governments of 16 other
                countries at The Hague;</def><def name="ConstituentCharter"><term>Constituent
                    Charter</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">組織章程</term>) shall be construed as meaning the
                Constituent Charter of the Bank granted by the Swiss Federal Government.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403442540_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>The Bank to have legal personality in Hong Kong</heading><leadIn>The Bank has legal personality in Hong Kong as a body corporate and has all the powers of a natural person of full age and capacity including power—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413323811_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to enter into contracts;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323811_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to acquire and dispose of movable and immovable property; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413323811_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to institute and defend legal proceedings.</content></paragraph></section><schedule id="ID_1438403442556_001" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap558D/s3">s. 3</ref>]</note><heading>Provisions
            of
            Host
            Country
            Agreement
            Having
            Force of Law in Hong Kong</heading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Article 3</crossHeading><crossHeading>Freedom of Action of the Bank</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746862_001" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">5.</num><content role="inline">The Bank shall not be subject to any form of financial or banking
                supervision or obliged to implement any form of accounting standard, or to comply
                with any form of licensing or registration requirement.</content></paragraph><crossHeading>Article 4</crossHeading><crossHeading>Inviolability</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746862_002" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">All or any part of the premises, regardless of ownership,
                occupied from time to time as offices by the Representative Office shall be
                considered as premises of the Bank in the HKSAR and shall be inviolable; such
                premises shall be under the control and authority of the Bank. No representative of
                ···
                the HKSAR authorities, may enter upon the premises of the Representative Office to
                perform any duty without the express consent of, and under the conditions, if any,
                agreed to by the President of the Bank, or the General Manager of the Bank, or the
                Assistant General Manager of the Bank, or the senior resident representative, or
                their duly authorized representative. Consent of the senior resident representative
                may, however, be assumed in the case of fire or other disaster requiring prompt
                protective action, if he or she cannot be reached in time.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746862_003" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">All archives and records of the Bank and, in general, all
                documents and any data or data media belonging to the Bank or in its possession,
                shall be inviolable at any time and in any place.</content></paragraph><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text><crossHeading>Article 5</crossHeading><crossHeading>Immunities from Jurisdiction and Execution</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746862_004" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">All deposits entrusted to the Bank, all claims against the Bank
                and the shares issued by the Bank shall, without the express prior agreement of the
                Bank, wherever located and by whomsoever held, be immune from any form of seizure,
                attachment, sequestration, execution, requisition, confiscation, expropriation,
                freeze or any other form of seizure by executive, judicial or legislative
                action.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746862_005" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">The Bank, including the Representative Office, shall enjoy
                immunity from every form of legal process in
                    <fillIn class=" width_9">.</fillIn> the HKSAR, except:</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746862_006" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content role="inline">with respect to contracts relating to real estate in the HKSAR or
                to the supply of goods or services for the Representative Office, which are
                concluded with a person resident or a body incorporated or having its principal
                place of business or domicile in the HKSAR at the time of the conclusion of the
                contract, unless otherwise agreed; or</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746862_007" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content role="inline">in the case of any civil action brought by a third party for
                damage resulting from an accident caused by a motor vehicle belonging to, or
                operated on behalf of the Bank, or in respect of a motor traffic offence involving
                such a vehicle.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_008" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">3.</num><content role="inline">The immunity provided for above may be expressly waived in
                individual cases by the President, the General Manager or the Assistant General
                Manager of the Bank or their duly authorized representative, in writing or in a duly
                authenticated telecommunication or by the terms of a contract.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_009" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">4.</num><content role="inline">Property and assets of the Bank shall be exempt from any measure
                of compulsory execution in
                    <fillIn class=" width_9">.</fillIn> the HKSAR, except for any final judgment rendered by
                any HKSAR court which has jurisdiction over the Bank pursuant to <ref>paragraph
                    2</ref> above.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_010" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">5.</num><content role="inline">The Administrative Tribunal of the Bank (as described in Article
                4.2 of the Headquarters Agreement of the 10th February 1987 determining the legal
                status of the Bank in Switzerland) shall have exclusive and final jurisdiction over
                all disputes arising in connection with employment, welfare and pension matters
                between the Bank and its personnel or its former personnel, or persons claiming
                through them.</content></paragraph><crossHeading>Article 6</crossHeading><crossHeading>Communications</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_011" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">All official correspondence and communications to or from the
                Representative Office, by whatever means and in whatever form transmitted or
                received, shall be immune from censorship and any other form of interception or
                interference.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_012" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">The Bank shall be entitled to use codes and encryption for its
                official communications. The Bank shall also be entitled to send and receive
                official correspondence and communications, on any form of data media, including by
                duly identified couriers or in sealed bags, which shall have privileges and
                immunities as accorded to the Specialized Agencies of the United Nations. The Bank
                shall in particular be entitled to unfettered access to world-wide telecommunication
                links of its choice. The Bank may, with the consent of the relevant HKSAR authority
                regarding technical requirements, use a wireless transmitter in the HKSAR and
                install and operate in the HKSAR point-to-point telecommunication facilities and
                such other telecommunications and transmission facilities as may be necessary to
                facilitate communications with the Representative Office both from within and
                outside the HKSAR.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_013" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">3.</num><content role="inline">The Bank shall benefit, in respect of all official
                communications, from the same treatment as granted by the Government to any
                Specialized Agency of the United Nations insofar as such treatment is compatible
                with the International Telecommunication Convention.</content></paragraph><crossHeading>Article 7</crossHeading><crossHeading>Publications, Data and Data Media</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The importation of
            publications and all kinds of data or data media for the Bank’s use, and the exportation
            of the Bank’s publications and all kinds of data or data media, shall not be subject to
            any restriction.</text><crossHeading>Article 8</crossHeading><crossHeading>Tax
            Exemptions</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_014" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">The Bank, its assets, income and other property shall be exempt
                from all direct taxes and other taxes, dues, duties or rates of any kind
                except:</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_015" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content role="inline">excise duties, taxes on the sale of movable and immovable
                property and taxes on the provision of services which form part of the price to be
                paid
                ...;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_016" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content role="inline">charges for specific services rendered to the Representative
                Office, provided such charges are non-discriminatory and generally levied;
                and</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_017" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content role="inline">the government rent levied by the Government of the HKSAR under
                Article 121 of the Basic Law or the terms of land leases.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_018" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">The Bank shall not be subject to taxation on the rent or lease
                for any premises rented by it and occupied by its services or personnel.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_019" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">3.</num><content role="inline">The operations of the Bank shall be exempt from all taxes, dues,
                duties or rates of any kind.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_020" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">4.</num><content role="inline">The Bank shall not be liable for the collection or payment of any
                tax, due, duty or rate of any kind.</content></paragraph><crossHeading>Article 9</crossHeading><crossHeading>Customs Treatment</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_021" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">The Bank shall be exempt in the HKSAR from all customs duties,
                license fees, taxes and other levies, and from economic restrictions on imports and
                exports, on all goods and articles, including motor vehicles, spare parts,
                publications, data and data media, which are imported or exported by the Bank for
                its official use, and from any obligation for the payment, withholding or collection
                of any customs duty.
                ...</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_022" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">The Bank shall receive the same preferential customs treatment as
                that granted by the Government to any Specialized Agency of the United Nations in
                the HKSAR.</content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Article 11</crossHeading><crossHeading>Pension and Special Funds</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The pension fund of the Bank
            (and any special fund created by the Bank in connection with other welfare arrangements
            provided by it, in particular in order to accumulate reserves) shall enjoy, irrespective
            of whether or not the fund has a separate legal personality, the same exemptions,
            privileges and immunities as are enjoyed by the Bank itself with regard to its property.
            These funds are exempt only to the extent that they are exclusively for the benefit of
            the Bank or its personnel or its former personnel or persons claiming through
            them.</text><crossHeading>Article 12</crossHeading><crossHeading>Social Welfare</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_023" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">The Bank, as an employer, shall be exempt from the Employment
                Ordinance, the Employees’ Compensation Ordinance, the Mandatory Provident Fund
                Schemes Ordinance and any legislation applicable in the HKSAR regarding old-age and
                surviving-dependents insurance, or incapacity insurance, or unemployment insurance,
                or insurance for health care or against accident, or occupational pension schemes,
                or welfare systems of any kind, save in respect of any person who is engaged by the
                Representative Office as a local employee.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746877_024" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">The Representative Office’s personnel, other than any person who
                is engaged by the Representative Office as a local employee, shall be exempt from
                such legislation as is referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> above and, in
                particular, from any mandatory contribution to any insurance or welfare scheme,
                unless an agreement to the contrary is reached between the Bank and the relevant
                HKSAR authorities. This exemption does not apply in relation to the employment of
                any person by personnel of the Representative Office in their private
                capacity.</content></paragraph><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">...</text><crossHeading>Article 13</crossHeading><crossHeading>Privileges, Immunities and Exemptions of Members of the Board
            of<br></br>Directors,
            the President of the Bank, the General Manager
            and<br></br>Assistant
            General Manager of the Bank and
            Representatives<br></br>of
            the Bank’s Member Central Banks</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">Members of the Board of
            Directors of the Bank, the President of the Bank, the General Manager of the Bank, the
            Assistant General Manager of the Bank and representatives of the central banks which are
            members of the Bank shall enjoy the following privileges, immunities and exemptions
            while carrying out official Bank activities and throughout their journey to or from the
            place where a meeting is held in the HKSAR:</text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_025" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content role="inline">immunity from arrest or imprisonment and immunity from inspection
                or seizure of personal baggage, except in flagrant instances of criminal
                offence;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_026" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content role="inline">immunity from inspection or seizure of official
                baggage;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_027" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content role="inline">inviolability of all papers, documents, data or data
                media;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_028" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(d)</num><content role="inline">immunity from the jurisdiction of any
                    <fillIn class=" width_9">.</fillIn> HKSAR
                    <fillIn class=" width_9">.</fillIn> court or tribunal with respect to things done or
                omitted to be done in connection with official Bank activities, including words
                spoken and writings, even after their mission has been accomplished;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_029" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(e)</num><content role="inline">the same customs privileges and facilities as those granted by
                the Government to officials of comparable rank of any Specialized Agency of the
                United Nations in the HKSAR;</content></paragraph><text class="left_indent_36 align_justified">...</text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_030" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(h)</num><content role="inline">the right to use codes or encryption in official communications,
                and the right to receive or send official documents or correspondence by means of
                duly identified couriers or sealed bags.</content></paragraph><crossHeading>Article 14</crossHeading><crossHeading>Status of the Senior Resident Representative and Senior
            Officials<br></br>of
            the Representative Office</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">The senior resident
            representative, as well as such senior officials as are designated by the General
            Manager of the Bank, or the Assistant General Manager of the Bank, and who are neither
            Chinese nationals nor permanent residents of the HKSAR, upon the notification of their
            designation to the relevant HKSAR authorities, shall enjoy the same privileges,
            immunities, exemptions and facilities as those granted by the Government to officials of
            comparable rank of any Specialized Agency of the United Nations in the HKSAR. In
            particular, such persons shall be granted, by the appropriate government authorities,
            the same customs privileges and facilities as those granted to officials of comparable
            rank of any Specialized Agency of the United Nations in the HKSAR.</text><crossHeading>Article 15</crossHeading><crossHeading>Privileges, Immunities and Exemptions Granted to All
            Personnel<br></br>of
            the Representative Office</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">All personnel of the
            Representative Office, regardless of nationality or permanent residence status, shall be
            immune from the jurisdiction of any HKSAR court or tribunal with respect to things done
            or omitted to be done while carrying out official Bank activities, including words
            spoken and writings, even when such persons are no longer employed by the Bank.</text><crossHeading>Article 16</crossHeading><crossHeading>Privileges, Immunities and Exemptions Granted to Personnel of
            the<br></br>Representative
            Office Who Are neither Chinese
            Nationals<br></br>nor
            HKSAR Permanent Residents</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">Personnel of the
            Representative Office together with their respective spouse and dependent children under
            the age of 21, who are neither Chinese nationals nor permanent residents of the HKSAR,
            shall:</text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1515644451858_001" name="0" temporalId="sch1_0"><num class="align_left" value="0">...</num></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_031" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(e)</num><content role="inline">enjoy immunity from inspection or seizure of official
                baggage;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_032" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(f)</num><content role="inline">enjoy the same customs privileges and facilities as those granted
                by the Government to the personnel of comparable rank of any Specialized Agency of
                the United Nations in the HKSAR;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_033" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(g)</num><content role="inline">be exempt from any tax on salaries, fees, emoluments and
                allowances paid to them by the Bank; and</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_034" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(h)</num><content role="inline">be exempt, at the time of payment, from any tax on capital
                payments, if any, paid to them by the Bank, including capital payments paid to them
                by way of indemnity for sickness or accident; income derived from such capital
                payments, as well as annuities and pensions paid to former personnel of the Bank,
                shall not be exempt from tax.</content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading>Article 18</crossHeading><crossHeading>Experts</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_035" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">Experts who are neither Chinese nationals nor permanent residents
                of the HKSAR and who carry out temporary missions for the Bank shall, in connection
                with their missions, be assimilated to the personnel of the Representative Office
                with respect to the privileges, immunities and exemptions specified in Articles 15
                and 16 of this Agreement.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_036" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">Experts who are Chinese nationals or permanent residents of the
                HKSAR and who carry out temporary missions for the Bank shall, in connection with
                their missions, enjoy the privileges, immunities and exemptions specified in Article
                15 of this Agreement.</content></paragraph><crossHeading>Article 19</crossHeading><crossHeading>Purpose of, Waiver of, and Exceptions to, Immunity</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_037" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">The privileges, immunities, exemptions, facilities, assurances
                and other rights referred to in this Agreement are solely granted to ensure, in all
                circumstances, the freedom of action of the Bank and the complete independence of
                persons performing official activities for the Bank, and are not granted for the
                personal benefit of those persons.</content></paragraph><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">...</text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_038" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">3.</num><content role="inline">The President of the Bank, or the General Manager of the Bank, or
                the Assistant General Manager of the Bank shall, if they consider that the immunity
                of any member of the personnel of the Representative Office or expert is being used
                to hinder the normal course of justice, and that it is possible to waive such
                immunity without prejudicing the interests of the Bank, waive that
                immunity.</content></paragraph><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">...</text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_039" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">5.</num><content role="inline">No person enjoying the privileges, immunities or exemptions
                referred to in this Agreement shall be immune from jurisdiction or, where
                applicable, from execution, in the event of legal proceedings against them with
                respect to damage occasioned by a motor vehicle in their ownership or
                control.</content></paragraph><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">...</text><crossHeading>...</crossHeading><crossHeading>Article 21</crossHeading><crossHeading>Security of the HKSAR</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_040" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">1.</num><content role="inline">Nothing in this Agreement shall affect the right of the
                Government to apply any appropriate safeguard in the interests of the security of
                the HKSAR.
                ...</content></paragraph><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">...</text><crossHeading>Article 22</crossHeading><crossHeading>Scope and Implementation</crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">...</text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_041" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">2.</num><content role="inline">All commitments undertaken and privileges, immunities,
                exemptions, facilities, assurances and other rights provided for in this Agreement
                shall, as the case may be, apply to:</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_042" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(a)</num><content role="inline">the Bank;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_043" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(b)</num><content role="inline">the Representative Office and any branch and any wholly owned
                subsidiary established and carrying out activities in the performance of the Bank’s
                objects;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_044" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(c)</num><content role="inline">any investment fund or similar fund which is established and
                maintained by the Bank in the performance of the Bank’s objects and which is wholly
                controlled by the Bank; and</content></paragraph><paragraph class="first_line_indent_36 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746893_045" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">(d)</num><content role="inline">subsidiaries of the Bank which are not wholly owned by the Bank
                but are carrying out activities in the performance of the Bank’s objects, and which
                are approved by the Government for these purposes.</content></paragraph><text class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified">...</text><paragraph class="first_line_indent_0 left_indent_0 align_justified" id="ID_1504775746909_046" name="1" temporalId="sch1_1"><num value="1" class="align_left">4.</num><content role="inline">Unless otherwise provided in this Agreement, the privileges and
                immunities conferred on the Bank by this Agreement shall be no less than those
                granted by the Government to the Specialized Agencies of the United Nations under
                the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the Specialized Agencies of 21st
                November 1947.</content></paragraph></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403442571_002" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-02-06" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
            2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap558D/s4">s. 4</ref>]</note><heading>Article
            1
            of
            Brussels Protocol
            Having
            Force of Law in Hong Kong</heading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">Article
                1</inline></crossHeading><text>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_24 left_indent_0 align_justified">The Bank for International
            Settlements, its property and assets as well as all the property and assets which are or
            will be entrusted to it, whether coin or other fungible goods, gold bullion silver or
            any other metal, precious objects, securities or any other objects the deposit of which
            is admissible in accordance with banking practice, are exempt from the provisions or
            measures referred to in <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of Article X of the Agreement with
            Germany and in Article 10 of the Constituent Charter consecutive to the Convention with
            Switzerland, of the 20th January 1930.</text><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_24 left_indent_0 align_justified">The property and assets of
            third parties, held by any other institution or person, on the instructions, in the name
            or for the account of the Bank for International Settlements, shall be considered as
            entrusted to the Bank for International Settlements and as enjoying the immunities laid
            down by the Articles above-mentioned by the same right as the property and assets which
            the Bank for International Settlements holds for the account of others, in the premises
            set apart for this purpose by the Bank, its branches or agencies.</text></schedule></main></subLeg>