<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" identifier="/hk/cap558I!en" xml:lang="en"><meta><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>558I</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><docName>Cap. 558 sub. leg. I</docName><dc:identifier>/hk/cap558I!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2016-10-20</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main><docTitle startPeriod="2016-10-20" id="ID_1457941927435_001" name="shortTitle" temporalId="shortTitle" status="operational" reason="inEffect">
            <content>International Organizations (Privileges and Immunities) (Permanent Court of
                Arbitration) Order</content>
        </docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap558/s3">Cap.
                558, section
                3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2016/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2016</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[6 April 2016]</commencementNote><section startPeriod="2016-10-20" id="ID_1457941927549_002" name="s1" temporalId="s1" status="omitted" reason="omittedAsSpent"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2016/er1">E.R. 1 of 2016</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section startPeriod="2016-04-06T00:00:00" id="ID_1457941927558_003" name="s2" temporalId="s2" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order—</leadIn><def name="HostCountryAgreement"><term>Host Country Agreement</term><i><b> </b></i>(<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">《東道國協議》</term>) means the Host Country Agreement Between the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Permanent Court of Arbitration on the Conduct of Dispute Settlement Proceedings in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China, done on 4 January 2015.</def></section><section startPeriod="2016-04-06T00:00:00" id="ID_1457941927603_004" name="s3" temporalId="s3" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Provisions of Host Country Agreement having force of law in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1457941927610_005" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It is declared that the provisions of the Host Country Agreement as specified in the <ref>Schedule </ref>have the force of law in Hong Kong and are, for that purpose, to be construed in accordance with subsections (2), (3) and (4).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1457941927619_006" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In applying <ref>Article 1</ref> of the Host Country Agreement—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1457941927625_007" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the reference to 1899 Convention is to be construed as meaning the Convention for the Pacific Settlement of International Disputes, done at The Hague on 29 July 1899;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1457941927634_008" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the reference to 1907 Convention is to be construed as meaning the Convention for the Pacific Settlement of International Disputes, done at The Hague on 18 October 1907.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1457941927646_009" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In applying <ref>Article 1</ref>, <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of <ref>Article 2</ref> and <ref>Articles 5</ref>, 6, 7, 8 and 9 of the Host Country Agreement, the reference to PCA is to be construed as meaning the Permanent Court of Arbitration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1457941927659_010" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In applying <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of <ref>Article 11</ref> of the Host Country Agreement, the reference to safeguard<i><b> </b></i>is to be construed as including any safeguard that the Central People’s Government authorizes the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region to apply.</content></subsection></section><schedule startPeriod="2016-04-06" id="ID_1457941927688_011" name="sch0" temporalId="sch0" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="0">Schedule </num><note role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap558I/s3">s. 3</ref>]</note><heading>Provisions of Host Country Agreement Having Force of Law in Hong
            Kong<marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article
            1</ref>   Definitions<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927800_012" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>For the purposes of the Agreement:<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927805_013" name="0-1" temporalId="sch0_0-1"><content>“Officials of the PCA” shall mean the Secretary-General and all officials of
                the International Bureau of the PCA;<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927813_014" name="0-2" temporalId="sch0_0-2"><content>“PCA Proceedings” shall mean any dispute resolution proceedings administered by
                or under the auspices of the PCA, whether or not pursuant to the 1899 Convention or
                the 1907 Convention or any of the PCA’s optional rules of
                procedure;<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927825_015" name="0-3" temporalId="sch0_0-3"><content>“PCA Adjudicator” shall mean any arbitrator, mediator, conciliator, or member
                of an international commission of inquiry taking part in a hearing, meeting, or
                other activity in relation to PCA Proceedings held in the
                HKSAR;<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927838_016" name="0-4" temporalId="sch0_0-4"><content>“Participant in Proceedings” shall mean any counsel, party, agent, or other
                party representative, witness, expert, as well as any interpreter, translator, or
                court reporter taking part in a hearing, meeting, or other activity in relation to
                PCA Proceedings held in the HKSAR;<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927852_017" name="0-5" temporalId="sch0_0-5"><content>“PCA Meeting” shall mean any meeting, including hearings in the context of PCA
                Proceedings and conferences, convened by the
                PCA;<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927860_018" name="0-6" temporalId="sch0_0-6"><content>“Local Personnel” shall mean any person assigned by the Chinese Government to
                assist in the conduct of any PCA Proceedings or PCA
                Meeting.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article 2</ref>   Legal
            Capacity<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0 align_left" id="ID_1457941927871_019" name="0-7" temporalId="sch0_0-7"><content>...<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927876_020" name="0-8" temporalId="sch0_0-8"><content>2. The PCA shall have the legal capacity necessary to fulfill its purposes and
                objectives in the … HKSAR.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article 5</ref>   Privileges and Immunities of the
            PCA<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph id="ID_1457941927892_021" name="0-9" temporalId="sch0_0-9" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><content>1.
                The
                PCA, and its property and assets wherever located and by whomsoever held, shall
                enjoy immunity from every form of legal process in the … HKSAR, except in the case
                of any civil action brought by a third party for damage resulting from an accident
                caused by a motor vehicle belonging to or operated on behalf of the PCA, where these
                damages are not recoverable from insurance, or in respect of a motor traffic offence
                or an unlawful act involving such a vehicle.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1457941927913_022" name="0-10" temporalId="sch0_0-10" class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0"><content class="first_line_indent_1">2.
                The PCA may expressly waive immunities provided for in
                    <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this Article in any specific case. However, it is
                understood that no waiver shall extend to the immunity from any measure of execution
                unless such immunity has been expressly and separately waived by the
                PCA.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927928_023" name="0-11" temporalId="sch0_0-11"><content>3. The property and assets of the PCA shall be exempt from any measures of
                compulsory execution in the … HKSAR, except for any final judgment rendered by any
                court in the … HKSAR which has jurisdiction pursuant to <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of
                this Article.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927942_024" name="0-12" temporalId="sch0_0-12"><content>4. Should the PCA be provided with, acquire, or rent office space or hearing
                space, its premises shall be inviolable. The premises of the PCA shall not be used
                in any manner incompatible with the objectives and functions of the
                PCA.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927952_025" name="0-13" temporalId="sch0_0-13"><content>5. The archives of the PCA, wherever located, and in general all documents
                belonging to it or held by it, shall be
                inviolable.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927959_026" name="0-14" temporalId="sch0_0-14"><content>6.
                The
                PCA may hold funds, currency of any kind, or other financial assets and operate
                accounts in any convertible currency, and the PCA shall be free to transfer its
                funds, currency, and other assets to, from, or within the HKSAR, and to convert any
                currency held by it into any other currency.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927969_027" name="0-15" temporalId="sch0_0-15"><content>7.
                The
                PCA, its assets, income and other property shall, within the HKSAR, be:</content></paragraph><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(a) exempt from all direct taxes;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(b) exempt from customs duties and prohibitions and restrictions on imports and
                exports in respect of articles imported or exported by the PCA for its official use;
                it is understood, however, that articles imported under such exemption will not be
                sold in the People’s Republic of China, including the HKSAR, except under conditions
                agreed with the Chinese Government; and</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(c) exempt from customs duties and prohibitions and restrictions on imports and
                exports in respect of its publications.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></item><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941927991_028" name="0-16" temporalId="sch0_0-16"><content>8.
                While
                the PCA will not, as a general rule, claim exemption from excise duties and from
                taxes on the sale of movable and immovable property which form part of the price to
                be paid, nevertheless when the PCA is making important purchases for official use of
                property on which such duties and taxes have been charged or are chargeable, the
                Government of the HKSAR will, whenever possible, make appropriate administrative
                arrangements for the remission or return of the amount of duty or
                tax.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928004_029" name="0-17" temporalId="sch0_0-17"><content>9.
                The … Government shall permit and protect free communication on
                the part of the PCA for all official purposes. The PCA shall enjoy in the … HKSAR,
                for its official communications treatment not less favourable than that accorded to
                other inter-governmental organizations, in the matter of priorities, rates and taxes
                on mails, cables, telephones and other communications; and press rates for
                information to the press and radio.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928016_030" name="0-18" temporalId="sch0_0-18"><content>10. The official correspondence of the PCA shall be inviolable. The consent of
                the relevant authorities of the Government of the HKSAR regarding technical
                requirements is required if wireless transmitter is
                used.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article 6</ref>   Privileges and Immunities of PCA
            Officials and Adjudicators<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928027_031" name="0-19" temporalId="sch0_0-19"><content>1. Officials of the PCA and PCA Adjudicators shall enjoy:</content></paragraph><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(a) immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or
                written and acts performed by them in the course of the discharge of their duties
                even after they have ceased to exercise their functions in connection with the PCA,
                except in the event of legal proceedings arising from an accident caused by a
                vehicle belonging to or driven by them;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(b) inviolability for all papers and documents for the purpose of their
                communications with the PCA and in relation to PCA Proceedings or PCA
                Meetings;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(c) the same facilities in respect of currency or exchange restrictions as are
                accorded to representatives of other inter-governmental organizations;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(d) exemption from taxation on any fees, salaries, and emoluments paid to them
                by or through the PCA for work completed in their official capacity;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(e) immunity from national service obligations;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(f) immunity from immigration restrictions and alien registration;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(g) the same repatriation facilities in time of international crises as
                representatives of other inter-governmental organizations; and</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(h) the right to import free of duty their furniture and personal effects at
                the time of first taking up their post.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></item><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928085_032" name="0-20" temporalId="sch0_0-20"><content>2. In addition to the privileges and immunities provided for in <ref>paragraph
                    1</ref> of this Article, the Secretary-General of the PCA, the Deputy
                Secretary-General of the PCA and PCA Adjudicators shall enjoy immunity from personal
                arrest or detention and from seizure of their personal
                baggage.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928095_033" name="0-21" temporalId="sch0_0-21"><content>3. Officials of the PCA and PCA Adjudicators who are either Chinese citizens or
                permanent residents of the People’s Republic of China including permanent residents
                of the HKSAR shall only enjoy the privileges and immunities provided for by
                    <ref>paragraph 1(a)</ref>, (b) and (d) of this
                Article.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article 7</ref>   Immunity of Local
            Personnel<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928104_034" name="0-22" temporalId="sch0_0-22"><content>Local Personnel shall enjoy immunity from legal process in respect of words
                spoken or written and any act performed by them in their official capacity in
                connection with the PCA, which immunity shall continue after they have ceased to
                exercise their functions in connection with the PCA, except in the event of legal
                proceedings arising from an accident caused by a vehicle belonging to or driven by
                them.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article 8</ref>   Privileges and Immunities of
            Participants in Proceedings<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928112_035" name="0-23" temporalId="sch0_0-23"><content>1. Participants in Proceedings shall be accorded the following privileges,
                immunities and facilities that are necessary for the independent exercise of their
                functions, subject to the production of the document referred to in <ref>paragraph
                    2</ref> of this Article:</content></paragraph><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(a) immunity from legal process of every kind in respect of words spoken or
                written and all acts performed by them in the course of their participation in PCA
                Proceedings or PCA Meetings, which immunity shall continue after they have ceased to
                exercise their functions in connection with the PCA, except in the event of legal
                proceedings arising from an accident caused by a vehicle belonging to or driven by
                them;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(b) inviolability of all papers, documents in whatever form and materials
                relating to their participation in PCA Proceedings or PCA Meetings, which immunity
                shall continue after they have ceased to exercise their functions in connection with
                the PCA;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(c) for purposes of their communications in relation to PCA Proceedings or PCA
                Meetings, the right to receive and send papers and documents in whatever form by
                duly identified couriers or in sealed bags;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(d) exemption from immigration restrictions or alien registration when they
                travel for purposes of their participation in PCA Proceedings or PCA Meetings;
                and</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(e) the same repatriation facilities in time of international crises as
                representatives of other inter-governmental
                organizations.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></item><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928135_036" name="0-24" temporalId="sch0_0-24"><content>2. A participant in Proceedings shall be provided by the PCA with a document
                certifying that his or her participation is required by the PCA and specifying a
                time period during which such participation is necessary. This document shall be
                withdrawn prior to its expiry if the Participant’s appearance in PCA Proceedings or
                PCA Meetings or his or her presence within the People’s Republic of China, including
                the HKSAR, is no longer required.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928140_037" name="0-25" temporalId="sch0_0-25"><content>3. The privileges, immunities and facilities referred to in <ref>paragraphs
                    1</ref> of this Article shall cease to apply after fifteen consecutive days
                following the date on which the presence of the Participant in Proceedings is no
                longer required by the PCA, provided such Participant has had an opportunity to
                leave the People’s Republic of China, including the HKSAR during that
                period.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928145_038" name="0-26" temporalId="sch0_0-26"><content>4. Participants in Proceedings who are either Chinese citizens or permanent
                residents of the People’s Republic of China including permanent residents of the
                HKSAR shall only enjoy the immunities and provided for by <ref>paragraph 1(a)</ref>,
                (b) and (c) of this Article.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article 9</ref>   Acquisition and Waiver of
            Privileges and Immunities<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928151_039" name="0-27" temporalId="sch0_0-27"><content>1. When an Official of the PCA or a PCA Adjudicator will be present in the
                People’s Republic of China, including the HKSAR, or may have need to invoke
                privileges and immunities under this Agreement, a certification of the status of
                such person shall be provided to the … Government under the signature of the
                Secretary-General. The … Government shall accord the privileges and immunities
                provided for in <ref>Article 6</ref> upon production of this
                certification.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928156_040" name="0-28" temporalId="sch0_0-28"><content>2. When Local Personnel are assigned to assist in the conduct of PCA
                Proceedings or PCA Meetings in the HKSAR, they shall enjoy immunities under this
                Agreement from the moment of their assignment.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928165_041" name="0-29" temporalId="sch0_0-29"><content>3. Upon receipt of notification from parties to PCA Proceedings as to the
                appointment of a Participant in Proceedings, a certification of the status of such
                person shall be provided to the … Government under the signature of an Official of
                the PCA. The authorities of the … Government shall accord the privileges and
                immunities provided for in <ref>Article 8</ref> upon production of this
                certification.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928174_042" name="0-30" temporalId="sch0_0-30"><content>4. Whenever a determination is required as to whether a person enjoys status
                under this Agreement entitling him or her to privileges and immunities, or whether
                words or acts are connected to the discharge of that person’s official duties, such
                determination shall be made by the competent authority in consultation with the
                Chinese Government.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928178_043" name="0-31" temporalId="sch0_0-31"><content>5. The privileges and immunities provided for in <ref>Articles 6 to 8</ref> of
                this Agreement are granted in the interests of the PCA and the good administration
                of justice, and not for the personal benefit of the individuals themselves. The
                competent authority has the right and the duty to waive the immunity in any case
                where, in the opinion of such authority, the immunity would impede the course of
                justice and can be waived without prejudice to the interests of the PCA or to any
                PCA Proceedings in connection with which those immunities are
                granted.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928181_044" name="0-32" temporalId="sch0_0-32"><content>6. For the purposes of this Article, the competent authority shall
                be:</content></paragraph><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(a) in the case of PCA Adjudicators and Officials of the PCA (other than the
                Secretary-General), the Secretary-General;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(b) in the case of the Secretary-General, the Administrative Council of the
                PCA;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(c) in the case of Local Personnel, the Secretary-General;</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(d) in the case of Participants in Proceedings representing or designated by a
                State which is a party to the relevant PCA Proceedings, that State; and</content></item><item class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12"><content>(e) in the case of other individuals appearing at the instance of a party to
                PCA Proceedings, the Secretary-General.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></item><text class="align_center">...<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0"><ref>Article
            11</ref>   Security<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0 align_left" id="ID_1457941928196_045" name="0-33" temporalId="sch0_0-33"><content>...<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0" id="ID_1457941928198_046" name="0-34" temporalId="sch0_0-34"><content>3. Nothing in this Agreement shall affect the right of the Chinese Government
                to apply any appropriate safeguard for the national security of the People’s
                Republic of China, including the security of the HKSAR.
                …<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_0 align_left" id="ID_1457941928201_047" name="0-35" temporalId="sch0_0-35"><content>...<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...</text></schedule></main></subLeg>