<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" identifier="/hk/cap558P!en" xml:lang="en"><meta><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>558P</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><docName>Cap. 558 sub. leg. P</docName><dc:identifier>/hk/cap558P!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-11-02</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main><docTitle startPeriod="2023-11-02" status="operational" reason="inEffect" name="shortTitle" temporalId="shortTitle" id="ID_1671696204936_001">
            <content>International Organizations (Privileges and Immunities) (International
                Organization for Mediation Preparatory Office) Order</content>
        </docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap558/s3">Cap. 558, section
            3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[23 December
            2022]</commencementNote><section startPeriod="2022-12-23" status="operational" reason="inEffect" name="s1" temporalId="s1" id="ID_1672194736158_001"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order—</leadIn><def name="Arrangement"><term>Arrangement</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">《安排》</term>)
            means the Arrangement on the Establishment of the International Organization for
            Mediation Preparatory Office in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (which is a
            translation of “《關於在香港特別行政區設立國際調解院籌備辦公室的安排》”) made between the Ministry of Foreign
            Affairs of the Central People’s Government and the Government of the Hong Kong Special
            Administrative Region signed on 21 October 2022;</def><def name="PreparatoryOffice"><term>Preparatory Office</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">籌備辦公室</term>) means the International Organization for Mediation Preparatory Office
            (which is a translation of “國際調解院籌備辦公室”) established under the Arrangement.</def></section><section startPeriod="2022-12-23" status="operational" reason="inEffect" name="s2" temporalId="s2" id="ID_1672194736447_002"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Provisions of Arrangement having force of law in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1672194134368_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>It is declared that the provisions of the Arrangement as specified in the
                Chinese text of the <ref>Schedule </ref>(<i><b>specified
                provisions</b></i>)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1672194134374_005" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>have the force of law in Hong Kong; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1672194134377_006" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for that purpose, are to be construed in accordance with subsection
                    (3).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1672194134379_007" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An English translation of the specified provisions is set out in the English
                text of the Schedule.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1672194134385_008" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In applying Articles 1, 5, 7, 9 and 11 of the Arrangement, a reference to
                “香港特區” (which is translated into English as “HKSAR” in this Order) is to be
                construed as meaning the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region.</content></subsection></section><schedule startPeriod="2022-12-23" status="operational" reason="inEffect" name="sch0" temporalId="sch0" id="ID_1672194736592_003"><num value="0">Schedule </num><note role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap558P/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Provisions of Arrangement Having Force of Law in Hong
            Kong<marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text class="align_center"><b>(English Translation)</b></text><text class="align_center">...</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 1<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134465_010" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>...</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134469_011" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>Within the HKSAR, the Preparatory Office has the legal capacity to perform its
                functions and duties.</content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 5<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134478_012" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The Preparatory Office, and its property and assets, regardless of where they
                are located or by whom they are held, are to enjoy immunity from all legal
                proceedings in the HKSAR, except:</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134486_013" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>in the case of any civil action for damages brought by a third party in respect
                of any damage that results from an accident caused by a motor vehicle belonging to
                or operated for the Preparatory Office, where the damages are not covered by
                insurance, or in respect of a motor traffic offence or an unlawful act involving
                such a vehicle.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134503_014" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The Preparatory Office may expressly waive the immunities provided for in
                    <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this Article in any specific case. The waiver is not
                to be understood as extending to any immunity from measure of execution, unless such
                immunity has been expressly and separately waived by the Preparatory
                Office.</content></paragraph><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 6<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134516_015" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The premises occupied as the Preparatory Office, whether owned by the
                Preparatory Office or not, is inviolable.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134524_016" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>All data, archives, documents and records of the Preparatory Office are
                inviolable, regardless of their form or medium, where they are located or by whom
                they are held.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134532_017" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>...</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134540_018" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>Free communication by the Preparatory Office for official purposes is to be
                permitted and protected. All official correspondence and communications, regardless
                of the means by which, and the form in which, they are transmitted or received, are
                immune from censorship, monitoring and any other form of interception or
                interference.</content></paragraph><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 7<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134558_019" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The Preparatory Office may hold any kind of funds, currency or other assets,
                and may open and operate accounts in any convertible currency. The Preparatory
                Office is free to transfer its funds, currency and other assets to, from or within
                the HKSAR, and may convert any currency held by it into another currency.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134569_020" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The Preparatory Office and its assets, income and other property within the
                HKSAR are exempt from all direct taxes and other taxes, dues, duties or rates of any
                kind, except:</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134573_021" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>excise duties, taxes on the sale of movable and immovable property, and taxes
                on the provision of services, that form part of the price to be paid; but when the
                Preparatory Office purchases any property or services for official uses on which
                such duties and taxes have been charged or are chargeable, the HKSAR Government may,
                as far as possible, make appropriate administrative arrangements for exemption or
                refund of the amount of such duties or taxes.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134581_022" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The Preparatory Office is exempt in the HKSAR from all customs duties, license
                fees, taxes and other levies, from economic restrictions on imports and exports of
                all goods and articles, including motor vehicles, spare parts, publications, data
                and data media, that are imported or exported by the Preparatory Office for its
                official uses, and from any obligation for the payment, withholding or collection of
                any customs duty. Goods or articles imported into the HKSAR by the Preparatory
                Office free of duty are to be used for discharging the functions and duties of the
                Preparatory Office, and may be disposed of locally in accordance with applicable
                laws or administrative regulations.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134587_023" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num value="4">4.</num><content>The Preparatory Office, as an employer, is exempt from the Employment
                Ordinance, the Employees’ Compensation Ordinance, the Mandatory Provident Fund
                Schemes Ordinance and any Ordinance applicable in the HKSAR regarding old-age and
                surviving-dependents insurance, incapacity insurance, unemployment insurance,
                insurance of health care or against accident, occupational pension schemes or
                welfare systems of any kind, except in respect of the personnel engaged by the
                Preparatory Office as local employees.</content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 8<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134592_024" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>The personnel of the Preparatory Office are to enjoy the following privileges,
                immunities and facilities:</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134595_025" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>immunity from any legal proceedings in respect of words spoken or written, and
                acts performed, by them in the course of discharging their duties, and the immunity
                is to continue to be enjoyed by them even after they have ceased to discharge their
                duties in connection with the Preparatory Office. However, the immunity does not
                apply to an action arising from a traffic accident caused by a vehicle belonging to
                or driven by them;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134599_026" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>inviolability of documents and information for the purpose of communicating
                with the Preparatory Office and relating to the discharge of their duties;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134602_027" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>exemption from taxation on any fees, salaries, emoluments and subsidies paid to
                them by the Preparatory Office for the discharge of their duties (except for the
                personnel engaged by the Preparatory Office as local employees).</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134605_028" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>...</content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 9<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134623_029" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Representatives participating in the negotiation for the Convention on the
                Establishment of the International Organization for Mediation are to enjoy the
                following privileges, immunities and facilities that are necessary for the
                independent discharge of their duties:</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134630_030" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>immunity from personal arrest or detention and from seizure of their personal
                baggage while attending any negotiation meeting for the Convention and during their
                journeys to and from the place of the meeting; immunity from any legal proceedings
                in respect of words spoken or written, and acts performed, by them in the course of
                their participation in any negotiation meeting for the Convention, and the immunity
                is to continue to be enjoyed by them even after they have ceased to discharge their
                duties in connection with their participation in the negotiation meeting for the
                Convention. However, these immunities do not apply to an action arising from a
                traffic accident caused by a vehicle belonging to or driven by them;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134640_031" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>inviolability of all documents and information relating to their participation
                in any negotiation meeting for the Convention, regardless of the form and materials
                of the documents and information, and the immunity is to continue to be enjoyed by
                them even after they have ceased to discharge their duties in connection with their
                participation in the negotiation meeting for the Convention;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134648_032" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>the right to send and receive documents and information in any form by duly
                recognized couriers or in sealed bags for the purpose of communications in relation
                to their participation in any negotiation meeting for the Convention;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134654_033" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>exemption from immigration restrictions and alien registration when they travel
                for the purpose of participating in any negotiation meeting for the
                Convention;</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134660_034" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>...</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_40" id="ID_1672194134661_035" name="6" temporalId="sch0_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>the same repatriation facilities in time of international crises as
                representatives of other inter-governmental international organizations.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134665_036" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">2.</num><content>The privileges, immunities and facilities referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref>
                of this Article are to cease to apply after five consecutive days following the date
                on which the negotiation meetings for the Convention conclude, on the condition that
                the negotiation representatives have had an opportunity to leave the HKSAR during
                that period.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134671_037" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The negotiation representatives who are citizens of the People’s Republic of
                China, permanent residents of the People’s Republic of China or permanent residents
                of the HKSAR may only enjoy the privileges, immunities and facilities under
                    <ref>paragraph 1(1)</ref>, (2), (3) ... of this Article.</content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 10<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134677_038" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>In all circumstances, the privileges, immunities and facilities provided for in
                this Arrangement are granted to ensure effective performance of the Preparatory
                Office’s functions and duties, and effective conduct of the work relating to the
                negotiation for the Convention, but not for the personal benefit of those
                persons.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134688_039" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>...</content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 11<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_36" id="ID_1672194134692_040" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Nothing in this Arrangement affects the right to apply any appropriate
                safeguard for the national security of the People’s Republic of China, including the
                security of the HKSAR.</content></paragraph><paragraph class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_28" id="ID_1672194134702_041" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><content>...</content></paragraph><text class="align_center">...</text></schedule></main></subLeg>