<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 577 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>577A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap577A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-08-15</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403482227_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2024-08-15">Tung
                                    Chung
                                    Cable
                                    Car
                                    Bylaw</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap577/s22">Cap.
                                                577, section
                                    22</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2024/er4">E.R. 4 of
                                                2024</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[4 November 2005]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2024/er4">E.R. 4 of
                                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403482242_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            1</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403482242_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Bylaw, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AuthorizedOfficial"><term>authorized
                official</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">授權人員</term>) means any person duly authorized to act on
            behalf of the Company;</def><def name="CableCar"><term>cable
                car</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">吊車</term>) means a car, which is part of the Cable Car
            System, for the carriage of persons;</def><def name="Child"><term>child</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">兒童</term>) means a person under 12 years of age;</def><def name="ConcessionaryTicket"><term>concessionary
                ticket</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">特惠車票</term>) means a ticket issued at a special fare or
            subject to special conditions, privileges or restrictions in the conditions of
            issue;</def><def name="ConditionsOfIssue"><term>conditions
                of
            issue</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車票發出條件</term>) means the conditions of issue of tickets
            published from time to time by or on behalf of the Company and posted in the Cable Car
            System area;</def><def name="Fare"><term>fare</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車費</term>) means the fare payable by any person to whom
            or on whose behalf a ticket is issued by or on behalf of the Company;</def><def name="Fauna"><term>fauna</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">動物群</term>) means all birds, fish and animals, whether
            wild or domestic;</def><def name="Flora"><term>flora</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">植物群</term>) means all trees, shrubs, plants and
            vegetation, whether wild or cultivated;</def><def name="PaidArea"><leadIn><term>paid
                    area</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已付車費區域</term>) means those parts of the Cable Car
                System area—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413526799_005" name="a" temporalId="s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>set aside for the use of fare-paying passengers; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413526799_013" name="b" temporalId="s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>provided with ticket gates, barriers or turnstiles for the purposes of entry or exit,</content></paragraph><continued>and includes cable cars when in service;</continued></def><def name="Platform"><term>platform</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">月台</term>) means a part of the Cable Car System area
            designated by the Company by notices, signs or in any other manner as will reasonably
            indicate the same as a place for boarding or alighting from a cable car;</def><def name="Surcharge"><term>surcharge</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附加費</term>) means such amount as may be specified in
            the conditions of issue as a surcharge;</def><def name="Ticket"><term>ticket</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車票</term>) means any form of ticket, card, pass or
            permit from time to time issued by the Company, or by persons duly authorized by the
            Company, for travel on the Cable Car System;</def><def name="TicketOffice"><term>ticket
                office</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">票務處</term>) means an office operated by or on behalf of
            the Company which is duly authorized to issue a ticket;</def><def name="Vehicle"><term>vehicle</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車輛</term>) includes the contents of a vehicle and any
            load carried by a vehicle.</def></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482258_002" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            2</num><heading>Trespass
            and Damage
            to
            Cable
            Car
            System</heading><section id="ID_1438403482258_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Admission</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413526861_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An authorized official may refuse to admit any person onto or into the Cable Car System or the Cable Car System area, or any part of the Cable Car System or the Cable Car System area, at any time if such authorized official has reasonable cause to believe that the refusal is necessary to ensure safety or order, or that such person is likely to contravene a provision of this Bylaw.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413526861_012" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An authorized official may refuse to admit any child onto or into the Cable Car System or the Cable Car System area if the child is not accompanied by a person who has attained 15 years of age.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482274_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Trespass</heading><leadIn>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413526892_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enter into the Cable Car System area, other than those parts clearly defined by means of notices, indicators and other directions for the use of persons using, or intending to use, the Cable Car System; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413526892_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enter or leave such parts other than by proper use of such gates, barriers or turnstiles (if any) provided for such entry or exit.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403482274_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Trespass on certain area</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413526924_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a warning notice is posted in respect of any part of the Cable Car System area, no person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official or except under any circumstances specified in the warning notice, enter or remain in that part.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413526924_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="WarningNotice">In subsection (1),
                    <term>warning
                    notice</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">警告告示</term>) means a notice in English and Chinese
                forbidding any member of the public from entering the relevant part of the Cable Car
                System area, which is posted in such a place as will reasonably be readily seen and
                read before he enters that part.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482289_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Damage to Cable Car System, cable cars, plant and equipment</heading><leadIn>No person shall improperly use, meddle, damage or otherwise interfere with—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413526955_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any machine or equipment used or employed on or in connection with the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area, or any part of such machine or equipment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413526955_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any cable car or any equipment on a cable car used or employed on or in connection with the Cable Car System;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413526955_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any cables, ropes, towers, pylons or supporting system used or employed on or in connection with the Cable Car System;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413526955_036" name="d" temporalId="s5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any electrical plant, overhead wiring or other form of electrical installation or equipment of any nature used or employed on or in connection with the Cable Car System; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413526970_006" name="e" temporalId="s5_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>any building or other construction owned or occupied by the Company in the Cable Car System area or otherwise used or employed in connection with the Cable Car System.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403482305_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Sewage, etc. placed on Cable Car System or in Cable Car System area</heading><content>No person shall cause or permit any sewage, drainage or other offensive matter to flow onto, enter or be placed on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482305_004" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Rubbish, etc. thrown at, on or from Cable Car System or Cable Car System area</heading><content>No person shall deposit or throw, or cause to be deposited or thrown, at, on or from the Cable Car System or the Cable Car System area any glass, stone, missile, rubbish or other offensive or waste matter.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482320_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Improper use of emergency equipment</heading><content>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official, activate any emergency or safety device on or in or otherwise used or employed in connection with the Cable Car System or the Cable Car System area, save for the express purpose for which such device is provided and in accordance with the instructions relating to such device.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482320_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Wrongfully boarding or alighting from cable cars</heading><content>No person shall board or alight from or attempt to board or alight from any cable car after the doors of the cable car have commenced to close.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482320_005" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            3</num><heading>Fares
            and
            Tickets</heading><section id="ID_1438403482336_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Conditions of issue of tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527080_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All tickets issued by or on behalf of the Company are issued subject to this Bylaw and to the conditions of issue.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527080_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who enters into the paid area, or to whom or on whose behalf a ticket is issued, or who otherwise acquires a ticket, shall be deemed to have knowledge of and to have agreed to the conditions of issue.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482336_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Fares</heading><content>The fares appearing in notices, lists or tables published from time to time by the Company and posted at the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area are the fares for travel on the Cable Car System.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482352_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Tickets contain no warranty or acceptance of liability</heading><content>All time-tables, if any, issued by the Company are issued by way of guidance only and any departure and arrival times for any cable car are estimates only. The issuance of a ticket for service of the Cable Car System does not warrant that a person will be conveyed on any particular cable car, or that any cable car shall depart or arrive at a particular time. Apart from any refunding arrangement made in accordance with the Company’s refund policy, the Company will not be liable to any person for any loss or damage caused by the alteration, suspension or withdrawal of all or any of the services of the Cable Car System, other than such loss or damage involving death or personal injury.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482352_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Compliance with conditions of issue</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527142_011" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official, enter or leave or attempt to enter or leave the paid area or travel or attempt to travel on the Cable Car System otherwise than in accordance with the conditions of issue.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527158_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person shall leave the paid area within such period as may be specified in the conditions of issue failing which he shall, where he has no reasonable excuse for remaining in the paid area after the expiry of such period, pay a surcharge.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482352_005" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Entry and travel without ticket</heading><leadIn>No person shall, without lawful authority or reasonable excuse—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527189_012" name="a" temporalId="s14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enter or leave or attempt to enter or leave the paid area; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527189_020" name="b" temporalId="s14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>travel or attempt to travel on the Cable Car System,</content></paragraph><continued>without first paying his fare and obtaining a valid ticket appropriate to the circumstances of his intended journey and using that ticket as required by the conditions of issue of such ticket.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403482367_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Failure to pay fares, etc.</heading><content>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official, prior to leaving the paid area, fail or refuse to pay any fare, surcharge or other sum payable in accordance with this Bylaw and the conditions of issue.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482367_004" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Travel where ticket is lost, damaged or expired</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527236_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If a person (other than a person who is under 3 years of age) is in the paid area and—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527236_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is without a ticket;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527236_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is using or attempting to use or has used a ticket improperly damaged, altered or interfered with or the coded data of which has been improperly altered, erased or damaged either wholly or in part;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527236_028" name="c" temporalId="s16_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>is using or attempting to use or has used a ticket that has expired; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527236_036" name="d" temporalId="s16_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>is using or attempting to use or has used a concessionary ticket when he does not meet any of the conditions upon which the ticket is issued,</content></paragraph><continued>he shall be regarded as not having paid his fare and shall be liable to pay the appropriate fare and a surcharge and to deliver up his ticket (if any) to an authorized official.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527236_049" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (1), a ticket shall expire in such circumstances as specified in the conditions of issue.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527251_005" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any person who has paid a surcharge or delivered up his ticket pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be entitled to apply in writing to the Chairman or Chief Executive Officer of the Company (or their respective appointed nominee) for a review of the circumstances in which he became liable to a surcharge or to deliver up his ticket and the said Chairman or Chief Executive Officer of the Company (or their respective appointed nominee) upon the conclusion of such review may at his absolute discretion reject such application or may authorize repayment of the whole or any part of the surcharge or the remaining value in the delivered up ticket.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482383_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Tickets and change, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527298_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person purchasing a ticket shall examine his ticket and any change tendered before leaving any ticket office and the Company shall not be liable for any error or omission not drawn to its attention at the time of the issue of the ticket.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527314_004" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person using an automatic vending machine shall insert not less than the appropriate fare in Hong Kong legal tender or pay by any other mode of payment as specified by notice on the machine for the purchase of a ticket and a person is entitled to a refund of the amount in excess of the appropriate fare inserted into an automatic vending machine.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527314_012" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person shall, without reasonable excuse, insert or attempt to insert into any automatic vending machine or coin change machine any coin, object or thing other than Hong Kong legal tender in the denominations identified by notice on the machine as suitable for use in that machine.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527329_003" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The amount (including a nil amount) from time to time encoded on a ticket shall be conclusive evidence of the amount paid in respect of such ticket and of the value (if any) remaining in such ticket.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527329_011" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person using, attempting to use or who has used a concessionary ticket shall, if requested by an authorized official to do so, produce to that authorized official acceptable proof of his entitlement to a concessionary ticket.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482383_004" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Producing tickets on demand</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527360_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person in the paid area or in any other part of the Cable Car System area after having immediately gained exit from the paid area shall produce his ticket for checking, inspection or verification at any time on demand by any authorized official.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527360_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who contravenes subsection (1) shall be regarded as not having paid his fare and shall be liable to pay a surcharge.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482398_002" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Improperly doing things to or with a ticket</heading><leadIn>No person shall improperly do anything to or with a ticket so that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527392_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the coded data on the ticket is erased wholly or in part, or is otherwise altered or interfered with; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527392_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the ticket is otherwise damaged.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403482398_004" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Refunds and exchanges</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527407_026" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A ticket may be refunded or exchanged only at the discretion of the Company, and the refund or exchange may be subject to the deduction of an administration charge specified in the conditions of issue.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527423_005" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The form of any refund shall be at the discretion of the Company.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527423_013" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Company shall not be liable to issue a ticket in replacement of a lost or unused ticket or to make a refund in respect of any such lost or unused ticket or in respect of a surcharge charged to any person in accordance with this Bylaw.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482414_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            4</num><heading>Safety
            Precautions</heading><section id="ID_1438403482414_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Compliance with notices, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527454_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person shall, while on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area, comply with all notices and indicators which are posted as will reasonably be readily seen and read and all reasonable directions and requests of any authorized official.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527470_005" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to subsection (1), if an authorized official determines at his absolute discretion that a cable car is full, no person shall board or remain therein if directed by such authorized official not to do so.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482430_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Children on Cable Car System and in Cable Car System area</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527485_019" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Unless authorized by an authorized official, a child shall not board a cable car or travel on the Cable Car System unless he is accompanied by a person who has attained 15 years of age.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527501_005" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The person accompanying a child on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area shall use his best endeavours to prevent the child from behaving in a manner likely to endanger persons or property.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527501_013" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person accompanying a child under 3 years of age on the Cable Car System shall hold or secure the child in a safe manner whilst the child is on a platform or boarding or alighting from a cable car.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482430_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Restriction on number of persons</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527532_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The maximum capacity of a cable car is 17 persons, subject to a maximum total
                weight of
                1 275
                kg.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527532_012" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person shall comply with all loading instructions given by an authorized official.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527532_020" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person shall board or alight from a cable car unless so directed by an authorized official.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482430_005" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Power of authorized official to give directions</heading><leadIn>An authorized official may give to any person any signal or verbal direction for the purpose of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527548_035" name="a" temporalId="s24_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>marshalling and controlling persons using or intending to use the Cable Car System so as to provide for safe and orderly embarkation and disembarkation; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527563_006" name="b" temporalId="s24_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>preventing any act or omission by such person which is likely to render the Cable Car System unsafe for person,</content></paragraph><continued>and a person to whom any such signal or direction is given shall forthwith comply with the signal or direction.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403482445_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Prohibited persons</heading><leadIn>An authorized official may refuse the admission into or remove from the Cable Car System area—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527579_034" name="a" temporalId="s25_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any person whom he believes or is given reasonable cause to believe is under the influence of alcohol or drugs or in a state of intoxication resulting from consuming or abusing medicine;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527594_006" name="b" temporalId="s25_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any person whom he believes or is given reasonable cause to believe is suffering from a contagious disease; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527594_014" name="c" temporalId="s25_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any person whom he believes or is given reasonable cause to believe may prejudice the safety of the Cable Car System.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403482445_003" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Adversely affecting safety</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527610_034" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall do anything that may adversely affect the safety of persons on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area or the safety of the Cable Car System.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527626_005" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who contravenes subsection (1) shall comply with such directions of an authorized official as the authorized official considers necessary or expedient to give.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482445_005" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Flying materials endangering safety or operations</heading><content>No person shall cause or permit any kite, balloon, model or other thing to fly which may in the reasonable opinion of an authorized official endanger the safety on, or the proper operation of, the Cable Car System.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482461_001" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            5</num><heading>Conduct
            of Persons
            on
            the
            Cable
            Car System
            or
            in the
            Cable
            Car
            System
            Area</heading><section id="ID_1438403482461_003" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Prohibited goods, etc. and smoking</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527672_004" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person shall carry onto the Cable Car System or into the Cable Car System area—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527672_012" name="a" temporalId="s28_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>subject to subsection (2), any arms or ammunition;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527672_020" name="b" temporalId="s28_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>subject to subsection (2), any dangerous goods within the meaning of the Dangerous Goods Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap295">Cap. 295</ref>); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527672_028" name="c" temporalId="s28_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any object likely to cause inconvenience or annoyance to any person on the Cable Car System or prejudice the safe operation of the Cable Car System.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527688_005" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> shall not apply to any public officer while on duty, and subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> shall not apply to any person authorized by the Company to carry any such dangerous goods for the purposes of the operation, management or maintenance of the Cable Car System.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527688_013" name="3" temporalId="s28_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person shall smoke or carry a lighted pipe, cigar or cigarette or naked flame in any form on any part of the Cable Car System or in any part of the Cable Car System area where smoking is prohibited by notice.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482461_005" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Spitting and littering</heading><leadIn>No person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527719_012" name="a" temporalId="s29_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>spit on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527719_020" name="b" temporalId="s29_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>place or throw any litter on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area, except into receptacles provided for that purpose.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403482508_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Nuisance or annoyance</heading><content>No person shall conduct himself on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area so as to cause a nuisance or annoyance to other persons.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482570_001" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Playing musical instruments, etc.</heading><content>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official, sing, dance or perform on or play any musical instrument on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482570_003" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Using radios, cassettes, etc.</heading><content>A person may only use or attempt to use any radio, cassette, compact disc player, record player, portable wireless television or any other similar device which generates sound on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area with an earphone or headset or with the authorization of an authorized official.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482586_001" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Bringing prohibited luggage, etc. and consumption of food or beverage</heading><leadIn>No person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527797_019" name="a" temporalId="s33_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>bring onto the Cable Car System or into the Cable Car System area any luggage, article or other thing which—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413527797_027" name="i" temporalId="s33_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>cannot be carried or otherwise accommodated on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area without risk of damage to property on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413527813_007" name="ii" temporalId="s33_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>cannot be carried or otherwise accommodated on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area without causing a nuisance or inconvenience to other persons on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413527813_015" name="iii" temporalId="s33_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>an authorized official has directed that person not to bring onto the Cable Car System or into the Cable Car System area; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527813_022" name="b" temporalId="s33_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>consume or attempt to consume any food or beverage (whether alcoholic or non-alcoholic) but excluding water on the Cable Car System or in the paid area.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403482586_003" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Animals, livestock or pets on Cable Car System or in Cable Car System area</heading><content>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official, bring any animal, livestock or pet onto the Cable Car System or into the Cable Car System area.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482586_005" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Improper operation of equipment, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413527860_011" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person, except an authorized official or unless and to the extent authorized by an authorized official, shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527860_019" name="a" temporalId="s35_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>operate, move, or work—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413527860_027" name="i" temporalId="s35_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any mechanical or electrical appliance on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413527860_035" name="ii" temporalId="s35_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any switch, lever or other device operating or controlling any mechanical or electrical appliance on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area, other than the proper use of any automatic gate or telephones;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527875_006" name="b" temporalId="s35_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>tamper with or wilfully impede or interfere with the operation of any mechanical or electrical appliance on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527875_014" name="c" temporalId="s35_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>ascend or descend, or attempt to ascend or descend, by means of any escalator on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area other than in such manner and order as is directed by the Company;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527875_022" name="d" temporalId="s35_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>travel or attempt to travel on any escalator or moving platform on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area in a direction other than the direction in which it is moving;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527875_030" name="e" temporalId="s35_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>sit on any escalator or moving platform or any handrail on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527891_006" name="f" temporalId="s35_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>open or attempt to open any gate or door leading to or from a platform or any part of the paid area.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527891_013" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person, except an authorized official or unless authorized by an authorized official, shall retain any key to any gate or door to or on the Cable Car System or to or in the Cable Car System area and if such a key comes into the possession of a person, the person shall immediately surrender the key to an authorized official.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413527891_021" name="3" temporalId="s35_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In cases of accident or other emergency, a person may operate, move, or work any switch, lever, mechanical or electrical appliance or other device on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area on or near which is displayed a notice that it is intended to be operated in cases of accident or emergency.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482601_002" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Climbing or jumping on or over barriers, turnstiles, etc.</heading><content>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official, climb or jump on or over any wall, fence, barrier, turnstile or post in the Cable Car System area.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482601_004" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Interference with, etc. flora or fauna</heading><content>No person shall, unless authorized by an authorized official, remove, interfere with, damage or injure any flora or fauna in the Cable Car System area or climb any tree in the Cable Car System area.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482617_001" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Boarding or alighting from cable cars</heading><leadIn>A person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413527969_019" name="a" temporalId="s38_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>board or attempt to board any cable car;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527969_027" name="b" temporalId="s38_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>wait at a platform for the arrival of a cable car or wait inside a cable car for the arrival at a platform; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413527984_006" name="c" temporalId="s38_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>gain access from the platform to a cable car or gain access from a cable car to a platform,</content></paragraph><continued>only at such time and location and in such manner as an authorized official shall reasonably direct.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403482617_003" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Soil or damage to dress, clothing or personal effects</heading><content>No person shall soil or damage the dress, clothing or personal effects of any other person on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482617_005" name="s40" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s40"><num value="40">40.</num><heading>Prohibited conduct</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413528016_011" name="1" temporalId="s40_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person shall, at any time while in the Cable Car System area—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413528016_019" name="a" temporalId="s40_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>use any threatening, abusive or obscene language, or behave in a riotous, disorderly or indecent manner or such manner as to cause a nuisance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528031_006" name="b" temporalId="s40_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>paint, write, draw or affix any word, representation or character on, or wilfully soil or defile or break, cut, scratch, tear, spray, deface or damage any part of the Cable Car System or any other property in the Cable Car System area, including any cable car, fittings, furniture, decorations, equipment, publication, notice, list, time-table, advertisement, sign, figure or letter, or remove or detach any such article or object;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528031_014" name="c" temporalId="s40_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>molest any person; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528031_022" name="d" temporalId="s40_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>unless authorized by an authorized official, and subject to such terms and conditions as an authorized official may impose, use any voice recording or video recording or camera equipment for the conduct of interviews or taking of photographs, films or videos for any commercial purpose.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528047_005" name="2" temporalId="s40_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who contravenes this section is liable to the Company for the amount of the damage done to any property or personal injury caused to the authorized officials of the Company or damage or injury suffered by any other person without prejudice to any penalty incurred as a result of the contravention of this section.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482632_002" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            6</num><heading>Soliciting, Hawking
            and
            Bill
            Posting</heading><section id="ID_1438403482632_004" name="s41" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s41"><num value="41">41.</num><heading>Soliciting alms</heading><content>No person shall on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area solicit alms.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482632_006" name="s42" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s42"><num value="42">42.</num><heading>Hawking</heading><content>No person shall, unless authorized in writing by an authorized official, sell or expose or offer for sale any goods, wares or services in the Cable Car System area, and <ref>sections 86</ref>, <ref>86A</ref>, <ref>86C</ref> and <ref>86D</ref> of the Public Health and Municipal Services Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap132">Cap. 132</ref>) shall apply to an offence under this section as if such offence were a hawker offence within the meaning of <ref>section 83</ref> of that Ordinance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482648_002" name="s43" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s43"><num value="43">43.</num><heading>Bill posting, etc.</heading><leadIn>No person shall, unless authorized in writing by an authorized official—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413528156_012" name="a" temporalId="s43_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>post, stick, paint or write or cause to be posted, stuck, painted or written any placard, bill, advertisement or any other matter; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528156_020" name="b" temporalId="s43_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>distribute any book, leaflet or other printed matter or any sample or other article,</content></paragraph><continued>on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area.</continued></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482648_004" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part
            7</num><heading>Vehicles
            in
            Cable
            Car
            System
            Area</heading><section id="ID_1438403482648_006" name="s44" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s44"><num value="44">44.</num><heading>Vehicles left in Cable Car System area</heading><leadIn>Except with the permission of an authorized official, no person shall leave or cause to be left any vehicle—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413528187_012" name="a" temporalId="s44_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the Cable Car System area;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528187_020" name="b" temporalId="s44_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at any entrance to the Cable Car System area; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528203_006" name="c" temporalId="s44_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>on any road which is under the control of the Company for the purposes of the operation, management or maintenance of the Cable Car System.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403482664_002" name="s45" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s45"><num value="45">45.</num><heading>Dealing with vehicles left in Cable Car System area</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413528218_012" name="1" temporalId="s45_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Company may, in such manner as it thinks fit, remove and detain any vehicle in respect of which a contravention of <ref>section 44</ref> is committed and may charge the owner or driver of the vehicle all costs and expenses occasioned by and incidental to such removal and detention without prejudice to any penalty incurred as a result of the contravention of that section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528234_005" name="2" temporalId="s45_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>As soon as practicable after a vehicle has been detained under subsection (1), the Company shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413528234_013" name="a" temporalId="s45_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in respect of a vehicle of which there is a registered owner (as defined in <ref>section 2</ref> of the Road Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap. 374</ref>)), serve on such registered owner a notice informing him of the matters stated in subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref> and (b); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528234_021" name="b" temporalId="s45_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in respect of any other vehicle of which there is no such registered owner, display a notice in the Cable Car System area in such a manner that it is reasonably to be readily seen and read, informing members of the public of the matters stated in subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref> and (b).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528250_005" name="3" temporalId="s45_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The notice referred to in subsection <ref>(2)(a)</ref> or (b) shall inform the registered owner or members of the public, as the case may be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413528250_013" name="a" temporalId="s45_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of the detention of the vehicle and the place of detention; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528250_021" name="b" temporalId="s45_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that, unless the vehicle is removed from the place of detention on payment of any costs and charges within 14 days after the service of the notice on him or the display of the notice, the vehicle shall become the property of the Company free from the rights of any person and may be disposed of by the Company by sale or otherwise.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528265_005" name="4" temporalId="s45_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If a vehicle is not removed in accordance with the notice served or displayed under subsection (2), the vehicle shall become the property of the Company free from the rights of any person and may be disposed of by the Company by sale or otherwise as it thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528265_013" name="5" temporalId="s45_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If, within 6 months after the day on which a vehicle is sold pursuant to subsection (4), any person satisfies the Company that at the time the vehicle became the property of the Company by virtue of that subsection, he was the owner of the vehicle, the Company shall pay to such person the balance of the proceeds of sale after deducting any costs and charges of removal and detention and any reasonable charges incurred by the Company in respect of the sale of the vehicle.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528281_005" name="6" temporalId="s45_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A notice under subsection <ref>(2)(a)</ref> may be served personally or by post.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482664_004" name="s46" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s46"><num value="46">46.</num><heading>Vehicle drivers to comply with signs, etc.</heading><content>Vehicle drivers shall, while in the Cable Car System area, obey all traffic signs and signals and the reasonable instructions and directions of any authorized official.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482679_001" name="s47" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s47"><num value="47">47.</num><heading>Dangerous driving</heading><content>No person shall drive any vehicle through, into or in the Cable Car System area at a rate of speed or in a manner liable to involve danger to others.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482679_003" name="s48" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s48"><num value="48">48.</num><heading>Vehicles in pedestrian areas</heading><content>No person shall drive any vehicle in or along any part of the Cable Car System area set apart by an authorized official for the exclusive use of pedestrians.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482679_005" name="P8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part
            8</num><heading>Lost
            Property</heading><section id="ID_1438403482695_001" name="s49" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s49"><num value="49">49.</num><heading>Lost property</heading><content>A person who finds any lost property on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area shall report to an authorized official as soon as practicable, and no person other than an authorized official shall remove from the Cable Car System or the Cable Car System area any property lost or left behind on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area, save for the purpose of handing over the property forthwith to an authorized official.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482695_003" name="s50" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s50"><num value="50">50.</num><heading>Disposal of lost property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413528421_004" name="1" temporalId="s50_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>All lost property found on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area which comes into the possession of the Company shall be dealt with as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413528421_012" name="a" temporalId="s50_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>perishable, noxious, dangerous or otherwise offensive goods or articles may be disposed of by the Company as soon as practicable after they have come into the possession of the Company by sale or otherwise as it thinks fit;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528421_020" name="b" temporalId="s50_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>identification documents, travel documents, certificates or any other document which the Company shall regard to be of an important or confidential nature may be disposed of by the Company within such time they have come into the possession of the Company and in such manner as the Company thinks fit; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528437_006" name="c" temporalId="s50_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all other goods or articles shall be retained by the Company for a period of 3 months after they have come into its possession and, if after the end of that period they remain unclaimed, they shall be deemed to become the property of the Company free of all other rights and encumbrances, and the Company may dispose of them by sale or otherwise as the Company thinks fit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528437_013" name="2" temporalId="s50_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If, within a period of 6 months of any sale or disposal by the Company under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref> or (c), the former owner or the person formerly entitled to the beneficial ownership of the goods establishes his ownership to the satisfaction of the Company, he shall be paid, subject to his providing the Company with an indemnity as the Company may reasonably require, the proceeds of sale, if any, less all expenses incurred by the Company of and incidental to the sale or disposal and, if after the end of that period the proceeds of sale, if any, less all expenses incurred by the Company of and incidental to the sale or disposal remain unclaimed, the Company shall donate the balance of the proceeds to charitable organizations on such terms and conditions as it thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528468_005" name="3" temporalId="s50_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Save as provided in subsection (2), the Company shall incur no liability whatsoever, other than liability for gross negligence or wilful default, to any person in respect of lost property as bailees or otherwise and no claim for damages or compensation shall be brought against it by any person in respect of the same.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403482695_005" name="P9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="P9"><num value="9">Part
            9</num><heading>Enforcement
            and
            Penalties</heading><section id="ID_1438403482710_002" name="s51" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s51"><num value="51">51.</num><heading>Removal of persons from Cable Car System or Cable Car System area</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413528530_004" name="1" temporalId="s51_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any person who is reasonably suspected by an authorized official of contravening or attempting to contravene a provision of this Bylaw, while on the Cable Car System or in the Cable Car System area shall, when required to do so by such authorized official—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413528530_012" name="a" temporalId="s51_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>give to that authorized official true and correct particulars of his name, address and telephone number; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413528530_020" name="b" temporalId="s51_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>produce to that authorized official proof of his identity and, if in his possession at such time, proof of his address and telephone number.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528546_005" name="2" temporalId="s51_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An authorized official may remove (if necessary by the use of reasonable force) from the Cable Car System or Cable Car System area any person whom he reasonably suspects of having contravened or attempting to contravene a provision of this Bylaw; without prejudice to any penalty or surcharge which may be imposed in accordance with this Bylaw, and in the case where such contravention is an offence under this Bylaw, the authorized official may detain such person until that person can be delivered into the custody of a police officer to be dealt with according to law.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403482710_004" name="s52" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s52"><num value="52">52.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><content>A person who contravenes a provision of this Bylaw set out in column 1 of the <ref>Schedule</ref> commits an offence and is liable to a fine at the level set out in column 3 of that <ref>Schedule</ref> opposite the reference to that section.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403482726_001" name="s53" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="s53"><num value="53">53.</num><heading>Saving of Company’s rights</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413528608_004" name="1" temporalId="s53_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in this Bylaw or the failure to institute any prosecution, or to take any step or action under this Bylaw shall bar any further or other claim for damages or other remedy or relief available to the Company against any person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413528608_012" name="2" temporalId="s53_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any sum payable to the Company under this Bylaw or otherwise (including, without limitation, any charge, fare, excess fare or surcharge) whether by way of debt, damages, costs, loss, expense or otherwise shall be receivable by the Company or its lawful agents as a debt due on demand and shall be enforceable as a civil debt.</content></subsection></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403482726_003" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-08-15" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap577A/s52">s. 52</ref>]</note><heading>Penalties<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%" class="repeat_header">
                <col width="17%"></col>
                <col width="57.7986%"></col>
                <col width="25.1979%"></col>
                <thead><tr>
                        
                        <td class="cellpadding_bottom_7">
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Column 1</center>
                            
                            <br></br>
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section</center>
                            
                        </td>
                        
                        <td class="cellpadding_bottom_7">
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Column 2</center>
                            
                            <br></br>
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Summary of
                                offence</center>
                            
                        </td>
                        
                        <td class="cellpadding_bottom_7">
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Column 3</center>
                            
                            <br></br>
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Maximum
                                penalty</center>
                            
                        </td>
                    </tr></thead>
                <tbody><tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">3</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Trespass</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 ">4(1)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Trespass on certain area</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">5</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Damage to Cable Car System,
                            cable cars, plant and equipment</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">6</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Sewage, etc. placed on Cable
                            Car System or in Cable Car System area</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">7</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Rubbish, etc. thrown at, on
                            or from Cable Car System or Cable Car System area</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">8</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">Improper use of emergency
                            equipment</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">9</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Wrongfully boarding or alighting from cable
                            cars</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">14</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Entry and travel without a ticket</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">15</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to pay fares, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">17(3)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Wrongfully using an automatic vending machine
                            or a coin change machine</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">18(1)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to produce a ticket on demand</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">19</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Improperly doing things to or with a
                            ticket</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">21(1)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Non-compliance with notices, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0">21(2)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Boarding or remaining in a full cable car</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">22(2)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to use best endeavours to prevent a
                            child from behaving in a manner likely to endanger persons or
                            property</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">22(3)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to hold or secure a child in a safe
                            manner whilst on a platform or boarding or alighting from a cable
                            car</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">23(2)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to comply with loading
                            instructions</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">23(3)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Boarding or alighting unless so directed by
                            an authorized official</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">24</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Non-compliance with signal or direction given
                            by an authorized official</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">26(1)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Adversely affecting safety of persons and
                            Cable Car System</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">26(2)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to comply with directions in relation
                            to safety of persons and Cable Car System</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">27</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Flying materials endangering safety or proper
                            operation</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">28(1)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Carrying prohibited objects, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">28(3)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Smoking, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">29</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Spitting and littering</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">30</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Causing nuisance or annoyance</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">31</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Singing, dancing or performing on or playing
                            musical instruments</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">32</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Using radios, cassettes, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">33(a)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Bringing prohibited luggage, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">33(b)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Consumption of food or beverage</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">34</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Bringing animals, livestock or pets</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">35(1)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Improper operation of equipment, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">35(2)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Retaining, or failing to surrender, a key for
                            Cable Car System or Cable Car System area</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">36</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Climbing or jumping on or over barriers,
                            turnstiles, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">37</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Removing, interfering with, damaging or
                            injuring flora or fauna or climbing trees</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">38</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Boarding or alighting from a cable car other
                            than as directed</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">39</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Soil or damage to dress, clothing or personal
                            effects</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">40(1)(a)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Using prohibited language or behaving in a
                            manner that is prohibited</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">40(1)(b)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Damaging, etc. part of Cable Car System or
                            other property in Cable Car System area</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">40(1)(c)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Molesting a person</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">40(1)(d)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Using voice or video recording equipment or
                            camera equipment in a manner that is prohibited</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">41</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Soliciting alms</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">42</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Hawking</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">43</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Bill posting, etc. or distributing articles,
                            etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">44</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Vehicles left in Cable Car System area</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">46</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure of vehicle drivers to comply with
                            signs, etc.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">47</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Dangerous driving</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">48</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Driving in pedestrian areas</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">49</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to report upon finding lost
                            property</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 1</center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">51(1)</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="first_line_indent_0">Failure to give true and correct particulars
                            of name, address and telephone number or to produce proof of identity
                            and, if in possession, proof of address and telephone number</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">level 2</center>
                    </td>
                </tr></tbody>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>