<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 308</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>308</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap308!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2018-06-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402963248_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2018-06-28">
            <content>To make provision for the approval of the adoption in Hong Kong of a
                pharmacopoeia and for the admission in evidence of copies thereof.</content>
        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/60">60 of 2000 s.
            3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[22 August 1958]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2018/er3">E.R. 3 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402963248_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Pharmacopoeia Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402963264_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Right of approving a pharmacopoeia to vest in the Medical Council</heading><editorialNote id="ID_1525251518078_001"></editorialNote><text>The Medical Council of Hong Kong as established by <ref>section 3</ref> of the Medical Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap161">Cap. 161</ref>), shall have the exclusive right of approving the adoption in Hong Kong of a pharmacopoeia containing descriptions of and standards for, and notes and other matter relating to, medicines, preparations, materials and articles used in the practice of medicine, surgery, or midwifery, and shall further have the exclusive right of approving the adoption of any amendments thereto.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/60">60 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402963264_004" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Substitution of approved pharmacopoeia for previous pharmacopoeias</heading><editorialNote id="ID_1525251809986_001"></editorialNote><text>A pharmacopoeia approved under <ref>section 2</ref> shall be deemed for all purposes to be substituted in Hong Kong for all other pharmacopoeias; and any enactment or custom relating to any of such last-mentioned pharmacopoeias shall be deemed, after approval of a pharmacopoeia under <ref>section 2</ref>, to refer to such pharmacopoeia and any amendments thereto which have been approved.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/60">60 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402963279_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Publication of notice of approval and admission in evidence of copies of approved pharmacopoeia</heading><content>Notice shall be published in the Gazette of any approval given under <ref>section 2</ref> and of any amendment thereto and a copy of the pharmacopoeia or of any amendment thereto of which such notice of approval has been given, being a copy purporting to be printed by such printer as may be named in such notice, shall be received in evidence as such pharmacopoeia or amendment, as the case may be.</content></section></main></ordinance>