<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en" identifier="/hk/cap557I!en"><meta><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>557I</docNumber><docName>Cap. 557 sub. leg. I</docName><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap557I!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2015-12-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main><docTitle startPeriod="2015-12-11" name="shortTitle" temporalId="shortTitle" id="ID_1464925716949_001" status="operational" reason="inEffect">Consular Relations (Additional Privileges and Immunities)
            (Philippines) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap557">Cap. 557</ref>, <ref>section
            4(1)</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2015/er3">E.R. 4 of
            2015</ref>)<marker></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[11 December 2015]</commencementNote><section startPeriod="2015-12-11" name="s1" temporalId="s1" id="ID_1464925989271_001" status="omitted" reason="omittedAsSpent"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2015/er4">E.R. 4 of 2015</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section startPeriod="2015-12-11" name="s2" temporalId="s2" id="ID_1464926493195_001" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order—</leadIn><def name="Agreement"><term>Agreement</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">《協定》</term>) means
            the Consular Agreement between the People’s Republic of China and the Republic of the
            Philippines done at Manila on 29 October 2009;</def><def name="RelevantProvisionsOfTheAgreement"><term>relevant provisions of the
                Agreement</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">《協定》有關條文</term>) means the provisions
            of <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of Article 4, <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 28, Articles
            29 and 30, <ref>paragraphs 2</ref>, <ref>3</ref> and <ref>4</ref> of Article 31,
            Articles 34, 35, 36, 37 and 38, <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 39, Article 40 (except
            sub-paragraphs (a) and (b) of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> and <ref>paragraph 3</ref>),
            Article 41, and Article 43 (except paragraph (a)), of the Agreement as set out in the
                <ref>Schedule</ref>.</def></section><def><marker role="section-break"></marker></def><section startPeriod="2015-12-11" name="s3" temporalId="s3" id="ID_1464926838391_001" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Additional privileges and immunities</heading><content>It is declared that the additional privileges and immunities accorded to a consular
            post of the Republic of the Philippines, or to persons connected with the consular post,
            or to both, under the relevant provisions of the Agreement, as read with the provisions
            of Article 1 (except paragraphs (b) and (h)), and Articles 42, 44 and 45, of the
            Agreement as set out in the Schedule, have the force of law in Hong Kong.</content></section><schedule name="sch0" temporalId="sch0" startPeriod="2015-12-11" id="ID_1464942715846_001" status="operational" reason="inEffect"><num value="0">Schedule </num><note role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap557I/s2">ss. 2</ref> &amp;
                <ref href="/hk/cap557I/s3">3</ref>]</note><heading>Provisions of the Agreement Referred to in this
            Order<marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">CHAPTER I</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">DEFINITION<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 1</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Definitions<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">For the purposes of the present
            Agreement, the following expressions shall have the meanings hereunder assigned to
            them:</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(a)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “consular
            post” means any consulate-general, consulate, vice-consulate or consular agency;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="align_center">………</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(c)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “head of
            consular post” means the consul-general, consul, vice consul or consular agent who is
            charged by the sending State to head a consular post;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(d)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “consular
            officer” means any person, including the head of a consular post, entrusted in that
            capacity with the exercise of consular functions;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(e)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “member of
            the administrative and technical staff of the consular post” means any person who
            performs administrative or technical service at a consular post;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(f)<inline class="width_18"></inline>“member of
            the service staff” means any person employed in the domestic service of a consular
            post;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(g)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “members of
            the consular post” means consular officers, administrative and technical staff and
            service staff of the consular post;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="align_center">………</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(i)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “consular
            premises” means the buildings or parts of buildings and the land ancillary thereto,
            irrespective of ownership, used exclusively for the purposes of the consular
            post;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(j)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “consular
            archives” means all the papers, documents, correspondence, books, films, tapes and
            registers of the consular post, together with the ciphers and codes, the card indexes,
            the data stored in memory medium and any articles of furniture intended for their
            protection or safe-keeping;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(k)<inline class="width_18"></inline> “national
            of the sending State” means any natural person having the nationality of the sending
            State, and when applicable, also any juridical person of the sending State;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(l)<inline class="width_21"></inline> “vessel of
            the sending State” means any vessel sailing under the flag of the sending State pursuant
            to its law, excluding military vessels;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(m)<inline class="width_15"></inline> “aircraft
            of the sending State” means any aircraft registered in the sending State and bearing
            that State’s registration marks, excluding military aircraft.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">CHAPTER II</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">ESTABLISHMENT OF A CONSULAR POST AND APPOINTMENT OF ITS
            MEMBERS<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 4</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Temporary Exercise of the Functions of the Head of a
            Consular Post<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The acting
            head of a consular post shall enjoy the same rights, facilities, privileges and
            immunities as enjoyed by a head of a consular post under this Agreement.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">CHAPTER IV</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">FACILITIES, PRIVILEGES AND
            IMMUNITIES<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 28</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Inviolability of Consular Premises and the Residences of
            Consular Officers<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Consular
            premises and the residences of consular officers shall be inviolable. The authorities of
            the receiving State may not enter the consular premises and the residences of consular
            officers without the consent of the head of the consular post or the head of the
            diplomatic mission of the sending State in the receiving State, or of a person
            designated by one of them. The consent of the head of the consular post may, however, be
            assumed in case of fire or other disaster requiring prompt protective action.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 29</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Immunity from Requisition of Consular
            Premises<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">The consular premises, their furnishings
            and the property and means of transport of the consular post shall be immune from any
            form of requisition.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 30</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Inviolability of the Consular
            Archives<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">The consular archives shall be inviolable
            at all times and wherever they may be.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 31</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Freedom of
            Communication<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The official
            correspondence of a consular post shall be inviolable. The consular bag shall neither be
            opened nor detained. The consular bag must bear visible external marks of its character
            and may contain nothing other than official correspondence, official documents and
            articles intended exclusively for official use.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">3.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The consular
            courier shall only be a national of the sending State, and not be a permanent resident
            of the receiving State. He shall be provided with an official document certifying his
            status. He shall enjoy the same rights, facilities, privileges and immunities in the
            receiving State as enjoyed by a diplomatic courier.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">4.<inline class="width_21"></inline> A consular
            bag may be entrusted to the captain of an aircraft or a vessel of the sending State. But
            he shall be provided with an official document indicating the number of packages
            constituting the bag, however, he shall not be considered as a consular courier. By
            arrangement with the appropriate authorities of the receiving State, a member of the
            consular post may directly and freely collect the bag from or deliver it to him.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 34</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Personal Inviolability of Consular
            Officers<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">The person of consular officers shall be
            inviolable, and they shall not be liable to any form of detention or arrest. The
            receiving State shall take appropriate measures to prevent any attack on their freedom
            of person and dignity.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 35</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Immunity from
            Jurisdiction<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> A consular
            officer shall be immune from the judicial or administrative jurisdiction of the
            receiving State, except in civil proceedings:</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(a)<inline class="width_18"></inline> arising out
            of a contract concluded by a consular officer in which he did not contract expressly as
            an agent of the sending State;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(b)<inline class="width_18"></inline> by a third
            party for damage arising from an accident in the receiving State caused by a vehicle,
            vessel or aircraft;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(c)<inline class="width_18"></inline> concerning
            private immovable property in the receiving State, unless a consular officer is holding
            it in the capacity of representative of the sending State and for the purposes of the
            consular post;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(d)<inline class="width_18"></inline> concerning
            private succession;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(e)<inline class="width_18"></inline> arising out
            of any professional or commercial activities in the receiving State by a consular
            officer outside of his official functions.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The
            receiving State shall not take measures of execution against a consular officer except
            in cases referred to in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this Article. In the event of taking
            such measures in such cases, the inviolability of the person and residence of the
            consular officer shall not be impaired.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">3.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Members of
            the administrative and technical staff and of the service staff of the consular post
            shall be immune from the jurisdiction of the judicial or administrative authorities of
            the receiving State in respect of any act in the performance of their functions, except
            in the civil proceedings referred to in sub-paragraphs (a) and (b) of <ref>paragraph
                1</ref> of this Article.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 36</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Liability to Give
            Evidence<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> A consular
            officer is under no obligation to give evidence as a witness.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> A member of
            the administrative and technical staff or of the service staff of the consular post may
            be called upon to give evidence in the course of judicial or administrative proceeding
            of the receiving State. He shall not, except in the cases referred to in <ref>paragraph
                3</ref> of this Article, decline to give evidence.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">3.<inline class="width_21"></inline> A member of
            the administrative and technical staff or of the service staff of the consular post is
            under no obligation to give evidence concerning matters connected with the exercise of
            their functions or to produce any official correspondence or documents relating thereto.
            He is entitled to decline to give evidence as expert witness with regard to the law of
            the sending State.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">4.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The
            competent authorities of the receiving State requiring the evidence of a member of the
            administrative and technical staff or of the service staff of the consular post shall
            avoid interference with the performance of his functions. They may, when possible, take
            such evidence at his residence or at the consular premises or accept a statement from
            him in writing.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 37</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Exemption from Services and Registration of Aliens and
            Residence Permits<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> A member of
            the consular post shall be exempt in the receiving State from any kind of personal
            services, public services and military obligations.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> A consular
            officer and a member of the administrative and technical staff of the consular post
            shall be exempt from all obligations under the laws of the receiving State concerning
            the registration of aliens and residence permits.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 38</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Exemption of Properties from
            Taxation<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> On a
            reciprocal basis and to the extent permitted by the laws and regulations of the
            receiving State, the followings shall be exempt from all dues and taxes:</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(a)<inline class="width_18"></inline> consular
            premises and residences of the members of a consular post acquired in the name of the
            sending State or its representative and transactions or instruments related
            thereto;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(b)<inline class="width_18"></inline> consular
            facilities and means of transport acquired exclusively for official purposes as well as
            their acquisition, possession or maintenance.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The
            provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this Article shall not apply in respect
            of:</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(a)<inline class="width_18"></inline> charges
            levied for specific services;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(b)<inline class="width_18"></inline> dues and
            taxes collectable under the laws and regulations of the receiving State from a person
            who concludes a contract with the sending State or its representative.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 39</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Exemption of Members of the Consular Post from
            Taxation<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Consular
            officers and members of the administrative and technical staff of the consular post
            shall be exempt from all national, regional or municipal dues and taxes of the receiving
            State on person or object, except:</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(a)<inline class="width_18"></inline> indirect
            taxes of a kind which are normally incorporated in the price of commodities or
            services;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(b)<inline class="width_18"></inline> dues and
            taxes on private immovable property situated in the territory of the receiving State,
            subject to the provisions in sub-paragraph (a) of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 38
            of this Agreement;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(c)<inline class="width_18"></inline> estate and
            inheritance duties and duties on transfers, subject to the provisions of Article 43<ref idref="ID_1467689741769_001"><sup>#</sup></ref> of this Agreement;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(d)<inline class="width_18"></inline> dues and
            taxes on private income other than the income acquired from their official functions in
            the receiving State;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(e)<inline class="width_18"></inline> charges
            levied for specific services rendered;</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(f)<inline class="width_18"></inline> registration, court or record fees, mortgage dues and stamp duties, subject to the
            provisions of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 38 of this Agreement.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1467689741769_001">
            <content><ref><sup>#</sup></ref>Article 43(a) reads as follows—<text>
                    <br></br>
                </text><text class="align_justified first_line_indent_30">“In the event of the death
                    of a member of a consular post or a member of his family, the receiving State
                    shall:</text><text>
                    <br></br>
                </text><text class="align_justified first_line_indent_30">(a)<inline class="width_18"></inline>permit the export of the movable property of the deceased
                    except any such property acquired by the deceased in the territory of the
                    receiving State the export of which was prohibited at the time of his
                    death;”.</text></content>
        </editorialNote><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 40</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Exemption from Customs Duties and
            Inspection<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The
            receiving State shall, in accordance with its laws and regulations, permit entry and
            exit of and grant exemption from all customs duties other than charges, for storage,
            cartage and similar services, on:</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="align_center">………</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(c)<inline class="width_18"></inline> articles
            imported at the time of first installation for the personal use of a member of the
            administrative and technical staff of the consular post, including household articles
            intended for his establishment.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Articles
            referred to in sub-paragraphs … (c) of <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this Article shall not
            exceed the quantities necessary for direct use by the person concerned.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 41</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Privileges and Immunities of Family
            Members<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">Family members of a consular officer and
            family members of a member of the administrative and technical staff of the consular
            post shall enjoy respectively the privileges and immunities to which the consular
            officer and the member of the administrative and technical staff are respectively
            entitled under the provisions of this Agreement; Family members of a member of the
            service staff of the consular post shall enjoy the privileges and immunities to which
            the member of service staff is entitled under <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Article 37 of
            this Agreement, except those who are nationals or permanent residents of the receiving
            State, or who carry on any private gainful occupation in the receiving State.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 42</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Persons Who Shall Not Enjoy Privileges and
            Immunities<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Members of
            the administrative and technical staff or of the service staff of the consular post who
            are nationals or permanent residents of the receiving State shall not enjoy the
            privileges and immunities provided for in this Agreement, subject to the provisions of
                <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of Article 36 of this Agreement.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Family
            members of the persons mentioned in <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of this Article shall not
            enjoy the privileges and immunities provided for in this Agreement.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 43</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Estate of Member of the Consular
            Post<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">In the event of the death of a member of
            a consular post or a member of his family, the receiving State shall:</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="align_center">………</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">(b)<inline class="width_18"></inline> exempt the
            movable property of the deceased from estate duties and all duties concerned.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 44</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Beginning and End of Privileges and
            Immunities<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Every member
            of the consular post shall enjoy the privileges and immunities provided in this
            Agreement from the moment he enters the territory of the receiving State on proceeding
            to take up his post or, if already in its territory, from the moment when he enters on
            his duties with the consular post.</text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> Family
            members of a member of the consular post shall enjoy the privileges and immunities
            provided in this Agreement from the date from which he enjoys privileges and immunities,
            or from the date of their entry into the territory of the receiving State or from the
            date of their becoming such family members in the case of their entry or becoming such
            family members after the date from which he enjoys privileges and immunities.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">3.<inline class="width_21"></inline> When the
            functions of a member of the consular post have come to an end, his privileges and
            immunities and those of his family members shall cease at the moment when the person
            concerned leaves the receiving State or on the expiry of a reasonable period in which to
            do so, whichever is sooner. The privileges and immunities of the family members of a
            member of the consular post shall come to an end when they cease to be the said family
            members. However if such persons intend to leave the receiving State within a reasonable
            period thereafter, their privileges and immunities shall subsist until the time of their
            departure.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">4.<inline class="width_21"></inline> In the event
            of the death of a member of the consular post, his family members shall continue to
            enjoy the privileges and immunities accorded to them until they leave the receiving
            State or until the expiry of a reasonable period in which to do so.</text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">5.<inline class="width_21"></inline> However,
            with respect to acts performed by a member of the consular post in the exercise of his
            functions during his tenure of office, immunity from jurisdiction shall continue to
            subsist without limitation of time.</text><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Article 45</crossHeading><crossHeading class="left_indent_0">Waiver of Privileges and
            Immunities<marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">1.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The sending
            State may waive any of the privileges and immunities enjoyed by the persons concerned
            under Article 35 and 36 of this Agreement. The waiver shall in all cases be explicit and
            shall be communicated to the receiving State in writing.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">2.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The
            initiation of proceedings by a person in a matter where he might enjoy immunity from
            jurisdiction under this Agreement shall preclude him from invoking immunity from
            jurisdiction in respect of any counter-claim directly connected with the principal
            claim.</text><text>
            <br></br>
        </text><text class="first_line_indent_30 align_justified">3.<inline class="width_21"></inline> The waiver
            of immunity from jurisdiction for the purposes of civil or administrative proceedings
            shall not be deemed to imply the waiver of immunity from the execution of judicial
            decision. In respect of such execution, a separate waiver of immunity in writing shall
            be necessary.</text></schedule></main></subLeg>