<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 319</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>319</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap319!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-04-11</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402988068_003" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2019-04-11">
            <content>To make provision for the enforcement in the Colony of Hong Kong of judgments
                given in other parts of the Commonwealth and foreign countries which afford
                reciprocal treatment to judgments given in the Colony of Hong Kong, for facilitating
                the enforcement in such parts or countries of judgments given in the Colony of Hong
                Kong, and for matters connected
                therewith.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[6 May 1960]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402988083_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Foreign Judgments (Reciprocal Enforcement) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402988099_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912248_018" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Appeal"><term>appeal</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">上訴</term>) includes any proceedings by way of
                discharging or setting aside a judgment or an application for a new trial or a stay
                of execution;</def><def name="CountryOfTheOriginalCourt"><term>country
                    of the original
                court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">原訟法院的國家</term>) means the country in which the
                original court is situated;</def><def name="ForeignCountry"><term>foreign
                    country</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">外地國家</term>) has the same meaning as in the United
                Kingdom Foreign Judgments (Reciprocal Enforcement) Act 1933 (1933 c. 13);</def><def name="Judgment">
                <leadIn><term>judgment</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">判決</term>) means—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912263_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a judgment or order given or made by a court in any civil proceedings;
                        or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912263_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a judgment or order given or made by a court in any criminal
                        proceedings for the payment of a sum of money in respect of compensation or
                        damages to an injured party,</content></paragraph>
                <continued>but does not include a judgment which by virtue of the Foreign Judgments
                    (Restriction on Recognition and Enforcement) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap46">Cap. 46</ref>) cannot be recognized or enforced in Hong Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1985/37">37
                            of 1985 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></continued>
            </def><def name="JudgmentCreditor"><term>judgment
                    creditor</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">判定債權人</term>) means the person in whose favour the
                judgment was given and includes any person in whom the rights under the judgment
                have become vested by succession or assignment or otherwise;</def><def name="JudgmentDebtor"><term>judgment
                    debtor</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">判定債務人</term>) means the person against whom the
                judgment was given, and includes any person against whom the judgment is enforceable
                under the law of the original court;</def><def name="JudgmentsGivenInTheSuperiorCourtsOfTheColony"><term>judgments
                    given in the superior courts of the
                Colony</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">香港高級法院作出的判決</term>) means judgments given in the
                Court of First Instance and includes judgments given in any court whether of the
                Colony or not, on appeals against any judgments so given;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="OriginalCourt"><term>original
                    court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">原訟法院</term>) in relation to any judgment means the
                court by which the judgment was given;</def><def name="Prescribed"><term>prescribed</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訂明</term>) means prescribed by rules of court made
                under the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>) as modified by
                    <ref>section 5</ref> of this Ordinance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1975/92">92 of 1975 s. 58</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="RegisteringCourt"><term>registering
                    court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">登記法院</term>) in relation to any judgment means the
                court to which an application to register the judgment is
                made;
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Registration,Register,Registered"><term>registration</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">登記</term>) means registration under <ref>section 4</ref>,
                and the expressions <term>register</term> (登記) and <term>registered</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已登記</term>) shall be construed accordingly.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of
                2019</ref>)</sourceNote></def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2019/er1">E.R. 1 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912279_025" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="ActionInPersonam">
                <leadIn>For the purposes of this Ordinance, the expression
                        <term>action
                        in
                    personam</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">對人的訴訟</term>) shall not be deemed to include
                    any matrimonial cause or any proceedings in
                    connexion
                    with any of the following matters—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912279_033" name="a" temporalId="s2_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>matrimonial matters;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912279_041" name="b" temporalId="s2_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>administration of the estates of deceased persons;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912279_049" name="c" temporalId="s2_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>bankruptcy;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912279_057" name="d" temporalId="s2_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>winding up of companies;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912279_065" name="e" temporalId="s2_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>lunacy;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912279_073" name="f" temporalId="s2_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>guardianship of infants.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 11 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph>
            </def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402988115_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Power to extend the provisions of the Ordinance to countries giving reciprocal treatment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912326_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Governor in Council, if he is satisfied that, in the event of the benefits conferred by this Ordinance being extended to judgments given in the superior courts of any foreign country, substantial reciprocity of treatment will be assured as respects the enforcement in that foreign country of judgments given in the superior courts of the Colony, may by order direct—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912326_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the provisions of this Ordinance shall extend to that foreign country; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912326_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that such courts of that foreign country as are specified in the order shall be deemed superior courts of that foreign country for the purposes of this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912326_027" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any judgment of a superior court of any foreign country to which the provisions of this Ordinance extend, other than a judgment of such a court given on appeal from a court which is not a superior court, shall be a judgment to which the provisions of this Ordinance apply, if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912326_035" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it is final and conclusive as between the parties thereto; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912341_005" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>there is payable thereunder a sum of money, not being a sum payable in respect of taxes or other charges of a like nature or in respect of a fine or other penalty; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912341_013" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>it is given after the coming into operation of the order directing that the provisions of this Ordinance shall extend to that foreign country.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912341_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of this section, a judgment shall be deemed to be final and conclusive notwithstanding that an appeal is pending against it, or that it may still be subject to appeal, in the courts of the country of the original court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912341_028" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Governor in Council may by a subsequent order vary or revoke any order previously made under this section.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402988115_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Application for, and effect of, registration of foreign judgments</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912372_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person, being a judgment creditor under a judgment to which the provisions of
                this Ordinance apply, may apply to the Court of First Instance at any time within 6
                years after the date of the judgment, or, where there have been proceedings by way
                of appeal against the judgment, after the date of the last judgment given in those
                proceedings, to have the judgment registered in the Court of First Instance, and on
                any such application the court shall, subject to proof of the prescribed matters and
                to the other provisions of this Ordinance, order the judgment to be
                    registered:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_1_proviso">
                <leadIn>Provided that a judgment shall not be registered if at the date of the
                    application—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912372_026" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it has been wholly satisfied; or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411912372_034" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it could not be enforced by execution in the country of the original
                        court.</content></paragraph>
            </proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912372_041" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance with respect to the setting aside of
                registration—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912372_049" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a registered judgment shall, for the purposes of execution, be of the same
                    force and effect; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912372_057" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>proceedings may be taken on a registered judgment; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912372_065" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the sum for which a judgment is registered shall carry interest;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912372_073" name="d" temporalId="s4_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the registering court shall have the same control over the execution of a
                    registered judgment,</content></paragraph><continued>as if the judgment had been a judgment originally given in the registering
                court and entered on the day of registration:</continued><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_2_proviso">Provided that the execution shall not
                issue on the judgment so long as, under the provisions of this Ordinance and any
                prescribed rules, it is competent for any party to make an application to have the
                registration of the judgment set aside, or, where such an application is made, until
                after the application has been finally determined.</proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912388_018" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the sum payable under a judgment which is to be registered is expressed
                in a currency other than the currency of the Colony, the judgment shall be
                registered as if it were a judgment for such sum in the currency of the Colony as,
                on the basis of the rate of exchange prevailing at the date of registration, is
                equivalent to the sum so payable.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/8">8 of 1981 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912388_026" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If at the date of the application for registration the judgment of the original
                court has been partly satisfied, the judgment shall not be registered in respect of
                the whole sum payable under the judgment of the original court, but only in respect
                of the balance remaining payable at that date.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912404_005" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If, on an application for the registration of a judgment, it appears to the
                registering court that the judgment is in respect of different matters and that
                some, but not all, of the provisions of the judgment are such that if those
                provisions had been contained in separate judgments those judgments could properly
                have been registered, the judgment may be registered in respect of the provisions
                aforesaid but not in respect of any other provisions contained therein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912404_013" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In addition to the sum of money payable under the judgment of the original
                court, including any interest which by the law of the country of the original court
                becomes due under the judgment up to the time of registration, the judgment shall be
                registered for the reasonable costs of and incidental to registration, including the
                costs of obtaining a certified copy of the judgment from the original
                court.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402988130_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Rules of Court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912450_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The power to make rules of court under the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>) shall, subject to the provisions of this section,
                include power to make rules for the following purposes—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1975/92">92 of 1975 s. 58</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of
                        1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912450_026" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for making provision with respect to the giving of security for costs by
                    persons applying for the registration of judgments;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912450_034" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for prescribing the matters to be proved on an application for the
                    registration of a judgment and for regulating the mode of proving those
                    matters;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912466_006" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>for providing for the service on the judgment debtor of notice of the
                    registration of a judgment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912466_014" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>for making provision with respect to the fixing of the period within which
                    an application may be made to have the registration of a judgment set aside and
                    with respect to the extension of the period so fixed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912466_022" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>for prescribing the method by which any question arising under the
                    provisions of this Ordinance whether a foreign judgment can be enforced by
                    execution in the country of the original court, or what interest is payable
                    under a foreign judgment under the law of the original court, is to be
                    determined;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912466_030" name="f" temporalId="s5_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>for prescribing any matter which under the provisions of this Ordinance is
                    to be prescribed.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912466_037" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Rules made for the purposes of this Ordinance shall be expressed to have, and
                shall have, effect subject to any such provisions contained in orders made by the
                Governor in Council under <ref>section 3</ref> as are declared by such orders to be
                necessary for the giving of effect to agreements made between Her Majesty and any
                foreign country in relation to matters with respect to which there is power to make
                rules of court for the purposes of the provisions of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402988146_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Cases in which registered judgments must, or may be set aside</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912528_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>On an application in that behalf duly made by any party against whom a registered judgment may be enforced, the registration of the judgment—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912544_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>shall be set aside if the registering court is satisfied—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912544_013" name="i" temporalId="s6_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>that the judgment is not a judgment to which the provisions of this Ordinance apply or was registered in contravention of any of the foregoing provisions of this Ordinance; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912544_021" name="ii" temporalId="s6_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that the courts of the country of the original court had no jurisdiction in the circumstances of the case; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912544_029" name="iii" temporalId="s6_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>that the judgment debtor, being the defendant in the proceedings in the original court, did not (notwithstanding that process may have been duly served on him in accordance with the law of the country of the original court) receive notice of those proceedings in sufficient time to enable him to defend the proceedings and did not appear; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912544_037" name="iv" temporalId="s6_1_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>that the judgment was obtained by fraud; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912544_045" name="v" temporalId="s6_1_a_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>that the enforcement of the judgment shall be contrary to public policy in the country of the registering court; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912560_007" name="vi" temporalId="s6_1_a_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>that the rights under the judgment are not vested in the person by whom the application for registration was made;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912560_014" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may be set aside if the registering court is satisfied that the matter in dispute in the proceedings in the original court had previously to the date of the judgment in the original court been the subject of a final and conclusive judgment by a court having jurisdiction in the matter.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912560_021" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section, the courts of the country of the original court shall, subject to the provisions of subsection (3), be deemed to have had jurisdiction—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912560_029" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in the case of a judgment given in an action in personam—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912560_037" name="i" temporalId="s6_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>if the judgment debtor, being a defendant in the original court, submitted to the jurisdiction of that court by voluntarily appearing in the proceedings; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/37">37 of 1985 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912560_045" name="ii" temporalId="s6_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the judgment debtor was plaintiff in, or
                        counter-claimed
                        in, the proceedings in the original court; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912560_053" name="iii" temporalId="s6_2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>if the judgment debtor, being a defendant in the original court, had before the commencement of the proceedings agreed, in respect of the subject matter of the proceedings, to submit to the jurisdiction of that court or of the courts of the country of that court; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912575_007" name="iv" temporalId="s6_2_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>if the judgment debtor, being a defendant in the original court, was at the time when the proceedings were instituted resident in, or being a body corporate had its principal place of business in, the country of that court; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912575_015" name="v" temporalId="s6_2_a_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>if the judgment debtor, being a defendant in the original court, had an office or place of business in the country of that court and the proceedings in that court were in respect of a transaction effected through or at that office or place;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912575_022" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a judgment given in an action of which the subject matter was immovable property or in an action in rem of which the subject matter was movable property, if the property in question was at the time of the proceedings in the original court situate in the country of that court;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912591_006" name="c" temporalId="s6_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of a judgment given in an action other than any such action as is mentioned in paragraph (a) or (b), if the jurisdiction of the original court is recognized by the law of the registering court.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912591_013" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding anything contained in subsection (2), the courts of the country of the original court shall not be deemed to have had jurisdiction—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912591_021" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the subject matter of the proceedings was immovable property outside the country of the original court; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912591_029" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1985/37">37 of 1985 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912591_037" name="c" temporalId="s6_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>if the judgment debtor, being a defendant in the original proceedings, was a person who under the rules of public international law was entitled to immunity from the jurisdiction of the courts of the country of the original court and did not submit to the jurisdiction of that court.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402988161_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Powers of registering courts on application to set aside registrations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912638_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If, on an application to set aside the registration of a judgment, the applicant satisfies the registering court either that an appeal is pending, or that he is entitled and intends to appeal, against the judgment, the court, if it thinks fit, may, on such terms as it may think just, either set aside the registration or adjourn the application to set aside the registration until after the expiration of such period as appears to the court to be reasonably sufficient to enable the applicant to take the necessary steps to have the appeal disposed of by the competent tribunal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912653_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the registration of a judgment is set aside under subsection (1), or solely for the reason that the judgment was not at the date of the application for registration enforceable by execution in the country of the original court, the setting aside of the registration shall not prejudice a further application to register the judgment when the appeal has been disposed of or if and when the judgment becomes enforceable by execution in that country, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912669_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the registration of a judgment is set aside solely for the reason that the judgment, notwithstanding that it had at the date of the application for registration been partly satisfied, was registered for the whole sum payable thereunder, the registering court shall, on the application of the judgment creditor, order judgment to be registered for the balance remaining payable at that date.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402988177_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Foreign judgments which can be registered not to be enforceable otherwise</heading><content>No proceedings for the recovery of a sum payable under a foreign judgment, being a judgment to which the provisions of this Ordinance apply, other than proceedings by way of registration of the judgment, shall be entertained in any court in the Colony.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402988177_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Application to the Commonwealth</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912716_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Governor in Council may by order direct that the provisions of this Ordinance shall apply to any part of the Commonwealth and to judgments obtained in the superior courts of such part, as they apply to foreign countries and judgments obtained in the superior courts of foreign countries; and upon the making of any such order the provisions of the Judgments (Facilities for Enforcement) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap9">Cap. 9</ref>) shall cease to have effect except in relation to such part of the Commonwealth to which it extends at the date of the order.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912731_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If at any time after the Governor in Council has directed as aforesaid an order is made under <ref>section 3</ref> extending the provisions of this Ordinance to any part of the Commonwealth to which the Judgments (Facilities for Enforcement) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap9">Cap. 9</ref>) extends, then in relation to such part—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912731_013" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the last mentioned Ordinance shall cease to have effect;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912731_021" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the provisions of this Ordinance shall have effect as if—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912731_029" name="i" temporalId="s9_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><def name="Judgment">the expression
                            <term>judgment</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">判決</term>) included an award in proceedings
                        on an arbitration if the award has, in pursuance of the law in force in the
                        place where it was made, become enforceable in the same manner as a judgment
                        given by a court in that place;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/ln386">L.N. 386 of
                                1993</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912731_036" name="ii" temporalId="s9_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the fact that a judgment was given before the coming into operation of the order did not prevent such judgment from being a judgment to which the provisions of this Ordinance apply, but the time limited for the registration of a judgment so given was 12 months from the date of the judgment or such longer period as may be allowed by the High Court; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912747_007" name="iii" temporalId="s9_2_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>any judgment registered in the High Court under the provisions of the Judgments (Facilities for Enforcement) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap9">Cap. 9</ref>) before the coming into operation of the order had been registered in that court under the provisions of this Ordinance and anything done in relation thereto under the provisions of the Judgments (Facilities for Enforcement) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap9">Cap. 9</ref>) or any rules of court or other provisions applicable thereto had been done under the provisions of this Ordinance or the corresponding rules of court or other provisions applicable thereto.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1964/13">13 of 1964 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402988193_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>General effect of certain foreign judgments</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912809_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this section, a judgment to which the provisions
                of this Ordinance apply or would have applied if a sum of money had been payable
                thereunder, whether it can be registered or not, and whether, if it can be
                registered, it is registered or not, shall be recognized in any court in the Colony
                as conclusive between the parties thereto in all proceedings founded on the same
                cause of action and may be relied on by way of defence or
                counter-claim
                in any such proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912825_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>This section shall not apply in the case of any judgment—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411912825_013" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>where a judgment has been registered and the registration thereof has been
                    set aside on some ground other than—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912825_021" name="i" temporalId="s10_2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>that a sum of money was not payable under the judgment; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912825_029" name="ii" temporalId="s10_2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that the judgment had been wholly or partly satisfied; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411912825_037" name="iii" temporalId="s10_2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>that at the date of the application the judgment could not be enforced
                        by execution in the country of the original court; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411912825_044" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the judgment has not been registered, it is shown (whether it could
                    have been registered or not) that if it had been registered the registration
                    thereof would have been set aside on an application for that purpose on some
                    ground other than one of the grounds specified in paragraph (a).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912840_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall be taken to prevent any court in the Colony
                recognizing any judgment as conclusive of any matter of law or fact decided therein
                if that judgment would have been so recognized before the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1548058281044_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 6 May
                1960.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438402988208_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Power to make foreign judgments unenforceable in the Colony, if no reciprocity</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411912856_072" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If it appears to the Governor in Council that the treatment in respect of recognition and enforcement accorded by the courts of any foreign country to judgments given in the superior courts of the Colony is substantially less favourable than that accorded by the courts of the Colony to judgments of the superior courts of that country, the Governor in Council may by order apply this section to that country.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912872_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Except in so far as the Governor in Council may by order under this section otherwise direct, no proceedings shall be entertained in any court in the Colony for the recovery of any sum alleged to be payable under a judgment given in a court of a country to which this section applies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411912887_005" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Governor in Council may by a subsequent order vary or revoke any order previously made under this section.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402988208_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Issue of certificates of judgments obtained in the Colony</heading><leadIn>Where a judgment under which a sum of money is payable, not being a sum payable in
            respect of taxes or other charges of a like nature or in respect of a fine or other
            penalty, has been entered in the Court of First Instance against any person and the
            judgment creditor is desirous of enforcing the judgment in a foreign country to which
            the provisions of this Ordinance apply, the court shall, on an application made by the
            judgment creditor and on payment of such fee as may be fixed for the purposes of this
            section by rules of court made under the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap.
                4</ref>) as modified by <ref>section 5</ref> of this Ordinance issue to the judgment
            creditor a certified copy of the judgment, together with a certificate containing such
            particulars with respect to the action, including the causes of action, and the rate of
            interest, if any, payable on the sum payable under the judgment, as may be
                prescribed:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1975/92">92 of 1975 s. 58</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s12_proviso">Provided that, where execution of a
            judgment is stayed for any period pending an appeal or for any other reason, an
            application shall not be made under this section with respect to the judgment until the
            expiration of that period.</proviso><referenceNote>[cf. 1933 c. 13 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402988224_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-04-11" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Transitional</heading><content>Notwithstanding the amendment of <ref>section 4(3)</ref> by <ref>section 2</ref> of
            the Foreign Judgments (Reciprocal Enforcement) (Amendment) Ordinance 1981 (<ref href="/hk/1981/8">8 of 1981</ref>) (hereinafter called the
                    <b><i>amending
                    Ordinance</i></b>),
            the provisions of <ref>section 4(3)</ref> immediately prior to the date of
            commencement*
            of the amending Ordinance shall continue to apply in relation to judgments registered
            before such date.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1981/8">8 of 1981 s. 3</ref> incorporated)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1548058476679_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 23 January
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></main></ordinance>