<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 339</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>339</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap339!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2018-06-28</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403032746_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2018-06-28">
            <content>To make amendments to the law relating to
                homicide.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[10 May 1963]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2018/er3">E.R. 3 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403032762_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Homicide Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403032762_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Abolition of “constructive malice”</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412017719_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a person kills another in the course or furtherance of some other offence, the killing shall not amount to murder unless done with the same malice aforethought (express or implied) as is required for a killing to amount to murder when not done in the course or furtherance of another offence.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412017719_019" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (1), a killing done in the course or for the purpose of resisting an officer of justice, or of resisting or avoiding or preventing a lawful arrest, or of effecting or assisting an escape or rescue from legal custody, shall be treated as a killing in the course or furtherance of an offence.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1957 c. 11 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403032778_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Persons suffering from diminished responsibility</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412017751_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a person kills or is a party to the killing of another, he shall not be convicted of murder if he was suffering from such abnormality of mind (whether arising from a condition of arrested or retarded development of mind or any inherent causes or induced by disease or injury) as substantially impaired his mental responsibility for his acts and omissions in doing or being a party to the killing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412017751_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On a charge of murder, it shall be for the defence to prove that the person charged is by virtue of this section not liable to be convicted of murder.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412017751_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who but for this section would be liable, whether as principal or as accessory, to be convicted of murder shall be liable instead to be convicted of manslaughter.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412017766_005" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The fact that one party to a killing is by virtue of this section not liable to be convicted of murder shall not affect the question whether the killing amounted to murder in the case of any other party to it.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1957 c. 11 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403032793_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Provocation</heading><content>Where on a charge of murder there is evidence on which the jury can find that the person charged was provoked (whether by things done or by things said or by both together) to lose his self-control, the question whether the provocation was enough to make a reasonable man do as he did shall be left to be determined by the jury; and in determining that question the jury shall take into account everything both done and said according to the effect which, in their opinion, it would have on a reasonable man.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1957 c. 11 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403032793_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Suicide pacts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412017797_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It shall be manslaughter, and shall not be murder, for a person acting in pursuance of a suicide pact between him and another to kill the other or be a party to the other being killed by a third person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412017797_026" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where it is shown that a person charged with the murder of another killed the
                other or was a party to his being killed, it shall be for the defence to prove that
                the person charged was acting in pursuance of a suicide pact between him and the
                other.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412017813_005" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="SuicidePact">For the purposes of this section,
                    <term>suicide
                    pact</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">自殺協定</term>) means a common agreement between two
                or more persons having for its object the death of all of them, whether or not each
                is to take his own life, but nothing done by a person who enters into a suicide pact
                shall be treated as done by him in pursuance of the pact unless it is done while he
                has the settled intention of dying in pursuance of the pact.</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2008/10">10 of 2008 s. 14</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1957 c. 11 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403032809_001" name="s6" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/24">24 of 1993 s. 23</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403032809_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2018-06-28" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Past offences</heading><content>The provisions of this Ordinance shall not have effect in relation to any offence
            in respect of which an indictment has been signed before the
                commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance but, subject
            thereto, such provisions shall have effect in relation to offences committed wholly or
            partly before the
                commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance in like
            manner as they apply to offences committed thereafter.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1957 c. 11 s. 16 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1527564485482_001">
            <content>Editorial Note: </content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>Commencement date: 10 May
                1963.</content>
        </editorialNote></section></main></ordinance>