<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 558 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>558A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap558A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2015-01-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403442337_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2015-01-29">International Organizations (Privileges
            and Immunities) (Office of the Commission of the European Communities) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula>(<ref href="/hk/cap558/s3">Cap. 558, section 3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2015/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2015</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[14 November 2003]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2015/er1">E.R. 1 of 2015</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403442337_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2015/er1">E.R. 1 of 2015</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403442353_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order—</leadIn><def name="Commission"><term>Commission</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">委員會</term>) means the Commission of the European Communities;</def><def name="Convention"><term>Convention</term> (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公約</term>》) means the Vienna Convention on Consular Relations done at Vienna on 24 April 1963;</def><def name="EuropeanCommunities"><term>European Communities</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">歐洲共同體</term>) means the European Coal and Steel Community, the European Community and the European Atomic Energy Community;</def><def name="OfficeAgreement"><term>Office Agreement</term> (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">辦事處協議</term>》) means the agreement concluded by exchange of letters in June 1997 between the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Commission concerning the maintenance of the Office of the Commission of the European Communities in Hong Kong from 1 July 1997.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403442369_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Provisions of Office Agreement</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413322766_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The provisions set out in the <ref>Schedule</ref> (being Articles of the Office Agreement) shall have the force of law in Hong Kong and shall for that purpose be construed in accordance with subsections (2) to (4).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413322766_019" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In those Articles—</leadIn><def name="Head"><term>Head</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主任</term>) shall be construed as meaning the person charged with the duty of acting as the Head of the Office;</def><def name="Office"><term>Office</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">辦事處</term>) shall be construed as meaning the Office of the Commission of the European Communities in Hong Kong;</def><def name="PermanentResidentOfTheHongKongSpecialAdministrativeRegion"><term>permanent resident of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">香港特別行政區永久性居民</term>) shall be construed as meaning a person who belongs to a class or description of persons specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Immigration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap115">Cap. 115</ref>).</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413322782_025" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The reference to any other law of the People’s Republic of China in Article 3 of the Office Agreement shall be construed as a reference to any national law of the People’s Republic of China listed in Annex III to the Basic Law and applied in Hong Kong by way of promulgation or legislation in accordance with Article 18 of the Basic Law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413322797_005" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The reference to the members of the Office in Article 4 of the Office Agreement shall be construed as a reference to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413322797_013" name="a" temporalId="s3_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the officers of the Office (including the Head) entrusted in that capacity with the exercise of the functions of the Office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413322797_021" name="b" temporalId="s3_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the persons employed in the administrative or technical service of the Office; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413322797_029" name="c" temporalId="s3_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the persons employed in the domestic service of the Office.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413322797_036" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The reference to the provisions of the Convention in Article 4 of the Office Agreement shall be construed as a reference to <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of Article 15, the Articles in Chapter II and Article 71 of the Convention as set out in the <ref>Schedule</ref> to the Consular Relations Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap557">Cap. 557</ref>).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403442369_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Authorized refund of duties paid on hydrocarbon oils</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413322844_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive may authorize the Commissioner of Customs and Excise to make such arrangements as the Chief Executive thinks fit for securing the refund of duties imposed on hydrocarbon oils under the Dutiable Commodities Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap109">Cap. 109</ref>) where such hydrocarbon oils are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413322844_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>imported into Hong Kong; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413322844_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>used for such purpose that, had they been imported for that use, exemption from customs duty would have been required to be granted under Article 50 of the Convention as set out in the <ref>Schedule</ref> to the Consular Relations Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap557">Cap. 557</ref>) as read with Article 4 of the Office Agreement.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413322860_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any arrangements made under this section may impose conditions subject to which any refund shall be made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413322860_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any amount of money refunded under arrangements made under this section shall be paid from the general revenue.</content></subsection></section><schedule id="ID_1438403442384_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2015-01-29" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap558A/s3">s. 3</ref>]</note><heading class="tied-tag-heading-center ">Provisions of Office Agreement Having the Force of
            Law in Hong
            Kong</heading><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="445">
                <col width="100%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_34">3.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_10"></inline>The
                            European Communities—the European Coal and Steel Community, the European
                            Community and the European Atomic Energy Community—shall each have legal
                            personality in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the
                            People’s Republic of
                            China.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_34">Accordingly,
                            the European Communities shall have the capacity to conclude contracts,
                            to acquire and dispose of immovable and movable property as necessary
                            for the effective fulfillment of their duties, in accordance with the
                            procedural and administrative requirements imposed by the law of the
                            Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of
                            China and by any other law of the People’s Republic of China, and to
                            conduct legal proceedings, and shall be represented for that purpose by
                            the
                            Commission.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_34">4.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_8"></inline>The
                            Office, its Head and members accredited by the Commission of the
                            European Communities who are nationals of the member states of the
                            European Communities but not in their capacity as the permanent
                            residents of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, as well as the
                            members of their families forming part of their respective households,
                            shall enjoy consular privileges and immunities as correspond to those
                            enjoyed by consular posts, Heads and members of consular posts in
                            accordance with the provisions of the Vienna Convention on Consular
                            Relations of 24 April 1963.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_34">They will,
                            consistent with the Basic Law of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                            Region of the People’s Republic of China and the other national laws of
                            China applicable in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region in
                            accordance with the Basic Law, enjoy such rights and consular privileges
                            and immunities as are necessary for the effective fulfillment of their
                            duties.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_34">5.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_10"></inline>The
                            laissez-passer issued by the European Communities to officials and other
                            servants of its institutions shall be recognized as a valid travel
                            document.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>