<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 312</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>312</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap312!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2013-04-25</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438402972078_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2013-04-25">
            <content>To control the emission of noise by aircraft and for matters ancillary thereto
                or connected therewith.</content>
            <content>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 May 1987]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1987/ln112">L.N. 112 of 1987</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438402972078_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Civil Aviation (Aircraft Noise) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438402972093_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882030_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Aerodrome"><term>aerodrome</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機坪</term>) means any area of land or water designed, equipped, set apart or commonly used for affording facilities for the landing and taking off of aircraft and includes any area or space, whether on the ground, on the roof of a building or elsewhere which is designed, equipped or set apart for affording facilities for the landing and taking off of aircraft capable of descending or climbing vertically and includes an aerodrome the management of which is vested in the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region or in the Chief Executive;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="AirTrafficManager"><leadIn><term>air traffic manager</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">航空交通經理</term>) means the person who for the time being—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882046_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>manages the air traffic of an aerodrome; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882046_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is responsible for giving permission or refusing to give permission for an aircraft to land or take off at the aerodrome,</content></paragraph><continued>	and, except in <ref>section 6(5)</ref>, includes a public officer who for the time being so manages or is so responsible;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></def><def name="AirportManager"><term>airport manager</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機場經理</term>) means the person who for the time being manages an aerodrome and, except in <ref>section 7(2)</ref> and (3), includes a public officer who for the time being so manages;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TheAnnex"><term>the Annex</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附件</term>) means Annex 16 to the Chicago Convention in so far as it relates to international standards and recommended practices for aircraft noise, any provision of the Chicago Convention for giving effect to Annex 16 and any amendment to Annex 16 made in accordance with the Chicago Convention in so far as it relates to such standards and practices;</def><def name="CertificateOfAirworthiness"><term>certificate of airworthiness</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">適航證明書</term>) includes any validation thereof and any flight manual, performance schedule or other document, whatever its title, incorporated by reference in that certificate relating to the certificate of airworthiness;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Chapter2StandardsOfNoise"><term>Chapter 2 standards of noise</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第2章噪音標準</term>)
                means the standards of noise specified in Volume I, Part II, Chapter 2 of the
                    Annex;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Chapter3StandardsOfNoise"><term>Chapter 3 standards of noise</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第3章噪音標準</term>)
                means the standards of noise specified in Volume I, Part II, Chapter 3 of the
                    Annex;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TheChicagoConvention"><term>the Chicago Convention</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">芝加哥公約</term>) means the Convention on International Civil Aviation which, on 7 December 1944, was opened for signature at the International Civil Aviation Conference held at Chicago;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ContractingState"><term>contracting State</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">締約國家</term>) means a State which is a party to the Chicago Convention;</def><def name="Director"><term>Director</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">處長</term>) means the Director-General of Civil Aviation;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/ln326">L.N. 326 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="MaximumTotalWeightAuthorized"><term>maximum total weight authorized</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">核准最高總重量</term>), in relation to an aircraft, means the maximum total weight of the aircraft and its contents at which the aircraft may take off anywhere in the world, in the most favourable circumstances in accordance with the certificate of airworthiness in force in respect of the aircraft;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="NarrowbodiedAircraft"><term>narrow-bodied aircraft</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">狹體飛機</term>) means an aircraft other than a wide-bodied aircraft;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="NoiseCertificate"><term>noise certificate</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">噪音標準合格證明書</term>) means a certificate of compliance, by the aircraft to which it relates, with the relevant standards of noise;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Operator"><term>operator</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經營人</term>), in relation to an aircraft, means the person having the management of the aircraft for the time being, or in relation to a time, at that time;</def><def name="Owner"><term>owner</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機主</term>), in relation to an aircraft, means the person in whose name the aircraft is registered in its place of registration;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="RelevantStandardsOfNoise"><term>relevant standards of noise</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關噪音標準</term>), in relation to an aircraft, means the standards of noise specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> and applicable to such an aircraft or standards of noise which are equivalent to, or more restrictive than, such standards;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ScheduledJourney"><term>scheduled journey</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">編定航程</term>) means one of a series of journeys which are undertaken between the same two places and which amount to a systematic service operated in such a manner that the benefits thereof are available to members of the public from time to time seeking advantage of them;</def><def name="WidebodiedAircraft"><term>wide-bodied aircraft</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">廣體飛機</term>) means an aircraft which has a maximum total weight authorized
                greater than 100
                000 kg and a maximum cabin width greater than 4.5 m.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994
                        s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882077_032" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any function vested in the Director by this Ordinance may be performed by the Deputy Director-General of Civil Aviation or by any public officer authorized by the Director or by the Deputy Director-General of Civil Aviation.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/ln326">L.N. 326 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402972109_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Prohibition on landing or taking off without a noise certificate</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882124_053" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to this Ordinance and the regulations, as from a day to be notified by the Chief Executive by notice in the Gazette an aircraft shall not land or take off in Hong Kong unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882139_005" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>there is in force in respect of that aircraft a noise certificate issued by—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411882139_013" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the Director; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411882139_021" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a contracting State; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882139_028" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>there is other documentary proof of compliance by the aircraft with the relevant standards of noise.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882139_035" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive may, in the exercise of his powers under subsection (1), specify different days for different classes of aircraft.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882139_043" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Chief Executive may by notice in the Gazette amend the <ref>Schedule</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402972125_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Exemptions</heading><leadIn>The Director may by notice in writing to the operator of any aircraft permit the aircraft to land or take off in Hong Kong in circumstances not permitted by <ref>section 3(1)</ref>:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_proviso">Provided that nothing in this section shall apply to an aircraft which lands or takes off when carrying passengers, mail or cargo for hire or reward upon a scheduled journey.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438402972125_004" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Requirements as to landing and take off</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882186_025" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may, by notice in the Gazette, provide that it shall be the duty of the operator of an aircraft which is to take off or land at an aerodrome designated in the notice to secure that, after the aircraft takes off or, as the case may be, before it lands at the aerodrome, such requirements as are specified in the notice are complied with in relation to the aircraft, being requirements appearing to the Director to be appropriate for the purpose of limiting or of mitigating the effect of noise and vibration connected with the taking off or landing of aircraft at the aerodrome.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882202_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>If it appears to the Director that any requirement specified in relation to an aerodrome in
                                                  a notice published in pursuance of subsection (1)
                                                  has not been complied with in respect of any
                                                  aircraft he may, after affording to the operator
                                                  of the aircraft an opportunity of making
                                                  representations to him with respect to the matter
                                                  and after considering any representations then
                                                  made by this operator, give either to the airport
                                                  manager or to the air traffic manager a direction
                                                  requiring him to secure that, until the Director
                                                  revokes the direction, facilities for using the
                                                  aerodrome are withheld to the extent specified in
                                                  the direction from aircraft of which the person
                                                  aforesaid is the operator and from his servants;
                                                  and it shall be
                                                  the
                                                  duty of the person to whom the
                                                  direction is given to comply with the direction:
                                                  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of
                                                  1994 s.
                                                  4</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_2_proviso"> Provided that nothing in this subsection shall
                    require the person to whom the direction is given to prevent an aircraft from
                    landing at the
                    aerodrome.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882217_011" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any notice published in pursuance of subsection (1) may contain such incidental or supplementary provisions as the Director considers appropriate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882217_019" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any operator of an aircraft who fails without reasonable excuse to comply with any requirement of a notice under subsection (1) commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402972140_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Restrictions on landing and
            taking
            off</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882233_055" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If the Director considers it appropriate, for the purpose of avoiding, limiting
                or mitigating the effect of noise and vibration connected with the taking off or
                landing of aircraft at an aerodrome, to prohibit aircraft from taking off or
                landing, or to limit the number of occasions on which they may take off or land, at
                an aerodrome during certain periods, he may by notice in the Gazette—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882249_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>prohibit aircraft of descriptions specified in the notice from taking off
                    or landing at the aerodrome (otherwise than in an emergency) during periods so
                    specified;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882249_013" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>specify the maximum number of occasions on which aircraft of descriptions
                    so specified may be permitted to take off or land at the aerodrome (otherwise
                    than in an emergency) during periods so specified; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882249_021" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>determine the persons who shall be entitled to arrange for aircraft of
                    which they are the operators to take off or land at the aerodrome during the
                    periods specified under
                    paragraph
                    (b) and, in respect of each of those persons, the number of occasions on which
                    aircraft of a particular description of which he is the operator may take off or
                    land at the aerodrome during those periods.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882249_036" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref> and (b) it shall be the duty of the air
                traffic manager to secure that the prohibitions or restrictions relating to the
                aerodrome which are imposed by notice under subsection (1) are complied
                with.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882264_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The following supplementary provisions shall have effect for the purposes of
                subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882264_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>nothing in that subsection shall require an air traffic manager to prevent
                    an aircraft from landing at the aerodrome;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882264_021" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Director may, by notice in writing to the air traffic manager to which
                    a notice under that subsection relates, determine that a particular occasion or
                    series of occasions on which aircraft take off or land at the aerodrome shall be
                    disregarded for the purposes of the notice under that subsection; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882264_029" name="c" temporalId="s6_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any notice published in pursuance of that subsection may contain such
                    exceptions and such incidental or supplementary provisions as the Director
                    considers appropriate.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882264_036" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any owner or operator of an aircraft who fails without reasonable excuse to
                comply with any prohibition or restriction imposed by a notice under subsection (1)
                commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882280_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Subject to subsection (3), an air traffic manager who fails without reasonable
                excuse to secure the compliance referred to in subsection (2) commits an offence and
                is liable on conviction to a fine at level 5.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s.
                    5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 5</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402972156_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Directions to managers of airports</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882311_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may give to an airport manager such directions as he considers appropriate for the purpose of avoiding, limiting or mitigating the effect of noise and vibration connected with the taking off or landing of aircraft at the aerodrome; and it shall be the duty of the airport manager to comply with the directions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882327_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Director may, after consultation with an airport manager, by notice in writing require him at his own expense—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882327_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to provide in an area and within a period specified in the notice, and to maintain and operate in accordance with any instructions so specified, such equipment for measuring noise in the vicinity of the aerodrome as is so specified; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882327_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to make to the Director such reports as are so specified with respect to the noise measured by the equipment and to permit any person authorized by the Director for the purpose to inspect the equipment on demand at any time,</content></paragraph><continued>	and it shall be the duty of the airport manager to comply with the requirements of the notice.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882327_034" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If an airport manager fails to perform any requirement or duty imposed on him by notice under subsection (2) the Director may, after affording him an opportunity of making representations to the Director with respect to the matter and after considering any representations then made by him—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882342_005" name="a" temporalId="s7_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>take such steps as the Director considers appropriate for remedying the failure, which may include steps to secure the provision, maintenance and operation of equipment by the Director; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882342_013" name="b" temporalId="s7_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>recover in any court of competent jurisdiction from the airport manager any reasonable expense attributable to the taking of those steps which is incurred by the Director from time to time,</content></paragraph><continued>	and if an airport manager fails without reasonable excuse to perform any duty imposed on him by a notice under subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref>, then without prejudice to the preceding provisions of this subsection he—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438411882342_027" name="i" temporalId="s7_3_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>commits an offence and is liable on conviction to a fine at level 4; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882342_035" name="ii" temporalId="s7_3_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the failure continues after his conviction of an offence under this subsection arising from the failure, is liable to a daily penalty of $10,000.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 6</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402972171_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Enforcement of prohibitions as to take off</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882373_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If it appears to the Director that an aircraft is about to take off in
                contravention of any prohibition or restriction imposed in pursuance of this
                Ordinance, then, without prejudice to any powers exercisable by virtue of this
                Ordinance by the airport manager or air traffic manager, any person authorized by
                the Director for the purpose may detain the aircraft for such period as that person
                considers appropriate for preventing the contravention and may, for the purpose of
                detaining the aircraft, enter upon any land.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882389_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If it appears to a person authorized for the purpose by the airport manager
                that an aircraft is about to take off in contravention of any prohibition or
                restriction imposed in pursuance of this Ordinance, then without prejudice to any
                other provision of this Ordinance, the person so authorized may detain the aircraft
                for such period as he considers appropriate for preventing the contravention and
                may, for the purpose of detaining the aircraft, enter upon any land.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s.
            7</ref>)<marker role="section-break"></marker></sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402972187_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Power to make regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882420_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882420_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for carrying out the Annex;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882420_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>specifying the circumstances in which a noise certificate may be granted and the conditions which may be imposed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882420_028" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>as to the manner and conditions of the issue, validation, renewal, extension of any certificate or other document required by this Ordinance or the regulations (including any examinations and tests to be undergone), and as to the form, custody, production, cancellation, suspension, endorsement and surrender of any such document;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882436_006" name="d" temporalId="s9_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>for specifying the fees to be paid in respect of the issue, validation, renewal, extension or variation of any certificate or other document or the undergoing of any examination or test required by the regulations and in respect of any other matters in respect of which it appears to the Chief Executive in Council to be expedient for the purposes of the regulations to charge fees;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882436_014" name="e" temporalId="s9_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>for exempting from the provisions of this Ordinance or the regulations, either absolutely or conditionally, any aircraft or class of aircraft;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882436_022" name="f" temporalId="s9_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>generally for restricting or mitigating aircraft noise and vibration;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882436_030" name="g" temporalId="s9_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>authorizing the taking of such steps as may be necessary or expedient for the better enforcement of the Ordinance including, without derogation from the generality of the foregoing, power to enter upon or detain any aircraft;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882451_005" name="h" temporalId="s9_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>prescribing the manner in which any notice under this Ordinance may be given; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882451_013" name="i" temporalId="s9_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>for any matter required or permitted by this Ordinance to be prescribed.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882451_020" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The regulations may make different provision with respect to different classes of aircraft and for different aerodromes or classes of aerodrome.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882451_028" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The regulations may provide that a contravention of specified provisions shall be an offence and may prescribe penalties therefor not exceeding a fine at level 6 and imprisonment for 2 years and, in the case of a continuing offence, to a further fine not exceeding $20,000 for each day during which the offence continues.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882451_036" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The regulations may be expressed so as to apply to aircraft in the service of the State and, if so expressed, they shall so apply.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882451_044" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>The regulations may provide that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411882451_052" name="a" temporalId="s9_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any certificate or other document required by this Ordinance or the regulations shall be in such form as is for the time being approved of by the Director; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411882467_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any <ref>Schedule</ref> to the regulations may be amended by the Director by notice in the Gazette.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1994/68">68 of 1994 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2013/er1">E.R. 1 of 2013</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438402972218_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Nuisance caused by aircraft and aircraft engines on aerodromes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411882576_008" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The regulations may regulate the conditions under which noise and vibration may be caused by aircraft or aircraft engines on aerodromes and may provide that subsection (2) shall apply to any aerodrome in respect of which provision as to noise and vibration caused by aircraft is so made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411882592_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No action shall lie in respect of nuisance by reason only of the noise and vibration caused by aircraft or aircraft engines on an aerodrome to which this subsection applies by virtue of the regulations, as long as the provisions of any such regulations are duly complied with.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438402972234_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Exemption of military aircraft</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall apply to military aircraft.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438402972249_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-04-25" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap312/s2">ss.
                2</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap312/s3">3</ref>]</note><heading class="tied-tag-heading-center">Standards of Noise to be Complied with by
            Aircraft<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                
                <col width="10.455%"></col>
                
                <col width="48%"></col>
                
                <col width="6.97%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="34.575%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_left">Item</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Aircraft</center>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td>
                        <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Standards of
                            noise </center>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_left">1.</p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="align_justified">
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">All subsonic jet aircraft
                            <sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2002/ln60">L.N. 60 of 2002</ref>)</sourceNote></p>
                    </td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    
                    <td class="align_justified">
                        
                        <p class="align_justified">Chapter 3 standards of noise</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_left">2.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="align_left">(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2002/ln60">L.N. 60 of
                        2002</ref>)</sourceNote></td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                    
                    <td></td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </text><sourceNote class="align_right">(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1995/ln539">L.N. 539 of
            1995</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>