<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 329</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>329</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap329!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403004666_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-04-14">
            <content>To codify the law relating to marine
                insurance.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[9 June 1961]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403004666_003" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Marine Insurance Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Marine
        Insurance</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403004682_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Marine insurance defined</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944165_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A contract of marine insurance is a contract whereby the insurer undertakes to
                indemnify the assured, in manner and to the extent thereby agreed, against marine
                losses, that is to say, the losses incident to marine adventure.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944165_019" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A contract of marine insurance may, by its express terms, or by usage of trade,
                be extended so as to protect the assured against losses on inland waters or on any
                land risk which may be incidental to any sea voyage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944165_027" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a ship in course of building, or the launch of a ship, or any adventure
                analogous to a marine adventure, is covered by a policy in the form of a marine
                policy, the provisions of this Ordinance, in so far as applicable, shall apply
                thereto; but, except as by this section provided, nothing in this Ordinance shall
                alter or affect any rule of law applicable to any contract of insurance other than a
                contract of marine insurance as by this Ordinance defined.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 ss. 1 &amp; 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403004775_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Marine adventure and maritime perils defined</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944196_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, every lawful marine adventure may be the subject of a contract of marine insurance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944196_019" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In particular there is a marine adventure where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411944196_027" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any ship goods or other movables are exposed to maritime peril. Such
                    property is in this Ordinance referred to as
                            <b><i>insurable
                            property</i></b>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944196_035" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the earning or acquisition of any freight, passage money, commission, profit, or other pecuniary benefit, or the security for any advances, loan, or disbursements, is endangered by the exposure of insurable property to maritime perils;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944196_043" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any liability to a third party may be incurred by the owner of, or other person interested in or responsible for, insurable property, by reason of maritime perils.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944212_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="MaritimePerils">For the purposes of this Ordinance,
                    <term>maritime
                    perils</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">海上危險</term>) means the perils consequent on, or
                incidental to, the navigation of the sea, that is to say, perils of the seas, fire,
                war perils, pirates, rovers, thieves, captures, seizures, restraints, and
                detainments of princes and peoples, jettisons, barratry, and any other perils,
                either of the like kind or which may be designated by the policy.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Insurable
        Interest</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403004807_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Avoidance of wagering or gaming contracts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944228_057" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every contract of marine insurance by way of gaming or wagering is
                void.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944228_065" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A contract of marine insurance is deemed to be a gaming or wagering
                contract—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411944243_005" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the assured has not an insurable interest as defined by this
                    Ordinance, and the contract is entered into with no expectation of acquiring
                    such an interest; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944243_013" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>where the policy is made “interest or no interest”, or “without further
                        proof of interest than the policy itself”, or “without benefit of salvage to
                        the insurer”, or subject to any other like term:</leadIn>
                    <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_2_b_proviso">Provided that, where there
                        is no possibility of salvage, a policy may be effected without benefit of
                        salvage to the insurer.</proviso>
                </content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403004822_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Insurable interest defined</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944259_018" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, every person has an insurable interest who is interested in a marine adventure.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944259_026" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In particular a person is interested in a marine adventure where he stands in any legal or equitable relation to the adventure or to any insurable property at risk therein, in consequence of which he may benefit by the safety or due arrival of insurable property, or may be prejudiced by its loss, or by damage thereto, or by the detention thereof, or may incur liability in respect thereof.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403004900_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>When interest must attach</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944290_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>The assured must be interested in the subject-matter insured at the time of the loss though he need not be interested when the insurance is effected:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_1_proviso">Provided that where the subject-matter is insured “lost or not lost”, the assured may recover although he may not have acquired his interest until after the loss, unless at the time of effecting the contract of insurance the assured was aware of the loss, and the insurer was not.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944290_018" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the assured has no interest at the time of the loss, he cannot acquire interest by any act or election after he is aware of the loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403004916_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Defeasible or contingent interest</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944321_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A defeasible interest is insurable, as also is a contingent interest.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944321_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In particular, where the buyer of goods has insured them, he has an insurable interest, notwithstanding that he might, at his election, have rejected the goods, or have treated them as at the seller’s risk, by reason of the latter’s delay in making delivery or otherwise.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 7 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403004916_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Partial interest</heading><content>A partial interest of any nature is insurable.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403004931_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Re-insurance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944352_018" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The insurer under a contract of marine insurance has an insurable interest in his risk, and may re-insure in respect of it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944352_026" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Unless the policy otherwise provides, the original assured has no right or interest in respect of such re-insurance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403004931_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Bottomry</heading><content>The lender of money on bottomry or respondentia has an insurable interest in respect of the loan.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403004947_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Master’s and seamen’s wages</heading><content>The master or any member of the crew of a ship has an insurable interest in respect of his wages.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 11 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403004963_001" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Advance freight</heading><content>In the case of advance freight, the person advancing the freight has an insurable interest, in so far as such freight is not repayable in case of loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 12 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403004963_003" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Charges of insurance</heading><content>The assured has an insurable interest in the charges of any insurance which he may effect.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 13 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403004978_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Quantum of interest</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944415_018" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the subject-matter insured is mortgaged, the mortgagor has an insurable interest in the full value thereof, and the mortgagee has an insurable interest in respect of any sum due or to become due under the mortgage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944415_026" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A mortgagee, consignee, or other person having an interest in the subject-matter insured may insure on behalf and for the benefit of other persons interested as well as for his own benefit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944415_034" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The owner of insurable property has an insurable interest in respect of the full value thereof, notwithstanding that some third person may have agreed, or be liable, to indemnify him in case of loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 14 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403004978_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Assignment of interest</heading><content>Where the assured assigns or otherwise parts with his interest in the subject-matter
            insured, he does not thereby transfer to the assignee his rights under the contract of
            insurance, unless there be an express or implied agreement with the assignee to that
                effect.<proviso>But
                the provisions of this section do not affect a transmission of interest by operation
                of law.</proviso></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 15 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Insurable
        Value</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403004994_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Measure of insurable value</heading><leadIn>Subject to any express provision or valuation in the policy, the insurable value of
            the subject-matter insured must be ascertained as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411944462_019" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in insurance on ship, the insurable value is the value, at the commencement of
                the risk, of the ship, including her outfit, provisions and stores for the officers
                and crew, money advanced for seamen’s wages, and other disbursements (if any)
                incurred to make the ship fit for the voyage or adventure contemplated by the
                policy, plus the charges of insurance upon the whole:</content><content>The insurable value, in the case of a steamship, includes also the machinery,
                boilers, and coals and engine stores if owned by the assured, and, in the case of a
                ship engaged in a special trade, the ordinary fittings requisite for that
                trade;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944462_033" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in insurance on freight, whether paid in advance or otherwise, the insurable
                value is the gross amount of the freight at the risk of the assured, plus the
                charges of insurance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944462_041" name="c" temporalId="s16_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in insurance on goods or merchandise, the insurable value is the prime cost of
                the property insured, plus the expenses of and incidental to shipping and the
                charges of insurance upon the whole;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944477_006" name="d" temporalId="s16_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in insurance on any other subject-matter, the insurable value is the amount at
                the risk of the assured when the policy attaches, plus the charges of
                insurance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 16 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Disclosure
        and Representations</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403004994_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Insurance is
            uberrimœ
            fidei</heading><content>A contract of marine insurance is a contract based upon the utmost good faith, and,
            if the utmost good faith be not observed by either party, the contract may be avoided by
            the other party.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 17 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005009_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Disclosure by assured</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944508_025" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this section, the assured must disclose to the insurer, before the contract is concluded, every material circumstance which is known to the assured, and the assured is deemed to know every circumstance which, in the ordinary course of business, ought to be known by him. If the assured fails to make such disclosure, the insurer may avoid the contract.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944524_005" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every circumstance is material which would influence the judgment of a prudent insurer in fixing the premium, or determining whether he will take the risk.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944524_013" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In the absence of inquiry the following circumstances need not be disclosed, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411944524_021" name="a" temporalId="s18_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any circumstance which diminishes the risk;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944524_029" name="b" temporalId="s18_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any circumstance which is known or presumed to be known to the insurer. The insurer is presumed to know matters of common notoriety or knowledge, and matters which an insurer in the ordinary course of his business, as such, ought to know;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944524_037" name="c" temporalId="s18_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any circumstance as to which information is waived by the insurer;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944524_045" name="d" temporalId="s18_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any circumstance which it is superfluous to disclose by reason of any express or implied warranty.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944524_052" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Whether any particular circumstance, which is not disclosed, be material or not is, in each case, a question of fact.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944524_060" name="5" temporalId="s18_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="Circumstance">The term
                    <term>circumstance</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">情況</term>) includes any communication made to, or
                information received by, the assured.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 18 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005025_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Disclosure by agent effecting insurance</heading><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 18</ref> as to circumstances which need not be disclosed, where an insurance is effected for the assured by an agent, the agent must disclose to the insurer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411944555_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>every material circumstance which is known to himself and an agent to insure is deemed to know every circumstance which in the ordinary course of business ought to be known by, or to have been communicated to, him; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944555_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>every material circumstance which the assured is bound to disclose, unless it comes to his knowledge too late to communicate it to the agent.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 19 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403005025_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Representations pending negotiation of contract</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944571_033" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every material representation made by the assured or his agent to the insurer during the negotiations for the contract, and before the contract is concluded, must be true. If it be untrue the insurer may avoid the contract.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944586_005" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A representation is material which would influence the judgment of a prudent insurer in fixing the premium, or determining whether he will take the risk.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944586_013" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A representation may be either a representation as to a matter of fact, or as to a matter of expectation or belief.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944586_021" name="4" temporalId="s20_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A representation as to a matter of fact is true, if it be substantially correct, that is to say, if the difference between what is represented and what is actually correct would not be considered material by a prudent insurer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944586_029" name="5" temporalId="s20_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A representation as to a matter of expectation or belief is true if it be made in good faith.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944586_037" name="6" temporalId="s20_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A representation may be withdrawn or corrected before the contract is concluded.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944586_045" name="7" temporalId="s20_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Whether a particular representation be material or not is, in each case, a question of fact.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 20 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005041_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>When contract is deemed to be concluded</heading><content>A contract of marine insurance is deemed to be concluded when the proposal of the assured is accepted by the insurer, whether the policy be then issued or not; and, for the purpose of showing when the proposal was accepted, reference may be made to the slip or covering note or other customary memorandum of the contract.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 21 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">The
        Policy</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005041_004" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Contract must be embodied in policy</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of any Ordinance, a contract of marine insurance is
            inadmissible in evidence unless it is embodied in a marine policy in accordance with
            this Ordinance. The policy may be executed and issued either at the time when the
            contract is concluded, or afterwards.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 22 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005056_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>What policy must specify</heading><content>A marine policy must specify the name of the assured, or of some person who effects the insurance on his behalf.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 23 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005072_001" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Signature of insurer</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944649_018" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A marine policy must be signed by or on behalf of the insurer, provided that in the case of a corporation the corporate seal may be sufficient, but nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring the subscription of a corporation to be under seal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944649_026" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a policy is subscribed by or on behalf of two or more insurers, each subscription, unless the contrary be expressed, constitutes a distinct contract with the assured.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 24 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005072_003" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Voyages and time policies</heading><content>Where the contract is to insure the subject-matter “at and from”, or from one place to another or others, the policy is called a “voyage policy”, and where the contract is to insure the subject-matter for a definite period of time the policy is called a “time policy”. A contract for both voyage and time may be included in the same policy.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 25 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005087_002" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Designation of subject-matter</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944680_025" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The subject-matter insured must be designated in a marine policy with reasonable certainty.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944696_005" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The nature and extent of the interest of the assured in the subject-matter insured need not be specified in the policy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944696_013" name="3" temporalId="s26_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the policy designates the subject-matter insured in general terms, it shall be construed to apply to the interest intended by the assured to be covered.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944696_021" name="4" temporalId="s26_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In the application of this section regard shall be had to any usage regulating the designation of the subject-matter insured.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 26 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005087_004" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Valued policy</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944727_004" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A policy may be either valued or unvalued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944727_012" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A valued policy is a policy which specifies the agreed value of the subject-matter insured.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944727_020" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, and in the absence of fraud, the value fixed by the policy is, as between the insurer and assured, conclusive of the insurable value of the subject intended to be insured, whether the loss be total or partial.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944727_028" name="4" temporalId="s27_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Unless the policy otherwise provides, the value fixed by the policy is not conclusive for the purpose of determining whether there has been a constructive total loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 27 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005103_002" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Unvalued policy</heading><content>An unvalued policy is a policy which does not specify the value of the subject-matter insured, but subject to the limit of the sum insured, leaves the insurable value to be subsequently ascertained, in the manner hereinbefore specified.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 28 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005119_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Floating policy by ship or ships</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944758_032" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A floating policy is a policy which describes the insurance in general terms, and leaves the name of the ship or ships and other particulars to be defined by subsequent declaration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944774_005" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The subsequent declaration or declarations may be made by endorsement on the policy, or in other customary manner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944774_013" name="3" temporalId="s29_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Unless the policy otherwise provides, the declarations must be made in the order of dispatch or shipment. They must, in the case of goods, comprise all consignments within the terms of the policy, and the value of the goods or other property must be honestly stated, but an omission or erroneous declaration may be rectified even after loss or arrival, provided the omission or declaration was made in good faith.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944774_021" name="4" temporalId="s29_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Unless the policy otherwise provides, where a declaration of value is not made
                until after notice of loss or arrival, the policy must be treated as an unvalued
                policy as regards the
                subject-matter
                of that declaration.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 29 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005119_003" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Construction of terms in policy</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944805_004" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A policy may be in the form in the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944805_012" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, and unless the context of the policy otherwise requires, the terms and expressions mentioned in the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall be construed as having the scope and meaning in that schedule assigned to them.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 30 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005134_001" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Premium to be arranged</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944820_019" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an insurance is effected at a premium to be arranged, and no arrangement is made, a reasonable premium is payable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944820_027" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an insurance is effected on the terms that an additional premium is to be arranged in a given event, and that event happens but no arrangement is made, then a reasonable additional premium is payable.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 31 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Double
        Insurance</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005134_003" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Double insurance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944836_033" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where two or more policies are effected by or on behalf of the assured on the
                same adventure and interest or any part thereof, and the sums insured exceed the
                indemnity allowed by this Ordinance, the assured is said to be over-insured by
                double insurance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944852_005" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where the assured is over-insured by double insurance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411944852_013" name="a" temporalId="s32_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the assured, unless the policy otherwise provides, may claim payment from
                    the insurers in such order as he may think fit, provided that he is not entitled
                    to receive any sum in excess of the indemnity allowed by this
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944852_021" name="b" temporalId="s32_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the policy under which the assured claims is a valued policy, the
                    assured must give credit as against the valuation for any sum received by him
                    under any other policy without regard to the actual value of the subject-matter
                    insured;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944852_029" name="c" temporalId="s32_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the policy under which the assured claims is an unvalued policy he
                    must give credit, as against the full insurable value, for any sum received by
                    him under any other policy;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411944852_037" name="d" temporalId="s32_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>where the assured receives any sum in excess of the indemnity allowed by
                    this Ordinance, he is deemed to hold such sum in trust for the insurers,
                    according to their right of contribution among themselves.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 32 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Warranties,
        etc.</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005150_002" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Nature of warranty</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944883_011" name="1" temporalId="s33_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A warranty, in the following sections relating to warranties, means a
                promissory warranty, that is to say, a warranty by which the assured undertakes that
                some particular thing shall or shall not
                be
                done, or that some condition shall be fulfilled, or whereby he affirms or negatives
                the existence of a particular state of facts.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944883_019" name="2" temporalId="s33_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A warranty may be express or implied.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944883_027" name="3" temporalId="s33_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A warranty, as above defined, is a condition which must be exactly complied
                with, whether it be material to the risk or not. If it be not so complied with,
                then, subject to any express provision in the policy, the insurer is discharged from
                liability as from the date of the breach of warranty, but without prejudice to any
                liability incurred by him before that date.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 33 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005197_001" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>When breach of warranty excused</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944914_004" name="1" temporalId="s34_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Non-compliance with a warranty is excused when, by reason of a change of circumstances, the warranty ceases to be applicable to the circumstances of the contract, or when compliance with the warranty is rendered unlawful by any subsequent law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944914_012" name="2" temporalId="s34_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a warranty is broken, the assured cannot avail himself of the defence that the breach has been remedied, and the warranty complied with, before loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944914_020" name="3" temporalId="s34_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A breach of warranty may be waived by the insurer.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 34 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005197_003" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Express warranties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944930_034" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An express warranty may be in any form of words from which the intention to warrant is to be inferred.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944930_042" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An express warranty must be included in, or written upon, the policy, or must be contained in some document incorporated by reference into the policy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944945_005" name="3" temporalId="s35_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An express warranty does not exclude an implied warranty, unless it be inconsistent therewith.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 35 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005259_001" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Warranty of neutrality</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411944961_004" name="1" temporalId="s36_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where insurable property, whether ship or goods, is expressly warranted neutral, there is an implied condition that the property shall have a neutral character at the commencement of the risk, and that, so far as the assured can control the matter, its neutral character shall be preserved during the risk.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411944961_012" name="2" temporalId="s36_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a ship is expressly warranted “neutral” there is also an implied condition that, so far as the assured can control the matter, she shall be properly documented, that is to say, that she shall carry the necessary papers to establish her neutrality, and that she shall not falsify or suppress her papers, or use simulated papers. If any loss occurs through breach of this condition, the insurer may avoid the contract.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 36 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005290_002" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>No implied warranty of nationality</heading><content>There is no implied warranty as to the nationality of a ship, or that her nationality shall not be changed during the risk.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 37 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005337_001" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Warranty of good safety</heading><content>Where the subject-matter insured is warranted “well” or “in good safety” on a particular day, it is sufficient if it be safe at any time during that day.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 38 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005509_002" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Warranty of seaworthiness of ship</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945023_004" name="1" temporalId="s39_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In a voyage policy there is an implied warranty that at the commencement of the voyage the ship shall be seaworthy for the purpose of the particular adventure insured.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945023_012" name="2" temporalId="s39_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the policy attaches while the ship is in port, there is also an implied warranty that she shall, at the commencement of the risk, be reasonably fit to encounter the ordinary perils of the port.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945023_020" name="3" temporalId="s39_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the policy relates to a voyage which is performed in different stages, during which the ship requires different kinds of or further preparation or equipment, there is an implied warranty that at the commencement of each stage the ship is seaworthy in respect of such preparation or equipment for the purposes of that stage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945023_028" name="4" temporalId="s39_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A ship is deemed to be seaworthy when she is reasonably fit in all respects to encounter the ordinary perils of the seas of the adventure insured.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945039_005" name="5" temporalId="s39_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In a time policy there is no implied warranty that the ship shall be seaworthy at any stage of the adventure, but where, with the privity of the assured the ship is sent to sea in an unseaworthy state, the insurer is not liable for any loss attributable to unseaworthiness.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 39 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005524_002" name="s40" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s40"><num value="40">40.</num><heading>No implied warranty that goods are seaworthy</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945054_035" name="1" temporalId="s40_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In a policy on goods or other movables there is no implied warranty that the goods or movables are seaworthy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945054_043" name="2" temporalId="s40_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In a voyage policy on goods or other movables there is an implied warranty that at the commencement of the voyage the ship is not only seaworthy as a ship, but also that she is reasonably fit to carry the goods or other movables to the destination contemplated by the policy.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 40 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005524_004" name="s41" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s41"><num value="41">41.</num><heading>Warranty of legality</heading><content>There is an implied warranty that the adventure insured is a lawful one, and that, so far as the assured can control the matter, the adventure shall be carried out in a lawful manner.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 41 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">The
        Voyage</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005540_002" name="s42" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s42"><num value="42">42.</num><heading>Implied condition as to commencement of risk</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945086_030" name="1" temporalId="s42_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the subject-matter is insured by a voyage policy “at and from” or “from”
                a particular place, it is not necessary that the ship should be at that place when
                the contract is concluded, but there is an implied condition that the adventure
                shall be commenced within a reasonable time, and that if the adventure be not so
                commenced the insurer may avoid the contract.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945101_005" name="2" temporalId="s42_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The implied condition may be negatived by showing that the delay was caused by
                circumstances known to the insurer before the contract was concluded, or by showing
                that he waived the condition.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 42 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005555_001" name="s43" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s43"><num value="43">43.</num><heading>Alteration of port of departure</heading><content>Where the place of departure is specified by the policy, and the ship instead of sailing from that place sails from any other place, the risk does not attach.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 43 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005555_003" name="s44" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s44"><num value="44">44.</num><heading>Sailing for different destination</heading><content>Where the destination is specified in the policy, and the ship, instead of sailing for that destination, sails for any other destination, the risk does not attach.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 44 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005571_002" name="s45" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s45"><num value="45">45.</num><heading>Change of voyage</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945164_004" name="1" temporalId="s45_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where, after the commencement of the risk, the destination of the ship is voluntarily changed from the destination contemplated by the policy, there is said to be a change of voyage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945164_012" name="2" temporalId="s45_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Unless the policy otherwise provides, where there is a change of voyage, the insurer is discharged from liability as from the time of change, that is to say, as from the time when the determination to change it is manifested; and it is immaterial that the ship may not in fact have left the course of voyage contemplated by the policy when the loss occurs.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 45 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005571_004" name="s46" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s46"><num value="46">46.</num><heading>Deviation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945179_026" name="1" temporalId="s46_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a ship, without lawful excuse, deviates from the voyage contemplated by the policy, the insurer is discharged from liability as from the time of deviation, and it is immaterial that the ship may have regained her route before any loss occurs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945179_034" name="2" temporalId="s46_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>There is a deviation from the voyage contemplated by the policy—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411945179_042" name="a" temporalId="s46_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the course of the voyage is specifically designated by the policy, and that course is departed from; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945195_006" name="b" temporalId="s46_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the course of the voyage is not specifically designated by the policy, but the usual and customary course is departed from.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945195_013" name="3" temporalId="s46_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The intention to deviate is immaterial; there must be a deviation in fact to discharge the insurer from his liability under the contract.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 46 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005587_002" name="s47" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s47"><num value="47">47.</num><heading>Several ports of discharge</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945210_008" name="1" temporalId="s47_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where several ports of discharge are specified by the policy, the ship may proceed to all or any of them, but, in the absence of any usage or sufficient cause to the contrary, she must proceed to them, or such of them as she goes to, in the order designated by the policy. If she does not there is a deviation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945210_016" name="2" temporalId="s47_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the policy is to “ports of discharge”, within a given area, which are not named, the ship must, in the absence of any usage or sufficient cause to the contrary, proceed to them, or such of them as she goes to, in their geographical order. If she does not there is a deviation.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 47 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005602_001" name="s48" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s48"><num value="48">48.</num><heading>Delay in voyage</heading><content>In the case of a voyage policy, the adventure insured must be prosecuted throughout its course with reasonable dispatch, and if without lawful excuse it is not so prosecuted, the insurer is discharged from liability as from the time when the delay became unreasonable.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 48 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005602_003" name="s49" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s49"><num value="49">49.</num><heading>Excuses for deviation or delay</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945242_032" name="1" temporalId="s49_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Deviation or delay in prosecuting the voyage contemplated by the policy is excused—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411945242_040" name="a" temporalId="s49_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where authorized by any special term in the policy; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945257_005" name="b" temporalId="s49_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where caused by circumstances beyond the control of the master and his employer; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945257_013" name="c" temporalId="s49_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where reasonably necessary in order to comply with an express or implied warranty; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945257_021" name="d" temporalId="s49_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>where reasonably necessary for the safety of the ship or subject-matter insured; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945257_029" name="e" temporalId="s49_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>for the purpose of saving human life, or aiding a ship in distress where human life may be in danger; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945257_037" name="f" temporalId="s49_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>where reasonably necessary for the purpose of obtaining medical or surgical aid for any person on board the ship; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945257_045" name="g" temporalId="s49_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>where caused by the barratrous conduct of the master or crew, if barratry be one of the perils insured against.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945257_052" name="2" temporalId="s49_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>When the cause excusing the deviation or delay ceases to operate, the ship must resume her course, and prosecute her voyage, with reasonable dispatch.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 49 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Assignment
        of Policy</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005618_002" name="s50" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s50"><num value="50">50.</num><heading>When and how policy is assignable</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945288_011" name="1" temporalId="s50_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A marine policy is assignable unless it contains terms expressly prohibiting
                assignment. It may be assigned either before or after loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945288_019" name="2" temporalId="s50_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a marine policy has been assigned so as to pass the beneficial interest
                in such policy, the assignee of the policy is entitled to sue thereon in his own
                name; and the defendant is entitled to make any defence arising out of the contract
                which he would have been entitled to make if the action had been brought in the name
                of the person by or on behalf of whom the policy was effected.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945288_027" name="3" temporalId="s50_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A marine policy may be assigned by endorsement thereon or in other customary
                manner.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 50 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005743_001" name="s51" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s51"><num value="51">51.</num><heading>Assured who has no interest cannot assign</heading><leadIn>Where the assured has parted with or lost his interest in the subject-matter insured, and has not, before or at the time of so doing, expressly or impliedly agreed to assign the policy, any subsequent assignment of the policy is inoperative:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s51_proviso">Provided that nothing in this section affects the assignment of a policy after loss.</proviso><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 51 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">The
        Premium</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005774_002" name="s52" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s52"><num value="52">52.</num><heading>When premium payable</heading><content>Unless otherwise agreed, the duty of the assured or his agent to pay the premium,
            and the duty of the insurer to issue the policy to the assured or his agent, are
            concurrent conditions, and the insurer is not bound to issue the policy until payment or
            tender of the premium.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 52 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005805_002" name="s53" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s53"><num value="53">53.</num><heading>Policy effected through broker</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945351_004" name="1" temporalId="s53_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Unless otherwise agreed, where a marine policy is effected on behalf of the assured by a broker, the broker is directly responsible to the insurer for the premium, and the insurer is directly responsible to the assured for the amount which may be payable in respect of losses, or in respect of returnable premium.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945351_012" name="2" temporalId="s53_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Unless otherwise agreed, the broker has, as against the assured, a lien upon the policy for the amount of the premium and his charges in respect of effecting the policy; and, where he has dealt with the person who employs him as a principal, he has also a lien on the policy in respect of any balance on any insurance account which may be due to him from such person, unless when the debt was incurred he had reason to believe that such person was only an agent.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 53 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005821_001" name="s54" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s54"><num value="54">54.</num><heading>Effect of receipt on policy</heading><content>Where a marine policy effected on behalf of the assured by a broker acknowledges the receipt of the premium, such acknowledgment is, in the absence of fraud, conclusive as between the insurer and the assured, but not as between the insurer and broker.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 54 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Loss
        and Abandonment</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005821_003" name="s55" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s55"><num value="55">55.</num><heading>Included and excluded losses</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945398_025" name="1" temporalId="s55_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, and unless the policy otherwise
                provides, the insurer is liable for any loss proximately caused by a peril insured
                against, but, subject as aforesaid, he is not liable for any loss which is not
                proximately caused by a peril insured against.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945398_033" name="2" temporalId="s55_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In particular—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411945398_041" name="a" temporalId="s55_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the insurer is not liable for any loss attributable to the wilful
                    misconduct of the assured, but, unless the policy otherwise provides, he is
                    liable for any loss proximately caused by a peril insured against, even though
                    the loss would not have happened but for the misconduct or negligence of the
                    master or crew;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945413_006" name="b" temporalId="s55_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>unless the policy otherwise provides, the insurer on ship or goods is not
                    liable for any loss proximately caused by delay, although the delay be caused by
                    a peril insured against;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945413_014" name="c" temporalId="s55_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>unless the policy otherwise provides, the insurer is not liable for
                    ordinary wear and tear, ordinary leakage and breakage, inherent vice or nature
                    of the subject-matter insured, or for any loss proximately caused by rats or
                    vermin, or for any injury to machinery not proximately caused by maritime
                    perils.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 55 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005836_002" name="s56" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s56"><num value="56">56.</num><heading>Partial and total loss</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945444_004" name="1" temporalId="s56_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A loss may be either total or partial. Any loss other than a total loss, as hereinafter defined, is a partial loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945444_012" name="2" temporalId="s56_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A total loss may be either an actual total loss, or a constructive total loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945444_020" name="3" temporalId="s56_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Unless a different intention appears from the terms of the policy, an insurance against total loss includes a constructive, as well as an actual, total loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945460_005" name="4" temporalId="s56_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the assured brings an action for a total loss and the evidence proves only a partial loss, he may, unless the policy otherwise provides, recover for a partial loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945460_013" name="5" temporalId="s56_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where goods reach their destination in specie, but by reason of obliteration of marks, or otherwise, they are incapable of identification, the loss, if any, is partial, and not total.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 56 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005852_002" name="s57" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s57"><num value="57">57.</num><heading>Actual total loss</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945491_050" name="1" temporalId="s57_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the subject-matter insured is destroyed, or so damaged as to cease to be a thing of the kind insured, or where the assured is irretrievably deprived thereof, there is an actual total loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945491_058" name="2" temporalId="s57_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In the case of an actual total loss no notice of abandonment need be given.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 57 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005867_002" name="s58" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s58"><num value="58">58.</num><heading>Missing ship</heading><content>Where the ship concerned in the adventure is missing, and after the lapse of a reasonable time no news of her has been received, an actual total loss may be presumed.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 58 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005867_004" name="s59" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s59"><num value="59">59.</num><heading>Effect of transhipment, etc.</heading><content>Where, by a peril insured against, the voyage is interrupted at an intermediate port or place, under such circumstances as, apart from any special stipulation in the contract of affreightment, to justify the master in landing and re-shipping the goods or other movables, or in transhipping them, and sending them on to their destination, the liability of the insurer continues notwithstanding the landing or transhipment.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 59 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005883_002" name="s60" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s60"><num value="60">60.</num><heading>Constructive total loss defined</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945538_025" name="1" temporalId="s60_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to any express provision in the policy, there is a constructive total loss where the subject-matter insured is reasonably abandoned on account of its actual total loss appearing to be unavoidable, or because it could not be preserved from actual total loss without an expenditure which would exceed its value when the expenditure had been incurred.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945554_005" name="2" temporalId="s60_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In particular, there is a constructive total loss—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411945554_013" name="a" temporalId="s60_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the assured is deprived of the possession of his ship or goods by a peril insured against, and (i) it is unlikely that he can recover the ship or goods, as the case may be, or (ii) the cost of recovering the ship or goods, as the case may be, would exceed their value when recovered; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945554_021" name="b" temporalId="s60_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of damage to a ship, where she is so damaged by a peril insured against that the cost of repairing the damage would exceed the value of the ship when repaired.</content><content>In estimating the cost of repairs, no deduction is to be made in respect of general average contributions to those repairs payable by other interests, but account is to be taken of the expense of future salvage operations and of any future general average contributions to which the ship would be liable if repaired; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945569_005" name="c" temporalId="s60_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of damage to goods, where the cost of repairing the damage and forwarding the goods to their destination would exceed their value on arrival.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 60 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005899_001" name="s61" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s61"><num value="61">61.</num><heading>Effect of constructive total loss</heading><content>Where there is a constructive total loss the assured may either treat the loss as a partial loss, or abandon the subject-matter insured to the insurer and treat the loss as if it were an actual total loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 61 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005899_003" name="s62" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s62"><num value="62">62.</num><heading>Notice of abandonment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945600_004" name="1" temporalId="s62_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this section, where the assured elects to abandon the subject-matter insured to the insurer, he must give notice of abandonment. If he fails to do so the loss can only be treated as a partial loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945600_012" name="2" temporalId="s62_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of abandonment may be given in writing, or by word of mouth, or partly in writing and partly by word of mouth, and may be given in any terms which indicate the intention of the assured to abandon his insured interest in the subject-matter insured unconditionally to the insurer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945600_020" name="3" temporalId="s62_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notice of abandonment must be given with reasonable diligence after the receipt of reliable information of the loss, but where the information is of a doubtful character the assured is entitled to a reasonable time to make inquiry.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945616_005" name="4" temporalId="s62_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where notice of abandonment is properly given, the rights of the assured are not prejudiced by the fact that the insurer refuses to accept the abandonment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945616_013" name="5" temporalId="s62_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The acceptance of an abandonment may be either express or implied from the conduct of the insurer. The mere silence of the insurer after notice is not an acceptance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945616_021" name="6" temporalId="s62_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Where notice of abandonment is accepted the abandonment is irrevocable. The acceptance of the notice conclusively admits liability for the loss and the sufficiency of the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945616_029" name="7" temporalId="s62_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Notice of abandonment is unnecessary where, at the time when the assured receives information of the loss, there would be no possibility of benefit to the insurer if notice were given to him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945616_037" name="8" temporalId="s62_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Notice of abandonment may be waived by the insurer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945616_045" name="9" temporalId="s62_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Where an insurer has re-insured his risk, no notice of abandonment need be given by him.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 62 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005914_002" name="s63" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s63"><num value="63">63.</num><heading>Effect of abandonment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945647_019" name="1" temporalId="s63_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where there is a valid abandonment the insurer is entitled to take over the interest of the assured in whatever may remain of the subject-matter insured, and all proprietary rights incidental thereto.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945647_027" name="2" temporalId="s63_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Upon the abandonment of a ship, the insurer thereof is entitled to any freight in course of being earned, and which is earned by her subsequent to the casualty causing the loss, less the expenses of earning it incurred after the casualty; and, where the ship is carrying the owner’s goods, the insurer is entitled to a reasonable remuneration for the carriage of them subsequent to the casualty causing the loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 63 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Partial
                Losses (Including Salvage and General
                Average
                and Particular Charges)</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005930_001" name="s64" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s64"><num value="64">64.</num><heading>Particular average loss</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945678_018" name="1" temporalId="s64_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A particular average loss is a partial loss of the subject-matter
                                insured, caused by a peril insured against, and which is not a
                                general average loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945678_026" name="2" temporalId="s64_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Expenses incurred by or on behalf of the assured for the safety or
                                preservation of the subject-matter insured, other than general
                                average and salvage charges, are called particular charges.
                                Particular charges are not included in particular average.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 64 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005930_003" name="s65" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s65"><num value="65">65.</num><heading>Salvage charges</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945694_033" name="1" temporalId="s65_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to any express provision in the policy, salvage charges incurred in preventing a loss by perils insured against may be recovered as a loss by those perils.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945694_041" name="2" temporalId="s65_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="SalvageCharges"><term>Salvage
                    charges</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">救助費用</term>) means the charges recoverable under
                maritime law by a salvor independently of contract. They do not include the expenses
                of services in the nature of salvage rendered by the assured or his agents, or any
                person employed for hire by them, for the purpose of averting a peril insured
                against. Such expenses, where properly incurred, may be recovered as particular
                charges or as a general average loss, according to the circumstances under which
                they were incurred.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 65 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005945_002" name="s66" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s66"><num value="66">66.</num><heading>General average loss</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945725_004" name="1" temporalId="s66_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A general average loss is a loss caused by or directly consequential on a general average act. It includes a general average expenditure as well as a general average sacrifice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945725_012" name="2" temporalId="s66_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>There is a general average act where any extraordinary sacrifice or expenditure is voluntarily and reasonably made or incurred in time of peril for the purpose of preserving the property imperilled in the common adventure.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945725_020" name="3" temporalId="s66_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where there is a general average loss, the party on whom it falls is entitled, subject to the conditions imposed by maritime law, to a rateable contribution from the other parties interested, and such contribution is called a general average contribution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945741_005" name="4" temporalId="s66_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subject to any express provision in the policy, where the assured has incurred a general average expenditure, he may recover from the insurer in respect of the proportion of the loss which falls upon him; and, in the case of a general average sacrifice, he may recover from the insurer in respect of the whole loss without having enforced his right of contribution from the other parties liable to contribute.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945741_013" name="5" temporalId="s66_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Subject to any express provision in the policy, where the assured has paid, or is liable to pay, a general average contribution in respect of the subject insured, he may recover therefor from the insurer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945741_021" name="6" temporalId="s66_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In the absence of express stipulation, the insurer is not liable for any
                general average loss or contribution where the loss was not incurred for the purpose
                of avoiding, or in
                connexion
                with the avoidance of, a peril insured against.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945756_005" name="7" temporalId="s66_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where ship, freight, and cargo, or any two of those interests, are owned by the same assured, the liability of the insurer in respect of general average losses or contributions is to be determined as if those subjects were owned by different persons.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 66 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Measure
                of Indemnity</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403005961_001" name="s67" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s67"><num value="67">67.</num><heading>Extent of liability of insurer for loss</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945772_058" name="1" temporalId="s67_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The sum which the assured can recover in respect of a loss on a
                                policy by which he is insured, in the case of an unvalued policy to
                                the full extent of
                                the
                                insurable value, or, in the case of a valued policy to the full
                                extent of the value fixed by the policy, is called the measure of
                                indemnity.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945788_005" name="2" temporalId="s67_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where there is a loss recoverable under the policy, the insurer, or
                                each insurer if there be more than one, is liable for such
                                proportion of the measure of indemnity as the amount of his
                                subscription bears to the value fixed by the policy in the case of a
                                valued policy, or to the insurable value in the case of an unvalued
                                policy.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 67 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403005961_003" name="s68" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s68"><num value="68">68.</num><heading>Total loss</heading><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance and to any express provision in the policy, where there is a total loss of the subject-matter insured—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411945803_041" name="a" temporalId="s68_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the policy be a valued policy, the measure of indemnity is the sum fixed by the policy;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945803_049" name="b" temporalId="s68_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the policy be an unvalued policy, the measure of indemnity is the insurable value of the subject-matter insured.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 68 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403005977_002" name="s69" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s69"><num value="69">69.</num><heading>Partial loss of ship</heading><leadIn>Where a ship is damaged, but is not totally lost, the measure of indemnity, subject to any express provision in the policy, is as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411945819_041" name="a" temporalId="s69_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the ship has been repaired, the assured is entitled to the reasonable cost of the repairs, less the customary deductions, but not exceeding the sum insured in respect of any one casualty;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945834_006" name="b" temporalId="s69_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the ship has been only partially repaired, the assured is entitled to the reasonable cost of such repairs, computed as above, and also to be indemnified for the reasonable depreciation, if any, arising from the unrepaired damage, provided that the aggregate amount shall not exceed the cost of repairing the whole damage, computed as above;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945834_014" name="c" temporalId="s69_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the ship has not been repaired, and has not been sold in her damaged state during the risk, the assured is entitled to be indemnified for the reasonable depreciation arising from the unrepaired damage, but not exceeding the reasonable cost of repairing such damage, computed as above.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 69 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403005977_004" name="s70" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s70"><num value="70">70.</num><heading>Partial loss of freight</heading><content>Subject to any express provision in the policy, where there is a partial loss of freight, the measure of indemnity is such proportion of the sum fixed by the policy in the case of a valued policy, or of the insurable value in the case of an unvalued policy, as the proportion of freight lost by the assured bears to the whole freight at the risk of the assured under the policy.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 70 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403005992_002" name="s71" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s71"><num value="71">71.</num><heading>Partial loss of goods, merchandise, etc.</heading><leadIn>Where there is a partial loss of goods, merchandise, or other movables, the measure of indemnity, subject to any express provision in the policy, is as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411945866_033" name="a" temporalId="s71_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where part of the goods, merchandise or other movables insured by a valued policy is totally lost, the measure of indemnity is such proportion of the sum fixed by the policy as the insurable value of the part lost bears to the insurable value of the whole, ascertained as in the case of an unvalued policy;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945881_006" name="b" temporalId="s71_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where part of the goods, merchandise, or other movables insured by an unvalued policy is totally lost, the measure of indemnity is the insurable value of the part lost, ascertained as in case of total loss;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945881_014" name="c" temporalId="s71_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the whole or any part of the goods or merchandise insured has been delivered damaged at its destination, the measure of indemnity is such proportion of the sum fixed by the policy in the case of a valued policy, or of the insurable value in the case of an unvalued policy, as the difference between the gross sound and damaged values at the place of arrival bears to the gross sound value;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411945897_006" name="d" temporalId="s71_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><def name="GrossValue,GrossProceeds"><term>Gross
                    value</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">毛值</term>) means the wholesale price or, if there
                be no such price, the estimated value, with, in either case, freight, landing
                charges, and duty paid beforehand; provided that, in the case of goods or
                merchandise customarily sold in bond, the bonded price is deemed to be the gross
                value.
                    <term>Gross
                    proceeds</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">毛收益</term>) means the actual price obtained at a
                sale where all charges on sale are paid by the sellers.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 71 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403006008_002" name="s72" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s72"><num value="72">72.</num><heading>Apportionment of valuation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945912_042" name="1" temporalId="s72_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where different species of property are insured under a single valuation, the valuation must be apportioned over the different species in proportion to their respective insurable values, as in the case of an unvalued policy. The insured value of any part of a species is such proportion of the total insured value of the same as the insurable value of the part bears to the insurable value of the whole, ascertained in both cases as provided by this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945928_005" name="2" temporalId="s72_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a valuation has to be apportioned, and particulars of the prime cost of each separate species, quality, or description of goods cannot be ascertained, the division of the valuation may be made over the net arrived sound values of the different species, qualities, or descriptions of goods.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 72 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006023_001" name="s73" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s73"><num value="73">73.</num><heading>General average contributions and salvage charges</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411945944_026" name="1" temporalId="s73_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to any express provision in the policy, where the assured has paid, or is liable for, any general average contribution, the measure of indemnity is the full amount of such contribution, if the subject-matter liable to contribution is insured for its full contributory value; but, if such subject-matter be not insured for its full contributory value, or if only part of it be insured, the indemnity payable by the insurer must be reduced in proportion to the under insurance, and where there has been a particular average loss which constitutes a deduction from the contributory value, and for which the insurer is liable, that amount must be deducted from the insured value in order to ascertain what the insurer is liable to contribute.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411945975_005" name="2" temporalId="s73_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the insurer is liable for salvage charges the extent of his liability must be determined on the like principle.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 73 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006023_003" name="s74" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s74"><num value="74">74.</num><heading>Liabilities to third parties</heading><content>Where the assured has effected an insurance in express terms against any liability to a third party, the measure of indemnity, subject to any express provision in the policy, is the amount paid or payable by him to such third party in respect of such liability.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 74 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403006039_001" name="s75" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s75"><num value="75">75.</num><heading>General provisions as to measure of indemnity</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946006_018" name="1" temporalId="s75_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where there has been a loss in respect of any subject-matter not expressly provided for in the foregoing provisions of this Ordinance, the measure of indemnity shall be ascertained, as nearly as may be, in accordance with those provisions, in so far as applicable to the particular case.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946006_026" name="2" temporalId="s75_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in the provisions of this Ordinance relating to the measure of indemnity shall affect the rules relating to double insurance, or prohibit the insurer from disproving interest wholly or in part, or from showing that at the time of the loss the whole or any part of the subject-matter insured was not at risk under the policy.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 75 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006039_003" name="s76" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s76"><num value="76">76.</num><heading>Particular average warranties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946037_004" name="1" temporalId="s76_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the subject-matter insured is warranted free from particular average, the assured cannot recover for a loss of part, other than a loss incurred by a general average sacrifice, unless the contract contained in the policy be apportionable; but, if the contract be apportionable, the assured may recover for a total loss of any apportionable part.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946037_012" name="2" temporalId="s76_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the subject-matter insured is warranted free from particular average, either wholly or under a certain percentage, the insurer is nevertheless liable for salvage charges, and for particular charges and other expenses properly incurred pursuant to the provisions of the suing and labouring clause in order to avert a loss insured against.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946053_005" name="3" temporalId="s76_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Unless the policy otherwise provides, where the subject- matter insured is warranted free from particular average under a specified percentage, a general average loss cannot be added to a particular average loss to make up the specified percentage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946053_013" name="4" temporalId="s76_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purpose of ascertaining whether the specified percentage has been reached, regard shall be had only to the actual loss suffered by the subject-matter insured. Particular charges and the expenses of and incidental to ascertaining and proving the loss must be excluded.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 76 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006055_001" name="s77" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s77"><num value="77">77.</num><heading>Successive losses</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946068_042" name="1" temporalId="s77_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Unless the policy otherwise provides, and subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, the insurer is liable for successive losses, even though the total amount of such losses may exceed the sum insured.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946084_005" name="2" temporalId="s77_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>Where, under the same policy, a partial loss, which has not been repaired or otherwise made good, is followed by a total loss, the assured can only recover in respect of the total loss:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s77_2_proviso">Provided that nothing in this section shall affect the liability of the insurer under the suing and labouring clause.</proviso></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 77 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006055_003" name="s78" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s78"><num value="78">78.</num><heading>Suing and labouring clause</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946100_004" name="1" temporalId="s78_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the policy contains a suing and labouring clause, the engagement thereby entered into is deemed to be supplementary to the contract of insurance, and the assured may recover from the insurer any expenses properly incurred pursuant to the clause, notwithstanding that the insurer may have paid for a total loss, or that the subject-matter may have been warranted free from particular average, either wholly or under a certain percentage.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946100_012" name="2" temporalId="s78_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>General average losses and contributions and salvage charges, as defined by this Ordinance, are not recoverable under the suing and labouring clause.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946115_005" name="3" temporalId="s78_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Expenses incurred for the purpose of averting or diminishing any loss not covered by the policy are not recoverable under the suing and labouring clause.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946115_013" name="4" temporalId="s78_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>It is the duty of the assured and his agents, in all cases, to take such measures as may be reasonable for the purpose of averting or minimizing a loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 78 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Rights
        of Insurer on Payment</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403006070_002" name="s79" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s79"><num value="79">79.</num><heading>Right of subrogation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946131_033" name="1" temporalId="s79_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the insurer pays for a total loss, either of the whole, or in the case of
                goods of any apportionable part, of the subject-matter insured, he thereupon becomes
                entitled to take over the interest of the assured in whatever may remain of the
                subject-matter
                so paid for, and he is thereby subrogated to all the rights and remedies of the
                assured in and in respect of that
                subject-matter
                as from the time of the casualty causing the loss.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946146_005" name="2" temporalId="s79_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to the foregoing provisions, where the insurer pays for a partial loss,
                he acquires no title to the subject-matter insured, or such part of it as may
                remain, but he is thereupon subrogated to all rights and remedies of the assured in
                and in respect of the subject-matter insured as from the time of the casualty
                causing the loss, in so far as the assured has been indemnified, according to this
                Ordinance, by such payment for the loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 79 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006086_001" name="s80" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s80"><num value="80">80.</num><heading>Right of contribution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946162_033" name="1" temporalId="s80_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the assured is over-insured by double insurance, each insurer is bound, as between himself and the other insurers, to contribute rateably to the loss in proportion to the amount for which he is liable under his contract.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946178_005" name="2" temporalId="s80_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any insurer pays more than his proportion of the loss, he is entitled to maintain an action for contribution against the other insurers, and is entitled to the like remedies as a surety who has paid more than his proportion of the debt.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 80 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006086_003" name="s81" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s81"><num value="81">81.</num><heading>Effect of under insurance</heading><content>Where the assured is insured for an amount less than the insurable value or, in the case of a valued policy, for an amount less than the policy valuation, he is deemed to be his own insurer in respect of the uninsured balance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 81 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Return
                of Premium</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403006101_001" name="s82" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s82"><num value="82">82.</num><heading>Enforcement of return</heading><leadIn>Where the premium or a proportionate part thereof is, by this Ordinance,
                        declared to be returnable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411946209_019" name="a" temporalId="s82_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if already paid, it may be recovered by the assured from the
                                insurer; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411946209_027" name="b" temporalId="s82_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if unpaid, it may be retained by the assured or his
                                agent.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 82 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403006101_003" name="s83" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s83"><num value="83">83.</num><heading>Return by agreement</heading><content>Where the policy contains a stipulation for the return of the premium, or a proportionate part thereof, on the happening of a certain event, and that event happens, the premium, or, as the case may be, the proportionate part thereof, is thereupon returnable to the assured.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 83 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403006117_002" name="s84" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s84"><num value="84">84.</num><heading>Return for failure of consideration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946240_004" name="1" temporalId="s84_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the consideration for the payment of the premium totally fails, and there has been no fraud or illegality on the part of the assured or his agents, the premium is thereupon returnable to the assured.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946240_012" name="2" temporalId="s84_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the consideration for the payment of the premium is apportionable and there is a total failure of any apportionable part of the consideration, a proportionate part of the premium is, under the like conditions, thereupon returnable to the assured.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946240_020" name="3" temporalId="s84_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In particular—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411946240_028" name="a" temporalId="s84_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the policy is void, or is avoided by the insurer as from the commencement of the risk, the premium is returnable, provided that there has been no fraud or illegality on the part of the assured; but if the risk is not apportionable, and has once attached, the premium is not returnable;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411946256_006" name="b" temporalId="s84_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content><leadIn>where the subject-matter insured, or part thereof, has never been imperilled, the premium, or, as the case may be, a proportionate part thereof, is returnable:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s84_3_b_proviso">Provided that where the subject-matter has been insured “lost or not lost” and has arrived in safety at the time when the contract is concluded, the premium is not returnable unless, at such time, the insurer knew of the safe arrival;</proviso></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411946256_020" name="c" temporalId="s84_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the assured has no insurable interest throughout the currency of the risk, the premium is returnable, provided that this rule does not apply to a policy effected by way of gaming or wagering;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411946256_028" name="d" temporalId="s84_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>where the assured has a defeasible interest which is terminated during the currency of the risk, the premium is not returnable;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411946256_036" name="e" temporalId="s84_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>where the assured has over-insured under an unvalued policy, a proportionate part of the premium is returnable;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411946256_044" name="f" temporalId="s84_3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content><leadIn>subject to the foregoing provisions, where the assured has over-insured by double insurance, a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>proportionate part of the several premiums is returnable:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s84_3_f_proviso">Provided that, if the policies are effected at different times, and any earlier policy has at any time borne the entire risk, or if a claim has been paid on the policy in respect of the full sum insured thereby, no premium is returnable in respect of that policy, and when the double insurance is effected knowingly by the assured no premium is returnable.</proviso></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 84 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Mutual
                Insurance</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403006117_004" name="s85" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s85"><num value="85">85.</num><heading>Modification of Ordinance in case of mutual insurance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946287_063" name="1" temporalId="s85_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where two or more persons mutually agree to insure each other
                                against marine losses there is said to be a mutual
                                insurance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946287_071" name="2" temporalId="s85_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The provisions of this Ordinance relating to the premium do not
                                apply to mutual insurance, but a guarantee, or such other
                                arrangement as may be agreed upon, may be substituted for the
                                premium.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946302_005" name="3" temporalId="s85_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The provisions of this Ordinance, in so far as they may be modified
                                by the agreement of the parties, may in the case of mutual insurance
                                be modified by the terms of the policies issued by the association,
                                or by the rules and regulations of the association.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946302_013" name="4" temporalId="s85_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subject to the exceptions mentioned in this section, the provisions
                                of this Ordinance apply to a mutual insurance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 85 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Supplemental</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403006133_002" name="s86" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s86"><num value="86">86.</num><heading>Ratification by assured</heading><content>Where a contract of marine insurance is in good faith effected by one
                        person on behalf of another, the person on whose behalf it is effected may
                        ratify the contract even after he is aware of a loss.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 86 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403006148_001" name="s87" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s87"><num value="87">87.</num><heading>Implied obligations varied by agreement or usage</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946334_025" name="1" temporalId="s87_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any right, duty, or liability would arise under a contract of marine insurance by implication of law, it may be negatived or varied by express agreement, or by usage, if the usage be such as to bind both parties to the contract.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946334_033" name="2" temporalId="s87_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The provisions of this section extend to any right, duty, or liability declared by this Ordinance which may be lawfully modified by agreement.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 87 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403006148_003" name="s88" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s88"><num value="88">88.</num><heading>Reasonable time, etc. a question of fact</heading><content>Where by this Ordinance any reference is made to reasonable time, reasonable premium, or reasonable diligence, the question what is reasonable is a question of fact.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 88 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403006164_001" name="s89" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s89"><num value="89">89.</num><heading>Slip as evidence</heading><content>Where there is a duly stamped policy, reference may be made, as heretofore, to the slip or covering note, in any legal proceeding.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 89 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403006164_003" name="s90" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s90"><num value="90">90.</num><heading>Interpretation of terms</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context or subject-matter otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Action"><term>action</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訴訟</term>) includes suit, counter-claim and
            set-off;</def><def name="Freight"><term>freight</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">運費</term>) includes the profit derivable by a shipowner
            from the employment of his ship to carry his own goods or movables, as well as freight
            payable by a third party, but does not include passage money;</def><def name="Movables"><term>movables</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">動產</term>) means any movable tangible property, other
            than the ship, and includes money, valuable securities, and other documents;
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2022</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Policy"><term>policy</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">保單</term>) means a marine policy.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 90 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403006179_001" name="s91" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s91"><num value="91">91.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>The rules of the common law including the law merchant, save in so far as they are inconsistent with the express provisions of this Ordinance, shall continue to apply to contracts of marine insurance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1906 c. 41 s. 91 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403006211_002" name="s92" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="s92"><num value="92">92.</num><heading>Prohibition of gambling on loss by maritime perils</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411946427_032" name="1" temporalId="s92_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411946427_040" name="a" temporalId="s92_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any person effects a contract of marine insurance without having any bona
                    fide interest, direct or indirect, either in the safe arrival of the ship in
                    relation to which the contract is made or in the safety or preservation of the
                    subject-matter insured, or a bona fide expectation of acquiring such an
                    interest; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411946443_006" name="b" temporalId="s92_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any person in the employment of the owner of a ship, not being a part owner
                    of the ship, effects a contract of marine insurance in relation to the ship, and
                    the contract is made “interest or no interest”, or “without further proof of
                    interest than the policy itself”, or “without benefit of salvage to the
                    insurer”, or subject to any other like term,</content></paragraph><continued>the contract shall be deemed to be a contract by way of gambling on loss by
                maritime perils, and the person effecting it shall be guilty of an offence, and
                shall be liable, on conviction, to imprisonment for a term not exceeding
                six
                months or to a fine not exceeding
                level
                1,
                or to both such fine and imprisonment and in either case to forfeit to the
                Government any money he may receive under the contract.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1966/13">13 of 1966
                    </ref>Schedule; <ref href="/hk/1999/64">64 of 1999 s.
                    3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946443_019" name="2" temporalId="s92_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any broker or other person through whom, and any insurer with whom, any such
                contract is effected shall be guilty of an offence and liable on conviction to the
                like penalties if he acted knowing that the contract was by way of gambling on loss
                by maritime perils within the meaning of this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946458_005" name="3" temporalId="s92_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Proceedings under this section shall not be instituted without the consent of
                the Secretary for Justice.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946458_013" name="4" temporalId="s92_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Proceedings shall not be instituted under this section against a person (other
                than a person in the employment of the owner of the ship in relation to which the
                contract was made) alleged to have effected a contract by way of gambling on loss by
                maritime perils until an opportunity has been afforded him of showing that the
                contract was not such a contract as aforesaid, and any information given by that
                person for that purpose shall not be admissible in evidence against him in any
                prosecution under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946474_005" name="5" temporalId="s92_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If proceedings under this section are taken against any person (other than a
                person in the employment of the owner of the ship in relation to which the contract
                was made) for effecting such a contract, and the contract was made “interest or no
                interest”, or “without further proof of interest than the policy itself”, or
                “without benefit of salvage to the insurer”, or subject to any other like term, the
                contract shall be deemed to be a contract by way of gambling on loss by maritime
                perils unless the contrary is proved.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946490_005" name="6" temporalId="s92_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>For the purpose of giving jurisdiction under this section, every offence shall
                be deemed to have been committed either in the place in which the same actually was
                committed or in any place in which the offender may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946490_013" name="7" temporalId="s92_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><def name="Owner">For the purposes of this section the expression
                    <term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船東</term>) includes charterer.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411946490_020" name="8" temporalId="s92_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall affect the operation of <ref>section
                4</ref>.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1909 c. 12 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><schedule id="ID_1438403006491_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-04-14" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap329/s30">s. 30</ref>]</note><heading>Form
            of
            Policy<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="450">
                
                <col width="85%"></col>
                
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">BE IT KNOWN
                                THAT<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_44"> </inline>as well in</p>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">own name as for
                            and in the name and names of all and every other person or persons to
                            whom the same doth, may, or shall appertain, in part or in all doth make
                            assurance and cause
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></p>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">and them, and
                            every of them, to be insured lost or not lost, at and from</p>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Upon any kind
                            of goods and merchandises, and also upon the body, tackle, apparel,
                            ordnance, munition, artillery, boat, and other furniture, of and in the
                            good ship or vessel called
                            the<br></br><br></br>whereof
                            is master under God, for this present voyage,<br></br>or whosoever else
                            shall go for master in the said ship, or by whatsoever other name or
                            names the said ship, or the master thereof, is or shall be named or
                            called; beginning the adventure upon the said goods and merchandises
                            from the loading thereof aboard the said ship, </p>
                        
                        
                        
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">upon the said
                            ship, etc. </p>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">and so shall
                            continue and endure, during her abode there, upon the said ship, etc.
                            And further, until the said ship, with all her ordnance, tackle,
                            apparel, etc., and goods and merchandises whatsoever shall be arrived at </p>
                        
                    </td>
                    
                    <td class="left_indent_11">
                        
                        <p><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="font_size_8">Lloyd’s<br></br>S.G.
                                Policy.</inline></p>
                        
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">upon the said
                            ship, etc., until she hath moored at anchor twenty-four hours in good
                            safety; and upon the goods and merchandises, until the same be there
                            discharged and safely landed. And it shall be lawful for the said ship,
                            etc., in this voyage, to proceed and sail to and touch and stay at any
                            ports or places whatsoever</p>
                    </td>
                    <td class="left_indent_11"></td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">without
                            prejudice to this insurance. The said ship, etc., goods and
                            merchandises, etc., for so much as concerns the assured by agreement
                            between the assured and assurers in this policy, are and shall be valued
                            at </p>
                    </td>
                    <td class="left_indent_11"></td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_25">Touching the
                            adventures and perils which we the assurers are contented to bear and do
                            take upon us in this voyage: they are of the seas, men of war, fire,
                            enemies, pirates, rovers, thieves, jettisons, letters of mart and
                            countermart, surprisals, takings at sea, arrests, restraints, and
                            detainments of all kings, princes, and people, of what nation,
                            condition, or quality soever, barratry of the master and mariners, and
                            of all other perils, losses, and misfortunes, that have or shall come to
                            the hurt, detriment, or damage of the said goods and merchandises, and
                            ship, etc., or any part thereof. And in case of any loss or misfortune
                            it shall be lawful to the assured, their factors, servants and assigns,
                            to sue, labour, and travel for, in and about the defence, safeguards,
                            and recovery of the said goods and merchandises, and ship, etc., or any
                            part thereof, without prejudice to this insurance; to the charges
                            whereof we, the assurers, will contribute each one according to the rate
                            and quantity of his sum herein assured. And it is especially declared
                            and agreed that no acts of the insurer or insured in recovering, saving,
                            or preserving the property insured shall be considered as a waiver, or
                            acceptance of abandonment. And it is agreed by us, the insurers, that
                            this writing or policy of assurance shall be of as much force and effect
                            as the surest writing or policy of assurance heretofore made in Lombard
                            Street, or in the
                            Royal
                            Exchange, or elsewhere in London. And so we, the assurers, are
                            contented, and do hereby promise and bind ourselves, each one for his
                            own part, our heirs, executors, and goods to the assured, their
                            executors, administrators, and assigns, for the true performance of the
                            premises, confessing ourselves paid the consideration due unto us for
                            this assurance by the assured, at and after the rate of
                            </p>
                        
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                        
                    </td>
                    <td class="left_indent_11">
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <p><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="font_size_8">(Sue and<br></br>labour<br></br>clause).</inline></p>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <p><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="font_size_8">(Waiver<br></br>clause).</inline>
                        </p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_24">IN WITNESS
                            whereof we, the assurers, have subscribed our names and sums assured in
                            London. </p>
                        
                        
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        
                        
                    </td>
                    <td class="left_indent_11"></td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_24">N.B.—Corn,
                            fish, salt, fruit, flour, and seed are warranted free from average,
                            unless general, or the ship be stranded—sugar, tobacco, hemp, flax,
                            hides and skins are warranted free from average, under five pounds per
                            cent, and all other goods, also the ship and freight, are warranted free
                            from average, under three pounds per cent unless general, or the ship be
                            stranded.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td class="left_indent_11">
                        <p><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="font_size_8">(Memoran-dum).</inline></p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
            </table>
        </text><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="450">
                
                <col width="84%"></col>
                
                <col width="16%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>Rules
                                    for Construction of
                                Policy</b><br></br></center>
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            
                            
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p>The following are the rules referred to by this Ordinance for the
                                construction of a policy in the above or other like form, where the
                                context does not otherwise require—</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>1.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Lost
                                    or not lost</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">Where the
                                subject-matter is insured “lost or not lost”, and the loss has
                                occurred before the contract is concluded, the risk attaches unless,
                                at such time the assured was aware of the loss, and the insurer was
                                not.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>2.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>From</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">Where the
                                subject-matter is insured “from” a particular place, the risk does
                                not attach until the ship starts on the voyage insured.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>3.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>At
                                    and from </b></p>
                            
                            
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_42 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1642382545804_001" name="1" temporalId="sch0_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a ship is insured “at and from” a particular place,
                                    and she is at that place in good safety when the contract is
                                    concluded, the risk attaches immediately.</content></paragraph>
                            
                            
                            
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_42 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1642382545804_002" name="2" temporalId="sch0_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If she be not at that place when the contract is concluded,
                                    the risk attaches as soon as she arrives there in good safety,
                                    and, unless the policy otherwise provides, it is immaterial that
                                    she is covered by another policy for a specified time after
                                    arrival.</content></paragraph>
                            
                            
                            
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <p class="left_indent_11 first_line_indent_0"><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="font_size_8">(Ship).</inline></p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_42 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1642382545804_003" name="3" temporalId="sch0_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where chartered freight is insured “at and from” a
                                    particular place, and the ship is at that place in good safety
                                    when the contract is concluded the risk attaches immediately. If
                                    she be not there when the contract is concluded, the risk
                                    attaches as soon as she arrives there in good safety.</content></paragraph>
                            
                            
                            
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_42 first_line_indent_-24 align_justified" id="ID_1642382545804_004" name="4" temporalId="sch0_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where freight, other than chartered freight, is payable
                                    without special conditions and is insured “at and from” a
                                    particular place, the risk attaches pro rata as the goods or
                                    merchandise are shipped; provided that if there be cargo in
                                    readiness which belongs to the shipowner, or which some other
                                    person has contracted with him to ship, the risk attaches as
                                    soon as the ship is ready to receive such cargo.</content></paragraph>
                            
                            
                            
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            
                            
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <p class="left_indent_11 first_line_indent_0"><inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="font_size_8">(Freight).</inline></p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>4.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>From
                                    the loading thereof</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">Where
                                goods or other movables are insured “from the loading thereof”, the
                                risk does not attach until such goods or movable are actually on
                                board, and the insurer is not liable for them while in transit from
                                the shore to the ship.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>5.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Safely
                                    landed</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">Where the
                                risk on goods or other movables continues until they are “safely
                                landed”, they must be landed in the customary manner and within a
                                reasonable time after arrival at the port of discharge, and if they
                                are not so landed the risk ceases.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>6.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Touch
                                    and stay</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">In the
                                absence of any further licence or usage, the liberty to touch and
                                stay “at any port or place whatsoever” does not authorize the ship
                                to depart from the course of her voyage from the port of departure
                                to the port of destination.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>7.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Perils
                                    of the seas</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">perils of the
                                    seas</term>
                                (海險) refers only to fortuitous accidents or casualties of the seas.
                                It does not include the ordinary action of the winds and waves.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>8.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Pirates</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">pirates</term>
                                (海盜) includes passengers who mutiny and rioters who attack the ship
                                from the shore.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>9.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Thieves</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_20">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">thieves</term>
                                (盜竊) does not cover clandestine theft or a theft committed by any
                                one of the ship’s company, whether crew or passengers.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>10.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Restraint
                                    of princes</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">arrests, etc., of
                                    kings, princes, and
                                people</term>
                                (君王、君主及人民所作的拘禁等) refers to political or executive acts, and does not
                                include a loss caused by riot or by ordinary judicial process.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>11.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Barratry</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">barratry</term>
                                (船上人員不當行為) includes every wrongful act wilfully committed by the
                                master or crew to the prejudice of the owner, or, as the case may
                                be, the charterer. </p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>12.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>All
                                    other perils</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">all other
                                    perils</term>
                                (一切其他類同危險)
                                includes only perils similar in kind to the perils specifically
                                mentioned in the policy.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>13.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Average
                                    unless general</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">average unless
                                    general</term>
                                (除非是共同海損的海損) means a partial loss of the subject-matter insured
                                other than a general average loss, and does not include
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">particular
                                    charges</term>
                                (單獨費用).</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>14.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Stranded</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">Where the
                                ship has stranded, the insurer is liable for the excepted losses,
                                although the loss is not attributable to the stranding, provided
                                that when the stranding takes place the risk has attached and, if
                                the policy be on goods, that the damaged goods are on board.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified"><b>15.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Ship</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">The
                                term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">ship</term>
                                (船舶) includes the hull, materials and outfit, stores and provisions
                                for the officers and crew, and, in the case of vessels engaged in a
                                special trade, the ordinary fittings requisite for the trade, and
                                also, in the case of a steamship, the machinery, boilers, and coals
                                and engine stores, if owned by the assured.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>16.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Freight</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">freight</term>
                                (運費) includes the profit derivable by a shipowner from the
                                employment of his ship to carry his own goods or movables, as well
                                as freight payable by a third party, but does not include passage
                                money.</p>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_22 first_line_indent_-20"><b>17.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_9"> </inline>Goods</b></p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">The term
                                    <term xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">goods</term>
                                (貨品) means goods in the nature of merchandise, and does not include
                                personal effects or provisions and stores for use on board.</p>
                            
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_0 left_indent_24">In the
                                absence of any usage to the contrary, deck cargo and living animals
                                must be insured specifically, and not under the general denomination
                                of goods.</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </text><referenceNote class="align_justified left_indent_140">[cf. 1906 c. 41 <ref>First Sch.</ref>
            U.K.]</referenceNote></schedule></main></ordinance>