<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 503 sub. leg. U</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>503U</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap503U!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-12-29</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403285732_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2020-12-29">Fugitive
                                    Offenders (Portugal) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap503/s3">Cap.
                                                503, section
                                    3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of
                                                2020</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[7 November 2004]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2004/ln170">L.N. 170 of
                                                  2004</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of
                                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403285748_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2020/er7">E.R. 7 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403285748_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Procedures in Ordinance to apply between Hong Kong and Portugal</heading><leadIn>In relation to the arrangements for the surrender of fugitive offenders—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412839451_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>which are applicable to the Government and the Government of the Portuguese Republic; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412839451_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the terms of which are recited in the <ref>Schedule</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>it is directed that the procedures in the Ordinance shall apply as between Hong Kong and the Portuguese Republic subject to the limitations, restrictions, exceptions and qualifications contained in the terms so recited.</continued></section><schedule id="ID_1438403285763_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-12-29" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap503U/s2">s. 2</ref>]</note><heading>Agreement
            between the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s
            Republic of China and the Government of the Portuguese
            Republic concerning Surrender
            of Fugitive Offenders</heading><crossHeading> </crossHeading><text class="first_line_indent_48 left_indent_0">The Government of the Hong Kong Special
            Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China (“Hong Kong Special
            Administrative Region”) having been duly authorised to conclude this Agreement by the
            Central People’s Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the
            Portuguese Republic,<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="first_line_indent_48 left_indent_0">Desiring to make provision for the
            reciprocal surrender of fugitive
            offenders;<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><leadIn class="first_line_indent_48 left_indent_0">Have agreed as
            follows:<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></leadIn><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            1</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">OBLIGATION TO
            SURRENDER<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_48">The Parties agree to surrender to each
            other, subject to the provisions laid down in this Agreement, any person who is found in
            the jurisdiction of the requested Party and who is wanted by the requesting Party for
            prosecution or for the imposition or enforcement of a sentence in respect of an offence
            described in Article 2.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            2</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">OFFENCES<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph class="left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973288_001" name="0" temporalId="sch0_0"><leadIn>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Surrender shall be granted for an offence
                coming within any of the following descriptions of offences in so far as it is
                according to the laws of both Parties punishable by imprisonment or other form of
                detention for more than one year, or by a more severe penalty:</leadIn><text class="left_indent_24">
                <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="align_justified left_indent_24" width="416">
                    <col width="8%"></col>
                    <col width="92%"></col>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(1)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(2)</p>
                                <p>(3)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>murder or manslaughter, including criminal negligence causing
                                    death; culpable homicide; assault with intent to commit
                                    murder</p>
                                <p>aiding, abetting, counselling or procuring suicide</p>
                                <p>maliciously wounding; maiming; inflicting grievous or actual
                                    bodily harm; assault occasioning actual bodily harm; threats to
                                    kill; intentional or reckless endangering of life whether by
                                    means of a weapon, a dangerous substance or otherwise, offences
                                    relating to unlawful wounding or injuring</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(4)<br></br><br></br> </p>
                                <p>(5)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(6)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>offences of a sexual nature including rape; sexual assault;
                                    indecent assault; unlawful sexual acts on children; statutory
                                    sexual offences</p>
                                <p>gross indecency with a child, a mental defective or an
                                    unconscious person</p>
                                <p>kidnapping; abduction; false imprisonment; unlawful confinement;
                                    dealing or trafficking in slaves or other persons; taking a
                                    hostage</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(7)</p>
                                <p>(8)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>criminal intimidation</p>
                                <p>offences against the law relating to dangerous drugs including
                                    narcotics and psychotropic substances and precursors and
                                    essential chemicals used in the illegal manufacture or narcotic
                                    drugs and psychotropic substances and offences related to the
                                    proceeds of drug trafficking</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(9)<br></br> </p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>obtaining property or pecuniary advantage by deception; theft;
                                    robbery; burglary (including breaking and entering);
                                    embezzlement; blackmail; extortion; unlawful handling or
                                    receiving of property; false accounting; any other offence in
                                    respect of property or fiscal matters involving fraud; any
                                    offence against the law relating to unlawful deprivation of
                                    property</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(10)</p>
                                <p>(11)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(12)</p>
                                <p>(13)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>offences against bankruptcy law or insolvency</p>
                                <p>offences against the law relating to companies including offences
                                    committed by officers, directors, and promoters</p>
                                <p>offences relating to securities and futures trading</p>
                                <p>any offence relating to counterfeiting; any offence against the
                                    law relating to forgery or uttering what is forged</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(14)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(15)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(16)</p>
                                <p>(17)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(18)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(19)</p>
                                <p>(20)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>an offence against the laws relating to protection of
                                    intellectual property, copyrights, patents or trademarks</p>
                                <p>an offence against the law relating to bribery, corruption,
                                    secret commissions, and breach of trust</p>
                                <p>perjury and subornation of perjury</p>
                                <p>offences relating to the perversion or obstruction of the course
                                    of justice</p>
                                <p>arson; criminal damage or mischief including mischief in relation
                                    to computer data</p>
                                <p>an offence against the law relating to firearms</p>
                                <p>an offence against the law relating to explosives</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(21)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>an offence against laws relating to environmental pollution or
                                    protection of public health</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(22)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>mutiny or any mutinous act committed on board a vessel at sea</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(23)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>piracy involving ships or aircraft, according to international
                                    law</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(24)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>unlawful seizure or exercise of control of an aircraft or other
                                    means of transportation</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(25)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>genocide or direct and public incitement to commit genocide</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(26)</p>
                                <p>(27)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>facilitating or permitting the escape of a person from
                                    custody</p>
                                <p>an offence against the laws relating to the control of
                                    exportation or importation of goods of any type, or the
                                    international transfer of funds</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(28)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>smuggling; offences against the laws relating to import and
                                    export of prohibited items, including historical and
                                    archaeological items</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(29)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(30)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(31)</p>
                                <p>(32)</p>
                                <p>(33)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(34)<br></br> </p>
                                <p>(35)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>immigration offences including fraudulent acquisition or use of a
                                    passport or visa</p>
                                <p>arranging or facilitating for financial gain, the illegal entry
                                    of persons into the jurisdiction of the requesting Party</p>
                                <p>an offence relating to gambling or lotteries</p>
                                <p>offences relating to the unlawful termination of pregnancy</p>
                                <p>stealing, abandoning exposing or unlawfully detaining a child;
                                    any other offences involving the exploitation of children</p>
                                <p>offences against the laws relating to prostitution and premises
                                    kept for the purposes of prostitution</p>
                                <p>offences involving the unlawful use of computers</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(36)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>offences relating to fiscal matters, taxes or duties,
                                    notwithstanding that the law of the requested Party does not
                                    impose the same kind of tax or duty or does not contain a tax
                                    duty or customs regulation of the same kind as the requesting
                                    Party</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(37) </p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>offences relating to the unlawful escape from custody; mutiny in
                                    prison</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(38)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>bigamy</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(39)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>an offence relating to women and girls</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(40)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>any offence against the law relating to false or misleading trade
                                    descriptions</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(41)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>offences relating to the possession or laundering of proceeds
                                    obtained from the commission of any offence for which surrender
                                    may be granted under this Agreement</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(42)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>impeding the arrest or prosecution of a person who has or is
                                    believed to have committed an offence for which surrender may be
                                    granted under this Agreement</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(43)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>offences for which fugitive offenders may be surrendered under
                                    international conventions binding on the Parties; offences
                                    created as a result of decisions of international organisations
                                    which are binding on the Parties</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(44)</p>
                                <p>(45)<br></br><br></br> </p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>conspiracy to commit fraud or to defraud</p>
                                <p>conspiracy to commit or any type of association to commit any
                                    offence for which surrender may be granted under this
                                    Agreement</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(46)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>aiding abetting counselling or procuring the commission of,
                                    inciting, being an accessory before or after the fact to, or
                                    attempting to commit any offence for which surrender may be
                                    granted under this Agreement</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <p>(47)</p>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <p>any other offence for which surrender may be granted in
                                    accordance with the laws of both Parties</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </text></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_002"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Where surrender is requested for the
                purpose of carrying out a sentence, a further requirement shall be that in the case
                of a period of imprisonment or detention at least six months remain to be
                served.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_003"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>For the purposes of this Article, in
                determining whether an offence is an offence punishable under the laws of both
                Parties the totality of the acts or omissions alleged against the person whose
                surrender is sought shall be taken into account without reference to the elements of
                the offence prescribed by the law of the requesting Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_004"><content>(4)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>For the purposes of paragraph (1) of this
                Article, an offence shall be an offence according to the laws of both Parties if the
                conduct constituting the offence was an offence against the law of the requesting
                Party at the time it was committed and an offence against the law of the requested
                Party at the time the request for surrender is received.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_005"><content>(5)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Where the surrender of a fugitive
                offender is requested for the purpose of carrying out a sentence the requested Party
                may refuse to surrender him if it appears that the conviction was obtained in his
                absence, unless he has the opportunity to have his case retried in his presence, in
                which case he shall be considered as an accused person under this
                Agreement.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            3</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">SURRENDER OF
            NATIONALS<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_48">The Government of the Portuguese Republic
            reserves the right to refuse the surrender of its citizens and permanent residents. The
            Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region reserves the right to refuse
            the surrender of its permanent residents and nationals of the People’s Republic of
            China.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            4</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">DEATH PENALTY, LIFE AND INDETERMINATE
            SENTENCES<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_006"><content>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If the offence for which surrender of a
                fugitive offender is requested under this Agreement is punishable according to the
                law of the requesting Party with the death penalty, surrender shall be
                refused.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_007"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If the offence for which surrender of a
                fugitive offender is requested under this Agreement is punishable according to the
                law of the requesting Party with life imprisonment or a prison sentence of
                undetermined duration, surrender shall be refused unless the requesting Party gives
                such assurances as the requested Party considers sufficient that these penalties
                will not be imposed or, if imposed, will not be carried
                out.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            5</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">BASIS FOR
            SURRENDER<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_48">A person shall be surrendered only if the
            evidence be found sufficient according to the law of the requested Party either to
            justify the committal for trial of the person sought if the offence of which that person
            is accused had been committed in the territory of the requested Party or to prove that
            the person sought is the person convicted by the courts of the requesting
            Party.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            6</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">MANDATORY REFUSAL OF
            SURRENDER<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_008"><leadIn>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>A fugitive offender shall not be
                surrendered if the requested Party has substantial grounds for believing:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973303_009" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the offence of which that person is accused or was convicted is an
                    offence of a political character;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973303_010" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>that the request for surrender (though purporting to be made on account of
                    an offence for which surrender may be granted) is in fact made for the purpose
                    of prosecution or punishment on account of race, religion, nationality or
                    political opinions; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973303_011" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(c)</num><content>that the person might, if returned, be prejudiced at that person’s trial or
                    punished, detained or restricted in his or her personal liberty by reason of
                    race, religion, nationality or political opinions.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973303_012"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>A fugitive offender who has been finally
                acquitted, convicted or pardoned or whose prosecution is barred or whose conviction
                has been set aside under the law of the requesting or requested Party for any
                offence set out in the request shall not be surrendered for that
                offence.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            7</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">DISCRETIONARY REFUSAL OF
            SURRENDER<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><leadIn class="left_indent_48">Surrender may be refused if the requested Party considers
            that:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973303_013" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the offence is, having regard to all the circumstances, not sufficiently
                serious to warrant the surrender;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973303_014" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>there has been excessive delay, for reasons which cannot be imputed to the
                person sought, in bringing charges, in bringing the case to trial or in making the
                person serve his or her sentence or the remainder thereof;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_015" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(c)</num><content>the offence for which surrender is sought was committed within the jurisdiction
                of its courts;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_016" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(d)</num><content>the surrender might place that Party in breach of its obligations under
                international treaties; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_017" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(e)</num><content>in the circumstances of the case, the surrender would be incompatible with
                humanitarian considerations in view of the age, health or other personal
                circumstances of the person
                sought.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subparagraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            8</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">POSTPONEMENT OF
            SURRENDER<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_48">If the person sought is being proceeded
            against or is under punishment in the jurisdiction of the requested Party for any
            offence other than that for which surrender is requested, surrender may be granted or
            deferred until the conclusion of the proceedings and the execution of any punishment
            imposed.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
            9</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">THE REQUEST AND SUPPORTING
            DOCUMENTS<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973319_018"><leadIn>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Requests for surrender shall—</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_019" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the Portuguese Republic is the requesting Party be made by the
                    consular representative of the Portuguese Republic in the Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region to the Department of Justice of the Hong Kong Special
                    Administrative Region;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_020" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>where the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region is the requesting Party
                    be made by the Department of Justice of the Hong Kong Special Administrative
                    Region to the consular representative of the Portuguese Republic in the Hong
                    Kong Special Administrative Region,</content></subparagraph><continued class="left_indent_48 first_line_indent_0">or be made through such other
                appropriate authorities as may be agreed by the Parties.</continued></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973319_021"><leadIn>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The request shall be accompanied
                by:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_022" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>as accurate a description as possible of the person sought, together with
                    any other information which would help to establish that person’s identity,
                    nationality and location;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_023" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>a statement of each offence for which surrender is sought and a statement
                    of the acts and omissions which are alleged against the person in respect of
                    each offence; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_024" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(c)</num><content>the text of the legal provisions, if any, creating the offence, and a
                    statement of the punishment which can be imposed therefor and any time limit on
                    the institution of proceedings, or on the execution of any punishment for that
                    offence.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973319_025"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If the request relates to an accused
                person it shall also be accompanied by a copy of the warrant of arrest issued by a
                judge, magistrate or other competent authority of the requesting Party and by such
                evidence as, according to the law of the requested Party, would justify committal
                for trial if the offence had been committed within the jurisdiction of the requested
                Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973319_026"><leadIn>(4)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If the request relates to a person already
                convicted or sentenced, it shall also be accompanied by:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_027" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a copy of the certificate of the conviction or sentence; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_028" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>if the person was convicted but not sentenced, a statement to that effect
                    by the appropriate court and a copy of the warrant of arrest; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973319_029" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(c)</num><content>if the person was sentenced, a statement indicating that the sentence is
                    enforceable and how much of the sentence has still to be
                    served.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></subparagraph></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                10</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">AUTHENTICATION<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_030"><leadIn>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Documents supporting a request for
                surrender shall be admitted in evidence as proof of the facts contained therein if
                duly authenticated. Documents are duly authenticated if they purport to be:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973335_031" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>signed or certified by a judge, magistrate or an official of the requesting
                    Party, and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973335_032" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>sealed with the official seal of a competent authority of the requesting
                    Party.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_033"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Any translation of documents submitted in
                support of a request for surrender provided by the requesting Party shall be
                admitted for all purposes in proceedings for
                surrender.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                11</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">LANGUAGE OF
            DOCUMENTATION<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_48">Requests shall be in, or translated into,
            an official language of the requested Party. All documents submitted in support of a
            request shall be accompanied, if so required by the requested Party, by a translation
            into an official language of the requested
            Party.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                12</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">ADDITIONAL
            INFORMATION<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_034"><content>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If the information communicated by the
                requesting Party is found to be insufficient to allow the requested Party to make a
                decision in pursuance of this Agreement, the latter Party shall request the
                necessary supplementary information and may fix a time-limit for receipt
                thereof.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_035"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If the person whose surrender is sought
                is under arrest and the additional information furnished is not sufficient in
                accordance with this Agreement or is not received within the time specified, the
                person may be discharged. Such discharge shall not preclude the requesting Party
                from making a fresh request for the surrender of the
                person.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                13</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">PROVISIONAL
            ARREST<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_036"><content>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>In urgent cases the person sought may, at
                the discretion of the requested Party and in accordance with its law, be
                provisionally arrested on the application of the requesting Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_037"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The application for provisional arrest
                shall contain an indication of intention to request the surrender of the person
                sought, a statement of the existence of a warrant of arrest or a judgment of
                conviction against that person, information concerning identity, nationality and
                probable location, a description of the person, a brief description of the offence
                and the facts of the case and a statement of the sentence that can be or has been
                imposed for the offence and, where applicable, how much of that sentence remains to
                be served.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_038"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>An application for provisional arrest may
                be transmitted by any means affording a record in writing through the consular
                channel or directly between the Department of Justice of the Hong Kong Special
                Administrative Region and Procuradoria-Geral da
                República
                of the Portuguese Republic. The facilities of the International Criminal Police
                Organisation may also be used to transmit such requests.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_039"><content>(4)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The provisional arrest of the person
                sought shall be terminated upon the expiration of sixty days from the date of arrest
                if the request for surrender and supporting documents have not been received. The
                release of a person pursuant to this paragraph shall not prevent the institution or
                continuation of surrender proceedings if the request and the supporting documents
                are received
                subsequently.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                14</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">CONCURRENT
            REQUESTS<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_48">If the surrender of a
            person is requested concurrently by one of the Parties and a State with whom the
            Portuguese Republic or the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, whichever is being
            requested, has agreements or arrangements for the surrender of accused and convicted
            persons, the requested Party shall make its decision having regard to all the
            circumstances including the provisions in this regard in any agreements in force between
            the requested Party and the requesting Parties, the relative seriousness and place of
            commission of the offences, the respective dates of the requests, the nationality and
            ordinary place of residence of the person sought and the possibility of subsequent
            surrender to another state, and furnish the other Party with information justifying its
            decision in the event of surrender of the person to another
            jurisdiction.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                15</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">REPRESENTATION AND
            COSTS<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_040"><content>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The requested Party shall make all
                necessary arrangements for and meet the costs of any proceedings arising out of a
                request for surrender and shall otherwise represent the interests of the requesting
                Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_041"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If it becomes apparent that exceptional
                expenses may be incurred as a result of a request for surrender the Parties shall
                consult with a view to deciding how these expenses will be met.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_042"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The requested Party shall bear the
                expenses arising out of the arrest and detention of the person whose surrender is
                sought until that person is surrendered. The requesting Party shall bear all
                subsequent expenses.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                16</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">ARRANGEMENTS FOR
            SURRENDER<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_043"><content>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The requested Party shall, as soon as a
                decision on the request for surrender has been made, communicate that decision to
                the requesting Party.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973335_044"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>When a person is to be surrendered, that
                person shall be sent by the authorities of the requested Party to such convenient
                place of departure within that Party’s jurisdiction as the requesting Party shall
                indicate.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_045"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Subject to the provisions of paragraph
                (4) of this Article, the requesting Party shall remove the person within the period
                specified by the requested Party and if the person is not removed within that period
                the requested Party may refuse to surrender that person for the same
                offence.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_046"><content>(4)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>If circumstances beyond its control
                prevent a Party from surrendering or taking over the person to be surrendered, it
                shall notify the other Party. In that case, the two Parties shall agree a new date
                for surrender and the provisions of paragraph (3) of this Article shall
                apply.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                17</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">SURRENDER OF
            PROPERTY<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_047"><leadIn>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>To the extent permitted under the law of
                the requested Party, when a request for surrender of a fugitive offender is granted,
                the requested Party:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_048" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>shall hand over to the requesting Party all articles, including sums of
                    money,</leadIn></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_72 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_049" name="i" temporalId="sch0_0_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>which may serve as proof of the offence; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_72 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_050" name="ii" temporalId="sch0_0_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>which have been acquired by the person sought as a result of the offence
                    and are in that person’s possession or are discovered subsequently.</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_051" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>may, if the articles in question are liable to seizure or confiscation
                    within the jurisdiction of the requested Party in connection with pending
                    proceedings, temporarily retain them or hand them over on condition they are
                    returned.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_052"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The provisions of paragraph (1) shall not
                prejudice the rights of the requested Party or of any person other than the person
                sought. When such rights exist the articles shall on request be returned to the
                requested Party without charge as soon as practicable after the end of the
                proceedings.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_053"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The articles in question shall, if the
                requesting Party so requests, be surrendered to that Party even if the surrender
                cannot be carried out due to the death or escape of the person
                sought.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                18</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">SPECIALTY AND
            RESURRENDER<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_054"><leadIn>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>A fugitive offender who has been
                surrendered shall not be proceeded against, sentenced, detained or subjected to any
                other restriction of personal liberty by the requesting Party for any offence
                committed prior to his surrender other than:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_055" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the offence or offences in respect of which his surrender was
                    granted;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_056" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>an offence, however described, based on substantially the same facts in
                    respect of which his surrender was granted, provided such offence is one for
                    which he could be surrendered under this Agreement, and provided further such
                    offence is punishable by a penalty no more severe than the penalty for the
                    offence for which he was surrendered;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_057" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(c)</num><content>any other offence for which surrender may be granted under this Agreement
                    in respect of which the requested Party may consent to his being dealt
                    with,</content></subparagraph><continued class="align_justified left_indent_0">unless he has first had an opportunity
                to exercise his right to leave the jurisdiction of the Party to which he has been
                surrendered and he has not done so within forty days or has voluntarily returned to
                that jurisdiction having left it.</continued></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_058"><leadIn>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>A fugitive offender who has been
                surrendered shall not be re-surrendered to another jurisdiction for an offence
                committed prior to his surrender unless:</leadIn><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_059" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the requested Party consents to such re-surrender; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph class="align_justified left_indent_48 first_line_indent_-22" id="ID_1525312973350_060" name="a" temporalId="sch0_0_a"><num value="a">(b)</num><content>he has first had an opportunity to exercise his right to leave the
                    jurisdiction of the Party to which he has been surrendered and has not done so
                    within forty days or has voluntarily returned to that jurisdiction having left
                    it.</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973350_061"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>A Party whose consent is requested under
                paragraphs <ref>(1)(c)</ref> or <ref>(2)(a)</ref> of this Article may require the
                submission of any document or statement referred to in Article 9, and any statement
                made by the surrendered person on the
                matter.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold"><inline class="underline">ARTICLE
                19</inline></inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="align_center">ENTRY INTO FORCE SUSPENSION AND
            TERMINATION<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973366_062"><content>(1)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>This Agreement shall enter into force
                thirty days after the date on which the Parties have notified each other in writing
                that their respective requirements for the entry into force of this Agreement have
                been complied with.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973366_063"><content>(2)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>The provisions of this Agreement shall
                apply to requests made after its entry into force regardless of the date of the
                commission of the offence or offences set out in the request.</content></paragraph><paragraph name="0" temporalId="sch0_0" class="align_justified left_indent_0" id="ID_1525312973366_064"><content>(3)<fillIn class="width_36"> </fillIn>Each of the Parties may suspend or
                terminate this Agreement at any time by giving notice to the other through the
                channel referred to in paragraph (1) of Article 9. Suspension shall take effect on
                receipt of the relevant notice. In the case of termination the Agreement shall cease
                to have effect six months after the receipt of notice to
                terminate.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></content></paragraph><text name="3" temporalId="sch0_19_3" class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">In witness whereof the
            undersigned, being duly authorised by their respective governments, have signed this
            Agreement.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text name="3" temporalId="sch0_19_3" class="align_justified left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24">Done at the Hong Kong Special
            Administrative Region, this twenty-fourth day of May Two Thousand and One in duplicate
            in the Chinese, Portuguese and English languages, each text being equally
            authentic.</text></schedule></main></subLeg>