<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 501 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>501A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap501A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2013-12-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403282222_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2012-08-02">Enduring Powers of Attorney (Prescribed Form) Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap501/s18">Cap. 501, section 18</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2012/er2">E.R. 2 of 2012</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[27 June 1997]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1997/ln365">L.N. 365 of 1997</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2012/er2">E.R. 2 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403282238_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2012/er2">E.R. 2 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403282238_003" name="s1A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-07-03" status="operational" temporalId="s1A"><num value="1A">1A.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation—</leadIn><def name="Form1"><term>Form 1</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">表格1</term>) means the form set out in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>;</def><def name="Form2"><term>Form 2</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">表格2</term>) means the form set out in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>.</def><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403282253_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-07-03" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Prescribed form</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412802385_032" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An instrument creating an enduring power of attorney which appoints only one attorney must be in Form 1.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802385_040" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An instrument creating an enduring power of attorney which appoints more than one attorney must be in Form 2.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802385_048" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If an instrument which purports to create an enduring power of attorney does not contain the explanatory information given under the heading “<b>Information you must read</b>” in Form 1 or Form 2, it does not create an enduring power of attorney.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802385_056" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An enduring power of attorney may include any conditions or restrictions that the donor specifies in <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of Part A of Form 1 or <ref>paragraph 4</ref> of Part A of Form 2 (as the case requires).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802401_005" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The form of execution by an attorney may be adapted to provide for execution by a trust corporation.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403282269_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-07-03" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Execution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412802416_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An instrument creating an enduring power of attorney must be signed by both the donor and the attorney, although not necessarily at the same time, in accordance with this section and <ref>section 5</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802416_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The attorney must sign in the presence of a witness.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802416_020" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The witness must sign the instrument and provide his or her full name and address in the instrument.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802416_028" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The donor must not witness the signature of the attorney nor one attorney witness the signature of another attorney.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802416_036" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The solicitor and the registered medical practitioner who certify as to the matters specified in <ref>sections 5(2)(d)</ref> and <ref>5(2)(e)</ref> of the Ordinance respectively must provide their full names and addresses in the instrument.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802432_005" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>If, under <ref>section 5(2)(b)</ref> of the Ordinance, the instrument is signed in the presence, and under the direction, of the donor, <ref>paragraph 8</ref> of Part A of Form 1 or <ref>paragraph 9</ref> of Part A of Form 2 (as the case requires) must be completed.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403282269_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-07-03" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Execution if more than one attorney is appointed</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412802448_051" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If more than one attorney is appointed and they are to act jointly and severally, then at least one of the attorneys so appointed must sign the instrument for it to take effect as an enduring power of attorney.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802448_059" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Only an attorney who has signed the instrument has the functions of an attorney under an enduring power of attorney in the event of the registration of the instrument under <ref>section 9</ref> of the Ordinance or the donor’s mental incapacity, whichever first occurs.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403282284_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Donor to specify decisions attorney may make</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412802494_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies for the purposes of <ref>section 8(1)</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802494_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The donor must—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412802494_020" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>specify, with reference to the list set out in subsection (3), the matters in which the attorney is given authority to act; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802494_028" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>specify the particular property or financial affairs in respect of which the attorney is given such authority.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802494_035" name="2A" temporalId="s5_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><content>To avoid doubt, subsection (2) is not to be construed as preventing the donor from specifying under both paragraphs of that subsection.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802494_043" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The list for the purposes of subsection <ref>(2)(a)</ref> is as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412802494_051" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to collect any income due to the donor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802494_059" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to collect any capital due to the
                    donor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802494_067" name="c" temporalId="s5_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to sell any of the donor’s movable property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802510_005" name="d" temporalId="s5_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to sell, lease or surrender the donor’s home or any of the donor’s immovable property;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802510_013" name="e" temporalId="s5_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to spend any of the donor’s income; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013 s. 58</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802510_021" name="f" temporalId="s5_3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to spend any of the donor’s capital.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013 s. 58</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802510_029" name="g" temporalId="s5_3_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013 s. 58</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403282300_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-07-03" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Nomination of persons to be notified</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412802526_067" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The donor may, in the instrument, nominate all or any of the following persons to be notified by the attorney applying for the registration of the instrument under <ref>section 9</ref> of the Ordinance before the application is made—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412802541_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the donor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802541_013" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any attorney who does not join in the application;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412802541_021" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a maximum of 2 other persons.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802541_028" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The donor must provide in the instrument the address of any person nominated under subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412802541_036" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the donor’s intention is not to make any nomination under subsection (1), the donor must indicate that intention by deleting <ref>paragraph 4</ref> of Part A of Form 1 or <ref>paragraph 5</ref> of Part A of Form 2 (as the case requires).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s. 12</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438405154768_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap501A/s1A">s. 1A</ref>]</note><heading>Form
            1<marker role="blank-line"></marker></heading><text class="first_line_indent_0"><ins><b>Information you must
            read</b></ins><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>1.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>This form is a legal document that allows you to
            create an enduring power of attorney (<i><b>EPA</b></i>). An EPA enables you to
            authorize another person (<i><b>your attorney</b></i>) to act on your behalf in relation
            to your property and financial affairs. You must use this form if you intend to appoint
            only one attorney. If you become mentally incapable, your attorney will be able to make
            decisions for you after your attorney has registered this form with the Registrar of the
            High
            Court.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>2.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><i>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013
                    s.
            59</ref>)</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>3.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>You must complete Part
            A.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>4.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 1</ref> of Part A:</b> You must
            include the name and address of the person you wish to appoint as your attorney at
                <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Part A. The person you appoint as your attorney must be
            over 18 years of age and must not be bankrupt or mentally incapable. Your attorney does
            not have to be a solicitor. Your attorney must complete Part B and sign this form in the
            presence of a
            witness.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>5.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 2</ref> of Part A:</b> You
            cannot give your attorney a general authority over all your property and financial
            affairs. If you do, your EPA will not be valid. Instead, you must specify at
                <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of Part A what you authorize your attorney to do with your
            property and financial affairs, or the particular property or financial affairs for
            which you have given your attorney authority to act. For example, you may decide to give
            your attorney authority only for a particular bank account, or a particular piece of
            property.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>6.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 3</ref> of Part A:</b> You may
            include any restrictions you like on the authority you give to your attorney. For
            example, you may include a restriction that your attorney must not act on your behalf
            until your attorney has reason to believe that you are becoming mentally incapable, or
            that your attorney must not enter into a contract without first seeking legal advice if
            its value exceeds a specified amount. You should set out these restrictions at
                <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of Part
            A.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>7.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>Unless you include a restriction preventing it,
            your attorney will be able to use any of your money or property to make any provision
            which you might be expected to make yourself for the needs of your attorney or the needs
            of other persons. Your attorney will be able to use your money to make gifts, but only
            for reasonable amounts in relation to the value of your money and
            property.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>8.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>Your attorney may recover out-of-pocket expenses
            for acting as your attorney. If your attorney is a professional person, such as an
            accountant or a solicitor, your attorney may charge for any professional services
            provided when acting as your
            attorney.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>9.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>If your attorney has reason to believe that you
            are, or are becoming, mentally incapable of managing your affairs, your attorney must
            apply to the Registrar of the High Court to register this EPA. Registration will allow
            your attorney to make decisions for you after you have become mentally
            incapable.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>10.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 4</ref> of Part A:</b> If you would
            like to be notified before your attorney applies to the Registrar of the High Court to
            register this EPA, or if you would like other persons to be notified, you must include
            the names and addresses of the persons to be notified at <ref>paragraph 4</ref> of Part
            A. You can include up to 2 persons to be notified in addition to yourself. If your
            attorney does not notify you or the persons you have nominated, that does not prevent
            the registration of your EPA or make it invalid. However, in any legal proceedings
            relating to the EPA the court may, if it considers it appropriate, draw an adverse
            inference from the failure to notify you or the nominated
            persons.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>11.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraphs 7</ref>, <ref>9</ref> and
                    <ref>10</ref> of Part A:</b> You must sign this form at <ref>paragraph 7</ref>
            of Part A and fill in the names and addresses of the registered medical practitioner and
            the solicitor who are present when you sign. If you do not sign in the presence of both
            the registered medical practitioner and the solicitor at the same time, you must sign
            the form in the presence of the solicitor no later than 28 days after the date on which
            you sign in the presence of the registered medical practitioner. The registered medical
            practitioner and the solicitor will need to complete the certificates at <ref>paragraphs
                9</ref> and <ref>10</ref> of Part A respectively to certify that you are mentally
            capable when you sign this
            form.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>12.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 8</ref> of Part A:</b> If you are
            physically incapable of signing this form yourself, you can direct someone else to sign
            on your behalf. In this case, <ref>paragraph 8</ref> of Part A must be completed and
            that person must sign at that paragraph in your presence and in the presence of the
            registered medical practitioner and the solicitor. The person signing on your behalf
            must not be your attorney, the spouse of your attorney, the registered medical
            practitioner or the solicitor before whom the instrument is signed or the spouse of the
            registered medical practitioner or the
            solicitor.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>13.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn>This form takes effect as an EPA in accordance with
                <ref>section 10</ref> of the Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>) when it is signed by you or the person signing on
            your behalf and under your direction before the solicitor. You should note that unless
            and until this form is so signed, it has no effect either as an EPA or an ordinary power
            of attorney. However, if you wish, you may choose a later date or later event, on which
            the EPA will take effect. In such case you must specify this later date or event in
                <ref>paragraph 5</ref> of Part
            A.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading class="align_left align_justified"><inline class="underline align_justified">Form of enduring power of attorney (for appointment of only one
            attorney)</inline></crossHeading><text class="align_left"><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>Part
                A</b></text><text><i>[This Part must be completed by the person appointing the attorney (</i><i><b>the
                    donor</b></i><i>), except for <ref>paragraphs 9</ref> and <ref>10</ref>, which
                must be completed by a registered medical practitioner and a solicitor respectively.
                You should read the explanatory information given under the heading
                </i>“<b>Information you must read</b>”<i> before you fill it in. Do not sign this
                form unless you understand what it
            means.]</i></text><text><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="89%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>1.</td>
                        <td><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Appointment of
                                attorney by
                                donor<marker role="blank-line"></marker></b></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">I, <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your name here] </i></td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">holder of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your identification
                                document here]</i></td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">of
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your
                                address here]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">appoint <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your attorney’s name
                                here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">holder of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[identification
                                document here] </i></td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your attorney’s
                                address here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified">to be my attorney under the Enduring
                            Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>).</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="73%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2.</td>
                        <td colspan="4"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Attorney’s
                                authority</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="4" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [You must specify
                                what you authorize your attorney to do. You cannot give a general
                                authority over all your property and financial affairs. </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>If you do, your
                                    EPA will not be valid</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">. You can </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>either</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> specify at
                                subparagraph (1) what you authorize your attorney to do by ticking
                                any or all of the appropriate boxes, </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>or</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> tick no box, in
                                which case you must list at subparagraph (2) the particular property
                                or financial affairs for which you have given your attorney
                                authority to act. If you have ticked any or all the boxes at
                                subparagraph (1), you may still list at subparagraph (2) any
                                particular property or financial affairs in relation to which you
                                have given your attorney authority to act. You must not make no
                                ticks at subparagraph (1) </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>and</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> list no property at
                                subparagraph
                            (2).]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(1)</td>
                        <td colspan="3">My attorney has authority to act on my
                            behalf:<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td>to collect any income due to
                            me;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td>to collect any capital due to
                            me;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(c)</td>
                        <td>to sell any of my movable
                            property;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(d)</td>
                        <td>to sell, lease or surrender my home or any of my immovable
                            property;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(e)</td>
                        <td>to spend any of my
                            income;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(f)</td>
                        <td>to spend any of my capital.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013 s.
                            59</ref>)</sourceNote><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(g)</td>
                        <td><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013 s.
                            59</ref>)</sourceNote><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(2)</td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="align_justified">My attorney has authority to act on
                            my behalf in respect of the following property or financial affairs: <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you want your
                                attorney to act for you only in relation to some of your property or
                                financial affairs, you must list them
                            here.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>3.</td>
                        <td><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Restrictions on
                                attorney</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">This enduring power of attorney is subject to
                            the following conditions and restrictions: <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you want to put
                                conditions or restrictions on the way your attorney exercises any
                                powers, you must list them here. For example, you may include a
                                restriction that your attorney must not act on your behalf until
                                your attorney has reason to believe that you are becoming mentally
                                incapable. If you do not want to impose any conditions or
                                restrictions, you must delete this
                            paragraph.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="85%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>4.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Notification of named
                            persons</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [If you do not want
                                anyone (including yourself) to be notified of the application for
                                the registration of this EPA, you must delete subparagraphs (1)
                                </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>and</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">
                                (2).]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(1)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">My attorney must notify me before applying for
                            the registration of this enduring power of attorney. <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you do not want
                                to be notified, you must delete this
                            subparagraph.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(2)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">My attorney must notify the following persons
                            before applying for the registration of this enduring power of attorney.
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[Fill in the names
                                and addresses of up to 2 persons (other than yourself) to be
                                notified. If you do not want other persons to be notified, you must
                                delete this
                            subparagraph.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Name: </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Address: </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Name: </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Address: </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <col width="89%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>5.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Commencement of
                            EPA</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [This EPA takes
                                effect on the date it is signed before the solicitor in
                                    <ref>paragraph 7</ref> or <ref>8</ref> below. If you want to
                                specify a later date or later event on which this EPA will take
                                effect, please fill in the gap in the sentence marked with an
                                asterisk below. Delete that sentence if you wish this EPA to take
                                effect on the date it is signed before the
                            solicitor.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>*</td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">This EPA takes effect on </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td><fillIn xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class=" width_174">.</fillIn>(insert a later date or event).</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>6.</td>
                        <td><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Power to
                            continue</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">I intend this enduring power of attorney to
                            continue even if I become mentally incapable.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>7.</td>
                        <td><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Signatures</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">Signed by me as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[sign here] </i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_. align_justified">in the presence of<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [name and address of
                                registered medical practitioner] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">Signed
                            by me as a deed [<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">sign
                                here]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">in the presence of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name and address of
                                solicitor] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="89%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>8.</td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you are
                                physically incapable of signing this form and you direct someone
                                else to sign on your behalf, that person must sign here and
                                    <ref>paragraph 7</ref> must be
                            deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_. align_justified">This enduring power of
                            attorney has been signed by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name of person
                                signing on your behalf]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">holder of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[identification
                                document] </i>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[address of person
                                signing on your behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_." colspan="2"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">under the direction and in the presence of the donor.</td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified leaders_."> Signed as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature of person
                                signing on your behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_. align_justified">in the presence of the
                            donor and <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name and
                                address of registered medical practitioner] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_." colspan="2"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified leaders_.">Signed as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature of person
                                signing on your behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">in the presence of the donor and <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name and address of
                                solicitor] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_." colspan="2"></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="76%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>9.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Certificate by registered medical
                            practitioner</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">I certify
                            that:<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">I am satisfied that the donor is mentally
                            capable in terms of <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 2</ref> of the Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>);
                            and<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">this form was signed by the donor in my presence
                            and the donor acknowledged signing it voluntarily. <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If someone else
                                signs this form on the donor’s behalf, this statement must be
                                deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (c)</td>
                        <td class="leaders_. align_justified">this form was signed, in the presence
                            of the donor and me, by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name of person
                                signing on donor’s behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">on behalf and under the direction of the donor.
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If the donor
                                signs this form, this statement must be
                            deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">Signed
                            by registered medical practitioner </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>on
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="76%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>10.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Certificate by
                            solicitor</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">I certify
                            that:<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">the donor appears to be mentally capable in
                            terms of <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                2</ref> of the Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>);
                            and<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">this form was signed by the donor in my presence
                            and the donor acknowledged signing it voluntarily. <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If someone else
                                signs this form on the donor’s behalf, this statement must be
                                deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (c)</td>
                        <td class="leaders_. align_justified">this form was signed, in the presence
                            of the donor and me, by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name of person
                                signing on donor’s behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified"> on behalf and under the direction of the donor.
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If the donor
                                signs this form, this statement must be deleted.]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>Signed
                            by solicitor </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>on
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><crossHeading class="align_left">Part
            B</crossHeading><text><i>[This Part must
                be completed by the
                attorney.]</i><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td>1.</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">I understand that I have a duty to apply to the
                            Registrar of the High Court to register this form under the Enduring
                            Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>) when the donor is, or is becoming, mentally
                            incapable.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2.</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">I also understand my limited power to use the
                            donor’s property to benefit persons other than the donor as provided in
                                <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                8(3)</ref> and (4) of that Ordinance and also my duties and
                            liabilities under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 12</ref> of that
                            Ordinance.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>3.</td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Signed by me as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature of
                                attorney] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_. align_justified">in the presence of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature and name
                                and address of witness, who must not be the donor]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_right"><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref>Schedule
                                    1</ref> replaced <ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s.
                                13</ref>)</sourceNote></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table></text></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403282378_001" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2013-12-01" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule 2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap501A/s1A">s. 1A</ref>]</note><heading>Form 2</heading><text class="first_line_indent_0"><ins><b>Information you must
            read</b></ins><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>1.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>This form is a legal document that allows you to
            create an enduring power of attorney (<i><b>EPA</b></i>). An EPA enables you to
            authorize another person to act on your behalf in relation to your property and
            financial affairs. You must use this form if you intend to appoint more than one person
            to act on your behalf. If you become mentally incapable, the persons you have appointed
                    (<i><b>your attorneys</b></i>) will be able to make decisions for you after they
            have registered this form with the Registrar of the High
            Court.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>2.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><i>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013
                    s.
            60</ref>)</i><marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>3.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 2</ref> of Part A:</b> You must
            decide whether your attorneys are to act—</text><paragraph name="a" temporalId="sch2_a" class="left_indent_72 first_line_indent_-24" id="ID_1522125582375_001"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>jointly (that is, they must all act together and cannot act separately);
                or</content></paragraph><paragraph name="b" temporalId="sch2_b" class="left_indent_72 first_line_indent_-24" id="ID_1522125582375_002"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>jointly and severally (that is, they can all act together but they can also act
                separately if they wish).</content></paragraph><text>You must indicate your decision at <ref>paragraph 2</ref> of Part A. You should note
            that if your attorneys are to act jointly, on the bankruptcy or death of any one of them
            this power of attorney becomes revoked under
            law.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>4.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>You must complete Part
            A.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>5.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 1</ref> of Part A:</b> You must
            include the names and addresses of the persons you wish to appoint as your attorneys at
                <ref>paragraph 1</ref> of Part A. The persons you appoint as your attorneys must be
            over 18 years of age and must not be bankrupt or mentally incapable. Your attorneys do
            not have to be solicitors. Your attorneys must complete Part B and each of them must
            sign this form in the presence of a
            witness.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>6.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 3</ref> of Part A:</b> You
            cannot give your attorneys a general authority over all your property and financial
            affairs. If you do, your EPA will not be valid. Instead, you must specify at
                <ref>paragraph 3</ref> of Part A what you authorize your attorneys to do with your
            property and financial affairs, or the particular property or financial affairs for
            which you have given your attorneys authority to act. For example, you may decide to
            give your attorneys authority only for a particular bank account, or a particular piece
            of
            property.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>7.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 4</ref> of Part A:</b> You may
            include any restrictions you like on the authority you give to your attorneys. For
            example, you may include a restriction that your attorneys must not act on your behalf
            until they have reason to believe that you are becoming mentally incapable, or that your
            attorneys must not enter into a contract without first seeking legal advice if its value
            exceeds a specified amount. You should set out these restrictions at <ref>paragraph
                4</ref> of Part
            A.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>8.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>Unless you include a restriction preventing it,
            your attorneys will be able to use any of your money or property to make any provision
            which you might be expected to make yourself for the needs of your attorneys or the
            needs of other persons. Your attorneys will be able to use your money to make gifts, but
            only for reasonable amounts in relation to the value of your money and
            property.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>9.<fillIn class="width_18"> </fillIn>Your attorneys may recover out-of-pocket expenses
            for acting as your attorneys. If any of your attorneys is a professional person, such as
            an accountant or a solicitor, that attorney may charge for any professional services
            provided when acting as your
            attorney.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>10.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn>If your attorneys have reason to believe that you are, or
            are becoming, mentally incapable of managing your affairs, they must apply to the
            Registrar of the High Court to register this EPA. Registration will allow your attorneys
            to make decisions for you after you have become mentally
            incapable.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>11.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 5</ref> of Part A:</b> If you would
            like to be notified before your attorneys apply to the Registrar of the High Court to
            register this EPA, or if you would like other persons to be notified, you must include
            the names and addresses of the persons to be notified at <ref>paragraph 5</ref> of Part
            A. If you have decided that your attorneys may act separately, you may also nominate any
            of your attorneys not joining in the application to be notified. You can include up to 2
            persons to be notified in addition to yourself and any attorney not joining in the
            application. If your attorneys do not notify you or the persons you have nominated, that
            does not prevent the registration of your EPA or make it invalid. However, in any legal
            proceedings relating to the EPA the court may, if it considers it appropriate, draw an
            adverse inference from the failure to notify you or the nominated
            persons.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>12.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraphs 8</ref>, <ref>10</ref> and
                    <ref>11</ref> of Part A:</b> You must sign this form at <ref>paragraph 8</ref>
            of Part A and fill in the names and addresses of the registered medical practitioner and
            the solicitor who are present when you sign. If you do not sign in the presence of both
            the registered medical practitioner and the solicitor at the same time, you must sign
            the form in the presence of the solicitor no later than 28 days after the date on which
            you sign in the presence of the registered medical practitioner. The registered medical
            practitioner and the solicitor will need to complete the certificates at <ref>paragraphs
                10</ref> and <ref>11</ref> of Part A respectively to certify that you are mentally
            capable when you sign this
            form.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>13.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn><b><ref>Paragraph 9</ref> of Part A:</b> If you are
            physically incapable of signing this form yourself, you can direct someone else to sign
            on your behalf. In this case, <ref>paragraph 9</ref> of Part A must be completed and
            that person must sign at that paragraph in your presence and in the presence of the
            registered medical practitioner and the solicitor. The person signing on your behalf
            must not be one of your attorneys, the spouse of any one of your attorneys, the
            registered medical practitioner or the solicitor before whom the instrument is signed or
            the spouse of the registered medical practitioner or the
            solicitor.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text>14.<fillIn class="width_12"> </fillIn>This form takes effect as an EPA in accordance with
                <ref>section 10</ref> of the Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>) when it is signed by you or the person signing on
            your behalf and under your direction before the solicitor. You should note that unless
            and until this form is so signed, it has no effect either as an EPA or an ordinary power
            of attorney. However, if you wish, you may choose a later date or later event, on which
            the EPA will take effect. In such case you must specify this later date or event in
                <ref>paragraph 6</ref> of Part A.</text><crossHeading class="align_left"><inline class="underline align_justified">Form of enduring
                power of attorney (for appointment of more than one
            attorney)</inline></crossHeading><text class="align_left"><marker role="blank-line"></marker><b>Part
                A</b></text><text class="align_justified"><i>[This Part must be completed by the person appointing the
                attorneys (</i><i><b>the donor</b></i><i>), except for <ref>paragraphs 10</ref> and
                    <ref>11</ref>, which must be completed by a registered medical practitioner and
                a solicitor respectively. You should read the explanatory information given under
                the heading</i>
            “<b>Information
                you must
                read</b>”<i>
                before you fill it in. Do not sign this form unless you understand what it
                means.]</i></text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="74%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>1.</td>
                        <td colspan="3"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Appointment of attorneys by
                                donor<marker role="blank-line"></marker></b></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">I, <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your name here]
                            </i></td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">holder of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your identification
                                document here] </i></td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_.">of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your address here]
                            </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3">appoint<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_center"> (a)</td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your attorney’s name
                                here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">holder of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[identification
                                document here] </i></td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your attorney’s
                                address here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                        <td class="align_right">;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>and<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="1" class="align_center"> (b)</td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your attorney’s name
                                here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">holder of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[identification
                                document here] </i></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[your attorney’s
                                address here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="align_justfied"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="align_justified"> [If you appoint more than 2 attorneys,
                                please add additional subparagraph(s) similar to subparagraphs (a)
                                and
                            (b).]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="align_justified">to be my attorneys under the
                            Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>).</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="76%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Whether
                                attorneys must act
                            jointly</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [You must decide
                                whether your attorneys are to act (a) jointly; </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>or</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> (b) jointly and
                                severally. See <ref>paragraph 3</ref> under the heading </i>“<b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Information you must
                                read</b>”<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> and
                                delete either (a) or (b) from the statement below. </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>If you do not,
                                    your EPA will not be valid.</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">My attorneys appointed under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">paragraph 1</ref> are
                            to
                            act—<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_center"> (a)</td>
                        <td>jointly.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_center"><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="align_center"><i>or</i></b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_center"> (b)</td>
                        <td>jointly and severally.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="73%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>3.</td>
                        <td colspan="4"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Attorneys’
                                authority</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="4" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [You must specify
                                what you authorize your attorneys to do. You cannot give a general
                                authority over all your property and financial affairs. </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>If you do, your
                                    EPA will not be valid.</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> You can</i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b> either</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> specify at
                                subparagraph (1) what you authorize your attorneys to do by ticking
                                any or all of the appropriate boxes, </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>or</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> tick no box, in
                                which case you must list at subparagraph (2) the particular property
                                or financial affairs for which you have given your attorneys
                                authority to act. If you have ticked any or all the boxes at
                                subparagraph (1), you may still list at subparagraph (2) any
                                particular property or financial affairs in relation to which you
                                have given your attorneys authority to act. You must not make no
                                ticks at subparagraph (1) </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>and</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> list no property at
                                subparagraph
                            (2).]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(1)</td>
                        <td colspan="3">My attorneys have authority to act on my
                            behalf:<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td>to collect any income due to
                            me;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td>to collect any capital due to
                            me;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(c)</td>
                        <td>to sell any of my movable
                            property;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(d)</td>
                        <td>to sell, lease or surrender my home or any of my immovable
                            property;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(e)</td>
                        <td>to spend any of my
                            income;<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(f)</td>
                        <td>to spend any of my capital.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013 s.
                            60</ref>)</sourceNote><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>□</td>
                        <td>(g)</td>
                        <td><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2013/13">13 of 2013 s.
                            60</ref>)</sourceNote><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(2)</td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="align_justified">My attorneys have authority to act
                            on my behalf in respect of the following property or financial affairs:
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you want your
                                attorneys to act for you only in relation to some of your property
                                or financial affairs, you must list them here.]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>4.</td>
                        <td><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Restrictions on
                                attorneys</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">This enduring power of attorney is subject to
                            the following conditions and restrictions:<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [If you want to put
                                conditions or restrictions on the way your attorneys exercise any
                                powers, you must list them here. For example, you may include a
                                restriction that your attorneys must not act on your behalf until
                                they have reason to believe that you are becoming mentally
                                incapable. If you do not want to impose any conditions or
                                restrictions, you must delete this
                            paragraph.]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    
                    
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="85%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>5.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Notification of named
                            persons</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [If you do not want
                                anyone (including yourself) to be notified of the application for
                                the registration of this EPA, you must delete subparagraphs (1), (2)
                                </i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><b>and</b></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">
                                (3).]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(1)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">My attorneys must notify me before applying for
                            the registration of this enduring power of attorney. <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you do not want
                                to be notified, you must delete this
                            subparagraph.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(2)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">Any attorney applying for the registration of
                            this enduring power of attorney must, before the application is made,
                            notify any attorney not joining in the application. <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you decide that
                                your attorneys may act separately and you do not require any
                                attorney applying for the registration of this EPA to notify any
                                attorney not joining in the application, you must delete this
                                subparagraph.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(3)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">My attorneys must notify the following persons
                            before applying for the registration of this enduring power of attorney.
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[Fill in the names
                                and addresses of up to 2 persons (other than yourself or any of your
                                attorneys) to be notified. If you do not want other persons to be
                                notified, you must delete this
                            subparagraph.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Name: </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Address:</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Name: </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">Address:</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <col width="89%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>6.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Commencement of
                            EPA</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [This EPA takes
                                effect on the date it is signed before the solicitor in
                                    <ref>paragraph 8</ref> or <ref>9</ref> below. If you want to
                                specify a later date or later event on which this EPA will take
                                effect, please fill in the gap in the sentence marked with an
                                asterisk below. Delete that sentence if you wish this EPA to take
                                effect on the date it is signed before the
                            solicitor.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>*</td>
                        <td class="leaders_.">This EPA takes effect on </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td><fillIn xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class=" width_165">.</fillIn> (insert a later date or event).</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>7.</td>
                        <td><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Power to
                            continue</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">I intend this enduring power of attorney to
                            continue even if I become mentally incapable.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="91%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>8.</td>
                        <td><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Signatures</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">Signed by me as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[sign here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_. align_justified">in the presence of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name and address of
                                registered medical practitioner] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_."><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>Signed
                            by me as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[sign
                                here] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">in the presence of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name and address of
                                solicitor] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="87%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>9.</td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If you are
                                physically incapable of signing this form and you direct someone
                                else to sign on your behalf, that person must sign here and
                                    <ref>paragraph 8</ref> must be
                            deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_. align_justified">This enduring power of
                            attorney has been signed by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name of person
                                signing on your behalf]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_.">holder of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[identification
                                document here] </i></td>
                        <td class="align_right">,</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">of<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [address of person
                                signing on your behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_." colspan="2"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">under the direction and in the presence of the donor.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified leaders_."><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>Signed
                            as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature
                                of person signing on your behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_. align_justified">in the presence of the
                            donor and <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name and
                                address of registered medical practitioner] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified leaders_."><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>Signed
                            as a deed <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature
                                of person signing on your behalf] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">in the presence of the donor and <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name and address of
                                solicitor] </i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="76%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>10.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Certificate by registered medical
                            practitioner</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">I certify
                            that:<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">I am satisfied that the donor is mentally
                            capable in terms of <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 2</ref> of the Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>);
                            and<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">this form was signed by the donor in my presence
                            and the donor acknowledged signing it voluntarily. <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If someone else
                                signs this form on the donor’s behalf, this statement must be
                                deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (c)</td>
                        <td class="leaders_. align_justified">this form was signed, in the presence
                            of the donor and me, by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name of person
                                signing on donor’s behalf]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified"> on behalf and under the direction of the donor.
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If the donor
                                signs this form, this statement must be deleted.]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>Signed
                            by registered medical practitioner </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
            
        </text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="76%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>11.</td>
                        <td colspan="2"><b xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Certificate by
                            solicitor</b><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2">I certify
                            that:<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">the donor appears to be mentally capable in
                            terms of <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                2</ref> of the Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>);
                            and<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">this form was signed by the donor in my presence
                            and the donor acknowledged signing it voluntarily. <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If someone else
                                signs this form on the donor’s behalf, this statement must be
                                deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_right cellpadding_right_10"> (c)</td>
                        <td class="leaders_. align_justified">this
                            form was signed, in the presence of the donor and me, by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[name of person
                                signing on donor’s behalf]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified">on behalf and under the direction of the donor.
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[If the donor
                                signs this form, this statement must be
                            deleted.]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">Signed
                            by solicitor
                            </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on
                                <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date]</i>
                            </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
        </text><crossHeading class="align_left">Part
            B</crossHeading><text class="align_justified"><i>[This Part must be completed by the attorneys. If you
                decide that your attorneys may act separately, then at least one of the attorneys
                appointed must sign this form for it to take effect as an EPA. An attorney will have
                the functions of an attorney under this EPA only if that attorney has signed this
                form.]</i></text><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" class="cellpadding_bottom_3">
                <col width="9%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="74%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>1.</td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="align_justified">We understand that we have a duty to
                            apply to the Registrar of the High Court to register this form under the
                            Enduring Powers of Attorney Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap501">Cap. 501</ref>) when the donor is, or is becoming, mentally
                            incapable.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2.</td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="align_justified">We also understand our limited power
                            to use the donor’s property to benefit persons other than the donor as
                            provided in <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                8(3)</ref> and (4) of that Ordinance and also our duties and
                            liabilities under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 12</ref> of that
                            Ordinance.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>3.</td>
                        <td colspan="3">Signed as a
                            deed—<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_center"> (a)</td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature and name
                                of attorney]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_. align_justified">in the presence of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature and name
                                and address of witness, who must not be the donor or another
                                attorney of the donor]</i></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_."></td>
                        <td class="align_right">;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>and<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="align_center"> (b)</td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature and name
                                of attorney]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_.">on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[date]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_. align_justified">in the presence of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">[signature and name
                                and address of witness, who must not be the donor or another
                                attorney of the donor]</i>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="leaders_."></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="leaders_." colspan="2"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="align_justified"><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> [If you appoint more
                                than 2 attorneys, please add additional subparagraph(s) similar to
                                subparagraphs (a) and
                            (b).]</i><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="3" class="align_right"><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref>Schedule
                                    2</ref> added <ref href="/hk/2011/25">25 of 2011 s.
                                14</ref>)</sourceNote></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>