<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 364 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>364A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap364A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403067472_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-12-02">The Hong Kong
            Association of Banks
            By-laws</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap364/s6">Cap.
                364,
                section
            6</ref>)</enactingFormula><commencementNote>[13 March 1981]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403067488_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>These by-laws may be cited as
                <shortTitle>The
                Hong Kong Association of Banks By-laws</shortTitle>.</content></section><part id="ID_1438403067488_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>The
            Committee</heading><section id="ID_1438403067503_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2025-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Nomination of elected members of the Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412100758_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Notice of an annual general meeting at which an election of elected
                                members of the Committee is to take place (hereinafter in this Part
                                called an
                                                <b><i>electoral
                                                general
                                meeting</i></b>)
                                shall be sent by the Secretary to all members not less than 30 days
                                prior to the date of the meeting and shall be accompanied by blank
                                nomination forms.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100774_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A member who is a candidate for election to the Committee under
                                        <ref>section 8(1)(b)(i)</ref> of the Ordinance
                                must
                                be nominated by 5 other members each of which is either incorporated
                                in Hong Kong or is a re-domiciled entity.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1986/27">27 of 1986 s. 137</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1990/43">43 of 1990 s.
                                        16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s.
                                        214</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100774_013" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A member who is a candidate for election to the Committee under
                                        <ref>section 8(1)(b)(ii)</ref> of the Ordinance
                                must
                                be nominated by 5 other members that are incorporated outside Hong
                                Kong and are not re-domiciled entities.
                                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s.
                                        214</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1748336544809_001" name="3A" temporalId="s2_3A"><num value="3A">(3A)</num><content>However, a member ceases to be a candidate for election to the
                                Committee if, after the nomination, any member who made the
                                nomination becomes a re-domiciled entity. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s.
                                        214</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1748336544840_002" name="3B" temporalId="s2_3B"><num value="3B">(3B)</num><content>Nothing in paragraph (3A) prevents a member who has ceased to be a
                                candidate by reason of that paragraph from being nominated again in
                                accordance with these by-laws. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s. 214</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100774_021" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The nominations referred to in paragraphs (2) and (3) shall
                                be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412100774_029" name="a" temporalId="s2_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in writing;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100774_037" name="b" temporalId="s2_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>signed on behalf of the 5 nominating members; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100789_006" name="c" temporalId="s2_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>accompanied by a notice in writing signed on behalf of the
                                        candidate indicating willingness to serve on the Committee,
                                        if elected.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100789_013" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The nomination papers and notices referred to in paragraph (4)
                                shall be lodged with the Secretary not less than 18 days prior to
                                the electoral general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100789_021" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A candidate may, by notice in writing addressed to the Secretary,
                                withdraw at any time before the election is held.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100789_029" name="7" temporalId="s2_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The Secretary shall, not less than 14 days prior to an electoral
                                general meeting, send to each member a notice containing the names
                                of the candidates nominated for election to the Committee under
                                        <ref>section 8(1)(b)(i)</ref> and <ref>8(1)(b)(ii)</ref> of
                                the Ordinance respectively and a list of the members eligible to
                                vote in each category.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067503_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Term of office of elected members</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412100836_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The first annual general meeting of the Association shall be an electoral general meeting and thereafter every third subsequent annual general meeting shall be an electoral general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100836_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All elected members shall retire at the conclusion of the next electoral general meeting after the meeting at which they were elected but shall be eligible for re-election.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067519_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Procedure for election</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412100852_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If the number of members nominated under <ref>by-law 2</ref> for election to the Committee at an electoral general meeting—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412100852_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>does not exceed the number of members to be elected from either category, then the candidates nominated from that category shall be deemed to have been duly elected with effect from the conclusion of that meeting;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100852_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>exceeds the number of the members to be elected in either category, the election shall be determined by ballot of the members in the relevant category present at that meeting, and the member or members receiving the largest number of votes shall be elected; and in the event of equality in votes the selection of membership of the Committee shall be determined by the drawing of lots between the candidates whose votes are equal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100867_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>is less than the number of members to be elected in either category, a fresh election shall be held to fill any vacancy remaining unfilled at the conclusion of that meeting, which fresh election shall proceed as if it were an election held under <ref>by-law 5</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100867_013" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If a ballot is required under paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref>, ballot papers shall be distributed to members present at the meeting in the respective categories provided under <ref>section 8(1)(b)(i)</ref> or <ref>8(1)(b)(ii)</ref> of the Ordinance as the case may be, and such ballot papers shall list the names of the candidates in the category in alphabetical order and indicate the number of members to be elected in that category.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100883_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Upon a ballot under paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref> the members in each category present and voting at the meeting shall mark the names of the candidates nominated for whom they vote as elected members, and no member shall, when so voting, mark more or fewer names than there are members to be elected; and if any member shall do so its vote shall be disqualified.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100883_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Ballots in each category shall be counted separately, and scrutineers shall be appointed by the Chairman of the electoral general meeting to prepare as soon as practicable the result of the ballot showing the votes cast for each candidate; and the scrutineers shall give the result to the Chairman of that meeting who shall announce the names of the successful candidates without revealing the votes cast for each candidate.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067534_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Filling of casual vacancies on the Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412100930_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a casual vacancy occurs among the elected members of the Committee, that vacancy shall be filled by election in accordance with this by-law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100930_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Upon the vacancy occurring, the Committee shall call a general meeting for the purpose of an election to fill that vacancy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100930_020" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Notice of the general meeting called under paragraph (2) shall be sent by the Secretary to all members from the category under <ref>section 8(1)(b)</ref> of the Ordinance in respect of which the vacancy has occurred not less than 30 days prior to the date of the meeting and the notice shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412100930_028" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notify members of the vacancy;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100930_036" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>specify the day, time and place for the holding of the meeting;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100930_044" name="c" temporalId="s5_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>call for nominations in respect of that vacancy; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100930_052" name="d" temporalId="s5_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>be accompanied by blank nomination forms.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100930_059" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><ref>By-laws 2</ref> and <ref>4</ref> shall apply to an election held under this by-law with such modifications as are necessary to make them applicable to the circumstances.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100945_005" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A member elected in an election held under this by-law shall hold office until the conclusion of the next electoral general meeting.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067534_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Vacation of office</heading><leadIn>An elected member shall be deemed to have vacated its office as a member of the Committee if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412100977_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it resigns office, by notice in writing to the Secretary;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100977_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it is absent without permission of the Chairman of the Committee from 3 consecutive meetings of the Committee of which it has had due notice, and the Committee resolves that its office be vacated; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412100977_028" name="c" temporalId="s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>it ceases to belong to the category of members to which it belonged when elected as a member of the Committee.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403067566_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Quorum for Committee meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412100992_027" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (2), 8 members of the Committee, 2 of whom shall be continuing members, shall form a quorum at a meeting of the Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412100992_035" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the business to be transacted at a Committee meeting includes consideration of the recommendations made by a Disciplinary Committee under <ref>section 21(1)</ref> of the Ordinance, 10 members, 2 of whom shall be continuing members, shall form a quorum at that meeting.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067566_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Notice of Committee meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101008_019" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Secretary shall give to each member of the Committee not less than 2
                days’
                notice of Committee meetings, but a meeting may be called at shorter notice at the
                request of the Chairman or Vice-Chairman.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101023_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A notice under paragraph (1) shall specify the time and place for the holding of the meeting and the business to be transacted.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067581_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Resolutions</heading><content>A resolution approved in writing by all members of the Committee shall be as valid and effectual as if passed at a meeting of the Committee.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403067597_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Chairman of Committee meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101039_017" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chairman, or in his absence the Vice-Chairman, shall be chairman at a meeting of the Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101039_025" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If, 15 minutes after the time appointed for any meeting of the Committee, neither the Chairman nor the Vice-Chairman is present, the members of the Committee may elect one of their number to be chairman of the meeting.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067597_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Voting at meetings of the Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101055_019" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 21(1)</ref> of the Ordinance, a question arising at a meeting of the Committee shall be decided by a majority vote of the members present and voting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101070_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>At a meeting of the Committee each member present shall have one vote, and in the event of an equality of votes the Chairman of the meeting shall have a second or casting vote.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067612_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Adjournments of meetings of the Committee</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101086_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A meeting of the Committee may be adjourned from time to time and place to place, but no business shall be transacted at an adjourned meeting other than the business left unfinished at the meeting which was adjourned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101086_012" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>It shall not be necessary to give notice of an adjourned meeting unless the meeting which was adjourned has so directed.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067612_004" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Minutes of meetings</heading><content>Minutes of meetings of the Committee and all sub-committees thereof shall be entered in the records kept by the Secretary for that purpose, and any such minutes, if purporting to be signed by the Chairman of the meeting at which the proceedings were held, or by the Chairman of the next succeeding meeting, shall be evidence of the proceedings.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403067628_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Custody of the Common Seal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101117_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Committee shall provide for the safe custody of the Common Seal of the Association.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101117_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 3(3)</ref> of the Ordinance, the Common Seal of the Association shall not be used or affixed to any instrument except on the authority of a resolution of the Committee or of a sealing sub-committee appointed by the Committee for that purpose.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403067628_004" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>The
            Consultative
            Council</heading><section id="ID_1438403067644_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Term of office of elected members of Consultative Council</heading><content>All elected members of the Consultative Council shall be elected at the Association’s annual general meeting and shall retire at the conclusion of the next annual general meeting after the meeting at which they were elected but, subject to <ref>section 9(1)(b)</ref> and (4) of the Ordinance, shall be eligible for re-election.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403067644_004" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2025-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Record of members eligible to be elected members of Consultative Council</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101164_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every member eligible to be an elected member of the Consultative Council shall
                give to the Secretary a written notice specifying—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101164_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>its place of
                    incorporation
                    and domicile, or, in the case of an unincorporated member, its
                    principal place of business; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/43">43 of 1990 s. 16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1991/30">30 of 1991 s.
                        9</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s.
                        215</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101164_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>its appropriate region, as set out in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the
                        Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1991/30">30 of 1991 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1748337090919_001" name="1A" temporalId="s16_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>For the purposes of paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref>, if a member is a re-domiciled
                entity, its appropriate region is Hong Kong. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/14">14
                        of 2025 s. 215</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101164_027" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Secretary shall maintain a record of all notices under paragraph (1) and
                shall produce the record at every annual general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101164_035" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where <ref>Schedule 1</ref> is amended pursuant to <ref>section 9(3)</ref> of
                the Ordinance or where there is a change in a member’s place of
                incorporation,
                place of domicile or principal place of business, a member affected by the amendment
                or to which the change relates must immediately give the Secretary
                a new notice under paragraph (1).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/43">43 of 1990 s. 16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1991/30">30 of
                        1991 s.
                    9</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s.
                215</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101179_005" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A notice under paragraph (1) shall be given to the Secretary—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101179_013" name="a" temporalId="s16_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of existing members, within 2 weeks of the
                    commencement*
                    of these by-laws; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101179_021" name="b" temporalId="s16_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of new members, within 2 weeks of becoming a member.</content></paragraph></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1748337091075_002">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 13 March
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403067659_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2025-05-23" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Nomination of elected members of the Consultative Council</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101195_058" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Notice of an annual general meeting at which an election of members of the
                Consultative Council is to take place shall be sent by the Secretary to all members
                not less than 30 days prior to the date of the meeting and shall be accompanied by
                blank nomination forms.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101211_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A member who is a candidate for election to the Consultative Council shall be
                proposed by one member from the same region as set out in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to
                the Ordinance as the candidate and seconded by another member from such
                    region.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1991/30">30
                        of 1991 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101211_013" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A candidate may act as its own proposer or seconder.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1748337512509_001" name="3A" temporalId="s17_3A"><num value="3A">(3A)</num><leadIn>However, a member ceases to be a candidate for election to the Consultative
                Council if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1748337512509_002" name="a" temporalId="s17_3A_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>after proposing the member, the proposer is no longer from the same region
                    as the member; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1748337512509_003" name="b" temporalId="s17_3A_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>after seconding the member, the seconder is no longer from the same region
                    as the member. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s.
                        216</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1748337512540_004" name="3B" temporalId="s17_3B"><num value="3B">(3B)</num><content>Nothing in paragraph (3A) prevents a member who has ceased to be a candidate by
                reason of that paragraph from being nominated again in accordance with these
                by-laws. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2025/14">14 of 2025 s.
                216</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101211_021" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The nomination referred to in paragraph (2) shall be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101211_029" name="a" temporalId="s17_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in writing;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101211_037" name="b" temporalId="s17_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>signed on behalf of the proposer and seconder; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101211_045" name="c" temporalId="s17_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>accompanied by a notice in writing signed on behalf of the candidate
                    indicating willingness to serve on the Consultative Council, if
                    elected.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101211_052" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The nomination paper and notice referred to in paragraph (4) shall be lodged
                with the Secretary not less than 18 days prior to the annual general
                meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101226_005" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A candidate may, by notice in writing addressed to the Secretary, withdraw at
                any time before the annual general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101226_013" name="7" temporalId="s17_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The Secretary shall, not less than 14 days prior to the annual general meeting,
                send to each member a notice containing the names of the candidates nominated for
                election to the Consultative Council in respect of each region set out in
                    <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Ordinance and a list of the members eligible to
                vote in respect of each such region; and the notice shall indicate the number of
                members to be elected in respect of each such region.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1991/30">30 of 1991 s.
                    9</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067675_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Procedure for election to Consultative Council</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101257_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If the number of members nominated under <ref>by-law 17</ref> for election to the Consultative Council in respect of any region set out in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> to the Ordinance—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1991/30">30 of 1991 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101257_012" name="a" temporalId="s18_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>does not exceed the number of members to be elected in respect of that region, then the candidates nominated for that region shall be deemed to have been duly elected with effect from the conclusion of the general meeting;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101257_020" name="b" temporalId="s18_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>exceeds the number of members to be elected in respect of that region, the election shall be determined by ballot of the members from that region present at the general meeting and the member or members receiving the largest number of votes shall be elected; and in the event of equality of votes the selection of the membership of the Consultative Council shall be determined by the drawing of lots between the candidates whose votes are equal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101273_006" name="c" temporalId="s18_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>is less than the number of members to be elected in respect of each such region, a fresh election shall be held to fill any vacancy remaining unfilled at the conclusion of that meeting, which fresh election shall proceed as if it were an election held under <ref>by-law 19</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101273_013" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If a ballot is required under paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref>, ballot papers shall be distributed to members present at the general meeting from the region and such ballot papers shall list the candidates in alphabetical order and indicate the number of members to be elected in respect of that region.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101289_005" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Upon a ballot under paragraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref> the members from such region present and voting at the meeting shall mark the names of the candidates nominated for whom they vote as elected members of the Consultative Council and no member shall, when so voting, mark more or fewer names than there are members to be elected; and if any member shall do so its vote shall be disqualified.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101289_013" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Ballots in respect of a region shall be counted separately and scrutineers shall be appointed by the Chairman of the general meeting to prepare as soon as practicable the result of the ballot showing the votes cast for each candidate, and the scrutineers shall give the result to the Chairman who shall announce the names of the successful candidates without revealing the votes cast for each candidate.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067675_003" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Filling of casual vacancies on the Consultative Council</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101335_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a casual vacancy occurs among the elected members of the Consultative Council, that vacancy shall be filled by election in accordance with this by-law.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101335_012" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Upon the vacancy occurring, the Committee shall call a general meeting for the purpose of an election to fill that vacancy.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101335_020" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Notice of the general meeting called under paragraph (2) shall be sent by the Secretary to all members from the region in respect of which the vacancy has occurred not less than 30 days prior to the date of the meeting and the notice shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101335_028" name="a" temporalId="s19_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notify members of the vacancy;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101335_036" name="b" temporalId="s19_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>specify the day, time and place for the holding of the meeting;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101335_044" name="c" temporalId="s19_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>call for nominations in respect of that vacancy; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101335_052" name="d" temporalId="s19_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>be accompanied by blank nomination forms.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101335_059" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><ref>By-laws 17</ref> and <ref>18</ref> shall apply to an election held under this by-law with such modifications as are necessary to make them applicable to the circumstances.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101335_067" name="5" temporalId="s19_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A member elected in an election held under this by-law shall hold office until the conclusion of the next annual general meeting.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403067690_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Vacation of office</heading><leadIn>An elected member of the Consultative Council shall be deemed to have vacated its office if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101367_012" name="a" temporalId="s20_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it resigns office, by notice in writing to the Secretary;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101367_020" name="b" temporalId="s20_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it is absent without permission of the Chairman of the Consultative Council from 3 consecutive meetings of that Council of which it has had due notice and the Council resolves that its office be vacated; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101367_028" name="c" temporalId="s20_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>it ceases to be incorporated or to have its principal place of business in the region in respect of which it was elected.</content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403067706_001" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Meetings of
            the
            Association</heading><section id="ID_1438403068049_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Annual general meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101398_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The first annual general meeting of the Association shall be held as soon as
                practicable after the
                commencement*
                of these by-laws.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101398_012" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An annual general meeting of the Association shall be held not less than once
                in every calendar year and not more than 15 months after the previous annual general
                meeting and on such date as the Committee shall determine.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101398_020" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The following business shall be transacted at an annual general
                meeting—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101398_028" name="a" temporalId="s21_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to approve a report of the Committee on the affairs of the Association and
                    to approve the accounts of the Association and the report of the
                    auditor;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101398_036" name="b" temporalId="s21_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to elect, in accordance with these by-laws, members of the Committee and
                    the Consultative Council; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101398_044" name="c" temporalId="s21_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to discuss any other business.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101398_051" name="4" temporalId="s21_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Notice of an annual general meeting shall be sent by the Secretary to each
                member not less than 14 days prior to the date of the meeting and shall specify the
                day, time and place for the holding of the meeting and the business to be transacted
                and shall be accompanied by the report of the Committee, the accounts of the
                Association and the report of the auditor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101413_005" name="5" temporalId="s21_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A member shall, if it wishes to propose a resolution as any other business at
                an annual general meeting, give to the Secretary not less than 7 days before the
                annual general meeting written notice of such resolution and shall in the notice
                give the name of another member willing to second the resolution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101413_013" name="6" temporalId="s21_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Secretary shall, not less than 3 days before the annual general meeting,
                send to each member a copy of a resolution under paragraph (5).</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1626419941246_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date:13 March
                1981.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403068112_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Extraordinary general meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101445_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Committee may, whenever it thinks fit, call an extraordinary general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101445_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Committee shall call an extraordinary general meeting upon receipt of a request in writing signed by not less than—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101445_020" name="a" temporalId="s22_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>75% of members eligible for election to the Committee under <ref>section 8(1)(b)(i)</ref> of the Ordinance; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101445_028" name="b" temporalId="s22_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>75% of members eligible for election to the Committee under <ref>section 8(1)(b)(ii)</ref> of the Ordinance; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101445_036" name="c" temporalId="s22_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>75% of the members of the Association.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101445_043" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Notice of an extraordinary general meeting shall be sent by the Secretary to each member—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101445_051" name="a" temporalId="s22_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the meeting is called under paragraph (1), not less than 14 days prior to the date of the meeting;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101460_006" name="b" temporalId="s22_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the meeting is called under paragraph (2), within 21 days of the receipt of the request and not less than 14 days prior to the date of the meeting.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101460_013" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The notice of an extraordinary general meeting shall specify the day, time and place for the holding of the meeting and the business to be transacted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101460_021" name="5" temporalId="s22_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>At an extraordinary general meeting, no business other than that specified in the notice shall be transacted.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403068112_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Quorum for general meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101476_059" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to paragraph (2), the quorum for a general meeting shall be 30 members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101491_005" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The quorum for a general meeting called under <ref>by-law 5(2)</ref> or <ref>19(2)</ref> shall be 15 members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101491_013" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If within 30 minutes from the time appointed for the meeting a quorum is not present the meeting, if convened at the request of members under <ref>by-law 22(2)</ref>, shall be dissolved, but in any other case it shall stand adjourned to the same day in the next week at the same time or if such day shall be a public holiday to the next succeeding business day, and if at such adjourned meeting a quorum is not present the business may be proceeded with by the members as may then be present.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101507_005" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a general meeting is adjourned under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall give notice of the place of the adjourned meeting to all members not less than 24 hours before the time for the meeting.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403068127_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Accidental omission to give notice etc.</heading><content>Accidental omission to give notice of a general meeting or to supply a ballot paper to any member shall not invalidate the proceedings or any resolution passed at such meeting.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403068143_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Chairman of general meetings</heading><content>The Chairman of the Committee or in his absence the Vice-Chairman shall be entitled to take the chair at every general meeting, and if within 10 minutes after the time appointed for the meeting neither of them shall be present, or if they shall have previously notified the Secretary of their intention not to be present, the members of the Committee present at the meeting shall determine which of them shall be chairman of the meeting.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403068158_001" name="s26" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Procedure at general meetings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101554_004" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Save as regards the election of elected members of the Committee, and the election of elected members of the Consultative Council, a resolution or amendment thereto proposed and seconded at a general meeting shall be put to the meeting by the Chairman of the meeting and (subject to paragraph (3)) be decided by a show of hands.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101554_012" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Each member shall have one vote on a question coming before a general meeting and in the event of equality of votes the Chairman of the meeting shall have a second or casting vote.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101554_020" name="3" temporalId="s26_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A poll shall be taken on a resolution or amendment thereto proposed and seconded at a general meeting if requested—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101554_028" name="a" temporalId="s26_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by not less than 30 members immediately after the declaration by the Chairman of the meeting of the result of a show of hands under paragraph (1); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101554_036" name="b" temporalId="s26_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by the Chairman of the meeting.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101554_043" name="4" temporalId="s26_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Unless a poll is held under paragraph (3) a declaration by the Chairman of the meeting that a resolution or amendment thereto has on a show of hands been carried, or lost, shall be conclusive evidence thereof, without proof of the numbers for or against the resolution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101569_005" name="5" temporalId="s26_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If a poll is held under paragraph (3) it shall be held in such manner as the
                Chairman of the meeting shall direct and the Chairman of the meeting shall appoint
                one or more scrutineers to sign a report on the result of the poll, which shall be
                declared by the Chairman of the
                meeting.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101569_013" name="6" temporalId="s26_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>No poll shall be held on a resolution for adjournment of the
                meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101569_021" name="7" temporalId="s26_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The Chairman of the meeting may with the consent of the meeting adjourn any meeting from time to time and from place to place. No business shall be transacted at any adjourned meeting other than the business left unfinished at the meeting which was adjourned, and no fresh notice shall be required unless the meeting otherwise directs.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101585_005" name="8" temporalId="s26_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Minutes of all proceedings at a general meeting shall be entered in records kept by the Secretary for that purpose, and any such minutes, if purporting to be signed by the Chairman of the meeting at which the proceedings were held, or by the Chairman of the next succeeding meeting, shall be evidence of the proceedings.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403068158_003" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Representation
            of
            Members</heading><section id="ID_1438403068174_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Designation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101632_004" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A designation in writing of a representative made by a member pursuant to <ref>section 10</ref> of the Ordinance shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101632_012" name="a" temporalId="s27_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>be addressed to the Chairman of the Association at its head office in Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101632_020" name="b" temporalId="s27_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be signed by a senior executive of the member; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101632_028" name="c" temporalId="s27_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>bear the specimen signature of the representative.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101632_035" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A designation made pursuant to paragraph (1) may be cancelled, or replaced by a fresh designation, by a document addressed to the Chairman of the Association at its head office in Hong Kong and signed by a senior executive of the member.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101647_005" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Committee shall be entitled to presume that the person signing a document under paragraph (1) or (2) above on behalf of a member has the requisite authority from the member to do so.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403068190_001" name="s28" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Register of designations</heading><content>The Committee shall cause the Secretary to maintain, and keep up to date, a register of designations made by members.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403068190_003" name="s29" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Closure of register before a general meeting</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101694_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The register of designations shall close 48 hours before a general meeting is held, and shall re-open at the conclusion of such meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101694_012" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Secretary shall bring to every general meeting of the Association the register of designations and before the start of every such meeting the Secretary shall use his best endeavours to ensure that persons present to represent members are in accordance with the register of designations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101694_020" name="3" temporalId="s29_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Accidental irregularity in the representation of a member at a general meeting or at a meeting of the Committee shall not invalidate the proceedings or any resolution passed thereat.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403068205_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Subscriptions
            and
            Accounts</heading><section id="ID_1438403068221_001" name="s30" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Entrance fees and subscriptions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101725_004" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Committee shall fix the entrance fee and annual subscription payable by
                each member, and may also determine the amount and date of payment of any special
                subscriptions that may be required from members to meet costs, expenses or
                liabilities incurred or entered into by the Association in pursuance of any object
                of the Association or in
                connexion
                with any matter or thing reasonably incidental thereto.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101725_012" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If any member fails to pay any fee or subscription under paragraph (1) within 1 month of a formal demand from the Committee for the payment thereof, the Committee may, for so long as the member continues not to pay such fee or subscription—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412101741_005" name="a" temporalId="s30_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the member is a member of the Committee or the Council, suspend or revoke such membership;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101741_013" name="b" temporalId="s30_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>deprive the member of the right to be a candidate for an election to the Committee or the Council;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412101741_021" name="c" temporalId="s30_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>deprive the member of the right to vote in any such election or to sign a nomination for any such election or to propose or second any other member for election.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101741_028" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Committee may exercise all or any of the power conferred on it under paragraph (2) in relation to a member.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101741_036" name="4" temporalId="s30_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where a member fails to pay in the circumstances described in paragraph (2), the Committee shall so inform the Financial Secretary and shall also inform him of the exercise or proposed exercise of any power under paragraph (2).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403068221_003" name="s31" reason="inEffect" role="bylaw" startPeriod="2021-12-02" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Accounts and audit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412101772_004" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Committee shall maintain proper accounts of all transactions of the Association and shall prepare for every financial year (as determined by the Committee) a statement of the accounts of the Association, containing an income and expenditure account and a balance sheet, both of which shall be signed by one continuing member and one elected member of the Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101772_012" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Committee shall appoint an auditor who shall be entitled to have access to all books of account, vouchers and other financial records of the Association and to require such information and explanations thereon as he thinks fit, and such auditor shall audit the statements drawn up under paragraph (1) as soon as possible and shall make a report thereon to the Committee.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101788_005" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A copy of the signed statement of accounts together with the audit report thereon shall be transmitted to members with the notice convening the annual general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412101788_013" name="4" temporalId="s31_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Committee may appoint a Treasurer to control the funds of the Association either on an honorary or salaried basis upon such terms and for such period as the Committee shall think fit and may delegate to any such Treasurer such duties as may be considered appropriate by the Committee.</content></subsection></section></part></main></subLeg>