<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 369 sub. leg. U</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>369U</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap369U!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2023-11-23</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403100185_002" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2023-11-23">Merchant
            Shipping (Safety) (Closing of Openings in Hulls and in Watertight Bulkheads)
            Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap369/s95">Cap.
                369,
                section
            95</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[2 August 1991]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403100201_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438412210582_004" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>These regulations may be cited as the Merchant Shipping (Safety) (Closing of
                Openings in Hulls and in Watertight Bulkheads) Regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210582_012" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403100216_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation and application</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412210614_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Locked"><term>locked</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">鎖上</term>) means secured by a device which prevents
                unauthorized operation;</def><def name="MarginLine"><term>margin
                    line</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">限界線</term>) has the same meaning as in the Merchant
                Shipping (Safety) (Passenger Ship Construction and Survey) (Ships Built On or After
                1 September 1984) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap369AM">Cap. 369 sub. leg. AM</ref>);
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="RequiredToBeWatertight"><term>required
                    to be
                watertight</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">必須水密</term>) means required by the Merchant
                Shipping (Safety) (Passenger Ship Construction and Survey) (Ships Built On or After
                1 September 1984) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap369AM">Cap. 369 sub. leg. AM</ref>)
                or the Merchant Shipping (Safety) (Passenger Ship Construction) (Ships Built Before
                1 September 1984) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap369AL">Cap. 369 sub. leg. AL</ref>)
                to be watertight;
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="RestrictedVisibility"><term>restricted
                    visibility</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有限能見度</term>) means any weather condition in which
                visibility is restricted by fog, mist, snow, rainstorm, sandstorm or any other
                similar cause.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210629_004" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>These regulations apply to passenger ships which are registered in Hong Kong and which are propelled by electricity or other mechanical means.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210629_012" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purpose of these regulations a voyage commences when a ship leaves her berth or anchorage at the port or other place from which the voyage is made.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210629_020" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purpose of these regulations, a closing appliance shall be regarded as being below the margin line if any part of the sill of the opening with which it is associated is below that line.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403100216_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Closure of hull openings, watertight doors, openings in watertight bulkheads, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412210660_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The following closing appliances shall be securely closed before a ship proceeds on any voyage and shall be kept so closed until the ship has been secured at a berth or anchorage—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412210660_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>watertight doors below the ship’s margin line fitted in bulkheads which are required to be watertight and which separate cargo spaces;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210660_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>sidescuttles which can be opened and which are situated below such margin line;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210660_028" name="c" temporalId="s3_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>deadlights of any sidescuttles which are situated below such margin line and which—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412210660_036" name="i" temporalId="s3_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>are not accessible while the ship is at sea; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412210660_044" name="ii" temporalId="s3_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>are situated in spaces appropriated for use at times for the carriage of cargo and at other times for use by passengers, while the spaces are used for the carriage of cargo; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210660_051" name="d" temporalId="s3_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>gangway and cargo loading doors below such margin line.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210660_058" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A closing appliance described in subregulation <ref>(1)(a)</ref>, (b), (c) or (d) shall not be regarded as being securely closed unless it is locked.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403100232_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Permitted openings while underway</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412210692_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A watertight door below the margin line and fitted in a bulkhead which is required to be watertight, other than a door described in <ref>regulation 3(1)</ref>, shall be kept closed while the ship is on a voyage except—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412210692_012" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>when opened in accordance with the procedures laid down in written operational instructions which are based upon the advice set out in the <ref>Schedules</ref> and approved by the Director of Marine;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210692_020" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>when opened for the purposes of drill required by <ref>regulation 7</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210692_028" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>when any such door is opened on the express authority of the master for a specific purpose and for no longer than a period of time specified by the master and all other watertight doors below the margin line, except those opened in accordance with paragraph (a), are closed during that period.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210707_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The operational instructions referred to in subregulation <ref>(1)(a)</ref> shall be kept on board a ship at all times in the custody of the master.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210707_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding subregulation <ref>(1)(a)</ref>, (b) and (c) every watertight door described in subregulation (1) shall, except where there is an immediate need to pass through, be kept closed while the ship is on a voyage—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412210707_021" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in conditions of restricted visibility;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210707_029" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>within any port limits or compulsory pilotage limits;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210707_037" name="c" temporalId="s4_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the depth of water is less than 3 times the ship’s draught; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210707_045" name="d" temporalId="s4_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>in any other conditions which the master considers potentially hazardous owing to—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412210707_053" name="i" temporalId="s4_3_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the proximity of underwater hazards;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412210707_061" name="ii" temporalId="s4_3_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the density of traffic; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412210707_069" name="iii" temporalId="s4_3_d_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>any other factor,</content></subparagraph></paragraph><continued>and if such a door is opened in such circumstances then it shall be closed immediately after passage through it has been effected.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210707_081" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any watertight door which may be opened in accordance with subregulation (1) or (3) shall be kept clear of obstructions which might prevent its rapid closure.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210723_005" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Notwithstanding the requirements of this regulation or <ref>regulation 3</ref>, in an emergency the master may authorize the opening or closing of any watertight door provided he is satisfied that such action is essential for the overall safety of the ship.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403100248_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Portable plates</heading><content>Every portable plate closing an opening below the margin line in any portion of the internal structure of a ship which is required to be watertight shall be fitted in place before the ship proceeds on any voyage and shall be kept in place, except in case of urgent necessity, until the ship has been secured at a berth or anchorage. In replacing any such plate all reasonable precautions shall be taken to ensure that the joints are watertight.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403100248_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Coverings, etc., for ash-shoots, etc.</heading><content>Both the watertight cover and the automatic non-return valve of any ash-shoot, rubbish-shoot or other similar device on a ship having its inboard opening below the margin line shall be kept closed and secured at all times when such device is not in use.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403100263_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Drills and inspections of deadlights, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412210785_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>All deadlights which are accessible, all watertight doors to the opening of which <ref>regulation 3</ref> applies, all valves and closing mechanisms of scuppers and the devices referred to in <ref>regulation 6</ref> shall be opened and closed for the purposes of drill—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412210785_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at intervals of not more than 7 days except so far as is necessary to avoid drills being conducted in any of the situations described in <ref>regulation 4(3)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210785_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>immediately before a ship proceeds to sea if the ship is intended to remain at sea for a period of more than 7 days.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210785_027" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All watertight doors fitted in bulkheads required to be watertight which may be opened for the working of the ship in accordance with <ref>regulation 4</ref> shall be opened and closed for the purposes of drill once in every period of 24 hours.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210801_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>All closing appliances and devices referred to in <ref>regulations 3</ref> and <ref>6</ref> shall be inspected by a person appointed by the master for that purpose—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412210801_013" name="a" temporalId="s7_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>before the ship proceeds on any voyage; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210801_021" name="b" temporalId="s7_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at intervals of not more than 7 days if the ship is intended to remain at sea for a period of more than 7 days, except where they are not accessible.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403100263_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Drills and inspections of watertight doors, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412210816_035" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The following closing appliances, mechanisms and other devices shall be inspected at intervals of not more than 7 days by a person appointed for that purpose, either generally or on any particular inspection, by the master—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412210816_043" name="a" temporalId="s8_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all watertight doors other than those of the type described in <ref>regulation 3(1)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210816_051" name="b" temporalId="s8_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all mechanisms, indicators and warning devices connected with such doors;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210816_059" name="c" temporalId="s8_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>all valves, the closing of which is necessary to make watertight any compartment below the margin line; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210832_006" name="d" temporalId="s8_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>all valves, the operation of which is necessary for the efficient operation of damage-control cross-connections.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210832_013" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Suitable notices and signs shall be provided on, or in the vicinity of, all the closing appliances referred to in subregulation (1) to indicate, as necessary, the procedures for operating the appliances, the purpose of the controls and any precautions to be observed.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403100279_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Training</heading><content>All members of the crew of a ship who will have occasion to use any watertight doors, shall be instructed in the safe operation of watertight doors. In addition, written instructions on the safe operation of the doors, given in easily understood terms and illustrated wherever possible, shall be available to all members of the crew. Such instructions shall be based upon the operational instructions referred to in <ref>regulation 4(1)(a)</ref>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403100294_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Entries in official log-book</heading><leadIn>Entries shall be made in a ship’s official log-book recording the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412210863_019" name="a" temporalId="s10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the times of the last closing, before the ship proceeds on any particular voyage, of watertight doors and other closing appliances referred to in <ref>regulation 3</ref> and of the next opening of such doors and closing appliances;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210863_027" name="b" temporalId="s10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the times of the opening and closing of any watertight door pursuant to <ref>regulation 4(1)(c)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210879_006" name="c" temporalId="s10_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the times when portable plates referred to in <ref>regulation 5</ref> are fitted in place and the times of any removal and replacement of such plate while the ship is on any voyage; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412210879_014" name="d" temporalId="s10_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the occasions on which drills are held and inspections made in compliance with these regulations and whether or not the closing appliances and devices to which such a drill or inspection relates are in good working order when the drill or inspection takes place.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403100294_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412210910_042" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If there is a breach of these regulations, then by virtue of <ref>section
                    95(2)</ref> of the Ordinance the master of the passenger ship involved in the
                contravention commits an offence and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210910_050" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who fails to carry out an inspection which he has been appointed by
                the master to carry out under <ref>regulation 7(3)</ref> or <ref>8</ref> shall be
                guilty of an offence and liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 2.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412210926_005" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In any proceedings for an offence under these regulations it shall be a defence
                for the defendant to show that he took steps to prevent the occurrence or
                continuation of the activity or contravention to which the alleged offence relates
                and that in the particular circumstances the steps were taken as soon as practicable
                and were reasonable.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438403100326_001" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap369U/s4">reg. 4(1)(a)</ref>]</note><heading>Design and
            Operational Principles for Watertight
            Doors</heading><crossHeading class="align_center">General
            Comment<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text>Most passenger ships are provided with internal watertight subdivision arrangements
            designed to withstand a specified volume of flooding in the event of the hull being
            breached. While the effectiveness of these arrangements is dependent upon a number of
            factors, it is essential to ensure that any watertight door in the divisional bulkheads
            is closed when breaching occurs, or almost immediately afterwards. It is also essential
            to limit the number of access openings placed in the divisional bulkheads and also to
            exercise the strictest control over the operation of the watertight doors provided to
            close such
            openings.</text><crossHeading class="align_left">Principles to be Observed when Fitting Watertight Doors in
            New
            Ships</crossHeading><crossHeading class="align_left"><inline class="not_bold"><i>Number and Location of Doors
                    (Applicable to New Ships)</i></inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412210957_020" name="s1" temporalId="sch1_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><subsection id="ID_1438412210972_001" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It has always been accepted that a number of access openings, closed by
                    means of watertight doors, will be required in some watertight bulkheads for
                    essential purposes, e.g. to inspect vital items of machinery, provide emergency
                    or alternative means of escape, etc. Equally however, it has always been
                    stressed, both nationally and internationally, that the number of such openings
                    should be kept to the absolute minimum compatible with the design and proper
                    working of the ship. Every effort should therefore be made to reduce, as far as
                    practicable, the number of watertight doors fitted in any new passenger ship.
                    This might be achieved in a number of ways. For example, in the accommodation
                    spaces, efforts should be made to arrange access and escape routes in a manner
                    which would minimize the need for people to pass through watertight bulkheads
                    below the level of the bulkhead deck. In the case of service spaces and other
                    working compartments, normal access should where possible be available without
                    the need for continual passage through main
                    bulkheads.</content></subsection><continued>Acceptance of the location of any watertight door will however be dependent
                upon the Director being satisfied that its presence is essential for the proper
                working of the
                ship.</continued><crossHeading class="align_left left_indent_0"><inline class="not_bold"><i>The Position
                        and Size of Watertight Doors (Applicable to New
                        Ships)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></i></inline></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412211004_021" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The possible effects of progressive flooding through an unclosed opening
                    should always be taken into account when deciding upon the position and size of
                    any watertight door. An unclosed door, lying wholly below the level of the
                    waterline obviously presents a great potential hazard. To lessen such dangers,
                    watertight doors should be kept as small as possible and be positioned, whenever
                    practicable, close to the centreline with their sills as high as is possible and
                    consistent with safe access and preferably above the level of the
                    waterline.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_justified"><inline class="not_bold align_justified"><i>Means of Controlling Watertight Doors
                    (Applicable to those Ships
                    Fitted
                    with Central/Local Control Facilities at Navigating Bridge
            Deck)</i></inline></crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211019_020" name="s2" temporalId="sch1_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><subsection id="ID_1438412211035_001" name="1" temporalId="sch1_s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The system adopted to give central control to the watertight doors fitted
                    throughout the ship should be designed not only to ensure their efficient
                    operation but also to reduce the risk of injury to personnel when passing
                    through the doorway. To this end, the watertight door central control unit
                    located on the navigating bridge should have two operating positions, one marked
                    “local control” and the other “doors closed”. When the “local control” position
                    is selected any door should be capable of being opened or closed only by means
                    of the local controller provided at each side of the
                    door—automatic
                    closure of the door should not be possible in this mode of
                    operation.</content></subsection><continued>Selection of the alternative
                position—“doors
                closed”—should
                cause all the doors to close. It should also ensure automatic closure of any door in
                the system if it is opened thereafter by the use of the local controllers.
                BECAUSE
                OF THE INCREASED RISK OF INJURY TO PERSONNEL WHEN USING THE DOORS IN THE AUTOMATIC
                CLOSING MODE
                use
                of the “doors closed” position should be restricted to emergency and drill or
                testing purposes, the latter always being preceded by an adequate warning
                signal.</continued><crossHeading class="align_left left_indent_0"><inline class="not_bold"><i>The Speed of
                        Closure of the Watertight Doors (Applicable to all
                        Ships)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></i></inline></crossHeading><subsection id="ID_1438412211050_013" name="2" temporalId="sch1_s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>All the power operated doors fitted in any ship must be capable of being
                    closed from the navigating bridge within one minute. Whilst this is a relatively
                    short period of time to close all doors, it should be borne in mind that recent
                    studies have shown that progressive flooding through doorways, before effective
                    closure of the watertight doors can be completed, could have disastrous results
                    in some
                    ships—in
                    particular, roro ferries. It follows, therefore, that prompt action must always
                    be taken to close any watertight door which may be open when an emergency
                    situation is
                    imminent.</content></subsection><continued>The speed of closure of an individual door should not cause unnecessary risk
                to the users. Where the closing mechanism permits the doors should be adjusted so
                that they can be closed from the fully open position in not less than 20 seconds nor
                more than 40 seconds from first movement.</continued></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403100341_001" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
            2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap369U/s4">reg. 4(1)(a)</ref>]</note><heading>Operational
            Instructions</heading><section id="ID_1438412211144_012" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><leadIn>Operational Instructions submitted for approval to the Director should specify
                in what circumstances, if any, and subject to what conditions, each watertight door
                in the ship may be opened. Two conditions of any voyage should always be catered for
                i.e. those applicable in potentially hazardous situations when the highest standard
                of watertight integrity is required and those applicable in normal conditions, i.e.
                when potentially hazardous situations are not present. Potentially hazardous
                situations for this purpose include voyages—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412211144_022" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in conditions of restricted visibility;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211144_031" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>during any part of a voyage within port limits, or within compulsory
                    pilotage limits;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211144_040" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>where the depth of water is less than 3 times the ship’s draught;
                    and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211160_007" name="d" temporalId="sch2_s1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>in a situation which the master considers potentially hazardous due
                    to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412211160_016" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s1_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the proximity of underwater hazards (having regard to the degree of
                        reliance that can be placed on the chart of the
                        area—see
                        Mariners Handbook Chapter 3, <ref>section 1</ref>); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211160_025" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s1_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the density of the traffic in the vicinity; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211160_034" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_s1_d_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>any other
                        factor.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Control Categories to be assigned to Watertight Doors
            for
            the purpose of Operational Instructions</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211160_055" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><subsection id="ID_1438412211160_060" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every watertight door, to which <ref>regulation 4(1)</ref> of the
                    regulations applies, should be given a specific number and, depending upon the
                    need there is for it to be opened or kept open in normal conditions, assigned
                    one of the following categories—</leadIn><continued>
                    
                    
                    <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="100%" class="left_indent_60">
                        <col width="20%"></col>
                        <col width="80%"></col>
                        <tbody>
                            <tr>
                                <td>Type “A”—</td>
                                
                                <td class="cellpadding_bottom_2">a door which may be open.</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td>Type “B”—</td>
                                
                                <td class="align_justified cellpadding_bottom_2">a door which should
                                    be closed. It may be open, but only while someone is working in
                                    the adjacent compartment.</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td>Type “C”—</td>
                                
                                <td class="align_justified cellpadding_bottom_2">a door which should
                                    be closed. It may be opened, but only for sufficient time to
                                    permit through passage.</td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody>
                    </table>
                    
                    
                </continued><paragraph id="ID_1510819157448_001" name="0" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_0"></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1510819157448_002" name="0-1" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_0-1"></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211160_089" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Instructions must state that in potentially hazardous situations every
                    watertight door must be closed except when a person is passing through it. They
                    must also state that in normal conditions the doors are to be opened or closed
                    in accordance with the category which has been assigned to them, see
                    subparagraph (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211175_006" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In deciding upon the appropriate category for each watertight door, account
                    should be taken of the following factors—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412211175_015" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>for each watertight door, other than those fitted in machinery
                        spaces—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211175_024" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>whether there is a genuine need for the door to be kept
                            open;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211175_033" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that whilst it may be very convenient to keep the door open for
                            prolonged periods such an arrangement could put the safety of the ship
                            at risk if the hull were suddenly breached;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211175_042" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>whether a closed door can be opened and then closed again, safely
                            and easily;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211175_050" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>for watertight doors fitted in machinery spaces—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211175_059" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the need for quick and easy surveillance of machinery spaces
                            containing main propulsion machinery,
                            essential
                            auxiliaries, gear boxes, thrustblocks, CPP equipment, electrical power
                            generating plant and fuel preparation and heating equipment; having
                            regard to the fire risk and the critical nature of a machinery
                            failure;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211191_008" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the increased risk of personnel being trapped by doors which do not
                            have the improved facilities for local operation described in
                                <ref>paragraph 2(1) of Schedule 1</ref>;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211191_017" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the extent to which fire detecting systems and bilge water level
                            alarms are fitted;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211191_026" name="iv" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>whether a machinery control room is provided and the degree of
                            remote control and remote surveillance that is possible; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211191_035" name="v" temporalId="sch2_s2_3_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the need to delay the onset of progressive
                            flooding.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Supervision of Control Procedures at Sea</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211191_048" name="s3" temporalId="sch2_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>The Instructions should state that the operation of all those doors which are
                indicated on the bridge control unit should be supervised by the officer in charge
                of the watch by means of that
                unit.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Plans and Particulars required to be Submitted for All
            Ships</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211191_064" name="s4" temporalId="sch2_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><leadIn>To enable the Director to make a proper assessment of the “Operational
                Instructions” being proposed the following plans and information should be
                submitted—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412211191_074" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the size, type and sill height of each door;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211206_007" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>(for new ships only) the reason why each door is to be fitted;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211206_016" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a brief outline of the method of operation of the doors;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211206_025" name="d" temporalId="sch2_s4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the category of door proposed (as specified in <ref>paragraph 2(1)</ref>)
                    and the reason for selecting such a category;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211206_034" name="e" temporalId="sch2_s4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the draft Operational Instructions, entitled “Operational Instructions for
                    the Control of Watertight Doors” to be issued to the master; such Instructions
                    to be presented in the form of the Director’s Model Instructions, set out in
                        <ref>Schedule 3</ref>.</content></subsection></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403100341_003" name="sch3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch3"><num value="3">Schedule 3</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap369U/s4">reg. 4(1)(a)</ref>]</note><heading>Model
            Instructions relating to the
            Control
            of Watertight
            Doors—Operational
            Instructions for the Control of Watertight Doors</heading><section id="ID_1438412211269_028" name="s1" temporalId="sch3_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>These are the Operational Instructions for the control of the ship’s watertight
                doors required by <ref>regulation 4</ref> of the Merchant Shipping (Safety) (Closing
                of Openings in Hulls and in Watertight Bulkheads) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap369U">Cap. 369 sub. leg. U</ref>).
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of
                2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></section><section id="ID_1438412211269_036" name="s2" temporalId="sch3_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><content>All the watertight doors which may be opened during a voyage are to be operated
                (kept closed or opened) in accordance with the procedures given in these
                instructions and in the appended diagram entitled “Operation of the Ship’s
                Watertight
                Doors”.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Marking and Categorization of Watertight
            Doors</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211269_052" name="s3" temporalId="sch3_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><content>Every one of the ship’s
                    [<inline class="width_21"> </inline>*]
                watertight doors is to be given a specific number and, if it is a door which may be
                opened at any time during a voyage in normal conditions, or a door which may be kept
                open at any such time, it shall also be assigned one of the following
                types—Type
                A, Type B or Type
                C—to
                indicate how it may be used in normal
                conditions.</content></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1679887844104_001">
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Insert appropriate number of
                doors.</content>
        </editorialNote><crossHeading class="align_left">Voyage Conditions</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211284_012" name="s4" temporalId="sch3_s4" class="no_header"><num value="4">4.</num><leadIn>The Instructions for the operation of the doors are given for two conditions of
                any voyage—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412211284_022" name="a" temporalId="sch3_s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>those applicable in potentially hazardous situations; and</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211284_031" name="b" temporalId="sch3_s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>those applicable in normal
                    conditions.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412211284_037" name="s5" temporalId="sch3_s5" class="no_header"><num value="5">5.</num><leadIn>For the purpose of these Instructions—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412211284_047" name="a" temporalId="sch3_s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>potentially hazardous situations are conditions where the ship is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412211284_056" name="i" temporalId="sch3_s5_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in conditions of restricted visibility;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211284_065" name="ii" temporalId="sch3_s5_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>on any part of a voyage within port limits or within compulsory
                        pilotage limits;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211284_074" name="iii" temporalId="sch3_s5_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>where the depth of water is less than 3 times the ship’s draught;
                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211300_008" name="iv" temporalId="sch3_s5_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><leadIn>in a situation which the master considers potentially hazardous due
                        to—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211300_016" name="A" temporalId="sch3_s5_a_iv_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>the proximity of underwater hazards (having regard to the degree of
                            reliance that can be placed on the chart of the
                            area—see
                            Mariner’s Handbook Chapter 3, <ref>section 1</ref>); or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211300_025" name="B" temporalId="sch3_s5_a_iv_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>the density of the traffic in the vicinity; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412211300_034" name="C" temporalId="sch3_s5_a_iv_C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content>any other factor;</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211300_042" name="b" temporalId="sch3_s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>normal conditions are all conditions in which potentially hazardous
                    situations do not
                    exist.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Operation of Watertight Doors</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211300_056" name="s6" temporalId="sch3_s6" class="no_header"><num value="6">6.</num><leadIn>The ship’s watertight doors are to be operated (opened and closed) as
                follows—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412211300_066" name="a" temporalId="sch3_s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in potentially hazardous situations every such door must be kept closed
                    except when a person is passing through it;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211300_075" name="b" temporalId="sch3_s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in normal conditions—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412211300_084" name="i" temporalId="sch3_s6_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a Type A door may be kept open;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211300_093" name="ii" temporalId="sch3_s6_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a Type B door must be closed. It may be open but only whilst someone is
                        working in the compartment adjacent to it;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412211300_102" name="iii" temporalId="sch3_s6_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>a Type C door must be closed. It may be opened but only for sufficient
                        time to permit someone to pass through it;</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211300_110" name="c" temporalId="sch3_s6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in addition to <ref>paragraph 2</ref> any watertight door may be opened on
                    the express authority of the master for a specific purpose and for no longer
                    than a specific period of time. Where the master authorizes the opening of any
                    door in this way, details of the opening and authorization must be recorded in
                    the official
                    log-book.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Obstructions in Doorways</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211316_014" name="s7" temporalId="sch3_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><content>Any watertight door which is open must be kept clear of obstructions which
                might prevent its rapid closure.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Control from Bridge</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211316_030" name="s8" temporalId="sch3_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><content>The control for watertight doors on the navigating bridge can be set at either
                “doors closed” or “local control”. It must be set at “local control” except during
                an emergency, a drill or for testing purposes.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Supervision from Bridge</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211316_046" name="s9" temporalId="sch3_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><content>The operation of all watertight doors which are indicated on the bridge control
                unit must be supervised by the officer in charge of the watch by means of that
                unit.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Inspections</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412211331_014" name="s10" temporalId="sch3_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><content>All watertight doors (which are accessible while the ship is on a voyage),
                their controls and alarms, must be kept in efficient working condition and be
                inspected at intervals of not more than 7 days.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Drills</crossHeading><section name="s11" temporalId="sch3_s11" id="ID_1511748196937_001" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><leadIn>The operation of the watertight doors must be tested at drills carried out as
                follows—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412211331_039" name="a" temporalId="sch3_s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any door which is normally kept closed, if accessible, is to be opened and
                    closed at least once every 7 days; this operation may however be delayed or
                    advanced if conditions of restricted visibility or any other potentially
                    hazardous situations prevail or are anticipated;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211331_048" name="b" temporalId="sch3_s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all doors to be opened and closed prior to departure if the ship is to
                    remain at sea for more than 7 days;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412211331_057" name="c" temporalId="sch3_s11_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>those doors which may be kept open or opened (i.e.
                    Types
                    A, B and C) during a voyage are to be opened and closed daily.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Instructions in the Use of the Watertight
            Doors</crossHeading><section name="s12" temporalId="sch3_s12" id="ID_1511748196937_002" class="no_header"><num value="12">12.</num><content>ALL MEMBERS OF THE CREW WHO HAVE OCCASION TO USE ANY WATERTIGHT DOORS MUST BE
                INSTRUCTED IN THE SAFE OPERATION OF THOSE DOORS. IN ADDITION WRITTEN INSTRUCTIONS ON
                THE SAFE OPERATION OF THE DOORS, GIVEN IN EASILY UNDERSTOOD TERMS AND ILLUSTRATED
                WHEREVER POSSIBLE, SHALL BE AVAILABLE TO ALL MEMBERS OF THE CREW, SUCH INSTRUCTIONS
                SHOULD BE BASED ON THE CONTENTS OF THIS DOCUMENT.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Emergency Situations</crossHeading><section name="s13" temporalId="sch3_s13" id="ID_1511748196937_003" class="no_header"><num value="13">13.</num><content>These Instructions govern the operation of watertight doors in either normal
                conditions or potentially hazardous situations. However when an emergency situation
                exists the master may ignore these instructions and authorize the opening or closing
                of any watertight door provided he is satisfied that such action is essential for
                the overall safety of the ship.</content></section><crossHeading class="align_left">Offences</crossHeading><section name="s14" temporalId="sch3_s14" id="ID_1511748196937_004" class="no_header"><num value="14">14.</num><content>It is a punishable offence to contravene any of the provisions of the Merchant
                Shipping (Safety) (Closing of Openings in Hulls and in Watertight Bulkheads)
                Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap369U">Cap. 369 sub. leg.
                    U</ref>).</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403100372_001" name="sch4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2023-11-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch4" orientation="landscape"><num value="4">Schedule
            4</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline" orientation="landscape">[<ref href="/hk/cap369U/s4">reg.
            4(1)(a)</ref>]<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><content orientation="landscape" class="align_center"><img src="images/CAP369U_en_sch4_20231123_000000_0002.jpg" alt="This image shows the operation of the ship’s watertight doors." height="87" width="407" title="This image shows the operation of the ship’s watertight doors."></img><marker role="section-break"></marker></content><content orientation="landscape">
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="font_size_7">
                <col width="28%"></col>
                <col width="1%"></col>
                <col width="3%"></col>
                <col width="4%"></col>
                <col width="15%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="13%"></col>
                <col width="1%"></col>
                <col width="10%"></col>
                <col width="19%"></col>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td rowspan="3" class="cellpadding_bottom_2 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 cellpadding_top_2 border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <p>The contents of this document satisfy the requirements of the
                                Merchant Shipping (Safety)
                                (Closing of Openings in Hulls and in Watertight
                                Bulkheads) Regulations (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap369U">Cap. 369 sub. leg. U</ref>) <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">regulation
                                    4</ref>.</p>
                            
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="2" class="cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 valign_center">
                            <p class="align_center">DOOR CATEGORY</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="2" class="cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 valign_center">
                            <p class="align_center">VOYAGE CONDITION</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td class="border_right_0.75  border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Signed
                                </i>.......................................................<p class="align_center"><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">The Director of
                                    Marine,<br></br>Hong
                            Kong</i></p></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td rowspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 valign_center">
                            <p class="align_center">NOR-MAL</p>
                        </td>
                        <td rowspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2  valign_center">
                            <p class="align_center">POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS SITUATIONS</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_right_2 cellpadding_left_2 valign_center">
                            <p class="align_left">DOOR CATEGORY AND CONTROL PROCEDURE</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td class="cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 leaders_. border_right_0.75  border_left_0.75">Date
                            </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 valign_center">
                            <p class="align_center">DOOR NO</p>
                        </td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 valign_center">
                            <p class=" align_center">ADJACENT COMPARTMENTS</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1" class="cellpadding_top_2 leaders_. cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 border_top_0.75  border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 valign_top">TYPE‘A’ </td>
                        <td rowspan="1" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 valign_center">
                            <p class="align_left">A DOOR WHICH MAY BE OPEN.</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td class="border_top_0.75">
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_top_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">
                            <p>1</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <p class="align_center">‘C’</p>
                        </td>
                        <td rowspan="7" class="border_right_0.75 valign_center"><img src="images/CAP369U_en_sch4_20231123_000000_0001.jpg" alt="This image displays the text of “ALL DOORS CLOSED”." height="135" title="This image displays the text of “ALL DOORS CLOSED”." width="73"></img></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td rowspan="4" colspan="1" class="leaders_. cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 border_top_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">TYPE ‘B’ </td>
                        <td rowspan="4" class="cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75">
                            <p class="align_left">A DOOR WHICH SHOULD BE CLOSED.
                                IT MAY BE OPEN, BUT ONLY WHILST SOMEONE IS WORKING
                                IN THE ADJACENT COMPARTMENT.</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_top_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">
                            <p>2</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <p class="align_center">‘C’</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">
                            <p>3</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_right_0.75">
                            <p>port</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <p class="align_center">‘C’</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">
                            <p>4</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_right_0.75">
                            <p>stb</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <p class="align_center">ETC</p>
                        </td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">
                            <p>5</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="1" class="leaders_. cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 border_top_0.75 border_left_0.75" rowspan="2">TYPE ‘C’ </td>
                        
                        <td class="cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_right_2 border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75" rowspan="4">A
                            DOOR WHICH SHOULD BE CLOSED. IT MAY BE OPENED, BUT
                            ONLY
                            FOR SUFFICIENT TIME TO PERMIT THROUGH PASSAGE.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">
                            <p>6</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75 cellpadding_left_2 cellpadding_bottom_2">
                            <p>7</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td colspan="1" class="border_left_0.75"></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75">
                            <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        </td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td class="border_top_0.75 border_right_0.75 border_bottom_0.75 border_left_0.75"></td>
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td class="border_left_0.75 border_bottom_0.75"></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </content><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/er4">E.R. 4 of 2023</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></subLeg>