<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 374 sub. leg. M</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>374M</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap374M!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-02-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403130293_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2024-02-08">Variation
                                    of Speed Limits
                                    Notice</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap374/s40">Cap.
                                                374, section
                                    40(2)</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></enactingFormula><commencementNote>[27 August 1984]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2024/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403130309_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2024-02-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>This
            Notice
            shall be cited as the Variation of Speed Limits Notice.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er1">E.R. 1 of 2024</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403130309_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2024-02-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Speed limit of 30 kilometres an hour</heading><text>The speed limit for the roads or parts thereof specified in this paragraph shall be 30
            kilometres an hour—</text><leadIn><b>Kowloon</b></leadIn><continued>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090856_001" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On Wan Road, for the whole section of this road forming the podium level at
                    Hung Hom Railway Terminus.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090858_002" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Railway Approach, from a point about 76 metres south of Hong Chong Road to
                    the podium level of Hung Hom Railway Terminus.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090859_003" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Cheong Wan Road, for the whole section of the road forming the podium level
                    at Hung Hom Railway Terminus.</content></subsection>
        </continued><leadIn><b>Lantau Island</b></leadIn><continued>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090859_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>South Lantao Road, from the junction of South Lantao Road with Mui Wo
                    Roundabout to a point 560 metres further west.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090860_005" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>South Lantao Road, from a point about 180 metres west of the junction of
                    South Lantao Road with Chi Ma Wan Road to a point about 820 metres east of the
                    junction of South Lantao Road with Chi Ma Wan Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090861_006" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>South Lantao Road, from a point about 80 metres west of the junction of
                    South Lantao Road with Ma Po Ping Road to a point about 690 metres east of the
                    junction of South Lantao Road with Ma Po Ping Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090862_007" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>South Lantao Road, from a point about 200 metres west of the centre of
                    Bridge No. 149, in Shui Hau Village, to a point about 440 metres east of the
                    centre of Bridge No. 149 in Shui Hau Village.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090863_008" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Tai O Road, from the eastern boundary of the junction of the turn round
                    area and Tai O Road to a point about 615 metres east of the junction of the
                    eastern boundary of the turn round area and Tai O Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090863_009" name="6" temporalId="s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Tung Chung Road, from the junction of Tung Chung Road with South Lantao
                    Road to Tung Chung Ferry Pier.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681354090864_010" name="7" temporalId="s2_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Chi Ma Wan Road, from the junction of Chi Ma Wan Road with South Lantao
                    Road to the junction of Chi Ma Wan Road with the access road leading to the
                    Department of Correctional Services Institutions, Chi Ma Wan.</content></subsection>
        </continued></section><section id="ID_1438403130325_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2024-02-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Speed limit of 70 kilometres an hour</heading><text>The speed limit for the roads or parts thereof specified in this paragraph shall be 70
            kilometres an hour—</text><leadIn><b>Hong
                Kong Island</b></leadIn><continued>
            
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197062_001" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Pok Fu Lam Road, from the junction of Pok Fu Lam Road with Pok Fu Lam
                    Garden Interchange near Claymore Avenue to the junction of Pok Fu Lam Road with
                    Shek Pai Wan Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197063_002" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Shek Pai Wan Road, from the junction of Shek Pai Wan Road with Pok Fu Lam
                    Road to the junction of Shek Pai Wan Road with Aberdeen Praya Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197064_003" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nam Fung Road, from the junction of Nam Fung Road with Deep Water Bay Road
                    to a point 150 metres from Wong Chuk Hang Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197065_004" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Gloucester Road, for both eastbound and westbound carriageways but
                    excluding the service road and the slip roads or ramps adjoining Canal Road
                    Flyover, from a point about opposite Arsenal Street to the junction of
                    Gloucester Road with Victoria Park Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197066_005" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Victoria Park Road, from the junction of Victoria Park Road with Gloucester
                    Road to a point about 150 metres west of Hing Fat Street.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197066_006" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Causeway Flyover, from the junction of the flyover with Victoria Park Road
                    to the junction of the flyover with Gloucester Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197067_007" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Island Eastern Corridor, from the junction of Island Eastern Corridor with
                    Victoria Park Road to the junction of Island Eastern Corridor with Tai Koo Shing
                    Interchange.</content></subsection>
            
            
        </continued><leadIn><b>Kowloon</b></leadIn><continued>
            
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197068_008" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>New Clear Water Bay Road, from a point about 50 metres north-west of the
                    junction of New Clear Water Bay Road with Lee On Road to the eastern junction of
                    New Clear Water Bay Road with Clear Water Bay Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197069_009" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Kwun Tong Road, westbound, from the junction of Kwun Tong Road with the
                    western end of the flyover joining Wai Yip Street Extension to the junction of
                    Kwun Tong Road with Prince Edward Road East.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197070_010" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Prince Edward Road East, westbound, from the junction of Prince Edward Road
                    East with Kwun Tong Road to a point, for the southernmost three lanes, about 16
                    metres east of lamp post No. E4354 at San Po Kong Interchange, and to a point,
                    for the other lanes, about 4 metres east of lamp post No. E4333 at San Po Kong
                    Interchange.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197071_011" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Prince Edward Road East, eastbound, from a point about 6 metres east of
                    lamp post No. E4326 at San Po Kong Interchange to, for both the northernmost
                    three lanes, and the other lanes, the junction of Prince Edward Road East with
                    Kwun Tong Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197072_012" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Kwun Tong Road, eastbound, from the junction of Kwun Tong Road with Prince
                    Edward Road East, to, for the northernmost three lanes, a point about 12 metres
                    west of lamp post No. K5686, and for the other lanes, to the junction of Kwun
                    Tong Road with the western end of the flyover leading to Wai Yip Street
                    Extension.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197073_013" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Ching Cheung Road, from the junction of Ching Cheung Road with Kwai Chung
                    Road to the junction of Ching Cheung Road with Tai Po Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197073_014" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Lung Cheung Road, from the junction of Lung Cheung Road with Tai Po Road to
                    a point about 25 metres west of lamp post No. K1049.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197075_015" name="8" temporalId="s3_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Tai Po Road, from the junction of Tai Po Road with Ching Cheung Road to the
                    junction of Tai Po Road with Lung Cheung Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197076_016" name="9" temporalId="s3_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Tai Po Road, from the junction of Tai Po Road with Lung Cheung Road to a
                    point about 240 metres north of the junction of Tai Po Road with Caldecott
                    Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197077_017" name="10" temporalId="s3_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Hong Chong Road, from the northern boundary of the Cross Harbour Tunnel
                    Area to the junction of Hong Chong Road with Princess Margaret Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197078_018" name="11" temporalId="s3_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>Princess Margaret Road, from the junction of Princess Margaret Road with
                    Hong Chong Road to the junction of Princess Margaret Road with Sheung Hing
                    Street and Pui Ching Road.</content></subsection>
            
            
        </continued><leadIn><b>New
                Territories</b></leadIn><continued>
            
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197079_019" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Clear Water Bay Road, from the eastern junction of Clear Water Bay Road
                    with New Clear Water Bay Road to a point about 150 metres south-east of the
                    junction of Clear Water Bay Road and Hiram’s Highway.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197080_020" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Clear Water Bay Road, from a point about 800 metres south of the junction
                    of Clear Water Bay Road with Hiram’s Highway to a point about 30 metres south of
                    the junction of Clear Water Bay Road with Hang Hau Road.</content></subsection>
            
            
            
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197081_021" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Hiram’s Highway, from the junction of Hiram’s Highway with Clear Water Bay
                    Road to a point about 1.2 kilometres north of the junction of Hiram’s Highway
                    with Clear Water Bay Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197082_022" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Tai Mong Tsai Road, from a point about 2.4 kilometres east of the junction
                    of Tai Mong Tsai Road with Sai Sha Road to the junction of Tai Mong Tsai Road
                    with Sai Kong Sai Wan Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197083_023" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Pak Tam Road, from the junction of Pak Tam Road with Tai Mong Tsai Road to
                    Wong Shek Pier.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197084_024" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Hoi Ha Road, from the junction of Hoi Ha Road with Pak Tam Road to Hoi
                    Ha.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197085_025" name="7" temporalId="s3_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Sai Sha Road, from the junction of Sai Sha Road with Tai Mong Tsai Road to
                    Nai Chung.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197086_026" name="8" temporalId="s3_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Lion Rock Tunnel Road, from the north boundary of the Lion Rock Tunnel Area
                    to the junction of Lion Rock Tunnel Road with Tai Po Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197087_027" name="9" temporalId="s3_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Road T1, Sha Tin, from the junction of Road T1 with Sha Tin Wai Road to the
                    junction of Road T1 with Tai Po Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197088_028" name="10" temporalId="s3_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Tai Po Road, from the junction of Tai Po Road with Lion Rock Tunnel Road to
                    the 41 mile milestone at Wong Yi Au.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197089_029" name="11" temporalId="s3_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>Tai Po Road, from a point about 250 metres north of the junction of Kwong
                    Fuk Road with Ting Kok Road to Wo Hop Shek access road.</content></subsection>
            
            
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197090_030" name="0" temporalId="s3_0"></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197091_031" name="0-1" temporalId="s3_0-1"></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197092_032" name="0-2" temporalId="s3_0-2"></subsection>
            
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197092_033" name="12" temporalId="s3_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>Ting
                    Kok Road, from the junction of Ting Kok Road with Tung Tsz Road to the junction
                    of Ting Kok Road with Bride’s Pool Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197093_034" name="13" temporalId="s3_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>Bride’s
                    Pool Road, from the junction of Bride’s Pool Road with Ting Kok Road to the
                    junction of Bride’s Pool Road with Luk Keng Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197095_035" name="14" temporalId="s3_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from a point about 330 metres east of the junction of Castle Peak
                    Road with Tan Kwai Tsuen Road to a point about 230 metres west of the junction
                    of Castle Peak Road with Ping Ha Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197096_036" name="15" temporalId="s3_15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from a point about 180 metres west of the junction of Castle Peak
                    Road with Yuen Long East Roundabout to the junction of Castle Peak Road with Au
                    Tau Roundabout.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197097_037" name="16" temporalId="s3_16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from the junction of Castle Peak Road with Au Tau Roundabout to a
                    point about 90 metres south of the 30 mile milestone on Castle Peak
                    Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197098_038" name="17" temporalId="s3_17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from a point about 390 metres east of the junction of Castle Peak
                    Road with Cassino Camp access road in San Tin to a point about 600 metres west
                    of the 33 mile milestone in Chau Tau.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197099_039" name="18" temporalId="s3_18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from a point about 300 metres west of the 34 mile milestone in Kwu
                    Tung to a point about 5 metres south of the junction of Castle Peak Road with
                    Fan Kam Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197100_040" name="19" temporalId="s3_19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content>Kam
                    Sheung Road, the whole length, both ends joining Kam Tin Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197101_041" name="20" temporalId="s3_20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content>Fan
                    Kam Road, from the junction of Fan Kam Road with Kam Tin Road to a point about
                    720 metres north of the 2 mile milestone in Ta Shek
                    Wu.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197102_042" name="21" temporalId="s3_21"><num value="21">(21)</num><content>Fan
                    Kam Road, from a point about 190 metres south of the junction of Fan Kam Road
                    with Lin Tong Mei access road to a point about 50 metres south of the junction
                    of Fan Kam Road with Castle Peak Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197103_043" name="22" temporalId="s3_22"><num value="22">(22)</num><content>Man
                    Kam To Road, from the junction of Man Kam To Road with Jockey Club Road to a
                    point about 60 metres south of the southern abutment of Man Kam To
                    Bridge.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197104_044" name="23" temporalId="s3_23"><num value="23">(23)</num><content>Sha
                    Tau Kok Road, from a point about 75 metres east of the junction of Sha Tau Kok
                    Road with Luen Shing Street to a point about 480 metres west of the junction of
                    Sha Tau Kok Road with Lin Ma Hang Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197105_045" name="24" temporalId="s3_24"><num value="24">(24)</num><content>Luk
                    Keng Road, from a point about 20 metres east of the eastern abutment of the
                    vehicular bridge near Luk Keng Wong Uk Village to the junction of Luk Keng Road
                    with Bride’s Pool Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197106_046" name="25" temporalId="s3_25"><num value="25">(25)</num><content>Tai
                    Po Road, from a point about 100 metres south-east of the junction of Tai Po Road
                    with Sha Tau Kok Road and a point about 450 metres south-east of the junction of
                    Tai Po Road with Wo Hop Shek access road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197107_047" name="26" temporalId="s3_26"><num value="26">(26)</num><content>Kam
                    Tin Road,
                    from
                    a point about 20 metres west of the junction of Kam Tin Road with Fan Kam Road
                    to a point about 210 metres west of the junction of Kam Tin Road with Kam Sheung
                    Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197108_048" name="27" temporalId="s3_27"><num value="27">(27)</num><content>Kam
                    Tin Road, from a point about 100 metres east of the junction of Kam Tin Road
                    with Au Tau Roundabout to a point about 10 metres west of the junction of Kam
                    Tin Road with Ko Po Tsuen access road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197109_049" name="28" temporalId="s3_28"><num value="28">(28)</num><content>Tuen
                    Mun Road, from the junction of Tuen Mun Road with Castle Peak Road in Tsuen Wan
                    to the northern abutment of the flyover across Castle Peak Road at Sam Shing
                    Hui.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197110_050" name="29" temporalId="s3_29"><num value="29">(29)</num><content>Road
                    P1, Tuen Mun, from the junction of Road P1, Tuen Mun with Tuen Mun Road to the
                    junction of Road P1, Tuen Mun with Pui To
                    Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197111_051" name="30" temporalId="s3_30"><num value="30">(30)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from a point about 330 metres south-west of the 13 mile milestone on
                    Castle Peak Road to a point about 200 metres north-west of the junction of
                    Castle Peak Road with Tai Lam Chung Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197112_052" name="31" temporalId="s3_31"><num value="31">(31)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from a point about 590 metres east of the 17 mile milestone on Castle
                    Peak Road to a point about 520 metres south-east of the 79 mile milestone on
                    Castle Peak Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197113_053" name="32" temporalId="s3_32"><num value="32">(32)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road,
                    from
                    a point about 160 metres north of the northern side of Tuen Mun Road at Sam
                    Shing Hui to a point about 25 metres north-west of the 20 mile milestone on
                    Castle Peak Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197114_054" name="33" temporalId="s3_33"><num value="33">(33)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, for the northbound carriageway, from a point about 830 metres south
                    of the junction of Castle Peak Road with Road D9 to a point about 65 metres
                    south-west of the junction of Castle Peak Road with Road LD4; for the southbound
                    carriageway, from a point about 690 metres south of the junction of Castle Peak
                    Road with Road D9 to a point about 45 metres south-west of the junction of
                    Castle Peak Road with Road LD4.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197115_055" name="34" temporalId="s3_34"><num value="34">(34)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak Road, from the 10 mile milestone of Castle Peak Road to Tin Kau at Beach
                    House 41.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197116_056" name="35" temporalId="s3_35"><num value="35">(35)</num><content>Castle
                    Peak
                    Road,
                    from a point about 150 metres west of Riviera Valley at Castle Peak Road to a
                    point about 350 metres south of Sham Tsz Street.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2024/er1">E.R. 1 of
                    2024</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197117_057" name="36" temporalId="s3_36"><num value="36">(36)</num><content>Kwai
                    Chung Road, from the Lai Chi Kok Bridge to the junction of Kwai Chung Road with
                    Tsuen Wan Road.</content></subsection>
            <subsection id="ID_1681367197118_058" name="37" temporalId="s3_37"><num value="37">(37)</num><content>Tsuen
                    Wan Road, from the junction of Tsuen Wan Road with Kwai Chung Road to the
                    junction of Tsuen Wan Road with Texaco Road.</content></subsection>
        </continued></section></main></subLeg>