<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 558 sub. leg. G</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>558G</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap558G!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2012-08-02</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403442883_003" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2012-08-02">International Organizations (Privileges and Immunities)
            (Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production, Stockpiling and Use of
            Chemical Weapons and on their Destruction) Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap558/s3">Cap. 558, section
                3</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2012/er2">E.R. 2 of
            2012</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[8 June 2012]</commencementNote><section id="ID_1438403442899_002" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2012-08-02" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2012/er2">E.R. 2 of 2012</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403442899_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-06-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Order—</leadIn><def name="Convention"><i><b>Convention </b></i>(《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公約</term>》) has the meaning given by <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Chemical Weapons (<term class="old_format">Convention</term>) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap578">Cap. 578</ref>);</def><def name="VerificationAnnex"><term>Verification Annex</term> (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">核查附件</term>》) means the Annex on Implementation and Verification to the Convention.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403442915_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-06-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Provisions of Convention having force of law in Hong Kong</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413326276_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>It is declared that the provisions of <ref>paragraphs 11</ref>, <ref>12</ref>, <ref>13</ref> (from “Without prejudice” to “the internal affairs of that State.”), 14 and 15 of Part II of the Verification Annex as specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref> have the force of law in Hong Kong and for that purpose are to be construed in accordance with subsections (2) and (3).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326276_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In applying the following paragraphs of Part II of the Verification Annex, the references to the following expressions are to be construed as meaning Hong Kong—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413326292_005" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in <ref>paragraph 11</ref>, “the territory of the inspected State Party or Host State”;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413326292_013" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in <ref>paragraph 11(g)</ref>, “the territory of the inspected State Party or Host State Party”;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413326292_021" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in <ref>paragraph 11(i)</ref>, “the territory of the inspected State Party or the Host State”;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413326292_029" name="d" temporalId="s3_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in <ref>paragraph 12</ref>, “the territory of non-inspected States Parties”; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413326292_037" name="e" temporalId="s3_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>in <ref>paragraph 13</ref>, “the inspected State Party or Host State”.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326292_044" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In applying <ref>paragraph 11(d)</ref> of Part II of the Verification Annex, the reference to “relevant regulations” is to be construed as meaning the laws of Hong Kong relating to the handling and transport of hazardous goods.</content></subsection></section><schedule id="ID_1438403442930_001" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2012-06-08" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap558G/s3">s. 3</ref>]</note><heading class="tied-tag-heading-center">Provisions of Convention Having Force of Law in
            Hong Kong</heading><crossHeading class="align_center">Part II of
            Verification
            Annex</crossHeading><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text><section class="no_header" id="ID_1536805038358_001" name="sB" temporalId="sch0_sB"><num value="B"><b>B.</b></num><content><b>PRIVILEGES AND IMMUNITIES</b></content></section><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text><section id="ID_1438413326338_038" name="s11" temporalId="sch0_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11"><inline class="not_bold">11.</inline></num><leadIn>To exercise their functions effectively, inspectors and inspection assistants
                shall be accorded privileges and immunities as set forth in subparagraphs (a) to
                (i). Privileges and immunities shall be granted to members of the inspection team
                for the sake of this Convention and not for the personal benefit of the individuals
                themselves. Such privileges and immunities shall be accorded to them for the entire
                period between arrival on and departure from the territory of the inspected State
                Party or Host State, and thereafter with respect to acts previously performed in the
                exercise of their official functions.</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438413326354_008" name="a" temporalId="sch0_s11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>The members of the inspection team shall be accorded the inviolability
                    enjoyed by diplomatic agents pursuant to Article 29 of the Vienna Convention on
                    Diplomatic Relations of 18 April 1961.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326370_008" name="b" temporalId="sch0_s11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>The living quarters and office premises occupied by the inspection team
                    carrying out inspection activities pursuant to this Convention shall be accorded
                    the inviolability and protection accorded to the premises of diplomatic agents
                    pursuant to Article 30, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, of the Vienna Convention on
                    Diplomatic Relations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326370_017" name="c" temporalId="sch0_s11_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>The papers and correspondence, including records, of the inspection team
                    shall enjoy the inviolability accorded to all papers and correspondence of
                    diplomatic agents pursuant to Article 30, <ref>paragraph 2</ref>, of the Vienna
                    Convention on Diplomatic Relations. The inspection team shall have the right to
                    use codes for their communications with the Technical Secretariat.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326385_008" name="d" temporalId="sch0_s11_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>Samples and approved equipment carried by members of the inspection team
                    shall be inviolable subject to provisions contained in this Convention and
                    exempt from all customs duties. Hazardous samples shall be transported in
                    accordance with relevant regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326385_017" name="e" temporalId="sch0_s11_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>The members of the inspection team shall be accorded the immunities
                    accorded to diplomatic agents pursuant to Article 31, <ref>paragraphs 1</ref>,
                        <ref>2</ref> and <ref>3</ref>, of the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic
                    Relations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326385_026" name="f" temporalId="sch0_s11_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>The members of the inspection team carrying out prescribed activities
                    pursuant to this Convention shall be accorded the exemption from dues and taxes
                    accorded to diplomatic agents pursuant to Article 34 of the Vienna Convention on
                    Diplomatic Relations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326401_008" name="g" temporalId="sch0_s11_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>The members of the inspection team shall be permitted to bring into the
                    territory of the inspected State Party or Host State Party, without payment of
                    any customs duties or related charges, articles for personal use, with the
                    exception of articles the import or export of which is prohibited by law or
                    controlled by quarantine
                    regulations.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326401_017" name="h" temporalId="sch0_s11_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>The members of the inspection team shall be accorded the same currency and
                    exchange facilities as are accorded to representatives of foreign Governments on
                    temporary official missions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413326416_008" name="i" temporalId="sch0_s11_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><leadIn>The members of the inspection team shall not engage in any professional or
                    commercial activity for personal profit on the territory of the inspected State
                    Party or the Host State.</leadIn></subsection></section><section name="s12" temporalId="sch0_s12" class="no_header" id="ID_1505098110445_001"><num value="12"><inline class="not_bold">12.</inline></num><content>When transiting the territory of non-inspected States Parties, the members of
                the inspection team shall be accorded the privileges and immunities enjoyed by
                diplomatic agents pursuant to Article 40, <ref>paragraph 1</ref>, of the Vienna
                Convention on Diplomatic Relations. Papers and correspondence, including records,
                and samples and approved equipment, carried by them, shall be accorded the
                privileges and immunities set forth in <ref>paragraph 11(c)</ref> and
                (d).</content></section><section name="s13" temporalId="sch0_s13" class="no_header" id="ID_1505098110445_002"><num value="13"><inline class="not_bold">13.</inline></num><content>Without prejudice to their privileges and immunities the members of the
                inspection team shall be obliged to respect the laws and regulations of the
                inspected State Party or Host State and, to the extent that is consistent with the
                inspection mandate, shall be obliged not to interfere in the internal affairs of
                that State. <inline class="not_bold">...</inline></content></section><section name="s14" temporalId="sch0_s14" class="no_header" id="ID_1505098110461_003"><num value="14"><inline class="not_bold">14.</inline></num><content>The immunity from jurisdiction of members of the inspection team may be waived
                by the Director-General in those cases when the Director-General is of the opinion
                that immunity would impede the course of justice and that it can be waived without
                prejudice to the implementation of the provisions of this Convention. Waiver must
                always be
                express.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></section><section name="s15" temporalId="sch0_s15" class="no_header" id="ID_1505098110461_004"><num value="15"><inline class="not_bold">15.</inline></num><content>Observers shall be accorded the same privileges and immunities accorded to
                inspectors pursuant to this section, except for those accorded pursuant to
                    <ref>paragraph 11(d)</ref>.</content></section><text><inline class="not_bold">...</inline></text></schedule></main></subLeg>