<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 337</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>337</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap337!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-10-08</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403030890_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2020-10-08">
            <content>To make provision concerning the re-development of sites of certain demolished
                buildings, and the compensation of certain tenants for loss of possession, and for
                purposes connected with the matters
                aforesaid.</content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[11 January 1963]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er5">E.R. 5 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403030906_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Demolished Buildings (Re-development of Sites) Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403030921_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412013866_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="BuildingAuthority"><term>Building
                    Authority</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">建築事務監督</term>) includes any person authorized to
                exercise the powers of the Building Authority under the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>);</def><def name="Director"><term>Director</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">署長</term>) means the Director of Buildings;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/ln76">L.N. 76
                        of 1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/ln94">L.N. 94 of 1986</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/ln291">L.N. 291 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="FinalAward"><term>final
                    award</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">最終判給額</term>) means the amount awarded under
                    <ref>section 7</ref> or, if the amount is reduced under <ref>section 8</ref>,
                the amount as so reduced;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of 1981 s. 60</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="LandRegistry"><term>Land
                    Registry</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地註冊處</term>) means the Land Registry established
                under the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap.
                    128</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2002/20">20 of 2002
                        s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Lease"><term>lease</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">租契</term>) includes an agreement for a lease and a
                tenancy agreement;</def><def name="Owner"><term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>) does not include a mortgagee;</def><def name="ProtectedBuilding"><term>protected
                    building</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受保障建築物</term>) means a building to which Part I of
                the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap.
                7</ref>) applies or at the relevant date applied, and it also means a building to
                any part of which that Part applies or so applied;</def><def name="ProtectedTenant"><term>protected
                    tenant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受保障租客</term>) means a tenant or sub-tenant at the
                relevant date of a protected building or part thereof but only where and to the
                extent Part I of the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap. 7</ref>) applies or at the relevant date applied to the
                subject matter of his tenancy;</def><def name="RedevelopmentNotice"><term>re-development
                    notice</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">重新發展通知書</term>) means a notice served by the
                Director under <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="RedevelopmentOrder"><term>re-development
                    order</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">重新發展令</term>)
                means
                an order made by the Director under <ref>section 4</ref>;</def><def name="TheRelevantDate"><leadIn><term>the
                        relevant
                    date</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關日期</term>) in relation to any protected
                    building means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412013882_033" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where an order has been made under <ref>section 26</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>) requiring the demolition of the building, the date of service of the order; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412013882_041" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where a fire or other calamity has occurred in consequence whereof the building has been demolished or certified by the Building Authority as being so dangerous as to require demolition, the date of the fire or calamity.</content></paragraph></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412013882_048" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The duties imposed on and the powers granted to the Director under this Ordinance may be carried out and exercised by any officer of the Buildings Department authorized by the Director either generally or particularly and subject to his instructions.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/ln76">L.N. 76 of 1982</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1986/ln94">L.N. 94 of 1986</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/ln291">L.N. 291 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403030937_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Premises made subject to Ordinance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412013929_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where under <ref>section 26</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>) the Building Authority serves an order in
                respect of a protected building requiring the demolition thereof, or where the
                Building Authority certifies that, as a result of fire or other calamity occurring
                after the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance, a protected building has been demolished or has in his opinion
                been rendered so dangerous as to require demolition, the Director may, within 3
                months of the service of the order or the occurrence of the fire or other calamity,
                serve notice in writing on the owner of the property comprising such building
                declaring that the property has become subject to the provisions of this
                Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412013944_005" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director shall cause a copy of such notice to be served on any person
                appearing from the Land Registry registers to have an interest in such property, and
                such notice shall be registered in the Land Registry by a memorial thereof signed by
                the Director.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1591342351403_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date:  11 January
                1963.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403030984_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Order for re-development</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412013975_019" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a re-development notice has been served in respect of any property, the
                Director may, within 3 months of the date of service thereof, by order in writing
                served on the owner require the re-development of the site of the property, within
                such time as he may prescribe, by the replacement of the building thereon or
                formerly thereon with a new, sound and substantial building, completed fit for
                occupation, conforming to the covenants, conditions and stipulations of the
                Government lease, and, subject to the provisions of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>), of no less gross floor area than the building
                replaced. The owner may, within 21 days of the date of service of such order or such
                extended time as the Lands Tribunal may allow, appeal to the Lands Tribunal against
                such order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/62">62 of 1974 s. 16</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1984/73">73 of
                        1984 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014007_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any order served under subsection (1) shall within one month of such service be
                registered in the Land Registry by a memorial thereof signed by the Director, and a
                copy of such order shall be served also on any person appearing from the Land
                Registry registers to have any interest in such property.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014022_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Upon the expiry of the time limited for appeal against an order made under
                subsection (1), or, in the event of an appeal, where such order is confirmed or
                another order is substituted therefor, the requirements made in such order or
                substituted order shall be deemed to be covenants, conditions or stipulations in the
                Government lease of the property to which the order relates, and thereafter failure
                to comply with any such requirement shall entitle the Government to re-enter upon
                the property under and in accordance with the provisions of the Government Rights
                (Re-entry and Vesting Remedies) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap126">Cap.
                126</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 65</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403030984_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Extinguishment of rights of protected tenants and compensation therefor</heading><leadIn>Where a re-development notice has been served in respect of any property—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412014053_035" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Part I of the Landlord and Tenant (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap7">Cap. 7</ref>) shall cease to apply to any part of any building comprised in the property, and the protected tenants shall cease to have any rights of occupation or possession in any such building; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412014069_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>every protected tenant shall be entitled to compensation in accordance with the provisions of this Ordinance from the person who was the owner of such property immediately before such notice was served.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403030999_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Assessment of incremental value</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014100_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a re-development notice has been served in respect of any property, the Director of Lands or any officer authorized by him shall assess the incremental value thereof, which shall be the amount by which the market value of the property with vacant possession after the service of such notice exceeds what was the market value of the property in occupation prior to the service by the Building Authority of the order for demolition or prior to the fire or other calamity occasioning the issue under <ref>section 3</ref> of the certificate of the Building Authority, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014116_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Director of Lands or any officer authorized by him shall give notice of such assessment to the owner of the property and to any person appearing from the Land Registry registers to have a mortgage on the property, and in addition he shall communicate it to any other person, not being a tenant, who makes application in writing to him and who he considers has good grounds for requiring such information.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014116_013" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The owner or any mortgagee so notified may, within 14 days of such notification, appeal to the Lands Tribunal against the assessment.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1974/62">62 of 1974 s. 16</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/ln291">L.N. 291 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403031015_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Claims for compensation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014147_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a re-development notice has been served in respect of any property, there shall be published in the Gazette and (with a translation in Chinese) affixed to the property, a copy of the notice together with, save where the Director of Lands or any officer authorized by him has found that no incremental value exists, a statement to the effect that protected tenants may apply in accordance with the provisions of subsection (2) to the Lands Tribunal to determine the amount of compensation payable to them.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of 1981 s. 60</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 19</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014163_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Within 3 weeks of the date of publication of the copy of the re-development notice in the Gazette, or such extended time as the Lands Tribunal may in its discretion allow, any protected tenant may, save where he and the owner of the property in respect of which the re-development notice has been served have entered into an agreement in writing for the payment of compensation or where the Director of Lands or any officer authorized by him has found that no incremental value exists, apply to the Lands Tribunal to determine the amount of compensation to which he is entitled under this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of 1981 s. 60</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 19</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014178_005" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of 1981 s. 60</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014178_013" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1975/58">58 of 1975 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014178_021" name="5...10" temporalId="s7_5...10"><num value="5...10">(5)-(10)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of 1981 s. 60</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014178_029" name="11" temporalId="s7_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><def name="Owner">For the purposes of this section and of <ref>sections 8</ref> and
                    <ref>9</ref>,
                    <term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">擁有人</term>) shall be deemed to include a
                mortgagee.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403031015_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Reduction of awards in excess of incremental value</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014194_051" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If the sum of the awards made by the Lands Tribunal, together with any amounts agreed to be paid to other protected tenants by the owner by way of compensation exceeds the assessment of the incremental value, the owner may, within 14 days of the notification of such awards, apply to the Lands Tribunal for the reduction of the awards made.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of 1981 s. 60</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014209_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>On an application being made under subsection (1) the Lands Tribunal shall
                proceed to determine the amount of compensation which it would have awarded to every
                protected tenant with whom the owner has entered into an agreement in writing for
                the payment of compensation had the tenant applied to the Lands Tribunal under
                    <ref>section 7(2)</ref>, and if the total (hereinafter referred to as
                        <b><i>the
                        said total</i></b>) of the amounts which it would have so awarded and of the
                amounts which it has awarded or such amounts as may have been substituted therefor
                on any appeal, exceeds the said assessment, the Lands Tribunal shall reduce the
                amounts which it has awarded to amounts which bear the same proportion to the
                amounts awarded as the said assessment does to the said total.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of
                        1981 s. 60</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s.
                    20</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014241_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The reduced awards shall be notified to the tenants in respect of whom they were made, to the owner and to the Director.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403031046_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Payment of compensation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014256_012" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The final awards shall be published in the Gazette, and shall be registered in the Land Registry by a memorial thereof signed by the Director. Such awards shall be payable within 3 weeks of the notification thereof.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014256_020" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any protected tenant who has been awarded compensation in accordance with <ref>section 7</ref> does not, within the period limited by subsection (1), demand payment of the compensation awarded to him, the owner may deposit with the Treasury the sum awarded together with any interest accrued due thereon under subsection (5).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014272_005" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any such sum so deposited may, within a period of 5 years from the date of such deposit, be claimed by the person entitled thereto and, upon any such claim being substantiated, shall be paid to the person so entitled.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014272_013" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>At the expiration of the said period of 5 years, any such sum remaining unpaid shall be transferred to the general revenue.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/71">71 of 1971 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 21</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014272_021" name="5" temporalId="s9_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In the event of any sum awarded as compensation not being paid within the period limited by subsection (1) or deposited with the Treasury in accordance with subsection (2) within 1 week thereafter, the sum awarded shall bear interest at the rate of 10 per cent per annum from the expiry of the period within which it should have been paid in accordance with subsection (1) until payment or deposit under subsection (2).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1981/76">76 of 1981 s. 60</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403031062_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Enforcement of awards</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014303_035" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The final awards may be enforced against the person liable to pay such
                compensation in the same manner as a judgment of the High Court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of
                        1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014303_043" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412014303_051" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a re-development notice has been served in respect of any property,
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412014319_006" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any person liable to pay, or whose interest in the property is or may be
                    made subject to a charge for, compensation under this Ordinance has applied for
                    permission to carry out building works, other than demolition, in relation to
                    that property,</content></paragraph><continued>the Building Authority may refuse to grant such permission until he is
                satisfied that all sums due to the protected tenants by way of compensation under
                this Ordinance (whether under an award or under an agreement) of which the
                Government has notice have been paid to the persons entitled thereto or have been
                deposited with the Treasury under <ref>section 9(2)</ref>.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403031062_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Provisions where property resumed by the Government</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014334_041" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a re-development notice has been served in respect of any property and
                the Government has resumed the same either in accordance with the terms of the
                Government lease under which the property is held or under the provisions of the
                Lands Resumption Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap124">Cap. 124</ref>), there shall be
                deducted from the compensation payable by the Government to the owner in respect of
                the resumption all sums due to the protected tenants by way of compensation under
                this Ordinance (whether under an award or under an agreement) of which the
                Government has notice.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 66</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014350_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any such sum deducted shall be paid by the Government to the person entitled
                thereto or, if such person cannot be found, shall be deposited with the
                Treasury.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014350_013" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any such sum so deposited may, within a period of 5 years from the date of such
                deposit, be claimed by the person entitled thereto, and, upon any such claim being
                substantiated, shall be paid to the person so entitled.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014365_005" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>At the expiration of the said period of 5 years, any such sum remaining unpaid
                shall be transferred to the general revenue.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/71">71 of 1971 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 21</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014365_013" name="5" temporalId="s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where any sum is deducted under subsection (1), no interest shall accrue
                thereon after the date of deduction.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403031077_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Charge for compensation awarded</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014381_043" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Upon the registration in the Land Registry under <ref>section 9(1)</ref> of a
                final award, the amount of such award and any interest accrued or thereafter
                accruing thereon shall, until the compensation and interest are paid, constitute a
                charge on the property in respect of which the compensation has been awarded in
                favour of The Financial Secretary Incorporated in trust for the person or persons
                entitled to the compensation and interest.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1975/ln63">L.N. 63 of 1975</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1985/ln180">L.N. 180 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1993/8">8
                        of 1993 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014397_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to the priority of instruments executed prior to the
                commencement*
                of this Ordinance a charge created by subsection (1) shall have priority over all
                other instruments affecting the property against which the charge is registered
                executed after such commencement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014397_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purpose of enforcing any such charge, The Financial Secretary
                Incorporated shall have all the same powers and remedies as are, under the
                Conveyancing and Property Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap219">Cap. 219</ref>), and
                otherwise, available in Hong Kong to a mortgagee under a legal charge or equitable
                mortgage by deed, and the provisions of the said Ordinance which apply where a
                mortgagee exercises any such power or avails himself of any such remedy shall apply
                where The Financial Secretary Incorporated exercises any such power or avails
                himself of any such remedy.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1985/ln180">L.N. 180 of 1985</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/61">61 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1591347244121_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline>  Commencement date:  11 January
                1963.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403031093_001" name="s13" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1971/72">72 of 1971 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403031093_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Determination of appeals under <ref>sections 4</ref> and <ref>6</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438412014459_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>In determining an appeal under <ref>section 4</ref> the Lands Tribunal may confirm or set aside the re-development order and may substitute therefor any other re-development order which it thinks proper and which could have been made by the Director.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 22</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014459_012" name="1A" temporalId="s14_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>In determining an appeal under <ref>section 6</ref> the Lands Tribunal may confirm or set aside the incremental value and may substitute therefor any other incremental value which it thinks proper and which could have been made by the Director of Lands or any officer authorized by him.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 22</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412014475_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The decision of the Lands Tribunal shall set out the matters for which allowance is made in making its determination and such decision shall be final.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1974/62">62 of 1974 s. 16</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403031108_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Service of notices and orders</heading><leadIn>Service of any notice, communication or order which may be given or served under the
            provisions of this Ordinance may be effected—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412014490_012" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>personally; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412014490_020" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by registered post addressed to the last known place of business or residence
                of the person to be served; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412014490_028" name="c" temporalId="s15_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>by leaving the same with an adult occupier of the premises to which the notice,
                communication or order relates; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412014490_036" name="d" temporalId="s15_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>
                <leadIn>by posting the same upon a conspicuous part of such premises:</leadIn>
                
            </content></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s15_d_proviso">Provided that in addition to or in
            substitution for any such method of service the publication in the Gazette of such
            notice or order together with the available particulars of the person to whom it is
            addressed shall be deemed to be good service.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438403031108_004" name="s16" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/68">68 of 1995 s. 23</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403031124_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-10-08" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Saving of rights of Government and powers of Building Authority</heading><leadIn>Nothing in this Ordinance shall be deemed to take away or affect—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412014521_019" name="a" temporalId="s17_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any rights of the Government or any remedies of the Government for the
                enforcement of, or otherwise in respect of, such rights; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s.
                    67</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412014521_027" name="b" temporalId="s17_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any powers of the Building Authority under the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>).</content></paragraph></section></main></ordinance>