<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 571 sub. leg. F</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>571F</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap571F!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403475020_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2017-02-15">Securities
            and
            Futures
            (Leveraged
            Foreign
            Exchange
            Trading)
            (Arbitration)
            Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap571/s118">Cap. 571, section
                118(2)</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of
            2017</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 April 2003]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2003/ln12">L.N. 12 of 2003</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403475035_001" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            1</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403475035_003" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="/hk/2017/er1">E.R. 1 of 2017</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403475035_005" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these Rules, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ArbitrationPanel"><term>arbitration
                panel</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">仲裁小組</term>) means the arbitration panel established by
                <ref>section 4</ref>;</def><def name="Arbitrator"><term>arbitrator</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">仲裁人</term>) means an arbitrator appointed under any
            provision of these Rules;</def><def name="Chairman"><term>chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">主席</term>) means the chairman of the arbitration
            panel;</def><def name="Claimant"><term>claimant</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">申索人</term>), in relation to a dispute being referred to
            arbitration, means the party making the claim;</def><def name="Clerk"><term>clerk</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">書記</term>) means the clerk to the arbitration panel
            referred to in <ref>section 4(6)</ref>;</def><def name="ClientContract"><term>client
                contract</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">客戶合約</term>) means any contract or arrangement between
            a licensed corporation and its client, which contains terms on which the licensed
            corporation is to provide leveraged foreign exchange trading services;</def><def name="DeputyChairman"><term>deputy
                chairman</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">副主席</term>) means the deputy chairman of the
            arbitration panel;</def><def name="Dispute"><term>dispute</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">爭議</term>) means any dispute between a licensed
            corporation and a client regarding or touching upon any matter concerning the carrying
            on of leveraged foreign exchange trading;</def><def name="HKIAC"><term>HKIAC</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">仲裁中心</term>) means the Hong Kong International
            Arbitration Centre;</def><def name="Member"><term>member</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">成員</term>) means a member of the arbitration
            panel;</def><def name="Party"><term>party</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">當事一方</term>) means a party to a dispute;</def><def name="Respondent"><term>respondent</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">答辯人</term>), in relation to a dispute being referred to
            arbitration, means the party against whom the claim is made.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403475051_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Purpose of these Rules</heading><content>These Rules govern the resolution of any dispute that is required to be settled by arbitration pursuant to <ref>section 118(1)(b)</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403475051_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Constitution of arbitration panel</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413482713_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>For the purposes of resolving disputes in accordance with these Rules, there is established a panel to be known as the arbitration panel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482713_019" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The arbitration panel consists of a chairman, a deputy chairman and other members, to be appointed by the Financial Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482729_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Directors and employees of the Commission are not eligible for appointment as members.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482729_013" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Financial Secretary may determine the term of office of a member, but a member may resign his office at any time by a notice in writing sent to the Financial Secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482729_021" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If the office of chairman is vacant or the chairman is unable to act as chairman due to illness, other incapacity or absence from Hong Kong, the deputy chairman or failing him, such other member as the Financial Secretary may designate, shall act as chairman in his place.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482729_029" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The arbitration panel shall have a clerk, who shall be appointed by the Commission.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482729_037" name="7" temporalId="s4_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>The clerk shall prepare and maintain a list of members, which shall be made available for public inspection at all reasonable times free of charge.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403475066_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            2</num><heading>Rules Relating
            to Commencement
            of
            Arbitration
            Proceedings</heading><section id="ID_1438403475082_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Commencement of proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413482807_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (3), a client may send a notice in writing, signed by him or on his behalf, to the licensed corporation with which he has a dispute requiring the dispute to be settled by arbitration in accordance with these Rules.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482807_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where the client has not sent a notice in writing under subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413482807_020" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the licensed corporation may send to the client with whom it has a dispute a notice in writing (containing the particulars described in subsection <ref>(7)(b)</ref>, (d) and (e)), signed by it or on its behalf, referring the client to his right to require the dispute to be settled by arbitration in accordance with these Rules; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413482822_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the client may send to the licensed corporation a notice in writing, signed by him or on his behalf, within 14 days after the receipt of the notice in writing under paragraph (a), requiring the dispute to be settled by arbitration in accordance with these Rules.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482822_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a licensed corporation has sent to a client a notice in writing under subsection <ref>(2)(a)</ref> and the client has not sent to the licensed corporation a notice in writing under subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref> within the time specified in subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref>, the client is not entitled to require the dispute to be settled by arbitration in accordance with these Rules.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482838_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subject to subsection (5), despite court proceedings having commenced in respect of a dispute, the client may require that the dispute be settled by arbitration, by sending a notice in writing signed by him or on his behalf to the licensed corporation to that effect within 14 days after the commencement of the court proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482838_013" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a licensed corporation has sent to a client a notice in writing under subsection <ref>(2)(a)</ref> and the client has not sent to the licensed corporation a notice in writing under subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref> within the time specified in subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref>, subsection (4) does not apply to that dispute.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482854_005" name="6" temporalId="s5_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Arbitration proceedings are deemed to commence on the date on which the notice in writing under subsection (1) or (4), or where applicable, the notice in writing under subsection <ref>(2)(b)</ref>, is sent to the licensed corporation in accordance with <ref>section 33</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482854_013" name="7" temporalId="s5_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>A notice in writing sent under subsection (1) or (4) shall include—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413482854_021" name="a" temporalId="s5_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a demand that the dispute be referred to arbitration;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413482854_029" name="b" temporalId="s5_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the names and addresses of the parties;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413482869_007" name="c" temporalId="s5_7_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a reference to the arbitration clause that the client is relying on, where applicable;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413482869_015" name="d" temporalId="s5_7_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>a reference to the client contract; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413482869_023" name="e" temporalId="s5_7_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a brief summary of the dispute, the remedy sought and an indication of the amount of money involved.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482869_030" name="8" temporalId="s5_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Any notice in writing sent under this section by a body corporate or a partnership shall be completed and signed on its behalf by one of its directors or partners (as the case may be).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482869_038" name="9" temporalId="s5_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>A party who has sent a notice in writing under this section shall send a copy of the notice to the clerk for filing as soon as reasonably practicable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482869_046" name="10" temporalId="s5_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>During the course of an arbitration under these Rules, neither party may pursue any suit, action or proceedings against the other in respect of the dispute referred to arbitration under these Rules.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475082_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Initial deposit</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413482932_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>When a copy of the notice in writing under <ref>section 5(1)</ref>, (2)(a) or (4) is sent to the clerk for filing, the party sending the notice shall deposit with the clerk a sum of $1,000.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482932_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a licensed corporation has sent to a client a notice in writing under <ref>section 5(2)(a)</ref> and the client has not sent to the licensed corporation a notice in writing under <ref>section 5(2)(b)</ref> within the time specified in <ref>section 5(2)(b)</ref>, the clerk shall, as soon as reasonably practicable, arrange to return to the licensed corporation the deposit that has been paid by the licensed corporation after deducting any amount reasonably incurred by the arbitration panel.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475098_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Representation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413482978_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A party may conduct arbitration proceedings in person or be represented by any other person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482978_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a party is a body corporate or a partnership, it may be represented by a director or a partner (as the case may be) or any other person authorized by it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482978_020" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A party shall send the name and address of its representative (if any) or other person (if any) authorized by it under subsection (1) or (2) (as the case may be) to the other party, with a copy sent to the clerk for filing, as soon as reasonably practicable after they have been decided on.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413482978_028" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A party shall notify the clerk and the other party immediately of any change of its representative or person authorized by it, or any change in the name or address of the representative or person authorized by it.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475098_004" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Oaths and affirmation</heading><content>All evidence shall be given under oath or affirmation.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403475113_001" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            3</num><heading>The
            Arbitrator</heading><section id="ID_1438403475113_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Selection of arbitrator</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483041_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The chairman shall appoint from the arbitration panel a tribunal consisting of a single arbitrator to conduct the arbitration as soon as reasonably practicable after—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483041_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the arbitration has commenced as provided in <ref>section 5(6)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483056_006" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a deposit has been received by the clerk in accordance with <ref>section 6(1)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483056_013" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The parties shall provide such information as may be required by the chairman to assist him in the selection of an arbitrator in respect of their arbitration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483056_021" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The chairman has full discretion in the selection of an arbitrator under these Rules.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483056_029" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The chairman shall notify the parties of his decision on the selection of an arbitrator in respect of their arbitration as soon as reasonably practicable.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475113_005" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Challenge of arbitrator</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483088_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A party may challenge an arbitrator if circumstances exist to give rise to justifiable doubts as to the impartiality or independence of the arbitrator.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483088_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A party challenging the appointment of an arbitrator shall send a notice of challenge to the clerk setting out the reasons for such challenge, with a copy to the other party, within 14 days of the notification of such appointment or, if later, of his becoming aware of the circumstances giving rise to justifiable doubts as to the impartiality or independence of the arbitrator.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483103_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the other party concurs with the challenge or the challenged arbitrator withdraws from the appointment, the challenged arbitrator’s office falls vacant and <ref>section 9</ref> applies for the purposes of selecting a new arbitrator. In neither case does this imply acceptance of the validity of the grounds for the challenge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483103_013" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the other party does not concur with the challenge or the challenged arbitrator does not withdraw from the appointment, the chairman shall make a decision on the challenge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483119_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If the chairman upholds the challenge, <ref>section 9</ref> applies for the purposes of selecting a new arbitrator.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475129_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Replacement of arbitrator</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483150_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn><ref>Section 9</ref> applies for the purposes of selecting a new arbitrator if, during the course of an arbitration, the arbitrator—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483150_012" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has died;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483150_020" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has resigned;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483150_028" name="c" temporalId="s11_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>is absent from Hong Kong; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483150_036" name="d" temporalId="s11_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>is unable to act as arbitrator due to illness or other incapacity.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483150_043" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If a new arbitrator is appointed, the hearing of the dispute shall start afresh
                unless both parties and the new arbitrator agree to continue with the proceedings on
                the basis of notes of proceedings taken at any such hearing prior to the replacement
                of the
                arbitrator.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475129_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Remuneration of arbitrator</heading><content>The arbitrator is to be paid such remuneration and allowances as the Financial Secretary may determine.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403475129_006" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            4</num><heading>Rules Relating
            to
            Arbitration
            Proceedings</heading><section id="ID_1438403475144_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Conduct of proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483212_004" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Despite other provisions of these Rules, the arbitrator—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483212_012" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may conduct the arbitration in such manner as he considers appropriate and has the power to adopt, whenever possible, a simplified or expedited procedure and to conduct proceedings to ensure the just, expeditious, economical and final determination of the dispute; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483212_020" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall ensure that the parties are treated with equality and that at any stage of the proceedings each party is given a full opportunity to present that party’s case.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483228_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The arbitrator may, with the consent of the parties, decide whether to hold hearings for the presentation of evidence by witnesses, including expert witnesses, or for oral argument, or to conduct proceedings only on the basis of documents and other materials.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483228_013" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>All documents or information to be supplied to an arbitrator shall be sent to the clerk for transmission to the arbitrator, save where documents or information are submitted during a hearing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483228_021" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>All documents and information to be supplied to an arbitrator shall be sent to the clerk as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483228_029" name="a" temporalId="s13_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where a party submits documents or information during a hearing, one copy shall be sent to the clerk by that party immediately after the hearing; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483244_006" name="b" temporalId="s13_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in all other cases, a party shall supply 2 sets of all documents or information to the clerk, except where they have been sent to the clerk by facsimile or electronic mail transmission in accordance with <ref>section 33</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483244_013" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The arbitrator may appoint any legally qualified person to advise him on any matter relating to the arbitration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483244_021" name="6" temporalId="s13_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Without prejudice to subsection (5), the arbitrator may seek advice from any representative of the HKIAC who is attending the proceedings in accordance with <ref>section 16</ref> on any matter relating to the practice and procedure of an arbitration.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475144_004" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Notes of proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483290_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Notes of proceedings before an arbitrator may be taken by a person appointed as a note-taker by the arbitrator and any party is entitled to inspect and take copies of the transcript of such notes on payment of the note-taker’s charges.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483290_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If no note-taker is appointed, the arbitrator shall take a note of the proceedings and any party is entitled to inspect and take copies of such note.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475160_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Designation of date, time and place of arbitration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483322_004" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The arbitrator shall designate a date, time and place in Hong Kong for the arbitration to take place.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483322_012" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of the date, time and place for the initial hearing shall be sent by the clerk to the parties, in accordance with <ref>section 33</ref>, at least 21 days prior to the date fixed for the hearing and notice for each hearing thereafter shall be given as the arbitrator may determine.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483322_020" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The arbitrator may conduct hearings, hear witnesses and hold meetings for consultation at any place he considers appropriate, having regard to the circumstances of the arbitration.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475160_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Attendance of representative of HKIAC</heading><content>A representative of the HKIAC may be present throughout the proceedings.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403475160_005" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Statement of claim</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483368_004" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Unless a statement of claim was contained in or attached to the notice in writing requiring settlement of a dispute by arbitration, the claimant shall send his statement of claim to the respondent and to the arbitrator in accordance with <ref>sections 13(3)</ref> and (4) and 33, within 14 days from the date the arbitration is deemed to have commenced under <ref>section 5(6)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483384_005" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A copy of the relevant client contract shall be annexed or otherwise attached to the statement of claim.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483384_013" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The statement of claim shall include the following particulars—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483384_021" name="a" temporalId="s17_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the names and addresses of the parties;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483384_029" name="b" temporalId="s17_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a statement of the facts supporting the claim;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483384_037" name="c" temporalId="s17_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the points at issue; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483384_045" name="d" temporalId="s17_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the remedy sought.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483384_052" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The claimant may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483384_060" name="a" temporalId="s17_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>annex or otherwise attach to the statement of claim all documents that the claimant considers relevant; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483384_068" name="b" temporalId="s17_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>add a reference to the documents or other evidence that the claimant
                    intends to
                    submit.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475176_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Statement of defence or counterclaim</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483431_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The respondent shall send a statement of defence to the claimant and to the arbitrator in accordance with <ref>sections 13(3)</ref> and (4) and 33, within 14 days from the date on which the statement of claim is sent to the respondent.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483446_005" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The statement of defence shall reply to the particulars of the statement of claim referred to in <ref>section 17(3)(b)</ref>, (c) and (d).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483446_013" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The respondent may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483446_021" name="a" temporalId="s18_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>annex or otherwise attach to the statement of defence documents on which the respondent relies in defence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483446_029" name="b" temporalId="s18_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>add a reference to the documents or other evidence that the respondent intends to submit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483446_036" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>In the statement of defence, or at a later stage in the arbitration proceedings if the arbitrator decides that the delay is justified under the circumstances, the respondent may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483446_044" name="a" temporalId="s18_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>make a counterclaim arising out of the same dispute; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483446_052" name="b" temporalId="s18_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>rely on a claim arising out of that dispute for the purpose of a set-off.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483446_059" name="5" temporalId="s18_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content><ref>Section 17</ref> applies to a counterclaim and a claim relied on for the purpose of a set-off in the same manner as it applies to a statement of claim.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475207_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Amendments and further statements</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483493_004" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>During the course of an arbitration, a party may amend or supplement that party’s claim, defence or counterclaim except where the arbitrator considers it inappropriate to allow this, having regard to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483493_012" name="a" temporalId="s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any delay involved;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483493_020" name="b" temporalId="s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the likelihood of prejudice to the other party; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483493_028" name="c" temporalId="s19_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any other relevant circumstances.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483493_035" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The arbitrator may require or accept amendment to or supplement of a party’s claim, defence or counterclaim, and shall fix the period for the sending of such amendment or supplement.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475207_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Time period for sending further statements</heading><content>The period fixed by the arbitrator for the sending of any amendments or supplements under <ref>section 19</ref>, may not exceed 21 days from the date of such amendments or supplements, unless an extension is requested by a party and the arbitrator is satisfied that such an extension is justified in the circumstances.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403475207_005" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Evidence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483540_011" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Each party has the burden of proving the facts relied on to support that party’s claim, defence or counterclaim.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483540_019" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The arbitrator—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483540_027" name="a" temporalId="s21_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall determine the admissibility, materiality, relevance and weight of any evidence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483540_035" name="b" temporalId="s21_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may admit evidence irrespective of the rules governing the admissibility of evidence in court if, in his opinion, the interest of justice is served by so doing.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483556_005" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the arbitrator considers it appropriate, he may require a party to send to him and to the other party, within a period stipulated by him, a summary of the documents and other evidence which that party intends to present in support of the facts in issue set out in that party’s statement.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475222_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Hearing of witnesses</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483587_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If any witness is to be heard, each party shall send a notice to the arbitrator and to the other party at least 14 days before the hearing specifying—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483587_012" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the name and address of the witness;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483587_020" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the subject matter of the witness’s testimony or, if the arbitrator so requires, a transcript of the witness’s statement or expert report; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483587_028" name="c" temporalId="s22_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the language in which the witness will give his testimony.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483587_035" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The arbitrator may arrange for translations or recordings to be made at a hearing as he considers appropriate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483587_043" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Hearings shall be held in public unless the arbitrator decides otherwise with the consent of the parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483587_051" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The arbitrator may require the retirement of any witness during the testimony of any other witness.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483602_005" name="5" temporalId="s22_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Evidence of a witness may also be presented in the form of a written statement signed by him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483602_013" name="6" temporalId="s22_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The arbitrator is free to determine the manner in which a witness is examined.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475222_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Default</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483634_004" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If, within the period fixed by the arbitrator, the claimant fails to file a statement of claim without showing sufficient cause for such failure, the arbitrator may make an order for the termination of the arbitration proceedings in accordance with <ref>section 27</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483634_012" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If, within the period fixed by the arbitrator, the respondent fails to file a statement of defence without showing sufficient cause for such failure, the arbitrator may, as he thinks fit, make an order in favour of the claimant or make an order for the termination of the arbitration proceedings in accordance with <ref>section 27</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483649_005" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If one of the parties, duly notified under these Rules, fails to appear at a hearing or fails to produce any document in that party’s possession when required to do so, without valid excuse, the arbitrator may proceed with the arbitration and such proceedings are deemed to have been conducted in accordance with <ref>section 13(1)</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475222_005" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Consolidation of proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483680_004" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where in relation to 2 or more arbitration proceedings it appears to the chairman—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483680_012" name="a" temporalId="s24_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that a common question of law or fact arises in both or all of them;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483680_020" name="b" temporalId="s24_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the claims arise out of the same transaction or series of transactions; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483680_028" name="c" temporalId="s24_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that it is desirable to make an order under this section for any other reason,</content></paragraph><continued>the chairman may—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438413483680_042" name="d" temporalId="s24_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><leadIn>order those arbitration proceedings—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413483680_050" name="i" temporalId="s24_1_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to be consolidated on such terms as he thinks just; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413483680_058" name="ii" temporalId="s24_1_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to be heard immediately after one another; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483696_006" name="e" temporalId="s24_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>order any of those arbitration proceedings to be stayed until after the determination of any other of them.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483696_013" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 10</ref>, the chairman may select another arbitrator to conduct the arbitration proceedings consolidated under subsection <ref>(1)(d)(i)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483696_021" name="3" temporalId="s24_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where the chairman selects an arbitrator pursuant to subsection (2), any prior appointment of an arbitrator for any of the arbitration proceedings being consolidated ceases to have effect.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475238_002" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Jurisdiction</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483727_020" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The arbitrator has the power to rule on any objection by either party to his jurisdiction to hear the dispute.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483727_028" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No objection to the arbitrator’s jurisdiction may be raised after the sending of the statement of defence or, with respect to a counterclaim, after the sending of the reply to the counterclaim.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483743_005" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The arbitrator may rule on an objection to his jurisdiction as a preliminary question or may proceed with the arbitration and rule on such an objection in his final award.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483743_013" name="4" temporalId="s25_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where applicable, an arbitration clause is treated as being independent of the other terms of a client contract and any decision made by the arbitrator or a court of law declaring that the client contract is void does not of itself invalidate the arbitration clause.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403475238_004" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            5</num><heading>Rules Relating
            to Termination
            of
            Arbitration
            Proceedings</heading><section id="ID_1438403475254_001" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Settlement</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483790_004" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If, before the award is made, the parties agree on a settlement of the dispute, the arbitrator shall record the settlement in the form of an arbitration award on agreed terms.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483790_012" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The arbitrator is not obliged to give reasons for an award made under subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483790_020" name="3" temporalId="s26_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An award made under subsection (1) shall be signed by the arbitrator, sent to the parties and lodged with the clerk for filing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483790_028" name="4" temporalId="s26_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An award made under subsection (1) is final and binding on the parties.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475254_003" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Termination of proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483821_004" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If, before the award is made, the continuation of the arbitration proceedings becomes unnecessary or impossible for any reason other than by way of an agreement to settle between the parties, the arbitrator may, either on his own initiative or at the request of a party, make an order for the termination of the arbitration proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483821_012" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The arbitrator shall state in the order the reasons for the termination.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483821_020" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An order made under subsection (1) shall be signed by the arbitrator, sent to the parties and lodged with the clerk for filing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483836_005" name="4" temporalId="s27_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An order made under subsection (1) is final and binding on the parties.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475254_005" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Form and effect of awards</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483852_026" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An award shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483852_034" name="a" temporalId="s28_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>give reasons for the decision;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483868_003" name="b" temporalId="s28_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be signed by the arbitrator; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483868_011" name="c" temporalId="s28_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>contain the date on which and the place where it was made.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483868_018" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In addition to making a final award, the arbitrator has the power to make interim, interlocutory or partial awards during the course of an arbitration.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483868_026" name="3" temporalId="s28_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An award made by the arbitrator under this section shall be sent to the parties and lodged with the clerk for filing.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483868_034" name="4" temporalId="s28_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An award made by the arbitrator shall be made public but, where the arbitrator considers it appropriate to do so, this may be done in a manner that preserves the anonymity of the parties.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483868_042" name="5" temporalId="s28_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Despite subsection (4), the Commission—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413483868_050" name="a" temporalId="s28_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall be notified by the clerk of any award made in respect of a licensed corporation; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413483868_058" name="b" temporalId="s28_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may make use of any findings made by an arbitrator for the purposes of performing its functions under the Ordinance including, but without limitation, assessing whether the licensed corporation is a fit and proper person to be so licensed.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483883_005" name="6" temporalId="s28_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>An award made by the arbitrator is final and binding on the
                parties.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475269_002" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Correction of awards</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483930_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Within 14 days after the receipt of the award, either party may, with notice to the other party, request the arbitrator to correct in the award any errors in computation, any clerical or typographical errors or any errors of a similar nature.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483930_012" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the arbitrator considers the request made under subsection (1) to be justified, he shall make the correction within 14 days after the receipt of the request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483930_020" name="3" temporalId="s29_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The arbitrator may, on his own initiative, correct any error of the type referred to in subsection (1) within 28 days after the date of the award.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483946_005" name="4" temporalId="s29_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><ref>Section 28</ref> applies in relation to such corrections.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475285_002" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Additional awards</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413483961_025" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Within 14 days after the receipt of an award, either party may, with notice to the other party, request the arbitrator to make an additional award as to claims presented during the course of the arbitration but omitted from the award.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483977_005" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the arbitrator considers the request for an additional award to be justified and considers that the omission can be rectified without any further evidence, he may make the additional award within 14 days after the receipt of the request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413483977_013" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Section 28</ref> applies in relation to such additional award.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475285_004" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Costs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413484008_004" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The arbitrator shall make an order for costs whenever he makes an arbitration award, including an award on agreed terms, and an order for the termination of the arbitration proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484008_012" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsection (3), the costs of an arbitration are to be borne by the unsuccessful party.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484008_020" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The arbitrator may apportion costs between the parties if he considers that apportionment is reasonable in the circumstances.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484008_028" name="4" temporalId="s31_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The order for costs shall specify—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413484008_036" name="a" temporalId="s31_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>the sum to be paid, which shall include—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413484008_044" name="i" temporalId="s31_4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the amount of fees of the arbitrator;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413484024_005" name="ii" temporalId="s31_4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>costs for legal advice or for other assistance such as translation, oral interpretation and note-taking required by the arbitrator;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413484024_013" name="iii" temporalId="s31_4_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>travel and other expenses of witnesses to the extent allowed by the arbitrator;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413484024_021" name="iv" temporalId="s31_4_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>costs of the successful party, including the costs for legal representation, to the extent allowed by the arbitrator; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413484024_029" name="v" temporalId="s31_4_a_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the amount of administrative or other costs incurred by the arbitrator and the arbitration panel;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484024_036" name="b" temporalId="s31_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the parties to and by whom payment shall be made; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484024_044" name="c" temporalId="s31_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the time limit for making payment.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484024_051" name="5" temporalId="s31_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A party against whom such an order is made shall make payment in accordance with the order.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475300_002" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Deposits of costs</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413484070_004" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>At any time during the arbitration proceedings, the arbitrator may require any party to deposit with the clerk such sum or sums to defray the expenses of the arbitration if the arbitrator considers it expedient to do so in the circumstances.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484070_012" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In determining the amount of any deposit, the arbitrator shall take into account the amount in dispute, the complexity of the subject matter, the costs incurred or to be incurred by the arbitrator, and other relevant circumstances of the case.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484070_020" name="3" temporalId="s32_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If payment of the required deposit is not made by the relevant party within 14 days after the receipt of the requirement, the arbitrator may make an order for the termination of the arbitration proceedings in accordance with <ref>section 27</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484086_005" name="4" temporalId="s32_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>After the termination of proceedings, with the assistance of the arbitrator, the clerk—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413484086_013" name="a" temporalId="s32_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall render an account to the parties of the total deposits received under these Rules; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484086_021" name="b" temporalId="s32_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>after all the costs required to be borne by a party have been paid, shall return any unexpended balance of the party’s portion of the deposits to that party.</content></paragraph></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403475316_001" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            6</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403475316_003" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Communication and notice period</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413484133_004" name="1" temporalId="s33_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any challenge, notice, order, award, or other document (however described) sent or lodged (however described) to or with a party or the clerk under these Rules may be sent or lodged in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 400</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484133_012" name="2" temporalId="s33_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of calculating a period of time under these Rules—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413484133_020" name="a" temporalId="s33_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the period begins to run on the day following the day when the document is sent or lodged;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484148_006" name="b" temporalId="s33_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if the last day of the period is a public holiday or a day on which banks are not generally open for business, the period is extended until the first business day that follows; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484148_014" name="c" temporalId="s33_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>public holidays or days on which banks are not generally open for business occurring during the running of the period of time are included in calculating the period.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475316_005" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Interest</heading><content>The arbitrator may order the payment of interest on any damages or costs, including the payment of compound interest if appropriate in the circumstances.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403475332_002" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Exclusion of liability</heading><leadIn>None of the following persons is liable to any party for any act or omission in
            connection with any arbitration conducted under these Rules unless he is found to have
            been fraudulent or dishonest—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413484195_012" name="a" temporalId="s35_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the chairman;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484195_020" name="b" temporalId="s35_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the deputy chairman;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484195_028" name="c" temporalId="s35_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a
                member;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1482136001136_001" name="d" temporalId="s35_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the arbitrator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484195_042" name="e" temporalId="s35_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the clerk;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484195_050" name="f" temporalId="s35_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>a representative of the HKIAC who attends arbitration proceedings in accordance
                with <ref>section 16</ref>.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403475332_004" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Destruction of documents</heading><leadIn>The clerk and the arbitrator may destroy any document relating to an arbitration sent to them under these Rules after the expiry of a period of one year after the later of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413484226_012" name="a" temporalId="s36_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the last correspondence relating to the arbitration received by the clerk;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484226_020" name="b" temporalId="s36_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the making of an arbitration award by the arbitrator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413484226_028" name="c" temporalId="s36_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the making of an order for the termination of the arbitration proceedings.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403475347_001" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Confidentiality</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413484258_004" name="1" temporalId="s37_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The arbitrator may in his discretion determine that certain information relating to the arbitration is to be kept confidential.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484258_012" name="2" temporalId="s37_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 28(5)</ref>, such confidential information may not be disclosed by any person without the written consent of the arbitrator.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475347_003" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Applicable law</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413484273_019" name="1" temporalId="s38_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Hong Kong law applies to the arbitration proceedings.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484289_005" name="2" temporalId="s38_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The arbitrator shall take into account the trade practice applicable to the transaction.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484289_013" name="3" temporalId="s38_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Pursuant to <ref>section 5</ref> of the Arbitration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap609">Cap. 609</ref>), the provisions of that Ordinance apply to an arbitration conducted under these Rules, save for those matters that have been specifically provided for in these Rules.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2010/17">17 of 2010 s. 112</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403475347_005" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2017-02-15" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413484320_004" name="1" temporalId="s39_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The arbitrator, or if the arbitration proceedings have not been commenced, the chairman, may modify the requirements of these Rules in relation to the sending of documents or the length of time periods in particular cases where, in his opinion, it is expedient to do so in the interest of justice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413484320_012" name="2" temporalId="s39_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A party who knows or reasonably ought to know that any provision of, or requirement under, these Rules has not been complied with and yet proceeds with the arbitration without promptly stating his objection to such non-compliance is deemed to have waived his right to object.</content></subsection></section></part></main></subLeg>