<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 406 sub. leg. E</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>406E</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap406E!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2025-08-24</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403162710_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2022-03-24">Electricity
                                    (Wiring) Regulations</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap406/s59">Cap.
                                                406, section
                                    59</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[1 June 1992]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/1992/ln100">L.N. 100 of
                                                  1992</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of
                                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403162851_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1544409680292_001" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>These regulations may be cited as the Electricity (Wiring)
                Regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1544409680292_002" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163022_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2025-08-24" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these regulations, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="ApprovedLoading"><term>approved
                loading</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">允許負載量</term>) means the maximum current demand approved
            by an electricity supplier in respect of a fixed electrical installation;</def><def name="BreakingCapacity"><term>breaking
                capacity</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">斷流容量</term>) means the value of current at which a
            switch, a switch-disconnector, a circuit breaker or a fuse is capable of breaking a
            circuit at a voltage and under conditions of use and behaviour specified by its
            manufacturer;</def><def name="Category1Circuit"><term>category
                1
            circuit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第1類電路</term>) means a circuit that operates at low
            voltage, but does not include a category 3 circuit;</def><def name="Category2Circuit"><term>category
                2
            circuit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第2類電路</term>) means a circuit for telecommunications,
            radio, telephone, sound distribution, intruder alarm, bell and call, or data
            transmission and that is supplied with electricity from a safety source, but does not
            include a category 3 circuit;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/36">36 of 2000 s. 28</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Category3Circuit"><term>category
                3
            circuit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第3類電路</term>) means a circuit for emergency lighting,
            air pressurisation systems and fire services installations including fire detection and
            alarm, fire pumps, fireman’s lifts and smoke extraction;</def><def name="Category4Circuit"><term>category
                4
            circuit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第4類電路</term>) means a high voltage circuit;</def><def name="Circuit"><term>circuit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電路</term>) means an assembly of electrically connected
            electrical equipment supplied from the same origin and protected against overcurrent by
            the same protective device or devices;</def><def name="Conductor"><term>conductor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">導體</term>) means a wire, cable or other form of metal
            used for conveying electric current from one piece of electrical equipment to another or
            to earth;</def><def name="CurrentcarryingCapacity"><term>current-carrying
                capacity</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">載流量</term>) means the maximum current that can be
            carried by a conductor as determined by using the methods in
            the
            Code of Practice for the Electricity (Wiring) Regulations, as published by the Director
            and as amended from time to time, without the conductor exceeding the
            permissible limit of steady state temperature for the type of insulation concerned as
            specified
            in
            the Code;
            <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2025/31">31 of 2025 s. 109</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="DistributionBoard"><term>distribution
                board</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">配電箱</term>) means an installed group of fuses,
            switches, circuit breakers or other outlet points arranged for the distribution of
            electricity;</def><def name="Earth"><term>earth</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">地</term>) means the conductive mass of the earth whose
            electric potential at any point is conventionally taken as zero;</def><def name="EarthElectrode"><term>earth
                electrode</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">接地極</term>) means a conductor or group of conductors in
            intimate contact with earth and providing an electrical connection to earth;</def><def name="EarthFaultCurrent"><term>earth
                fault
            current</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電路的接地故障電流</term>) of a circuit means an unintended
            current that flows in a circuit when a live part of the circuit comes into direct
            contact with earth;</def><def name="EarthLeakageCurrent"><term>earth
                leakage
            current</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">對地漏電電流</term>) means a current that flows to earth, or
            to extraneous conductive parts, in a circuit that is not intended to be connected to
            earth during normal operation;</def><def name="Earthing"><term>earthing</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">接地</term>) means connecting a conductor with
            earth;</def><def name="ExposedConductivePart"><term>exposed
                conductive
            part</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">外露非帶電金屬部分</term>) means a conductive part of electrical
            equipment that can be touched and that is not a live part but which may become live
            under faulty conditions;</def><def name="ExtraneousConductivePart"><term>extraneous
                conductive
            part</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">非電氣裝置金屬部分</term>) means a conductive part liable to
            introduce a potential, generally earth potential, that does not form part of an
            electrical installation;</def><def name="FinalCircuit"><term>final
                circuit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">最終電路</term>) means a circuit connected directly to
            current-using equipment, a socket outlet or other outlet point;</def><def name="Isolation"><term>isolation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">隔離</term>) means cutting off an electrical
            installation, a circuit or an item of electrical equipment from every source of
            electricity;</def><def name="LinkedCircuitBreaker,LinkedIsolator,LinkedSwitch"><term>linked
                circuit
            breaker</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">連動斷路器</term>),
                <term>linked
                isolator</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">連動隔離器</term>) or
                <term>linked
                switch</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">連動開關掣</term>) means a circuit breaker, isolator or
            switch the contacts of which are so arranged as to make or break all poles
            simultaneously or in a definite sequence;</def><def name="LivePart"><term>live
                part</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">帶電部分</term>) means a conductor that is intended to be
            energised in normal use, and includes a neutral conductor;</def><def name="MainEarthingTerminal"><term>main
                earthing
            terminal</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">總接地終端</term>) means the terminal or bar provided for
            the connection of protective conductors, including equipotential bonding conductors, and
            conductors for functional earthing if any, to the means of earthing;</def><def name="NeutralConductor"><term>neutral
                conductor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">中性導體</term>) means a conductor connected to the neutral
            point of a system and contributing to the transmission of electricity;</def><def name="OverheadLine"><term>overhead
                line</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">架空電纜</term>) means a conductor that is placed above
            ground and is suspended in the open air;</def><def name="PhaseConductor"><term>phase
                conductor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">相導體</term>) means a conductor of an alternating current
            circuit for the transmission of electricity, but does not include a neutral
            conductor;</def><def name="ResidualCurrentDevice"><term>residual
                current
            device</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電流式漏電斷路器</term>) means a device or association of
            devices intended to cause the opening of contacts when the residual current attains a
            specified amperage under conditions specified by its manufacturer;</def><def name="SafetySource"><leadIn><term>safety
                    source</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">安全電源</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412447_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a double-insulated safety isolating transformer with its secondary winding being isolated from earth, and having a nominal output voltage not exceeding 55V;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412447_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a source of electricity providing a degree of safety equivalent to that of the safety isolating transformer referred to in paragraph (a) (for example, a motor- generator with windings providing equivalent isolation); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412447_042" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a source providing electricity at a voltage not exceeding extra low voltage and independent of a higher voltage circuit;</content></paragraph></def><def name="Substation"><term>substation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">電力分站</term>) means premises or an enclosed part of
            premises that contains electrical equipment for transforming or converting energy to or
            from high voltage (other than transforming or converting energy solely for the operation
            of switching devices or instruments) or for switching, controlling or regulating energy
            at high voltage and that are large enough to admit the entrance of a person after the
            electrical equipment is in position;</def><def name="Switching"><term>switching</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">開關</term>) means making or breaking a current under
            normal circuit conditions;</def><def name="Switchroom"><term>switchroom</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">開關房</term>) means premises or an enclosed part of
            premises that contains electrical equipment for switching, controlling or regulating
            electricity at low voltage and above and that are large enough to admit the entrance of
            a person after the electrical equipment is in position.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403163069_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Application</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412509_053" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>These regulations apply to fixed electrical installations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412509_061" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>These regulations, except <ref>regulation 5(1)</ref>, do not apply to a category 2 circuit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163069_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>General safety requirements</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412525_033" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Good workmanship and suitable materials shall be used.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412540_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A fixed electrical installation shall be designed, constructed, installed and protected so as to prevent danger.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412540_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Electrical equipment shall be installed so that it is capable of being identified, maintained, inspected and tested, where appropriate, so as to prevent danger.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412540_021" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Electrical equipment that requires operation, maintenance or attention shall be installed so as to provide adequate and safe means of access and working space.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412540_029" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The owner and person in control of a substation or switchroom shall ensure that unauthorized entry into his substation or switchroom is prevented.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412540_037" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The owner and person in control of premises in which a switchroom or substation is located shall ensure that their entrances and exits are kept clear of obstructions that could prevent easy access to the switchroom or substation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412540_045" name="7" temporalId="s4_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A registered electrical worker shall ensure that safety precautions are taken to prevent danger arising from electrical wiring work done by him or under his supervision.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163085_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Segregation of circuit categories</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412572_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Category 1, 2, 3 and 4 circuits shall be segregated from one another as far as
                is necessary to prevent danger and electrical interference.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412572_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Category 4 circuits shall not be installed in the same conduit, ducting or trunking as circuits of other categories and shall be segregated from circuits of other categories at a distance sufficient to prevent danger and electrical interference with the circuits of those other categories.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163085_004" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Circuit arrangement</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412587_026" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A wiring installation shall be divided into as many circuits as are necessary in order to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412587_034" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>avoid danger in the event of a fault; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412587_042" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>facilitate safe operation, inspection, testing and maintenance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412587_049" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A separate circuit shall be provided for each part of a wiring installation that needs to be separately controlled.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412603_005" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where a wiring installation comprises more than one final circuit—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412603_013" name="a" temporalId="s6_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>each final circuit shall be separately protected against overcurrent and connected to a separate isolation device in a distribution board;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412603_021" name="b" temporalId="s6_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the wiring of each final circuit shall be electrically separated from that of every other final circuit, so as to prevent indirect energisation of the final circuit intended to be isolated; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412603_029" name="c" temporalId="s6_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>each final circuit shall be designed so that it is not affected by the failure of any other final circuit.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163100_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Current demand</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412634_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A circuit shall be suitable for the maximum current demand of all current-using equipment that is connected or intended to be connected to the circuit when the current-using equipment is functioning in its intended manner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412634_012" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The maximum current demand of a fixed electrical installation shall not exceed the approved loading.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163116_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Isolation and switching</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412650_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Effective means, readily accessible for operation, shall be provided so that all voltage may be cut off from every fixed installation, from each of its circuits and from all electrical equipment connected to each circuit, as may be necessary to prevent or remove danger.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412650_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where motorised drives are involved with moving parts that are readily accessible and that may cause bodily injury, there shall be an effective means of disconnection locally placed for ready operation so that all voltage may be cut off from the motorised drives.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163131_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Overcurrent protective devices</heading><leadIn>A circuit shall be protected against overcurrent by a device that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412665_034" name="a" temporalId="s9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>operates automatically to break the circuit before the safe current rating of the circuit is exceeded;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412665_042" name="b" temporalId="s9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is of adequate breaking capacity;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412681_006" name="c" temporalId="s9_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>is suitably located; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412681_014" name="d" temporalId="s9_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>is properly constructed,</content></paragraph><continued>so as to prevent danger from overheating, arcing or the scattering of hot particles when the device comes into operation and so as to permit restoration of the supply without danger.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403163131_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Neutral conductor protective devices, isolators and switches</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412712_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A single-pole switch shall be inserted in the phase conductor of a single phase circuit only.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412712_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No fuse and no circuit breaker, isolator or switch, other than a linked circuit breaker, linked isolator or linked switch, shall be inserted in a neutral conductor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412712_020" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Notwithstanding subregulations (1) and (2), a single-pole switch may be inserted between the earthing connection and the neutral terminals of generators running or likely to be running in parallel so long as adequate precautions have been taken to avoid danger.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412712_028" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A solid link may only be inserted in a neutral conductor so long as it cannot
                be disconnected without first disconnecting the related phase
                conductors or
                without using a tool.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1990/ln323">L.N. 323 of
                1990</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412712_036" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A linked circuit breaker, a linked isolator or a linked switch inserted in a neutral conductor shall be arranged to break also the related phase conductors.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163147_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Earth leakage and earth fault currents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412743_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A circuit shall be provided with effective means to prevent the persistence of
                earth fault currents and dangerous earth leakage currents.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412743_012" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where metalwork of electrical equipment, other than its current-carrying
                conductors, may become charged with electricity in a manner that would cause danger
                if the insulation of a conductor becomes defective or if a fault occurs in the
                equipment, the metalwork shall be earthed in a manner that will cause safe discharge
                of electricity, or other effective means shall be provided to prevent the occurrence
                of danger.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412759_005" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where metalwork is earthed in accordance with subregulation (2), the circuits
                concerned shall be protected against the persistence of earth fault current
                by—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412759_013" name="a" temporalId="s11_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an overcurrent protective device in accordance with <ref>regulation
                    9</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412759_021" name="b" temporalId="s11_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a residual current device or an equally effective device,</content></paragraph><continued>to automatically disconnect the faulty circuit in time to avoid
                danger.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412759_034" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where metalwork of electrical equipment is earthed in accordance with
                subregulation (2) and the metalwork is accessible simultaneously to a substantial
                extraneous conductive part, the extraneous conductive part shall be effectively
                connected to the main earthing terminal of the fixed electrical
                installation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412759_042" name="5" temporalId="s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Subregulation (4) applies only to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412759_050" name="a" temporalId="s11_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a fixed electrical installation that was completed on or after 1 January
                    1985; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412759_058" name="b" temporalId="s11_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a fixed electrical installation that was substantially altered on or after
                    1 January 1985 or that is substantially altered after the
                    commencement*
                    of this regulation.</content></paragraph></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1631086984106_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 June
                1992.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403163163_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Earthing arrangement</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412790_019" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A fixed electrical installation shall have an effective earthing arrangement,
                including a connection to earth electrodes, for its protection against earth fault
                currents and dangerous earth leakage currents.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412790_027" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In addition to the requirement under subregulation (1), where the supply is
                taken directly from an electricity supplier’s transformer within the premises in
                which the fixed electrical installation is situated, the main earthing terminal of
                the installation shall be bonded to the supplier’s bonding terminal that connects to
                the earthed point of the transformer.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412806_005" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In addition to the requirement under subregulation (1), where the supply is
                taken from the electricity supplier’s underground cable that has exposed conductive
                parts at the cable termination at the point of supply, the main earthing terminal of
                the fixed electrical installation shall be bonded to those exposed conductive
                parts.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412806_013" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where bonding referred to in subregulations (2) and (3) is used to prevent the
                rise of a dangerous earth potential, the fixed electrical installation shall satisfy
                all the requirements of <ref>regulation 11</ref> even if the bonding is
                disconnected.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412821_005" name="5" temporalId="s12_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Subregulations (2) to (4) apply only to a fixed electrical installation that is
                completed or substantially altered on or after the
                commencement*
                of this regulation.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1630658074520_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 1 June
                1992.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403163178_001" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Conductors, joints and connections</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412837_019" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A conductor shall be of sufficient size and current-carrying capacity for its intended purpose.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412837_027" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A live conductor shall be protected against accidental direct contact by a person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412837_035" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An electrical joint, connection and conductor shall be properly constructed and installed with respect to conductance, insulation, mechanical strength and protection.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163178_003" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Wiring installation enclosure</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412852_034" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An enclosure of a wiring installation shall be properly designed, constructed, installed, protected and maintained so as to prevent danger.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412868_004" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Good workmanship and suitable materials shall be used for the enclosure of a wiring installation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163194_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Adverse conditions installation</heading><leadIn>Where all or part of a fixed electrical installation is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412868_048" name="a" temporalId="s15_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in or likely to be in water or exposed or likely to be exposed to weather;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412884_008" name="b" temporalId="s15_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>exposed or likely to be exposed to high ambient temperature, corrosive atmosphere, polluting substances or other adverse hazardous conditions; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412884_016" name="c" temporalId="s15_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in surroundings susceptible to risk of fire or explosion,</content></paragraph><continued>it, or the relevant part of it, shall be specially constructed, installed or protected to prevent danger arising from those adverse conditions.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403163209_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Overhead line installations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412899_018" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A low voltage overhead line shall be designed, constructed, installed and protected so as to prevent danger.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412899_026" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The height above ground of a low voltage overhead line at any point of the span shall not be less than 5.8 m across any place accessible to vehicular traffic and 5.2 m otherwise.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412899_034" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No overhead line operating at high voltage shall be installed without the Director’s approval.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163209_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Display of labels and notices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412915_034" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An identification label and an appropriate warning notice including the words “Danger” and “危險” shall be displayed in a conspicuous position at every entrance of a substation and switchroom.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412915_042" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A warning notice bearing the words “DO NOT REMOVE” and “切勿移去” shall be displayed in a conspicuous position at or near the point of connection of each earthing conductor to an earth electrode, and at or near each main bonding connection.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412930_005" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A warning notice bearing the words
                “CAUTION—EQUIPMENT
                UNDER REPAIR” and
                “小心——器具待修”
                or
                “CAUTION—MEN
                AT WORK” and
                “小心——工程進行中”,
                or bearing both warnings, shall be displayed in a conspicuous position at or near
                the electrical equipment and at the isolation device associated with the electrical
                equipment on which work is being carried out.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412930_013" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A notice bearing the words “This installation must be tested and certified by a grade (A/B/C/H/R) electrical worker before (date)” and “本裝置須於(日期)前由(A/B/C/H/R)級電業工程人員測試及發出證明書” shall be displayed in a conspicuous position at or near the main distribution board of a fixed electrical installation referred to in <ref>regulation 20</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412946_005" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The letters and Chinese characters in a warning notice or identification label shall be legible and large enough for easy reading.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412946_013" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>An identification label and warning notice referred to in subregulations (1), (2) and (4) shall be durable and securely fixed in position.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412946_021" name="7" temporalId="s17_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A warning notice under subregulation (3) shall be reasonably durable and shall be placed or affixed so that it cannot be accidentally displaced.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163241_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Alterations and additions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412412977_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No alteration or addition shall be made to an existing fixed electrical installation unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412412977_012" name="a" temporalId="s18_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the ratings and the conditions of the existing electrical equipment of the affected parts are suitable and adequate for the altered circumstances; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412412977_020" name="b" temporalId="s18_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the protection against overcurrent, earth fault currents and dangerous earth leakage currents for the affected parts is altered as necessary for the altered circumstances.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412412977_027" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The maximum current demand of a fixed electrical installation after an alteration or addition shall not exceed the existing approved loading for the installation unless the electricity supplier approves a new loading for the installation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163241_003" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>First inspection, testing and certification</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412413008_041" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A fixed electrical installation shall, after completion (including any work completed after repair, alteration or addition) and before it is energised for use, be inspected, tested and certified by a registered electrical worker to confirm that the requirements of the Ordinance have been met.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413024_005" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In the case of a repair, alteration or addition to a fixed electrical installation, only the affected parts of the installation need to be inspected, tested and certified under this regulation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163256_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-31" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Periodic inspection, testing and certification</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412413040_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An owner of a fixed electrical installation located in one of the following type
                of premises
                must
                have it inspected, tested and certified at least once every 12 months—
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2021/29">29 of 2021
                s.37</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412413040_012" name="a" temporalId="s20_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a place of public entertainment as defined in the Places of Public
                    Entertainment Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap172">Cap. 172</ref>) other than a
                    sea-going vessel;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412413040_020" name="b" temporalId="s20_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>premises for the manufacturing or storing of dangerous
                    goods
                    described in section 6(a) of the Dangerous Goods (Application and Exemption)
                    Regulation 2012 (<ref href="/hk/cap295E">Cap. 295 sub. leg. E</ref>);
                        and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/10">10 of 2005 s.
                        213</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2021/29">29 of 2021
                    s.37</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412413040_028" name="c" temporalId="s20_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>premises with a high voltage fixed electrical installation fed directly
                    from a high voltage supply.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413040_035" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An owner of a low voltage fixed electrical installation that has an approved loading exceeding 200A, single or three phase, at nominal low voltage, that is in a factory or industrial undertaking, as those terms are defined in <ref>section 2</ref> of the Factories and Industrial Undertakings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap59">Cap. 59</ref>), shall, unless the factory or industrial undertaking is a premises referred to in subregulation (1), have the installation inspected, tested and certified at least once every 5 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413055_005" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An owner of a low voltage fixed electrical installation that has an approved loading exceeding 100A, single or three phase, at nominal low voltage, that is in premises other than those referred to in subregulation (1) or (2), shall have the installation inspected, tested and certified at least once every 5 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413071_005" name="4" temporalId="s20_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>An owner of a low voltage fixed electrical installation located in one of the
                following type of premises shall have it inspected, tested and certified at least
                once every 5 years—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412413071_013" name="a" temporalId="s20_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a hotel as defined in <ref>section 2</ref> of the Hotel Proprietors
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap158">Cap. 158</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412413071_021" name="b" temporalId="s20_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a
                    private
                    healthcare facility that is a hospital as defined in the Private Healthcare
                    Facilities Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap633">Cap. 633</ref>);
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2018/34">34 of 2018 s. 183</ref> and <ref href="hk/2018/er5">E.R. 5 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1609383658013_001" name="ba" temporalId="s20_4_ba"><num value="ba">(ba)</num><content>a scheduled nursing home within the meaning of the Private Healthcare
                    Facilities Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap633">Cap. 633</ref>) for which an
                    exemption granted under <ref>section 128</ref> of that Ordinance is in force;
                        <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2018/34">34 of 2018 s. 183</ref> and <ref href="hk/2018/er5">E.R. 5 of 2018</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1609383658013_002" name="bb" temporalId="s20_4_bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content>a nursing home within the meaning of the Residential Care Homes (Elderly
                    Persons) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap459">Cap. 459</ref>); <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2018/34">34 of 2018 s. 183</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412413071_029" name="c" temporalId="s20_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a school as defined in <ref>section 3</ref> of the Education Ordinance
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap279">Cap. 279</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412413071_037" name="d" temporalId="s20_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>premises of the institutions listed in <ref>section 2</ref> of the
                    Education Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap279">Cap. 279</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412413071_045" name="e" temporalId="s20_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>a child care centre that is registered under the Child Care Services
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap243">Cap. 243</ref>); and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/32">32 of 2000 s.
                        36</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412413086_006" name="f" temporalId="s20_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>premises that the Director may, by notice posted to or served on the owner,
                    specify that he considers could cause great harm in the event of an electrical
                    accident.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413086_013" name="5" temporalId="s20_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The owner shall deliver a certificate prepared under this regulation to the Director for endorsement within 2 weeks after the date of the certificate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413086_021" name="6" temporalId="s20_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The owner shall submit an endorsement fee of $695 for each certificate delivered to the Director under subregulation (5).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln451">L.N. 451 of 1993</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1994/ln602">L.N. 602 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln33">L.N. 33 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/ln22">L.N. 22 of 1998</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/ln135">L.N. 135 of 1998</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/ln352">L.N. 352 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163272_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Procedures for inspection, testing and certification</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412413118_050" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Tests on a fixed electrical installation shall be carried out with proper tools and testing equipment and in accordance with accepted practices so that no danger to persons or property can occur even if the circuit being tested is defective.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413133_005" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Results of tests and inspections shall be recorded, dated and certified by the registered electrical worker who carried out the tests and inspections.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413133_013" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where a fixed electrical installation is divided into more than one part, the individual parts need not be inspected, tested and certified by the same registered electrical worker, and a single certificate in a form specified by the Director may be issued and certified by a registered electrical worker to cover a number or all of the individual parts, as long as he has received the appropriate certificates certified by other registered electrical workers for the individual parts, and is satisfied that the certificates are completed and signed by a registered electrical worker of appropriate grade.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413149_005" name="4" temporalId="s21_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A registered electrical worker shall ensure that the tests and inspections covered in his certificate have been carried out within a reasonable time, normally not exceeding one month, before the date of certification and that the results of the tests and inspections are satisfactory.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163272_004" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Making and keeping of records</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412413180_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered electrical contractor shall make and keep all relevant records of electrical work carried out by his employees for the lesser of 5 years or the time since his registration as an electrical contractor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413180_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The owner of a fixed electrical installation referred to in <ref>regulation 20</ref> shall make available, for inspection as and when required by the Director, latest test certificates, and, where applicable, a written summary of safety precautions taken for each event of testing and maintenance work carried out on an installation referred to in <ref>regulation 20(1)(c)</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163287_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Prescribed period for <ref>section 12(2)</ref></heading><content>For the purposes of <ref>section 12(2)</ref>, <ref>4</ref> months is the prescribed period.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403163303_001" name="s24" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" startPeriod="2022-03-24" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412413211_018" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who contravenes <ref>regulation 4(5)</ref> or (6), 20 or 22(2) commits
                an offence and is liable to a
                fine at level
                3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413211_026" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An owner of a fixed electrical installation who fails to comply with the
                requirements of <ref>regulation 17(1)</ref>, (2), (4), (5) or (6) commits an offence
                and is liable to a fine
                at
                level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412413211_034" name="3" temporalId="s24_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An owner of a fixed electrical installation who causes or knowingly allows
                another person to contravene <ref>regulation 18</ref> commits an offence and is
                liable to a fine
                at
                level 5 on a first conviction and a fine
                at
                level 6 on a subsequent conviction for the same offence and in
                either case is liable to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2022/er1">E.R. 1 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section></main></subLeg>