<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 406 sub. leg. H</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>406H</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap406H!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403163724_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2021-11-11">Electricity
            Supply Lines (Protection)
            Regulation</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap406/s59">Cap. 406, section
                59</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[14 June 2000]
            <sourceNote><ref href="hk/2000/ln132">L.N. 132 of 2000</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="add-toc">Preliminary</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403163740_001" name="s1" reason="omittedAsSpent" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="omitted" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403163740_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Regulation, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="CompetentPerson"><term>competent
                person</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">合資格人士</term>) means a person approved as a competent
            person under <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="OverheadElectricityLine"><term>overhead
                electricity
            line</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">架空電纜</term>) means an electricity supply line located
            at or above ground level;</def><def name="SiteContractor"><term>site
                contractor</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">工地承建商</term>) means a person who carries out or is
            engaged to carry out any works on a particular works site;</def><def name="UndergroundElectricityCable"><term>underground
                electricity
            cable</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">地下電纜</term>) means an electricity supply line located
            below ground level;</def><def name="Works"><leadIn><term>works</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">工程</term>) means—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412414678_047" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>any kind of works involving or in connection with—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414678_055" name="i" temporalId="s2_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>building works within the meaning assigned to that term in <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Buildings Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap123">Cap. 123</ref>), and for the purposes of this subparagraph reference in that section to “ground investigation in the scheduled areas” shall be read as a reference to “ground investigation”;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414693_007" name="ii" temporalId="s2_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the laying out, construction, alteration or repair of any road (whether or not at ground level), footpath, cycle track, pedestrian subway, footbridge, tunnel, airport runway, canal, reservoir, pipeline, railway or tramway;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414693_015" name="iii" temporalId="s2_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><leadIn>trench works, including—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414693_022" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s2_a_iii_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>water mains, storm water drains and sewers; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414693_030" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s2_a_iii_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>such works when carried out by or for any public utility;</content></subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414693_038" name="iv" temporalId="s2_a_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>the extraction of material from land or the seabed;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414693_046" name="v" temporalId="s2_a_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>landfill works, river training works, slope works or reclamation works; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414693_054" name="vi" temporalId="s2_a_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>levelling, piling, ramming, dredging, boring, tunnelling or blasting works; </content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412414693_061" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the use of any crane or hoist (within the meaning assigned to those terms
                    in <ref>regulation 2(1)</ref> of the Construction Sites (Safety) Regulations
                        (<ref href="/hk/cap59I">Cap. 59 sub. leg. I</ref>)) or other equipment for
                    the purpose of lifting objects;
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2021/er5">E.R. 5 of 2021</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412414709_006" name="c" temporalId="s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the use of any heavy machinery or other equipment for the purpose of earth moving,</content></paragraph><continued>but does not include works necessary to ascertain the alignment and depth of an underground electricity cable, nor any electrical work carried out by a registered electrical worker or registered electrical contractor;</continued></def><def name="WorksSite"><term>works
                site</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">工地</term>) means any area in which works are being
            carried out.</def></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Competent Persons</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403163755_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Approval, etc. of competent person</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412414818_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may, in accordance with this section, approve a person as a competent person for the purposes of this Regulation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414818_019" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An application for approval as a competent person shall be in such form as may be specified by the Director and shall be accompanied by the fee specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414818_027" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (4), the Director shall grant an application for approval as a competent person if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412414834_005" name="a" temporalId="s3_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>the Director is satisfied that—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414834_013" name="i" temporalId="s3_3_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the person has attended and passed a course in the locating of underground electricity cables which has been approved by the Director for the purposes of this section; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412414834_021" name="ii" temporalId="s3_3_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>during the period of 3 years immediately preceding his application, the person has had not less than 6 months’ practical experience in locating underground electricity cables, or has had such other practical experience as the Director may consider relevant and equivalent for the purposes of this Regulation; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412414834_028" name="b" temporalId="s3_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the opinion of the Director, the person is by reason of his knowledge and practical experience capable of carrying out the work of locating underground electricity cables in a competent manner,</content></paragraph><continued>and the Director may grant his approval subject to such conditions as he reasonably thinks fit.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414834_041" name="4" temporalId="s3_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director may refuse an application for approval under this section if a previous approval granted to the person has been revoked on grounds other than the grounds specified in <ref>section 6(2)(d)</ref> or (e).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414849_005" name="5" temporalId="s3_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>An approval granted under this section shall be valid for a period of 3 years from the date of its grant.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414849_013" name="6" temporalId="s3_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Director shall publish in the Gazette notice of any approval, granted by him for the purposes of this section, of a course in the locating of underground electricity cables.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163771_001" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Variation of conditions of approval</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412414896_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may, on the application of a competent person accompanied by payment of the fee specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, vary the conditions subject to which an approval granted under <ref>section 3</ref> has effect, but a variation of conditions under this subsection shall not result in the approval having effect subject to conditions which are more onerous than those applying before the variation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414912_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Director is satisfied that the present circumstances in relation to a
                person who holds an approval under <ref>section 3</ref>
                        (<b><i>current
                        approval</i></b>)
                are such that, if the person were to make a fresh application for approval as a
                competent person, any such approval
                        (<i><b>new
                        approval</b></i>)
                would be granted subject to conditions which differ from the conditions applying in
                relation to the current approval, the Director may order that the conditions
                applying in relation to the current approval be varied so that they reflect the
                conditions that would apply in relation to any such new approval so granted, and the
                person’s current approval shall as from the date of the order have effect subject to
                those conditions as so varied.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414927_005" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (2)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412414927_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>no order shall be made by the Director under that subsection unless the Director has given to the person holding the approval notice of his intention to make such an order and has allowed that person an opportunity to be heard on the matter;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412414943_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>reference to the variation of conditions applying in relation to a current approval as a competent person includes reference to the imposition of conditions where no conditions apply in relation to that approval.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163771_003" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Renewal of approval as competent person</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412414990_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Director may, on the application by a competent person, renew an approval granted to that person under <ref>section 3</ref> if he is satisfied that, within the period of 3 years immediately preceding the application for renewal, the person has had not less than 3 months’ practical experience in locating underground electricity cables.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414990_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Application for renewal of approval as a competent person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412414990_020" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall be made at least 1 month before, but not earlier than 4 months before, the expiry of the current approval; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412414990_028" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall be in such form as may be specified by the Director and shall be accompanied by the fee specified in the <ref>Schedule</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412414990_035" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>An approval which is renewed under this section—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412414990_043" name="a" temporalId="s5_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall be valid for a further period of 3 years; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412414990_051" name="b" temporalId="s5_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>subject to any variation under <ref>section 4</ref>, shall have effect subject to the same conditions, if any, as applying to the approval immediately before the renewal takes effect.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163787_002" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Suspension, etc. of approval</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415021_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Director may, in accordance with <ref>section 7</ref>, suspend a person’s approval as a competent person for a period of up to 12 months if he considers that the person—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln95">L.N. 95 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415021_012" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>has acted in breach of any provision of the Ordinance; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415021_020" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has failed to perform his work as a competent person to the standard reasonably expected of a competent person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln95">L.N. 95 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415021_027" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Director may, in accordance with <ref>section 7</ref>, revoke a person’s approval as a competent person if he is satisfied that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415021_035" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the person has been convicted of an offence under this Regulation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415021_043" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in performing his duties as a competent person, the person has acted in breach of any condition of the approval, or has been guilty of such negligence or misconduct as to render him unfit to be a competent person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415036_006" name="c" temporalId="s6_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the person obtained his approval by fraud or on the basis of misleading or inaccurate information;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415036_014" name="d" temporalId="s6_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the approval was granted in error; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415036_022" name="e" temporalId="s6_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the person is no longer capable of performing the duties of a competent person.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163802_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Notice of intention to suspend or revoke approval</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415083_051" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where the Director considers that there are grounds for suspending or revoking an approval in accordance with <ref>section 6</ref>, he shall notify the competent person accordingly—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415083_059" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>specifying the grounds; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415083_067" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>advising the competent person that he is entitled to a hearing or to submit a written representation, and that if he intends to request a hearing or submit a written representation he must do so within 4 weeks after the date of the Director’s notice.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415099_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If, within 4 weeks after the date of the notice sent under subsection (1), the Director does not receive from the competent person a request for a hearing he may, after considering the written representations (if any) submitted by the competent person, suspend or revoke the certificate of approval, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415099_013" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If, within 4 weeks after the date of the notice sent under subsection (1), the Director receives a request for a hearing, he shall afford the competent person a reasonable opportunity of being heard.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415099_021" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>After the hearing, or if the competent person fails without reasonable excuse to attend at the time set by the Director for the hearing, the Director may, if he so decides, exonerate the competent person or order the suspension or revocation of the certificate of approval, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415114_005" name="5" temporalId="s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>On service on the competent person of a notice informing him of the Director’s decision to suspend or revoke a certificate of approval and stating the reasons for that decision, the person shall cease to be approved as a competent person.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163802_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Certificate of approval</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415130_058" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>On granting or varying the conditions of an approval as a competent person or on renewing any such approval, the Director shall issue to the competent person a certificate confirming the approval and specifying the period of validity of the approval and the conditions, if any, subject to which the approval has been granted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415146_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A competent person who has been served with a notice of suspension or revocation of his approval shall, not later than 14 days after service of the notice, surrender to the Director any certificate of approval issued to him.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163818_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Notice of change of particulars</heading><content>Where there is any change in the particulars of the name or address of a person who is approved as a competent person, the person shall give written notice to the Director of the changed particulars within 21 days after the change takes place.</content></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Works in Vicinity of Electricity Supply Lines</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403163818_004" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Requirements relating to works in vicinity of electricity supply lines</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415177_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A person shall not—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415177_019" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>carry out or cause or permit another to carry out in the vicinity of an underground electricity cable any works which are below ground level; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415177_027" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>carry out or cause or permit another to carry out in the vicinity of an overhead electricity line works of any kind,</content></paragraph><continued>unless before the works are begun all reasonable steps have been taken to ascertain the existence within the proposed works site and its vicinity of any such underground electricity cable and its alignment and depth or of any such overhead electricity line and its alignment, distance from the ground and voltage, as the case may be.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415177_040" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>A person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415177_048" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>carries out or causes or permits another to carry out in the vicinity of an underground electricity cable any works which are below ground level; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415192_006" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>carries out or causes or permits another to carry out in the vicinity of an overhead electricity line works of any kind,</content></paragraph><continued>shall ensure that all reasonable measures are taken to prevent the occurrence of an electrical accident or an interruption to the supply of electricity arising from those works.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415192_019" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (1) as it applies in relation to works in the vicinity of an underground electricity cable, and without affecting the generality of that subsection, reasonable steps shall not be regarded as having been taken unless a competent person has undertaken an investigation for the purpose of ascertaining the existence within the proposed works site and its vicinity of any such underground electricity cable and its alignment and depth and has provided a written report of his findings as to those matters.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415208_005" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 11(7)</ref>, where the Director has approved a code of practice for any of the requirements of paragraph (a) or (b) of subsection (1) or (2), then, subject to subsection (3), compliance with the provisions of that code shall be deemed to constitute the taking of all reasonable steps, or the taking of all reasonable measures, as the case may be, for the purposes of that requirement.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415208_013" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>A competent person who undertakes an investigation to ascertain the existence, alignment and depth of an underground electricity cable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415208_021" name="a" temporalId="s10_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall not delegate the function and duty of the investigation to another person;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415224_006" name="b" temporalId="s10_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may carry out the investigation with the assistance of any other persons, but such persons shall be directly supervised by that competent person at the proposed works site in the course of the investigation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415224_014" name="c" temporalId="s10_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>shall carry out the investigation in a manner that does not cause damage to, or impair the operation of, the underground electricity cable; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415224_022" name="d" temporalId="s10_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>shall provide the person requesting the investigation with a written report of his findings as to that matter.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Remedial Notices</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403163833_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Remedial notices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415286_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where the Director is of the opinion that a person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415286_019" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is contravening a requirement under this Regulation; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415286_027" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has contravened such a requirement in circumstances that make it likely that the contravention will continue or be repeated,</content></paragraph><continued>he may serve on the person a notice
                        (<b><i>remedial
                        notice</i></b>)
                stating that he is of that opinion, giving particulars as to why he is of that
                opinion, and directing the person to remedy the contravention or the matter
                occasioning it, as the case may be, within the period specified in the
                notice.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415286_040" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Except as provided in subsection (3), the period to be specified in a remedial notice under subsection (1) shall be a period of not less than 14 days.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415286_048" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If the Director is of the opinion that the circumstances of the contravention are such that there is an undue risk of an electrical accident or an interruption to the supply of electricity occurring, he may specify in the remedial notice such lesser period as he reasonably considers appropriate in the circumstances.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415302_005" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A remedial notice may contain instructions as to the measures to be taken to remedy any contravention or matter to which the notice relates, and any such instructions may be framed—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415302_013" name="a" temporalId="s11_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>wholly or in part by reference to any approved code of practice; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415302_021" name="b" temporalId="s11_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>so as to afford the person on whom the notice is served a choice between different ways of remedying such contravention or matter.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415302_028" name="5" temporalId="s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 43(4)</ref> of the Ordinance, a direction specified in a remedial notice shall take effect at the time of the notice being served or at such later date, if any, as may be specified in the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415302_036" name="6" temporalId="s11_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In addition to service as provided under <ref>section 52</ref> of the Ordinance, service of a remedial notice on a person who is a site contractor may also be effected by delivering the notice to a person at the works site who appears to be the person in charge of the site activities or who identifies himself as being the site contractor’s representative on the site.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415317_005" name="7" temporalId="s11_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415317_013" name="a" temporalId="s11_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Director has approved a code of practice for any of the requirements of paragraph (a) or (b) of <ref>section 10(1)</ref> or (2); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415317_021" name="b" temporalId="s11_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Director has served a remedial notice under subsection (1) in relation to a contravention of the same paragraph,</content></paragraph><continued>then, subject to <ref>section 10(3)</ref>, compliance with the provisions of that code and the direction in that notice shall be deemed to constitute the taking of all reasonable steps, or the taking of all reasonable measures, as the case may be, for the purposes of that requirement.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln95">L.N. 95 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415317_034" name="8" temporalId="s11_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (7), where there is any conflict or inconsistency between any provision in the code of practice and any direction in the remedial notice, then that direction shall, to the extent of that conflict or inconsistency, as the case may be, prevail over that provision.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/ln95">L.N. 95 of 2000</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163849_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Failure to comply with remedial notice</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415364_011" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If a person on whom a remedial notice is served fails to remedy the contravention or the matter occasioning it, as the case may be, within the period specified in the notice, then the Director may, after giving notice of his intention to the person, do either or both of the following—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415364_019" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>he may prohibit the carrying out of all or any particular works on the works site; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415364_027" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he may himself do, or cause to be done, anything necessary to remedy the contravention or the matter occasioning it, as the case may be.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415380_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If the Director exercises his power under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref>, he shall display prominently on or near the works site a notice, in the Chinese and English languages—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415380_013" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>stating that the carrying out of certain or all works on the works site has been prohibited; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415380_021" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>setting out the provisions of subsection (3) and <ref>section 17(6)</ref> and (7).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415380_028" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>No person shall without the consent in writing of the Director—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415380_036" name="a" temporalId="s12_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>carry out on the works site any works which he knows or ought reasonably to know have been prohibited by the Director under subsection <ref>(1)(a)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415380_044" name="b" temporalId="s12_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>remove or mark, or damage or destroy, a notice referred to in subsection (2).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415380_051" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If the Director takes any action under subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> in connection with remedying the contravention or the matter occasioning it, the person on whom the remedial notice was served shall be liable to reimburse the Director for the amount of any expenses reasonably incurred by the Director in taking that action, and such amount shall be recoverable summarily as a civil debt.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415395_005" name="5" temporalId="s12_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content><ref>Section 11(6)</ref> applies to the giving of a notice under subsection (1) as it applies to the service of a remedial notice under <ref>section 11</ref>.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163865_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Appeals against notices under <ref>sections 11</ref> and <ref>12</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415426_011" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Part IX of the Ordinance, in its application to or in relation to an appeal
                against a decision or action of the Director under <ref>section 11</ref> or
                    <ref>12</ref>, shall have effect subject to the following modifications and
                variations—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415426_019" name="a" temporalId="s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a notice of appeal as required under <ref>section 43(2)</ref> of the
                    Ordinance shall be delivered to the Director within 14 days of the decision or
                    action being appealed against;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415426_027" name="b" temporalId="s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the
                    Secretary
                    for Environment and Ecology shall appoint to the appeal board
                    panel provided for under <ref>section 44(1)</ref> of the Ordinance not more than
                    5 persons from organizations that he considers represent the interests of the
                    construction industry;
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/ln106">L.N. 106 of 2002</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                        2007</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2022/ln144">L.N. 144 of
                        2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415442_006" name="c" temporalId="s13_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>an appeal board appointed under <ref>section 45(1)</ref> of the Ordinance
                    to hear an appeal shall consist of a public officer, one member from each of the
                    categories specified in <ref>section 44(1)(a)</ref>, (b) and (c) of the
                    Ordinance and 2 members from the category specified in paragraph (b);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415442_014" name="d" temporalId="s13_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the quorum of an appeal board appointed pursuant to this section is 4
                    members;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415442_022" name="e" temporalId="s13_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the powers conferred on an appeal board under <ref>section 47(1)</ref> of
                    the Ordinance shall include the power to authorize a person to inspect a works
                    site or former works site and, for that purpose, to authorize entry into
                    premises other than domestic premises on which the works site is or was
                    situated.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415442_029" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Unless the context otherwise requires, reference in the Ordinance or any other
                Ordinance to an appeal under, or an appeal board appointed under, Part IX of the
                Ordinance includes reference to an appeal pursuant to, or an appeal board appointed
                pursuant to, this section.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Powers of Entry, etc.</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403163880_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Powers of entry, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415473_043" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to this section, the Director may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415473_051" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enter, inspect and examine any premises or place in which works are being undertaken in the vicinity of an electricity supply line or in which he reasonably suspects such works are being undertaken, and may, in the interests of safety or of ensuring the continuity of supply of electricity, there make enquiries as to the observance of any requirement under this Regulation and all matters and things relating to the electricity supply line concerned;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415489_006" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enter and search any premises or place, forcibly if necessary, in which he reasonably suspects that there may be anything which is liable to seizure under paragraph (c); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415489_014" name="c" temporalId="s14_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>seize, remove and detain—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412415489_022" name="i" temporalId="s14_1_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>anything in respect of which he has reasonable grounds for suspecting that an offence against this Regulation has been committed; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412415489_030" name="ii" temporalId="s14_1_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any other thing which appears to him likely to be or to contain evidence of any such offence.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415489_036" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purpose of exercising the powers conferred under <ref>section 12(1)(b)</ref>, but subject to this section, the Director may enter, inspect and examine any premises or place, forcibly if necessary, in respect of which a notice has been given under <ref>section 12(1)</ref> and may there do such things as are necessary to remedy the contravention or the matter occasioning it, as the case may be.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415504_005" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The powers conferred under subsections <ref>(1)(a)</ref> and (2) to enter, inspect and examine a premises or place may be exercised at any time of the day or night, but in exercising that power the Director shall use every effort to avoid unnecessarily impeding or obstructing works being carried out in the premises or place.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415520_005" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>The powers conferred under subsections (1) and (2) to enter and search any premises may be exercised in relation to any domestic premises if, and only if, one or other of the following requirements is satisfied—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415520_013" name="a" temporalId="s14_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a warrant has been issued by a magistrate, where the magistrate is satisfied by information on oath that there is reasonable ground for suspecting that an offence against this Regulation has been, is being or is about to be, committed in such premises or there is in such premises anything likely to be or to contain evidence of such offence; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415520_021" name="b" temporalId="s14_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Director is of the opinion, having regard to the circumstances of the case, that the delay likely to be occasioned in obtaining a warrant as is mentioned in paragraph (a) would be likely to result in the occurrence of an electrical accident.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415520_028" name="5" temporalId="s14_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Director may exercise any of his powers under this section with the assistance of such other persons as he thinks fit.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Codes of Practice</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403163896_001" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Approval of code of practice by Director</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415567_011" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of providing practical guidance in respect of any requirement under this Regulation, the Director may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415567_019" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>approve and issue such codes of practice (whether prepared by him or not) as in his opinion are suitable for that purpose; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415567_027" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>approve such codes of practice issued or proposed to be issued otherwise than by him as in his opinion are suitable for that purpose.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415567_034" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where a code of practice is approved under subsection (1), the Director shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415567_042" name="a" temporalId="s15_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>publish a copy of the code in the Gazette; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415567_050" name="b" temporalId="s15_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by notice in the Gazette, specify for which of the requirements under this Regulation the code is so approved and the date on which the approval is to take effect.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415582_005" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Director may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415582_013" name="a" temporalId="s15_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>from time to time revise the whole or any part of any code of practice prepared by him in pursuance of this section; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415582_021" name="b" temporalId="s15_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>approve any revision or proposed revision of the whole or any part of any code of practice for the time being approved under this section,</content></paragraph><continued>and the provisions of subsection (2) shall, with necessary modifications, apply in relation to any revision approved under this subsection as they apply in relation to a code of practice approved under subsection (1).</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415582_034" name="4" temporalId="s15_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director may at any time withdraw his approval from any code of practice approved under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415582_042" name="5" temporalId="s15_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where under subsection (4) the Director withdraws his approval from a code of practice approved under this section, he shall, by notice in the Gazette, identify the code concerned and specify the date on which his approval of it is to cease to have effect.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415582_050" name="6" temporalId="s15_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>References in this Regulation to an approved code of practice are references to that code as it has effect for the time being by virtue of any revision of the whole or any part of it approved under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415598_005" name="7" temporalId="s15_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><def name="CodeOfPractice">The power of the Director under subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref>
                to approve a code of practice issued or proposed to be issued otherwise than by him
                shall include power to approve part of such a code and, accordingly, in this
                Regulation
                    <term>code
                    of
                practice</term>
                may be read as including part of such a code.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163896_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Use of approved code of practice in criminal proceedings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415629_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where in any criminal proceedings before a magistrate or court a party is alleged to have committed an offence by reason of a contravention of a requirement under this Regulation, being a requirement for which there was an approved code of practice at the time of the alleged contravention, then—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415629_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any provision of the code of practice which appears to the magistrate or court to be relevant to the requirement alleged to have been contravened shall be admissible in evidence in the proceedings; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415629_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>subject to subsection (2), if it is proved that there was at any material time a failure to observe any provision of the code which appears to the magistrate or court to be relevant to any matter which it is necessary for the prosecution to prove in order to establish a contravention of such requirement, then such failure may be relied upon by the prosecution as tending to establish that matter.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415645_005" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> shall not have effect if the magistrate or court is satisfied that the requirement alleged to have been contravened was, as regards the matter which it is necessary for the prosecution to prove, complied with otherwise than by way of observance of the code of practice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415645_013" name="3" temporalId="s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In any criminal proceedings, a code of practice which appears to a magistrate or court to be the subject of a notice under <ref>section 15(2)</ref> shall be taken to be the subject of such notice unless the contrary is proved.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415645_021" name="4" temporalId="s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the avoidance of doubt, it is hereby declared that a failure on the part of any person to observe any provision of an approved code of practice shall not of itself render him liable to any civil or criminal proceedings.</content></subsection></section><crossHeading class="add-toc">Offences</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403163911_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Offences and penalties</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412415692_011" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who contravenes any requirement of <ref>section 8(2)</ref> commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415692_019" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who contravenes any requirement of <ref>section 9</ref> commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 1.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415692_027" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who contravenes any requirement of <ref>section 10(1)(a)</ref> or (b) commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 4 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415692_035" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A person who contravenes any requirement of <ref>section 10(2)(a)</ref> or (b) commits an offence and is liable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415692_043" name="a" temporalId="s17_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the contravention results in an electrical accident or an interruption to the supply of electricity, to a fine of $200,000 and to imprisonment for 12 months; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415692_051" name="b" temporalId="s17_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in any other case, to a fine at level 4 and to imprisonment for 6 months,</content></paragraph><continued>and, in the case of a continuing offence, to an additional fine of $10,000 for each day on which the offence continues.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415707_004" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with any direction specified in a remedial notice issued under <ref>section 11</ref> commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415707_012" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A person who contravenes any requirement of <ref>section 12(3)(a)</ref> commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 4 and, in the case of a continuing offence, to an additional fine of $10,000 for each day on which the offence continues.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415707_020" name="7" temporalId="s17_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A person who contravenes any requirement of <ref>section 12(3)(b)</ref> commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 3.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412415707_028" name="8" temporalId="s17_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>No person shall advertise or otherwise hold himself out as—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415707_036" name="a" temporalId="s17_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a competent person if he is not such person as approved under this Regulation; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415707_044" name="b" temporalId="s17_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a competent person approved to do works which he is not approved to do pursuant to the terms of his approval under this Regulation,</content></paragraph><continued>and a person who contravenes this provision commits an offence and is liable to a fine at level 4.</continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403163927_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Defence</heading><leadIn>It shall be a defence to a charge under <ref>section 17(4)</ref> alleging a contravention of <ref>section 10(2)</ref> for the person charged to show that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412415738_058" name="a" temporalId="s18_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>before the works began, all reasonable steps had been taken for the purposes of <ref>section 10(1)</ref>; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412415754_006" name="b" temporalId="s18_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any failure in the taking of all reasonable measures for the purposes of <ref>section 10(2)</ref> was due to reliance on information contained in a report prepared by a competent person or on information provided by the electricity supplier who is the owner of the electricity supply line concerned.</content></paragraph></section><schedule id="ID_1438403163927_003" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2021-11-11" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap406H/s3">ss. 3(2)</ref>, <ref href="/hk/cap406H/s4">4(1)</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap406H/s5">5(2)</ref>]<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></note><heading>Fees</heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <col width="11.8264%"></col>
                <col width="80.6424%"></col>
                <col width="7.5243%"></col>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Item</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_center">Particular</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_center">Fee</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td></td>
                    <td></td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_center">$ </p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_5">1.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0 align_left">Application for
                            approval as a competent person under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 3</ref></p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_center">436</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_5">2.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0 align_left">Application for
                            variation of conditions of approval as a competent person under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 4</ref></p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_center">436</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_5">3.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0 align_left">Application for
                            renewal of approval as a competent person under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 5</ref></p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_center">423</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_5">4.</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0 align_left">Application for
                            replacement copy of certificate of approval</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_center">322</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>