<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 497</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>497</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap497!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-08-18</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403271988_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2022-08-18">
            <content>An Ordinance to give effect in Hong Kong to the Convention for the Protection
                of Submarine Cables made at Paris on 14 March 1884.</content>
            
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[27 December 1996]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><section id="ID_1438403272004_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Submarine Telegraph
                Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403272004_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Master"><term>master</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船長</term>) includes every person having command or
            charge of a vessel;</def><def name="Officer"><term>officer</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">高級船員</term>) means an officer commanding such a ship as
            described in Article X of the <ref>Schedule</ref>;</def><def name="Person"><term>person</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">人</term>) includes a body of persons corporate or
            unincorporate;</def><def name="TheConvention"><term>the Convention</term> (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公約</term>》) means the Convention for the Protection of Submarine Cables which was
            made at Paris on 14 March 1884 and which was established in the French language;</def><def name="Vessel"><term>vessel</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船隻</term>) means every description of vessel used in
            navigation in whatever way it is propelled; and any reference to a vessel shall include
            a reference to a boat belonging to such vessel.</def><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/28">28 of 1998 s.
            2</ref>; <ref href="hk/2022/er3">E.R. 3 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 12 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403272051_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Convention to have the force of law</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, the Convention as set out in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, being an English translation of the French original, shall continue to have the force of law in Hong Kong.</content><referenceNote> [cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403272051_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Contravention of Article II of the Convention</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412739049_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A person who unlawfully and wilfully breaks or damages any submarine cable to which the Convention applies, in such manner as might interrupt or obstruct in whole or in part telegraphic communication, commits an offence and is liable on conviction on indictment to a fine of $500,000 and to imprisonment for 5 years.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739049_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A person who by culpable negligence breaks or damages any submarine cable to which the Convention applies, in the manner described in subsection (1), commits an offence and is liable on summary conviction to a fine at level 6 and to imprisonment for 1 year.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739049_020" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who attempts to break or damage, unlawfully and wilfully, any submarine cable to which the Convention applies, in the manner described in subsection (1), commits an offence and is liable to be punished in like manner as if he had committed an offence under subsection (1).</content><referenceNote> [cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 3(1) &amp; (2) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403272066_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Defences and exceptions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412739080_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a person does any act for the purposes of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412739080_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>preserving the life of or preventing injury to himself or any other person; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412739080_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>preserving the vessel to which he belongs or any other vessel,</content></paragraph><continued>and takes all reasonable precautions to avoid damage to a submarine cable, such person is deemed not to have acted unlawfully and wilfully within the meaning of <ref>section 4</ref>.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739080_033" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If in a bona fide attempt to repair a submarine cable, another cable is broken or damaged, such breakage or damage is deemed not to be unlawful and wilful.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739080_041" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subsection (2) shall not apply so as to exempt any person from any liability under this Ordinance or otherwise to pay the cost of repairing any breakage of or damage to any submarine cable.</content><referenceNote> [cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 3(3) &amp; (4) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403272082_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Accessories</heading><leadIn>A person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412739111_019" name="a" temporalId="s6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>within Hong Kong; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412739111_027" name="b" temporalId="s6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>being a permanent resident of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region or a
                body corporate incorporated or established in Hong Kong, in any place outside Hong
                    Kong,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/28">28 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>in any manner procures, counsels, aids, abets or is accessory to the commission
            of an offence under <ref>section 4</ref>, commits an offence and is liable to be tried
            and punished for the offence as if he had been a principal.</continued><referenceNote>[cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 3(5) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403272082_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Obstruction of officers</heading><content>A person who obstructs an officer in the exercise or performance of the powers and duties vested in and imposed on him by any Article of the <ref>Schedule</ref>, or who refuses or neglects to comply with any demand or direction lawfully made or given by such officer in pursuance of this Ordinance, commits an offence and is liable on summary conviction to a fine at level 6 and to imprisonment for 1 year.</content><referenceNote> [cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 6(1) &amp; (2) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403272098_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Evidence</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412739143_025" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any document drawn up in pursuance of Article VII or Article X of the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall be admissible in any proceeding, civil or criminal, as prima facie evidence of the facts or matters stated in the document.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739143_033" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If evidence contained in any document as mentioned in subsection (1) was taken on oath in the presence of the person accused in such evidence, and the person accused had an opportunity of cross-examining the person giving such evidence and of making his reply to such evidence, the master or officer drawing up such document may certify the said facts, or any of them.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739158_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any document or certificate mentioned in this section purporting to be signed by a master or officer shall be admissible in evidence without proof of such signature, and, if purporting to be signed by any other person, shall, if certified by any such master or officer to have been so signed, be deemed until the contrary is proved to have been signed by such other person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739158_013" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412739158_021" name="a" temporalId="s8_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>forges the signature of any master or officer to any such document or certificate as is mentioned in this section; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412739174_006" name="b" temporalId="s8_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>makes use of any such document or certificate knowing the signature to it to be forged,</content></paragraph><continued>commits an offence and is liable on conviction on indictment to a fine of $150,000 and to imprisonment for 2 years.</continued><referenceNote> [cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403272113_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Liability of masters of vessels</heading><content>Where an offence against this Ordinance has been committed by means of a vessel, or of any boat belonging to a vessel, the master of such vessel shall, unless some other person is shown to have been in charge of and navigating such vessel or boat, be deemed to have been in charge of and navigating the same, and be liable to be punished accordingly.</content><referenceNote> [cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403272129_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Savings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412739221_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The provisions of this Ordinance shall be in addition to and not in derogation from any other provisions existing at common law or under any enactment for the protection of submarine cables.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739221_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (3)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412739221_020" name="a" temporalId="s10_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>nothing in this Ordinance shall prevent a person being liable under any Ordinance or otherwise to any indictment, proceeding, punishment, or penalty other than as is provided for by this Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412739221_028" name="b" temporalId="s10_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>nothing in this Ordinance, nor any proceedings with respect to any matter, shall exempt a person from any liability in any action or suit with reference to the same matter.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739221_035" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The provisions of subsection (2) shall not apply so that a person—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412739221_043" name="a" temporalId="s10_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>is punished twice for the same offence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412739221_051" name="b" temporalId="s10_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>is required to pay compensation twice in respect of the same damage.</content><referenceNote> [cf. 1885 c. 49 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403272129_003" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Repeal of Submarine Telegraph Act 1885</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412739252_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Submarine Telegraph Act 1885 (1885 c. 49 U.K.), in so far as it is part of the law of Hong Kong, is repealed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412739252_012" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Sections 23 to 25</ref> of the Interpretation and General Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>) apply in relation to the repeal of Act referred to in subsection (1) as they apply in relation to the repeal of an Ordinance.</content></subsection></section><schedule id="ID_1438403272144_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-08-18" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap497/s2">ss. 2</ref>, <ref href="/hk/cap497/s3">3</ref>, <ref href="/hk/cap497/s7">7</ref>
            &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap497/s8">8</ref>]</note><heading>Convention
            for the Protection of Submarine
            Cables</heading><crossHeading class="align_center"><inline class="not_bold">[</inline><i><inline class="not_bold">Preamble
                omitted</inline></i><inline class="not_bold">]</inline></crossHeading><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            I</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">The present Convention
            applies outside territorial waters to all legally established submarine cables landed on
            the territories, colonies, or possessions of one or more of the High Contracting
            Parties.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            II</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">It is a punishable offence
            to break or injure a submarine cable, wilfully or by culpable negligence, in such manner
            as might interrupt or obstruct telegraphic communication, either wholly or partially,
            such punishment being without prejudice to any civil action for
            damages.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">This provision does not
            apply to cases where those who break or injure a cable do so with the lawful object of
            saving their lives or their ship, after they have taken every necessary precaution to
            avoid so breaking or injuring the cable.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            III</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">The High Contracting
            Parties undertake that, on granting a concession for landing a submarine cable, they
            will insist, so far as possible, upon proper measures of safety being taken, both as
            regards the track of the cable and its dimensions.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            IV</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">The owner of a cable who,
            on laying or repairing his own cable breaks or injures another cable, must bear the cost
            of repairing the breakage or injury, without prejudice to the application, if need be,
            of Article II of the present Convention.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            V</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Vessels engaged in laying
            or repairing submarine cables shall conform to the regulations as to signals which have
            been, or may be, adopted by mutual agreement among the High Contracting Parties, with
            the view of preventing collisions at sea.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">When a ship engaged in
            repairing a cable exhibits the said signals, other vessels which see them, or are able
            to see them, shall withdraw to or keep beyond a distance of one nautical mile at least
            from the ship in question, so as not to interfere with her
            operations.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Fishing gear and nets shall
            be kept at the same distance.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Nevertheless, fishing
            vessels which see or are able to see a telegraph ship exhibiting the said signals shall
            be allowed a period of twenty-four hours at most within which to obey the notice so
            given, during which time they shall not be interfered with in any
            way.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">The operations of the
            telegraph ships shall be completed as quickly as
            possible.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            VI</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Vessels which see, or are
            able to see, the buoys showing the position of a cable when the latter is being laid, is
            out of order, or is broken, shall keep beyond a distance of one-quarter of a nautical
            mile at least from the said buoys.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Fishing nets and gear shall
            be kept at the same distance.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            VII</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Owners of ships or vessels
            who can prove that they have sacrificed an anchor, a net, or other fishing gear in order
            to avoid injuring a submarine cable shall receive compensation from the owner of the
            cable.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">In order to establish a
            claim to such compensation, a statement supported by the evidence of the crew, should,
            whenever possible, be drawn up immediately after the occurrence; and the master must,
            within twenty-four hours after his return to, or next putting into port, make a
            declaration to the proper authorities.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">The latter shall
            communicate the information to the consular authorities of the country to which the
            owner of the cable belongs.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            VIII</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">The tribunals competent to
            take cognizance of infractions of the present Convention are those of the country to
            which the vessel on board of which the offence was committed
            belongs.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">It is, moreover, understood
            that, in cases where the provisions in the previous paragraph cannot apply, offences
            against the present Convention will be dealt with in each of the Contracting States in
            accordance, so far as the subjects and citizens of those States respectively are
            concerned, with the general rules of criminal jurisdiction prescribed by the laws of
            that particular State, or by international treaties.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            IX</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Prosecutions for
            infractions provided against by Articles II, V, and VI of the present Convention shall
            be instituted by the State, or in its name.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            X</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">Offences against the
            present Convention may be verified by all means of proof allowed by the legislation of
            the country of the court. When the officers commanding the ships of war, or ships
            specially commissioned for the purpose by one of the High Contracting Parties, have
            reason to believe that an infraction of the measures provided for in the present
            Convention has been committed by a vessel other than a vessel of war, they may demand
            from the captain or master the production of the official documents proving the
            nationality of the said vessel. The fact of such document having been exhibited shall
            then be endorsed upon it immediately. Further, formal statements of the facts may be
            prepared by the said officers, whatever may be the nationality of the vessel
            incriminated. These formal statements shall be drawn up in the form and in the language
            used in the country to which the officer making them belongs; they may be considered, in
            the country where they are adduced, as evidence in accordance with the laws of that
            country. The accused and the witnesses shall have the right to add, or to have added,
            thereto, in their own language, any explanations they may consider useful. These
            declarations shall be duly signed.<marker role="blank-line"></marker></text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">ARTICLE
            XI</inline><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 first_line_indent_24 align_justified">The proceedings and trial
            in cases of infraction of the provisions of the present Convention shall always take
            place as summarily as the laws and regulations in force will permit.</text><crossHeading><inline class="not_bold">[<i>Articles XII to XVII
            omitted</i>]</inline></crossHeading></schedule></main></ordinance>