<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 556 sub. leg. H</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>556H</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap556H!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2019-12-12</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403440809_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-12-12">Mass
            Transit
            Railway
            (North-west
            Railway)
            Bylaw</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap556/s34">Cap. 556, section
                34</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[2
            December 2007]<sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><ref href="/hk/2007/ln200">L.N. 200 of 2007</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403440824_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            1</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403440840_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438413315777_004" name="1" temporalId="s1_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent—<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413315777_012" name="2" temporalId="s1_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In this Bylaw, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AutomaticProcessingDevice"><term>automatic
                    processing
                device</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">自動處理裝置</term>) means a processing device used by
                the Corporation for the automatic collection of fares;</def><def name="Bus"><term>bus</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">巴士</term>) means a bus as defined in the Road
                Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap. 374</ref>) and operated by or on
                behalf of the Corporation within the North-west Transit Service Area;</def><def name="Corporation"><term>Corporation</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公司</term>) means the MTR Corporation Limited;</def><def name="Fare"><term>fare</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車費</term>) means the fare payable by any passenger
                for travel on any bus or on the railway irrespective of whether a ticket is issued
                to him by or on behalf of the Corporation for travel on any bus or on the
                railway;</def><def name="InvalidTicket">
                <leadIn><term>invalid
                        ticket</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">失效車票</term>) means a ticket—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413315777_055" name="a" temporalId="s1_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for which the period of validity has expired; or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413315777_063" name="b" temporalId="s1_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>which is invalid for travel on any bus or on the railway in which the
                        ticket holder is travelling; or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413315793_006" name="c" temporalId="s1_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>which the passenger is not entitled to use pursuant to the conditions
                        of use contained or referred to in any other publications, notices, lists or
                        tables relating to such ticket or travel; and</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413315793_014" name="d" temporalId="s1_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>in case of a smart card includes a smart card which has not had the
                        appropriate authorization code recorded on it by an automatic processing
                        device immediately before the ticket holder travels or attempts to travel on
                        any bus or boards or attempts to board any vehicle of the North-west Railway
                        or travels or attempts to travel on any such vehicle;</content></paragraph>
            </def><def name="Official"><term>official</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">人員</term>) means any person duly authorized to act
                on behalf of the Corporation and includes any employee, servant or lawfully
                appointed agent of the Corporation;</def><def name="Passenger"><term>passenger</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">乘客</term>) means a person who has paid a fare or on
                whose behalf a fare has been paid and who is lawfully travelling on any bus or the
                railway during the hours of business of the Corporation irrespective of whether a
                ticket is issued to him or on his behalf or has been otherwise acquired by him for
                such purpose;</def><def name="PersonalizedTicket"><term>personalized
                    ticket</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">個人車票</term>) means a ticket which has been issued
                to the person or individual identified on the ticket;</def><def name="Railway"><term>railway</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">鐵路</term>) means the North-west Railway;</def><def name="RailwayPremises"><term>railway
                    premises</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">鐵路處所</term>) means railway premises belonging to or
                appertaining to the North-west Railway but excludes any carriageway of the
                North-west Railway not designated by the Commissioner for Transport for the purpose
                of the definition of
                        <b><i>road</i></b>
                under <ref>section 2</ref> of the Road Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap. 374</ref>);</def><def name="SmartCard"><term>smart
                    card</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">聰明卡</term>) means a card or chip issued by or on
                behalf of the Corporation for the purpose of communicating with automatic processing
                devices;</def><def name="Surcharge">
                <leadIn><term>surcharge</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">附加費</term>) means such amount as may be
                    specified in notices, lists, tables or other publications issued by or on behalf
                    of the Corporation from time to time and shall be—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413315824_005" name="a" temporalId="s1_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an amount equal to fifty times the prevailing maximum adult single fare
                        on any bus or railway at the time the surcharge is imposed; or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438413315824_013" name="b" temporalId="s1_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the maximum fine prescribed in this
                        Bylaw,</content></paragraph>
                <continued>whichever is the lower;</continued>
            </def><def name="Ticket"><term>ticket</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車票</term>) means any form of ticket, smart card,
                pass or permit issued from time to time by or on behalf of the Corporation, for
                travel on any bus or on the railway;</def><def name="TicketOffice"><term>ticket
                    office</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">票務處</term>) means any office operated by or on
                behalf of the Corporation which is duly authorized to issue tickets;</def><def name="Vehicle"><term>vehicle</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車輛</term>) means a vehicle as defined in the Road
                Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap. 374</ref>);</def><def name="VehicleOfTheNorthwestRailway"><term>vehicle
                    of the North-west
                Railway</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">西北鐵路車輛</term>) means any train or carriage or
                compartment thereof used on or in connection with the railway.</def></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403440840_003" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            2</num><heading>Tickets
            and
            Fares</heading><section id="ID_1438403440855_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413315902_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>All tickets whether specifically referred to in this Bylaw or not are issued subject to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413315902_012" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>this Bylaw; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413315902_020" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any special conditions stated or referred to on such tickets or any special conditions otherwise contained or referred to in any notices, lists, tables or other publications issued by or on behalf of the Corporation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413315918_004" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A passenger shall be deemed to have knowledge of and to have agreed to this Bylaw and any special conditions in relation to any ticket used by him or any special conditions otherwise contained or referred to in any notices, lists, tables or other publications issued by or on behalf of the Corporation and the liability of the Corporation (if any) shall be limited but not extended thereby.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440855_004" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Fares</heading><content>The fares appearing from time to time in notices, lists, tables or other publications issued by or on behalf of the Corporation are the authorized fares for travel on any bus or on the railway. </content></section><section id="ID_1438403440871_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Tickets contain no warranty or acceptance of liability</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413315964_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation does not warrant that a passenger will be conveyed on any particular bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or that any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway shall arrive or depart at a particular time or stop or that the issue of a ticket will be completed before the departure of any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway and the Corporation will not be liable to any person for any loss or damage whatsoever arising from any delay or detention caused by the alteration suspension interference with or withdrawal of the Corporation’s bus or railway services (or a part thereof) for any reason whatsoever.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413315980_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Corporation may in its absolute discretion do all or any of the following without being liable to any person for any loss or damage caused thereby—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413315980_013" name="a" temporalId="s4_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>suspend or discontinue the issue of tickets howsoever issued; </content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413315980_021" name="b" temporalId="s4_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>despatch any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway from a stop before the arrival of any other bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway without affording passengers an opportunity of alighting and boarding the bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413315996_006" name="c" temporalId="s4_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>suspend, discontinue or otherwise withdraw all or any bus or railway service from any stop at any time and for any period of time or suspend, discontinue or withdraw the running of any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway at any time and for any period of time and alter the times of departure and arrival of any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway and the routes thereof. </content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413315996_013" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Corporation may in its absolute discretion consider applications for a refund where a ticket is unused as a consequence of the circumstances described in subsection (2).</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440887_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Entry and travel prohibited without payment of fare</heading><leadIn>No person shall without the authority of an official, which authority shall not be unreasonably withheld, or except as provided in <ref>section 12(1)</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316042_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>travel on any bus;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316042_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>board or attempt to board any vehicle of the North-west Railway; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316042_028" name="c" temporalId="s5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>travel or attempt to travel upon any vehicle of the North-west Railway,</content></paragraph><continued>unless having first paid the appropriate fare and, where a ticket is issued, obtaining the appropriate ticket and in the case of using a smart card as a ticket, using it in the appropriate manner in conjunction with an automatic processing device so that the appropriate fare is paid to the Corporation. </continued></section><section id="ID_1438403440887_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Production of tickets and surcharge</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316074_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All tickets shall remain the property of the Corporation and must be produced at any time on any bus or on the railway on demand being made therefor by any official.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316074_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who refuses or fails to pay the appropriate fare or refuses or fails to produce his ticket shall be liable to pay a surcharge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316074_020" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person holding or using a free or concessionary ticket while on the railway or on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway shall produce on demand by an official sufficient evidence to prove his entitlement to hold and use the ticket.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316074_028" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any person who uses a free or concessionary ticket but fails to produce sufficient evidence to prove his entitlement to such use shall be liable to pay a surcharge as if no ticket were held.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316089_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Any person who without the authority of an official, which authority shall not be unreasonably withheld, holds a free or concessionary ticket and fails to produce sufficient evidence to prove his entitlement to hold such ticket shall be required upon demand by an official to surrender such ticket to the official.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440902_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Damaging and using damaged tickets</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316120_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person shall improperly do anything to or with a ticket whereby—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316120_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the coded or printed data thereon is erased wholly or in part or is otherwise altered or interfered with; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316120_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the ticket is otherwise damaged.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316120_027" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall use or attempt to use for travel on any bus or the railway a
                ticket which has been improperly
                altered,
                damaged or which has been otherwise interfered with and, in the case of using a
                smart card as a ticket which is unable to communicate with an automatic processing
                device for tickets.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440902_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Failures to pay fare, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316152_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Save as provided under subsections (2), (3), (4), (5) and (6), no person prior to leaving any bus or the railway shall fail to or refuse to pay any fare or other sum payable to the Corporation in accordance with this Bylaw.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316152_012" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>When a person is liable to pay a surcharge, payment shall be made immediately on demand by an official and payment shall be made to the official demanding the surcharge.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316152_020" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>When a person aged 16 years and over is unable in the opinion of an official to make immediate payment of a surcharge, the demand of the surcharge by the Corporation shall be made by way of service of a notice in writing and the person upon whom the notice is served shall sign the notice and shall make payment of the surcharge not later than 14 days from the date of service of the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316167_005" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>When a person under the age of 16 years is unable in the opinion of an official to make immediate payment of the surcharge, the demand of the surcharge by the Corporation shall be made by way of service of a notice in writing upon his parent, legal guardian or next of kin and the person who receives the notice shall make payment of the surcharge not later than 14 days from the date of service of the notice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316183_005" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The decision as to whether a person is unable to make immediate payment of a surcharge shall be in the absolute discretion of an official dealing with tickets or passengers and shall be final and binding for all purposes without liability of whatever nature for any loss and damage whatsoever and howsoever arising from any such decision.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316183_013" name="6" temporalId="s8_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Corporation shall be entitled at its own discretion to deduct the surcharge wholly or in part from any smart card held by any passenger liable in respect thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440918_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Travel without a ticket or with expired or inappropriate ticket</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316230_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If a person (other than a person who is under the age of 3 years) travels or attempts to travel on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316230_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>without a ticket;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316230_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>with a ticket which has been altered without the authority of the Corporation or any of its officials or which has been damaged;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316230_028" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>with an invalid ticket; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316230_036" name="d" temporalId="s9_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>with a personalized ticket which has been issued to another person,</content></paragraph><continued>he shall be regarded as not having paid his fare and shall be liable to pay a surcharge to the Corporation.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316230_049" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316230_057" name="a" temporalId="s9_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a ticket shall expire and becomes invalid in the event that a passenger fails to complete the journey to which the ticket relates within 2 hours of being issued with a ticket;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316230_065" name="b" temporalId="s9_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the period of validity and special conditions governing a season ticket or a stored value ticket shall be those printed upon the ticket or, if no period of validity or special conditions are printed upon the ticket such period of validity and special conditions as are set out in the publications, notices, lists or tables issued by or on behalf of the Corporation from time to time;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316245_006" name="c" temporalId="s9_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a person who is on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway and who subsequently leaves or attempts to leave the bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or the railway premises shall, in the absence of proof to the contrary, be presumed to have travelled upon the railway;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316245_014" name="d" temporalId="s9_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>all tickets issued by or on behalf of the Corporation shall be delivered up at the request of an official if they have become invalid whether or not any stored value remains in such ticket. </content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440918_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Passengers to examine tickets and change</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316292_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All persons shall examine their tickets and any change tendered before leaving any ticket office.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316292_012" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Neither the Corporation nor any official shall be liable for any error or omission not drawn to their attention at the time of issue of a ticket.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316292_020" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person boarding any bus shall insert not less than the appropriate fare into a farebox in payment of the fare or shall produce for inspection a valid ticket or authority for travel.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316292_028" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person using an automatic vending machine shall insert not less than the appropriate fare in legal tender including a valid stored value ticket for the purchase of a ticket.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316308_005" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>No person shall be entitled to any refund of any amount inserted into an automatic vending machine or a farebox which is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316308_013" name="a" temporalId="s10_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in excess of the appropriate fare; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316308_021" name="b" temporalId="s10_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in excess of the balance required to make up the appropriate fare where the value remaining in a stored value ticket is inadequate.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316308_028" name="6" temporalId="s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The amount (including a nil amount) from time to time printed on or encoded on a ticket shall be conclusive evidence of the amount paid in respect of such ticket and in the case of a stored value ticket the value (if any) remaining in such ticket.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316308_036" name="7" temporalId="s10_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Any person who is requested to do so by any official shall immediately produce to that official acceptable proof of his entitlement to any concessionary or other special type of ticket or fare.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440933_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Exchanges and refunds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316354_004" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A fare may be refunded or a ticket may be refunded or exchanged at the absolute discretion of the Corporation. Any such exchange or refund may be subject to the deduction of an administration charge determined and published by the Corporation from time to time.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316354_012" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The form of any refund shall be at the absolute discretion of the Corporation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316354_020" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Corporation shall not be obliged to issue a ticket in replacement of a lost or mislaid or unused ticket nor will it be obliged to make a refund in respect of the value of any such ticket or the amount of a fare or a surcharge levied as a consequence of failure to produce a ticket when required.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440933_004" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Children travelling on buses and the railway</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316386_027" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Except when otherwise specified in notices, lists, tables or other publications issued by or on behalf of the Corporation, up to two children under 3 years of age may accompany each adult passenger on any bus or on the railway free of charge provided that such child or children do not occupy a seat or seats that are required for other passengers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316401_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Each adult passenger accompanied by more than two children under 3 years of age shall pay the child fare as provided for in <ref>section 3</ref> for any children exceeding two in number.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316401_013" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any child over 3 years of age but under 12 years of age when travelling on any bus or on the railway shall pay the child fare as provided for in <ref>section 3</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316417_005" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In the absence of proof as to the age of any child referred to in this Bylaw the decision as to age shall be in the absolute discretion of the officials dealing with tickets or passengers and shall be final and binding for all purposes without liability of whatever nature for any loss or damage whatsoever and howsoever arising from any such decision.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440949_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Refusal of access</heading><content>The Corporation or any official may refuse to admit any person onto any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or to any part of the railway premises at any time whom it or he believes is likely to act in a riotous, disorderly or offensive manner or whom it or he reasonably suspects of committing or attempting to commit any offence contrary to any of this Bylaw.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403440965_002" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            3</num><heading>Trespass
            and Damage
            to Buses
            and
            the
            Railway</heading><section id="ID_1438403440980_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Trespass and removal of trespassers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316479_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No person shall enter into or upon any part of the railway premises other than those parts clearly defined by means of notices, indicators and other directions for the use of persons using the railway, nor shall any person enter or leave such parts other than by use of the designated entrances or exits. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316495_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who, without lawful excuse or the authority of the Corporation or its officials is on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or on any part of the railway premises or who otherwise being in breach of this Bylaw refuses to leave the same on being requested so to do by any official may be immediately removed therefrom without prejudice to any penalty or surcharge which may be imposed in accordance with this Bylaw.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403440996_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Offensive matter, materials, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316526_012" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person shall cause, permit or suffer—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316526_020" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any sewage, drainage or any other offensive matters to flow onto or otherwise come onto or be upon any part of the railway;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316542_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any waste product, waste material or food or refuse of any kind to be deposited on or otherwise come onto any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316542_014" name="c" temporalId="s15_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any kite, balloon, model or other thing to fly or otherwise pass over any part of the airspace above any part of the railway;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316542_022" name="d" temporalId="s15_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any kind of construction materials, construction plant or equipment to be deposited on or otherwise come upon and remain upon or pass across the railway premises except with the written authority of the Corporation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316542_029" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall
                cause,
                permit or suffer any missile, article or other object whatsoever to be propelled at
                or thrown at or wilfully dropped upon any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway
                or other part of the railway.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403441011_001" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            4</num><heading>Conduct
            of
            Persons
            on
            Buses
            and the
            Railway</heading><section id="ID_1438403441011_003" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Unlawful use of equipment on buses and the railway</heading><leadIn>No person except an official shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316604_012" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>actuate any emergency or safety device on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or upon the railway except for the express purpose for which the same is provided and in accordance with the instructions printed thereon or on a notice displayed near thereto;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316604_020" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enter or leave (or attempt to enter or leave) any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway whilst it is in motion or (except in case of accident or other emergency) between stops or otherwise than at the side of the bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway adjacent to the stop or the platform appointed for passengers to enter or leave the bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316620_006" name="c" temporalId="s16_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>enter or leave (or attempt to enter or leave) any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway after the doors have commenced to close;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316620_014" name="d" temporalId="s16_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>where notices are exhibited on a bus or a vehicle of the
                North-west
                Railway indicating that a door shall be used for entrance thereto and another door
                for exit therefrom (except in case of accident or other emergency) enter or attempt
                to enter by the door indicated for exit or leave or attempt to leave by the door
                indicated for entry;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316620_022" name="e" temporalId="s16_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>operate, move, work or tamper with any mechanical or electrical appliance or any plant or equipment whatsoever which belongs to the Corporation or is constructed for the purposes of or in connection with the railway.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403441027_002" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Indemnities for damage caused to persons and property</heading><leadIn>A person who by reason of bringing any animal, article or object on to any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway causes any injury, loss or damage whatsoever to the Corporation or its officials or any other person or causes any loss or damage whatsoever to the property of the Corporation, its officials or any other person shall indemnify the Corporation against all or any claims, demands, costs and expenses whatsoever arising therefrom in respect of any such injury, loss or damage howsoever caused: </leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s17_proviso">Provided that this section shall not apply in circumstances where the damage or loss to the property or persons referred to herein arises entirely from the neglect or default of an official.</proviso></section><section id="ID_1438403441043_001" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Compliance with notices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316682_018" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every person while on a bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or on any part of the railway premises shall comply with all notices, indicators and all reasonable directions and requests of officials.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316682_026" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall stand on the upper deck or any staircase of a bus. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316698_005" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (1) if any official determines that a bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway is full, no person shall enter or remain therein having just entered if directed by such official not to do so.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403441043_003" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Feet not to be placed on seats</heading><content>No person shall place his feet on any seat in any bus or on any vehicle of the North-west Railway or on any other part of the railway premises.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441058_001" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Smoking prohibited</heading><content>No person shall smoke or carry a lighted pipe, cigar or cigarette in any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway, or any other part of the railway premises where smoking is prohibited by notice.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441058_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Spitting and litter prohibited</heading><leadIn>No person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316760_012" name="a" temporalId="s21_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>spit in or on any bus or on any vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316760_020" name="b" temporalId="s21_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>deposit or throw any litter on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or on any part of the railway premises except into receptacles provided for that purpose.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403441074_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Nuisance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413316776_012" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No person shall at any time while upon the railway premises—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316776_020" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>use any threatening, abusive, obscene or offensive language or behave in a riotous, disorderly, indecent or offensive manner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316791_006" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>paint, write, draw or affix any word, representation or character upon or wilfully soil or defile the railway premises or break, cut, scratch, tear, deface or otherwise damage any part of the railway premises including any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any of the fittings, furniture, decorations, or equipment thereof or any publication, notice, list, time-table, advertisement, number plate, number, figure or letter therein or thereupon or remove therefrom or detach any such article or object;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316807_006" name="c" temporalId="s22_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>damage any property upon the railway premises;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316807_014" name="d" temporalId="s22_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>molest or wilfully interfere with the comfort or convenience of any person; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316807_022" name="e" temporalId="s22_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>obstruct, impede or distract an official from performing his duties.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413316807_029" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref>section 40</ref>, any person who contravenes subsection (1) shall be liable to the Corporation for the amount of the damage done to any property of the Corporation or of any other person.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403441074_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Passengers in unfit or improper condition</heading><content>No person in a state of intoxication or who is in an unfit or improper condition shall enter or remain upon any part of the railway premises.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441089_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Singing, dancing and musical instruments prohibited</heading><content>No person unless authorized in writing by the Corporation or any of its officials while upon any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises shall sing, dance or perform on any musical or other instrument or use a radio, cassette recorder, compact disc player or similar device, television or any other such electrical or mechanical device which is likely to cause annoyance, inconvenience or disturbance to any other person.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441089_004" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Prohibited items</heading><leadIn>No person shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316885_012" name="a" temporalId="s25_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>bring onto any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises any luggage, article, object or any other thing which by reason of its nature, in the opinion of an official, cannot be carried or otherwise accommodated on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises without the likelihood of causing damage to the property of the Corporation or without the likelihood of causing a nuisance or inconvenience to other persons using any bus or the railway;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316900_006" name="b" temporalId="s25_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>except as authorized by the Corporation consume any food or beverage (whether alcoholic or non-alcoholic) on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316900_014" name="c" temporalId="s25_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>unless the Corporation in its sole discretion allows or permits, bring any animal or other livestock into or upon any part of the railway premises (provided that this restriction shall not apply to a guide dog accompanying a blind person); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316900_022" name="d" temporalId="s25_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>place or throw any lighted cigarette end, match, tobacco, liquid, substance or any other thing upon the railway premises in a manner which constitutes or is likely to constitute a fire hazard.</content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403441105_002" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            5</num><heading>Hawkers,
            Loiterers
            and
            Bill
            Posting</heading><section id="ID_1438403441105_004" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Unauthorized bill posting, advertising and touting</heading><leadIn>No person on any bus or on any vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises shall, except with the written authority of the Corporation—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413316947_012" name="a" temporalId="s26_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>post, stick, paint or write or cause to be posted, stuck, painted or written any bill, placard, advertisement or any other matter;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316947_020" name="b" temporalId="s26_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>display or exhibit or cause to be displayed or exhibited any printed, written or pictorial matter or any article for the purpose of advertisement or publicity, or distribute any book, leaflet or other printed matter or any sample or other article; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413316963_006" name="c" temporalId="s26_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>tout, ply for, or solicit alms, reward or custom or employment of any description.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403441121_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Hawking prohibited</heading><content>No person, unless authorized in writing by the Corporation, shall sell or expose or offer for sale any goods, wares or services in or on any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises and <ref>sections 86</ref>, <ref>86A</ref>, <ref>86C</ref>, and 86D of the Public Health and Municipal Services Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap132">Cap. 132</ref>) shall apply to an offence under this section as if such offence were a hawker offence within the meaning of <ref>section 86</ref> of that Ordinance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441121_004" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Loitering prohibited</heading><content>No person other than passengers or other persons having the authority of the Corporation and on lawful business in or in connection with the railway shall loiter in or about any part of the railway premises.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403441136_002" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            6</num><heading>Vehicles
            on the
            Railway
            Premises</heading><section id="ID_1438403441152_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Vehicles not to be left on railway premises</heading><content>Except with the written authority of the Corporation, no person shall park or leave or cause any vehicle to be parked or left on any part of the railway premises.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441152_003" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Dealing with vehicles left on railway premises</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413317056_004" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Corporation may in such manner as it thinks fit remove and detain any vehicle in respect of which a contravention of <ref>section 29</ref> is committed and may charge the owner or driver thereof all costs and expenses occasioned by and incidental to such removal and detention without prejudice to any penalty incurred by contravention of that section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317056_012" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If a vehicle detained under subsection (1) is not claimed and removed and all costs and expenses are not paid within 3 days after its detention, the Corporation shall where practicable except in the case of emergency serve on the registered owner of the vehicle (as defined in the Road Traffic Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap374">Cap. 374</ref>)) a notice informing him—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413317072_002" name="a" temporalId="s30_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of the detention of the vehicle and the place of detention; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413317072_010" name="b" temporalId="s30_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that, unless the vehicle is removed from the place of detention on payment of any costs and charges within 14 days after the service of the notice on him, the vehicle shall become the property of the Corporation free from the rights of any person and may be disposed of by the Corporation by sale or otherwise.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317072_017" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If a vehicle is not removed in accordance with the notice served under subsection (2) or, if the service of such notice is impracticable, within 14 days of the date of its first detention, the vehicle shall become the property of the Corporation free from the rights of any person and may be disposed of by the Corporation by sale or otherwise as it thinks fit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317088_005" name="4" temporalId="s30_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If, within 6 months after the day on which a vehicle is sold pursuant to subsection (3), any person satisfies the Corporation that at the time the vehicle became the property of the Corporation by virtue of that subsection, he was the owner of the vehicle, the Corporation shall pay to such person the balance of the proceeds of sale after deducting any costs and charges of removal and detention and any reasonable charges incurred by the Corporation in respect of the sale of the vehicle.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317103_005" name="5" temporalId="s30_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A notice under subsection (2) may be served personally or by post.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317103_013" name="6" temporalId="s30_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><def name="Vehicle">For the purpose of this section,
                <term>vehicle</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">車輛</term>) includes the equipment carried by or on
                a vehicle.
                <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2019/er6">E.R. 6 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403441167_001" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Drivers to comply with traffic signs</heading><content>Vehicle drivers while in or upon any part of the railway premises shall obey all traffic signs and signals and the reasonable instructions and directions of officials.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441167_003" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Dangerous driving</heading><content>No person shall drive or operate any vehicle through, into or upon any part of the railway premises in excess of the speed indicated by a notice, indicator, sign or signal or by an official or in a manner likely to involve danger to others.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441183_002" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Vehicles prohibited on certain parts of railway premises</heading><content>No person shall drive or operate any vehicle upon or along any part of the railway premises set apart for the exclusive use of pedestrians.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403441183_004" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part
            7</num><heading>Dangerous
            Goods</heading><section id="ID_1438403441199_002" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Dangerous goods</heading><content>No person not being an official duly authorized in that behalf shall bring onto any bus or any vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises any substance or other thing which is subject to the provisions of the Dangerous Goods Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap295">Cap. 295</ref>).</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403441214_001" name="P8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part
            8</num><heading>Lost
            Property</heading><section id="ID_1438403441214_003" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Lost property</heading><content>Every person who finds any article or object in or upon any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises shall hand over the same to an official as soon as is practicable and no person other than an official shall remove from any bus or vehicle of the North-west Railway or any part of the railway premises any property lost or left behind therein, save for the purpose of handing over the same as soon as is practicable to an official and all articles or objects so found shall as between the finder and the Corporation be deemed to be in the possession of the Corporation.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441230_001" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Disposal of lost property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413317259_004" name="1" temporalId="s36_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>All articles or objects found and which come into the possession of the Corporation shall be dealt with as follows—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413317275_005" name="a" temporalId="s36_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>perishable, noxious or otherwise offensive goods or articles may be disposed of by the Corporation by sale or otherwise as in its absolute discretion it sees fit as soon as practicable after the same comes into its possession;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413317275_013" name="b" temporalId="s36_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>all other articles or objects shall be retained by the Corporation for a period of 1 month after they have come into its possession and, if at the end of that period they remain unclaimed, they shall be deemed to become the absolute property of the Corporation free from any other rights and encumbrances, and the Corporation may dispose of them by sale or otherwise and at such price (if any) as the Corporation in its absolute discretion thinks fit.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317290_005" name="2" temporalId="s36_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If within a period of 6 months from the date of any sale by the Corporation of any article or object the former owner thereof (which expression includes the person formerly entitled to the beneficial interest therein) establishes to the satisfaction of the Corporation prior lawful ownership of the article or object the former owner shall be paid the proceeds of sale less all expenses incurred by the Corporation in respect of and incidental to such sale provided that the former owner shall provide the Corporation with an indemnity in such form as may be required by the Corporation as a pre-condition to payment by the Corporation of any such sale proceeds.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317306_005" name="3" temporalId="s36_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Corporation shall not be liable to any person for any loss or damage whatsoever and howsoever arising from the loss of any article or object or the retention, sale or other disposal thereof or the restoration under subsection (2) of any article or object to a person other than the former lawful owner thereof.</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403441230_003" name="P9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P9"><num value="9">Part
            9</num><heading>Limitation
            of
            Liabilities</heading><section id="ID_1438403441245_002" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Payment of sums sufficient to indemnify Corporation</heading><content>Any passenger or person or the owner of any animal, vehicle, luggage, goods, articles or things howsoever mentioned or referred to in this Bylaw shall pay to the Corporation the amount of all or any sum or sums required to indemnify the Corporation or any official from and against all or any claim made by or on behalf of any passenger or owner or other person including personal representatives of the same arising out of the carriage or custody by the Corporation or any official of any animal, vehicle, luggage, goods, articles or things and any cost, loss, damage or expense incurred in connection herewith and the Corporation shall hold any such sums paid in respect of any such claims against any cost, damage, loss or expense of any official in trust for the official concerned.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441245_004" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Limitations and exemptions</heading><content>The Corporation in making this Bylaw do so for themselves and for and on behalf of each and every official and the payment of a fare or the acceptance of a ticket by any passenger or person shall be conclusive evidence of his or their agreement that each and every limitation and exemption afforded to the Corporation by this Bylaw or all or any of them shall extend to each such official.</content></section></part><part id="ID_1438403441261_002" name="P10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="P10"><num value="10">Part
            10</num><heading>Enforcement
            and
            Penalties</heading><section id="ID_1438403441261_004" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Removal of persons from railway</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413317446_004" name="1" temporalId="s39_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any person who is reasonably suspected by an official of committing or attempting to commit any breach of this Bylaw, while in or upon any part of the railway premises shall, when required to do so by such official—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413317446_012" name="a" temporalId="s39_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>give to that official true and correct particulars of his name and address and of his telephone number, if any, and produce proof to that effect for inspection; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413317446_020" name="b" temporalId="s39_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>produce to that official proof of his identity for inspection.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317446_027" name="2" temporalId="s39_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An official acting in execution of the powers conferred under subsection (1) shall produce the authorization issued by the Corporation prior to executing those powers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317446_035" name="3" temporalId="s39_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person shall wilfully provide false information when required to provide information under subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317462_005" name="4" temporalId="s39_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An official shall have the power to remove (if necessary by the use of reasonable force) from the railway premises any person whom he reasonably suspects of having committed or attempting to commit any breach of this Bylaw, without prejudice to any penalty or surcharge which may be imposed in accordance with this Bylaw and in the case where such breach is an offence as herein provided he shall have power to detain such person until he can be delivered into the custody of a police officer to be dealt with according to law.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403441277_002" name="s40" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s40"><num value="40">40.</num><heading>Penalties</heading><content>A person who contravenes a section set out in the first column of the <ref>Schedule</ref> commits an offence and is liable to the penalty set out in the third column of that <ref>Schedule</ref> opposite the reference to that section.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403441277_004" name="s41" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="s41"><num value="41">41.</num><heading>Preservation of other causes of action</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413317509_011" name="1" temporalId="s41_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Unless the context otherwise requires nothing in this Bylaw and no prosecution or step or action hereunder shall bar any further or other claim for damages or other remedy or relief which the Corporation or its agents or other persons may be entitled to prosecute or bring.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413317524_005" name="2" temporalId="s41_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any sum levied by or payable to the Corporation or its agents (including, without limitation, any fare, or surcharge) whether by way of penalty, debt, damages, costs, loss, expense or otherwise shall be due to the Corporation or its lawful agents as a debt due on demand and shall be enforceable as a civil debt.</content></subsection></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403441292_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2019-12-12" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap556H/s40">s. 40</ref>]</note><heading>Penalties</heading><text>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="repeat_header">
                
                <col width="17%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="2%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="55%"></col>
                
                <col width="2%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="24%"></col>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="first_line_indent_0 ">Section</center>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Summary of
                                offence</center>
                            
                            <br xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"></br>
                            
                            
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Penalty</center>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">5</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Entry and travel without payment of fare</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">6</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Failure to produce tickets or pay surcharge</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">7</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Damaging and using damaged tickets </p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">8</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Failures to pay fare, etc.</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">9(1)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Travel without a ticket or with expired or
                                inappropriate ticket</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">12(3)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Failure to pay child fare</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$2,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">14</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Trespass</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">15</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Depositing offensive matter, materials, etc. </p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                6 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">16(a)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Improper use of emergency or safety device </p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                6 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">16(b), (c)
                                and (d)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Improperly entering or leaving any bus or vehicle
                                of the North-west Railway</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$2,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">16(e)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Tampering with equipment belonging to Corporation,
                                etc.</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                6 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">18</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Failure to comply with notices</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$1,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">19</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Feet placed on seats</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$1,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">20</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Smoking</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">21</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Spitting and litter</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">22</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Nuisance</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">23</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Passengers in unfit or improper condition entering
                                railway premises, etc.</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">24</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Singing, dancing and musical instruments</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$2,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">25(a), (b)
                                and (c)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Bringing prohibited items, consumption of food or
                                beverages, etc.</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$3,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">25(d)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Causing fire hazard</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                6 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">26</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Unauthorized bill posting, advertising and
                                touting</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">27</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Hawking</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                6 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">28</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Loitering</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$2,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">29</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Vehicles left on railway premises</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">31</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Failure of drivers to comply with traffic
                                signs</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                3 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">32</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Dangerous driving</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                6 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">33</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Vehicles on certain parts of railway premises</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">34</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Dangerous goods</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$5,000 fine and
                                6 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">35</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Failure to hand over lost property found</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$2,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">39(1)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Failure to give particulars of name, address or
                                telephone number or to produce proof thereof or of identity</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$1,000 fine</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="left_indent_6 first_line_indent_-6">39(3)</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left">Wilfully providing false information</p>
                        </td>
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        <td>
                            
                            <p class="align_left left_indent_8 first_line_indent_0">$3,000 fine and
                                3 months imprisonment</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
        </text></schedule></main></subLeg>