<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 347</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>347</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap347!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-07-09</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403039408_002" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2020-07-09">
                                    <content>To consolidate and amend the law relating to the
                                                limitation of actions.</content>
                        </longTitle><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2010/17">17 of 2010
                                                s.
                                    112</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></sourceNote><commencementNote>[11 June 1965]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of
                                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403039423_002" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403039423_004" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Limitation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403039439_002" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412034879_004" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Action"><term>action</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訴訟</term>) includes any proceeding in a court of
                law;</def><def name="Land"><term>land</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地</term>) includes corporeal hereditaments and
                rentcharges, and any legal or equitable estate or interest therein, including an
                interest in the proceeds of the sale of land held upon trust for sale, but save as
                aforesaid does not include any incorporeal hereditament;</def><def name="PersonalEstate,PersonalProperty"><term>personal
                    estate</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">非土地遺產</term>) and
                    <term>personal
                    property</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">非土地財產</term>) do not include chattels real;</def><def name="PersonalInjuries,Injury"><term>personal
                    injuries</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">人身傷害</term>) includes any disease and any
                impairment of a person’s physical or mental condition, and
                    <term>injury</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">傷害</term>) shall be construed accordingly;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of
                        1976 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Rent"><term>rent</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">租金</term>) includes a rentcharge and a rent
                service;</def><def name="Rentcharge"><term>rentcharge</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">租費</term>) means any annuity or periodical sum of
                money charged upon or payable out of land, except a rent service or interest on a
                mortgage on land;</def><def name="Ship"><term>ship</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">船舶</term>) includes every description of vessel
                used in navigation not propelled solely by oars;</def><def name="TheCourt"><term>the court</term> (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院</term>), in
                relation to an action, means the court in which the action has been, or is intended
                to be, brought;</def><def name="Trust,Trustee,TrustForSale"><term>trust</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">信託</term>),
                    <term>trustee</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受託人</term>) and
                    <term>trust
                    for
                sale</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">售產信託</term>) have the same meanings respectively as
                in the Trustee Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap29">Cap. 29</ref>).</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er4">E.R. 4 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438412034879_074" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>A person shall be deemed to claim through another person, if he became
                    entitled by, through, under, or by the act of that other person to the right
                    claimed:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s2_2_proviso">Provided that a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>person becoming entitled to any estate or interest
                    by virtue of a special power of appointment shall not be deemed to claim through
                    the appointer.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034895_011" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>References in this Ordinance to a right of action to recover land shall include
                references to a right to enter into possession of the land or, in the case of
                rentcharges, to distrain for arrears of rent, and references to the bringing of such
                an action shall include references to the making of such an entry or
                distress.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034895_019" name="4" temporalId="s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In the case of rentcharges, references in this Ordinance to the possession of
                land shall be construed as references to the receipt of the rent, and references to
                the date of dispossession or discontinuance of possession of land shall be construed
                as references to the date of the last receipt of rent.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034895_027" name="5" temporalId="s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>In Part III of this Ordinance, references to a right of action shall include
                references to a cause of action and to a right to receive money secured by a
                mortgage or charge on any property or to recover proceeds of the sale of land, and
                to a right to receive a share or interest in the personal estate of a deceased
                person; and references to the date of the accrual of a right of action
                shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412034911_005" name="a" temporalId="s2_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of an action for an account, be construed as references to the
                    date on which the matter arose in respect of which an account is
                    claimed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412034911_013" name="b" temporalId="s2_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of an action upon a judgment, be construed as references to the
                    date on which the judgment became enforceable;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412034911_021" name="c" temporalId="s2_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of an action to recover arrears of rent or interest, or damages
                    in respect thereof, be construed as references to the date on which the rent or
                    interest became due.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 31 U.K.; 1954 c. 36 s. 2(3) U.K.]</referenceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403039454_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Periods
            of Limitation
            for
            Different Classes
            of
            Action</heading><section id="ID_1438403039454_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Part II to be subject to Part III</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412034957_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This Part prescribes the ordinary limitation periods for bringing actions of the various classes mentioned in this Part.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034957_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The ordinary limitation periods are subject to extension or exclusion in accordance with Part III.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1980 c. 58 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Actions of Contract and
        Tort
        and
        Certain
        Other
        Actions</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039470_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Limitation of actions of contract and tort, and certain other actions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412034973_040" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The following actions shall not be brought after the expiration of 6 years from
                the date on which the cause of action accrued, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412034973_048" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>actions founded on simple contract or on tort;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412034973_056" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>actions to enforce a recognizance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412034973_064" name="c" temporalId="s4_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>actions to enforce an award, where the submission is not by an instrument
                    under seal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412034973_072" name="d" temporalId="s4_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>
                    <leadIn>actions to recover any sum recoverable by virtue of any Ordinance or
                        imperial enactment, other than a penalty or forfeiture or sum by way of
                        penalty or forfeiture:</leadIn>
                    
                </content></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_1_d_proviso">
                <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412034989_012" name="i" temporalId="s4_1_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412034989_020" name="ii" temporalId="s4_1_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>nothing in this subsection shall be taken to refer to any action to
                        which <ref>section 6</ref> applies.</content></paragraph>
            </proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034989_027" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An action for an account shall not be brought in respect of any matter which
                arose more than 6 years before the commencement of the action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034989_035" name="3" temporalId="s4_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                <leadIn>An action upon a specialty shall not be brought after the expiration of 12
                    years from the date on which the cause of action accrued:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_3_proviso">Provided that this subsection
                    shall not affect any action for which a shorter period of limitation is
                    prescribed by any other provision of this Ordinance.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034989_049" name="4" temporalId="s4_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An action shall not be brought upon any judgment after the expiration of 12
                years from the date on which the judgment became enforceable, and no arrears of
                interest in respect of any judgment debt shall be recovered after the expiration of
                6 years from the date on which the interest became due.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412034989_057" name="5" temporalId="s4_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>
                <leadIn>An action to recover any penalty or forfeiture, or sum by way of penalty or
                    forfeiture, recoverable by virtue of any Ordinance or imperial enactment shall
                    not be brought after the expiration of 2 years from the date on which the cause
                    of action accrued:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s4_5_proviso">Provided that for the purposes of
                    this subsection the expression
                        <term>penalty</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">罰金</term>) shall not include a fine to which
                    any person is liable on conviction of a criminal offence.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035004_011" name="6" temporalId="s4_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Subsection (1) shall apply to an action to recover seamen’s wages, but save as
                aforesaid this section shall not apply to any cause of action within the Admiralty
                jurisdiction of the High Court which is enforceable in rem.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035004_019" name="7" temporalId="s4_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>This section shall not apply to any claim for specific performance of a
                contract or for an injunction or for other equitable relief, except in so far as any
                provision thereof may be applied by the court by analogy in like manner as the
                corresponding enactment contained in the Limitation Act 1980 (1980 c. 58 U.K.) is
                applied in the English Courts.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035004_027" name="8" temporalId="s4_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 2 U.K.; 1954 c. 36 s. 2(1) U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039486_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Limitation in case of successive conversions and extinction of title of owner of converted goods</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035051_004" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where any cause of action in respect of the conversion or wrongful detention of a chattel has accrued to any person and, before he recovers possession of the chattel, a further conversion or wrongful detention takes place, no action shall be brought in respect of the further conversion or detention after the expiration of 6 years from the accrual of the cause of action in respect of the original conversion or detention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035051_012" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any such cause of action has accrued to any person and the period prescribed for bringing that action and for bringing any action in respect of such a further conversion or wrongful detention as aforesaid has expired and he has not during that period recovered possession of the chattel, the title of that person to the chattel shall be extinguished.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039486_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Time limit for claiming contribution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035082_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where under <ref>section 3</ref> of the Civil Liability (Contribution) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap377">Cap. 377</ref>) any person becomes entitled to a right to recover contribution in respect of any damage from any other person, no action to recover contribution by virtue of that right shall (subject to <ref>sections 22</ref> and <ref>26</ref>) be brought after the end of the period of 2 years from the date on which that right accrued.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035082_012" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section the date on which a right to recover
                contribution in respect of any damage accrues to any person (in this subsection
                referred to as
                    <term>the
                    relevant
                date</term>)
                shall be ascertained as follows, that is to say—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412035098_005" name="a" temporalId="s6_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if the person in question is held liable in respect of that damage by a
                    judgment given in any civil proceedings, or an award made on any arbitration,
                    the relevant date shall be the date on which the judgment is given, or the date
                    of the award, as the case may be;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412035098_013" name="b" temporalId="s6_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if, in any case not falling within paragraph (a), the person in question
                    makes or agrees to make any payment to one or more persons in compensation for
                    that damage (whether he admits any liability in respect of the damage or not),
                    the relevant date shall be the earliest date on which the amount to be paid by
                    him is agreed between him (or his representative) and the person (or each of the
                    persons, as the case may be) to whom the payment is to be made,</content></paragraph><continued>and for the purposes of this subsection no account shall be taken of any
                judgment or award given or made on appeal in so far as it varies the amount of
                damages awarded against the person in question.</continued></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/77">77 of 1984 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1978 c. 47 Sch. 1 para. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Actions to Recover
        Land
        and
        Rent</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039501_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Limitation of actions to recover land</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035129_040" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No action shall be brought by the Crown to recover any land after the
                expiration of 60 years from the date on which the right of action accrued to the
                Crown or, if it first accrued to some person through whom the Crown claims, to that
                person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035129_048" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>No action shall be brought by any other person to recover any land after the
                    expiration of 12 years from the date on which the right of action accrued to him
                    or, if it first accrued to some person through whom he claims, to that
                    person:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s7_2_proviso">Provided that, if the right of
                    action first accrued to the Crown through whom the person bringing the action
                    claims, the action may be brought at any time before the expiration of the
                    period during which the action could have been brought by the Crown, or of 12
                    years from the date on which the right of action accrued to some person other
                    than the Crown, whichever period first expires.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s.
                            5</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039517_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Accrual of right of action in case of present interests in land</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035160_011" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the person bringing an action to recover land, or some person through whom he claims, has been in possession thereof, and has while entitled thereto been dispossessed or discontinued his possession, the right of action shall be deemed to have accrued on the date of the dispossession or discontinuance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035160_019" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any person brings an action to recover any land of a deceased person, whether under a will or on intestacy, and the deceased person was on the date of his death in possession of the land or, in the case of a rentcharge created by will or taking effect upon his death, in possession of the land charged, and was the last person entitled to the land to be in possession thereof, the right of action shall be deemed to have accrued on the date of his death.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035176_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where any person brings an action to recover land, being an estate or interest in possession assured otherwise than by will to him, or to some person through whom he claims by a person who, at the date when the assurance took effect, was in possession of the land or, in the case of a rentcharge created by the assurance, in possession of the land charged, and no person has been in possession of the land by virtue of the assurance, the right of action shall be deemed to have accrued on the date when the assurance took effect.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 5 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039517_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Accrual of right of action in case of future interests</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035207_019" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject as hereafter provided in this section the right of action to recover any land shall, in a case where the estate or interest claimed was an estate or interest in reversion or remainder or any other future estate or interest and no person has taken possession of the land by virtue of the estate or interest claimed, be deemed to have accrued on the date on which the estate or interest fell into possession by the determination of the preceding estate or interest.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035223_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>If the person entitled to the preceding estate or interest, not being a term of years absolute, was not in possession of the land on the date of the determination thereof, no action shall be brought by the person entitled to the succeeding estate or interest after the expiration of 12 years from the date on which the right of action accrued to the person entitled to the preceding estate or interest, or 6 years from the date on which the right of action accrued to the person entitled to the succeeding estate or interest, whichever period last expires:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_2_proviso">Provided that, where the Crown is entitled to the succeeding estate or interest, the foregoing provisions of this subsection shall have effect with the substitution for the reference to 12 years of a reference to 60 years, and for the reference to 6 years of a reference to 12 years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1968/ln100">L.N. 100 of 1968</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035223_019" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No person shall bring an action to recover any estate or interest in land under an assurance taking effect after the right of action to recover the land had accrued to the person by whom the assurance was made or some person through whom he claimed or some person entitled to a preceding estate or interest, unless the action is brought within the period during which the person by whom the assurance was made could have brought such an action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035238_005" name="4" temporalId="s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where any person is entitled to any estate or interest in land in possession and, while so entitled, is also entitled to any future estate or interest in that land, and his right to recover the estate or interest in possession is barred under this Ordinance, no action shall be brought by that person, or by any person claiming through him, in respect of the future estate or interest, unless in the meantime possession of the land has been recovered by a person entitled to an intermediate estate or interest.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 6 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039532_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Provisions in case of land held on trust</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035269_041" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 20(1)</ref>, the provisions of this Ordinance shall apply to equitable interests in land, including interests in the proceeds of the sale of land held upon trust for sale, in like manner as they apply to legal estates, and accordingly a right of action to recover the land shall, for the purposes of this Ordinance but not otherwise, be deemed to accrue to a person entitled in possession to such an equitable interest in the like manner and circumstances and on the same date as it would accrue if his interest were a legal estate in the land.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035301_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where any land is held upon trust, including a trust for sale, and the period prescribed by this Ordinance has expired for the bringing of an action to recover the land by the trustees, the estate of the trustees shall not be extinguished if and so long as the right of action to recover the land of any person entitled to a beneficial interest in the land or in the proceeds of sale either has not accrued or has not been barred by this Ordinance, but if and when every such right of action has been so barred, the estate of the trustee shall be extinguished.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035316_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where land is held upon trust, including a trust for sale, an action to recover the land may be brought by the trustees on behalf of any person entitled to a beneficial interest in possession in the land or in the proceeds of sale whose right of action has not been barred by this Ordinance, notwithstanding that the right of action of the trustees would apart from this provision have been barred by this Ordinance.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 7 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039548_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Accrual of right of action in case of forfeiture or breach of condition</heading><leadIn>A right of action to recover land by virtue of a forfeiture or breach of condition shall be deemed to have accrued on the date on which the forfeiture was incurred or the condition broken:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s11_proviso">Provided that, if such a right has accrued to a person entitled to an estate or interest in reversion or remainder and the land was not recovered by virtue thereof, the right of action to recover the land shall not be deemed to have accrued to that person until his estate or interest fell into possession, as if no such forfeiture or breach of condition had occurred.</proviso><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 8 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039548_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Accrual of right of action in case of certain tenancies</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035363_011" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A tenancy at will shall, for the purposes of this Ordinance, be deemed to be
                determined at the expiration of a period of 1 year from the commencement thereof,
                unless it has previously been determined, and accordingly the right of action of the
                person entitled to the land subject to the tenancy shall be deemed to have accrued
                on the date of such determination.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035363_019" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>A tenancy from year to year or other period, without a lease in writing,
                    shall, for the purposes of this Ordinance, be deemed to be determined at the
                    expiration of the first year or other period, and accordingly the right of
                    action of the person entitled to the land subject to the tenancy shall be deemed
                    to have accrued at the date of such determination:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s12_2_proviso">Provided that, where any rent has
                    subsequently been received in respect of the tenancy, the right of action shall
                    be deemed to have accrued on the date of the last receipt of rent.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035379_004" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where any person is in possession of land by virtue of a lease in writing by
                which a rent of not less than $20 is reserved, and the rent is received by some
                person wrongfully claiming to be entitled to the land in reversion immediately
                expectant on the determination of the lease, and no rent is subsequently received by
                the person rightfully so entitled, the right of action of the last-named person to
                recover the land shall be deemed to have accrued at the date when the rent was first
                received by the person wrongfully claiming as aforesaid and not at the date of the
                determination of the lease.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035394_005" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subsections (1) and (3) shall not apply to any tenancy at will or lease granted
                by the Government.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/29">29 of 1998 s. 105</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 9 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039564_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Right of action not to accrue or continue unless there is adverse possession</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035410_048" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No right of action to recover land shall be deemed to accrue unless the land is
                in the possession of some person in whose favour the period of limitation can run
                (hereafter in this section referred to as
                    <term>adverse
                    possession</term>) and where under the foregoing provisions of this Ordinance
                any such right of action is deemed to accrue on a certain date and no person is in
                adverse possession on that date, the right of action shall not be deemed to accrue
                unless and until adverse possession is taken of the land.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035425_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a right of action to recover land has accrued and thereafter, before the right is barred, the land ceases to be in adverse possession, the right of action shall no longer be deemed to have accrued and no fresh right of action shall be deemed to accrue unless and until the land is again taken in adverse possession.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035441_005" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412035441_013" name="a" temporalId="s13_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>possession of any land subject to a rentcharge by a person (other than the person entitled to the rentcharge) who does not pay the rent shall be deemed to be adverse possession of the rentcharge; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412035441_021" name="b" temporalId="s13_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>receipt of rent under a lease by a person wrongfully claiming, in accordance with <ref>section 12(3)</ref>, the land in reversion shall be deemed to be adverse possession of the land.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 10 U.K.]</referenceNote></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039579_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Limitation of redemption actions</heading><content>When a mortgagee of land has been in possession of any of the mortgaged land for a period of 12 years, no action to redeem the land of which the mortgagee has been so in possession shall thereafter be brought by the mortgagor or any person claiming through him.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 12 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039579_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>No right of action to be preserved by formal entry or continual claim</heading><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, no person shall be deemed to have been in possession of any land by reason only of having made a formal entry thereon, and no continual or other claim upon or near any land shall preserve any right of action to recover the land.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 13 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039595_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Administration to date back to death</heading><content>For the purposes of the provisions of this Ordinance relating to actions for the recovery of land, an administrator of the estate of a deceased person shall be deemed to claim as if there had been no interval of time between the death of the deceased person and the grant of the letters of administration.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 15 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039595_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Extinction of title after expiration of period</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 10</ref>, at the expiration of the period prescribed by this Ordinance for any person to bring an action to recover land (including a redemption action), the title of that person to the land shall be extinguished.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 16 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039610_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Limitation of actions to recover rent</heading><content>No action shall be brought, or distress made, to recover arrears of rent, or damages in respect thereof, after the expiration of 6 years from the date on which the arrears became due.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 17 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Actions to
        Recover
        Money
        Secured
        by a
        Mortgage
        or
        Charge
        or
        to<br></br>Recover
        Proceeds
        of the
        Sale
        of
        Land</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039626_001" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Limitation of action to recover money secured by a mortgage or charge or to recover
            proceeds of the sale of land</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035535_018" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No action shall be brought to recover any principal sum of money secured by a
                mortgage or other charge on property, or to recover proceeds of the sale of land,
                after the expiration of 12 years from the date when the right to receive the money
                    accrued.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035535_026" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>No foreclosure action in respect of mortgaged personal property shall be
                    brought after the expiration of 12 years from the date on which the right to
                    foreclose accrued:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s19_2_proviso">Provided that if, after that date
                    the mortgagee was in possession of the mortgaged property, the right to
                    foreclose on the property which was in his possession shall not, for the
                    purposes of this subsection, be deemed to have accrued until the date on which
                    his possession
                    discontinued.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035535_040" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The right to receive any principal sum of money secured by a mortgage or other
                charge and the right to foreclose on the property subject to the mortgage or charge
                shall not be deemed to accrue so long as that property comprises any future interest
                or any life insurance policy which has not matured or been determined.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035550_005" name="4" temporalId="s19_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall apply to a foreclosure action in respect of
                mortgaged land, but the provisions of this Ordinance relating to actions to recover
                land shall apply to such an action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035550_013" name="5" temporalId="s19_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>
                <leadIn>No action to recover arrears of interest payable in respect of any sum of
                    money secured by a mortgage or other charge or payable in respect of proceeds of
                    the sale of land, or to recover damages in respect of such arrears, shall be
                    brought after the expiration of 6 years from the date on which the interest
                    became due:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s19_5_proviso">
                    <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412035550_028" name="a" temporalId="s19_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where a prior mortgagee or other incumbrancer has been in
                            possession of the property charged, and an action is brought within 1
                            year of the discontinuance of such possession by the subsequent
                            incumbrancer, he may recover by that action all the arrears of interest
                            which fell due during the period of possession by the prior incumbrancer
                            or damages in respect thereof, notwithstanding that the period exceeded
                            6 years;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412035566_006" name="b" temporalId="s19_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where the property subject to the mortgage or charge comprises any
                            future interest or life insurance policy and it is a term of the
                            mortgage or charge that arrears of interest shall be treated as part of
                            the principal sum of money secured by the mortgage or charge, interest
                            shall not be deemed to become due before the right to receive the
                            principal sum of money has accrued or is deemed to have
                            accrued.</content></paragraph>
                </proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035566_013" name="6" temporalId="s19_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>This section shall not apply to any mortgage or charge on a ship.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 18 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Actions in respect of
        Trust
        Property
        or the Personal
        Estate
        of
        Deceased
        Persons</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039626_003" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Limitation of actions in respect of trust property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035597_055" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No period of limitation prescribed by this Ordinance shall apply to an action by
                a beneficiary under a trust, being an action—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412035613_005" name="a" temporalId="s20_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in respect of any fraud or fraudulent breach of trust to which the trustee
                    was a party or privy; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412035613_013" name="b" temporalId="s20_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to recover from the trustee trust property or the proceeds thereof in the
                    possession of the trustee, or previously received by the trustee and converted
                    to his use.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035613_020" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Subject as aforesaid, an action by a beneficiary to recover trust property
                    or in respect of any breach of trust, not being an action for which a period of
                    limitation is prescribed by any other provision of this Ordinance, shall not be
                    brought after the expiration of 6 years from the date on which the right of
                    action accrued:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s20_2_proviso">Provided that the right of action
                    shall not be deemed to have accrued to any beneficiary entitled to a future
                    interest in the trust property, until the interest fell into
                    possession.</proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035613_034" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No beneficiary as against whom there would be a good defence under this
                Ordinance shall derive any greater or other benefit from a judgment or order
                obtained by any other beneficiary than he could have obtained if he had brought the
                action and this Ordinance had been pleaded in defence.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 19 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039642_002" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Limitation of actions claiming personal estate of a deceased person</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 20(1)</ref>, no action in respect of any claim to the personal estate of a deceased person or to any share or interest in such estate, whether under a will or on intestacy, shall be brought after the expiration of 12 years from the date when the right to receive the share or interest accrued, and no action to recover arrears of interest in respect of any legacy, or damages in respect of such arrears, shall be brought after the expiration of 6 years from the date on which the interest became due.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 20 U.K.]</referenceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403039657_001" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Extension
            or Exclusion
            of
            Limitation Periods
            in
            Certain
            Cases</heading><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Disability</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039657_003" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Extension of limitation period in case of disability</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035675_011" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>
                <leadIn>If on the date when any right of action accrued for which a period of
                    limitation is prescribed by this Ordinance, the person to whom it accrued was
                    under a disability, the action may be brought at any time before the expiration
                    of 6 years from the date when the person ceased to be under a disability or
                    died, whichever event first occurred, notwithstanding that the period of
                    limitation had expired:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s22_1_proviso">
                    <leadIn>Provided that—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412035675_026" name="a" temporalId="s22_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>this section shall not affect any case where the right of action
                            first accrued to some person (not under a disability) through whom the
                            person under a disability claims;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412035675_034" name="b" temporalId="s22_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>when a right of action which has accrued to a person under a
                            disability accrues, on the death of that person while still under a
                            disability, to another person under disability, no further extension of
                            time shall be allowed by reason of the disability of the second
                                person;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1968/ln100">L.N. 100 of
                            1968</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412035675_042" name="c" temporalId="s22_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>no action to recover land or money charged on land shall be brought
                            by virtue of this section by any person after the expiration of 30 years
                            from the date on which the right of action accrued to that person or
                            some person through whom he claims;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412035691_006" name="d" temporalId="s22_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>this section shall not apply to any action to recover a penalty or
                            forfeiture, or sum by way thereof, by virtue of any Ordinance or
                            imperial enactment, except where the action is brought by an aggrieved
                            party.</content></paragraph>
                </proviso>
            </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035691_013" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the action is one to which <ref>section 27</ref> or <ref>28(3)</ref> applies
                subsection (1) shall have effect as if for the words “6 years” there were
                substituted the words “3 years”.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1975
                    c. 54 s. 2 U.K.]</referenceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035691_021" name="2A" temporalId="s22_2A"><num value="2A">(2A)</num><content>Where this section applies by virtue of <ref>section 6</ref>, subsection (1)
                shall have effect as if for the words “6 years” there were substituted the words “2
                    years”.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035691_029" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of this section and <ref>section 22A</ref>, a person shall be
                deemed to be under a disability while he is an infant or of unsound mind, and,
                without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing provisions of this subsection,
                a person shall be conclusively presumed to be of unsound mind while he is detained
                in pursuance of any Ordinance or imperial enactment authorizing the detention of
                persons of unsound mind, including persons convicted of offences or awaiting trial,
                or while he is receiving treatment voluntarily under the provisions of the Mental
                Health Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap136">Cap. 136</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s.
                    10</ref>)</sourceNote></content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 ss. 22 &amp; 31(2) &amp; (3) U.K.; 1954 c. 36 s. 2(2)
                U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039673_002" name="s22A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s22A"><num value="22A">22A.</num><heading>Extension for cases where the limitation period is the period under <ref>section 31(4)(b)</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035769_004" name="1" temporalId="s22A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (2), if in the case of any action for which a period of limitation is prescribed by <ref>section 31</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412035769_012" name="a" temporalId="s22A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the period applicable in accordance with <ref>section 31(4)</ref> is the period mentioned in <ref>section 31(4)(b)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412035784_006" name="b" temporalId="s22A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on the date which is for the purposes of that section the date of knowledge, the person by reference to whose knowledge that date fell to be determined under <ref>section 31(1)</ref> was under a disability; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412035784_014" name="c" temporalId="s22A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content><ref>section 22</ref> does not apply to the action,</content></paragraph><continued>the action may be brought at any time before the expiration of 3 years from the date when he ceased to be under a disability or died (whichever first occurred) notwithstanding that the period mentioned above has expired.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035800_004" name="2" temporalId="s22A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An action may not be brought by virtue of subsection (1) after the end of the period of limitation prescribed by <ref>section 32</ref>.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1980 c. 58 s. 28A U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Acknowledgment and
        Part
        Payment</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039688_002" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Fresh accrual of action on acknowledgment or part payment</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035815_025" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where there has accrued any right of action (including a foreclosure action) to
                recover land or any right of a mortgagee of personal property to bring a foreclosure
                action in respect of the property, and—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412035815_033" name="a" temporalId="s23_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the person in possession of the land or personal property acknowledges the
                    title of the person to whom the right of action has accrued; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412035815_041" name="b" temporalId="s23_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a foreclosure or other action by a mortgagee, the person in
                    possession as aforesaid or the person liable for the mortgage debt makes any
                    payment in respect thereof, whether of principal or interest,</content></paragraph><continued>the right shall be deemed to have accrued on and not before the date of the
                acknowledgment or payment.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1968/ln100">L.N. 100 of 1968</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035831_011" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a mortgagee is by virtue of the mortgage in possession of any mortgaged
                land and either receives any sum in respect of the principal or interest of the
                mortgage debt or acknowledges the title of the mortgagor, or his equity of
                redemption, an action to redeem the land in his possession may be brought at any
                time before the expiration of 12 years from the date of the payment or
                acknowledgment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035831_019" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Where any right of action has accrued to recover any debt or other
                    liquidated pecuniary claim, or any claim to the personal estate of a deceased
                    person or to any share or interest therein, and the person liable or accountable
                    therefor acknowledges the claim or makes any payment in respect thereof, the
                    right shall be deemed to have accrued on and not before the date of the
                    acknowledgment or the last payment:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s23_3_proviso">Provided that a payment of a part
                    of the rent or interest due at any time shall not extend the period for claiming
                    the remainder then due, but any payment of interest shall be treated as a
                    payment in respect of the principal debt.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1982/ln346">L.N. 346 of
                            1982</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 23 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039704_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Formal provisions as to acknowledgments and part payments</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035862_011" name="1" temporalId="s24_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every such acknowledgment as aforesaid shall be in writing and signed by the person making the acknowledgment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035862_019" name="2" temporalId="s24_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any such acknowledgment or payment as aforesaid may be made by the agent of the person by whom it is required to be made under <ref>section 23</ref>, and shall be made to the person, or to an agent of the person, whose title or claim is being acknowledged or, as the case may be, in respect of whose claim the payment is being made.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 24 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403039720_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Effect of acknowledgment or part payment on persons other than the maker or recipient</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035878_026" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An acknowledgment of the title to any land or mortgaged personalty by any person in possession thereof shall bind all other persons in possession during the ensuing period of limitation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035893_005" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A payment in respect of a mortgage debt by the mortgagor or any person in possession of the mortgaged property shall, so far as any right of the mortgagee to foreclose or otherwise to recover the property is concerned, bind all other persons in possession of the mortgaged property during the ensuing period of limitation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035893_013" name="3" temporalId="s25_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where 2 or more mortgagees are by virtue of the mortgage in possession of the mortgaged land, an acknowledgment of the mortgagor’s title or of his equity of redemption by one of the mortgagees shall bind only him and his successors and shall not bind any other mortgagee or his successors, and where the mortgagee by whom the acknowledgment is given is entitled to a part of the mortgaged land and not to any ascertained part of the mortgage debt, the mortgagor shall be entitled to redeem that part of the land on payment, with interest, of the part of the mortgage debt which bears the same proportion to the whole of the debt as the value of the part of the land bears to the whole of the mortgaged land.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035925_005" name="4" temporalId="s25_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where there are 2 or more mortgagors, and the title or right to redemption of one of the mortgagors is acknowledged as aforesaid, the acknowledgment shall be deemed to have been made to all the mortgagors.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035925_013" name="5" temporalId="s25_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content><leadIn>An acknowledgment of any debt or other liquidated pecuniary claim shall bind the acknowledgor and his successors but not any other person:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s25_5_proviso">Provided that an acknowledgment made after the expiration of the period of limitation prescribed for the bringing of an action to recover the debt or other claim shall not bind any successor on whom the liability devolves on the determination of a preceding estate or interest in property under a settlement taking effect before the date of the acknowledgment.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035925_027" name="6" temporalId="s25_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content><leadIn>A payment made in respect of any debt or other liquidated pecuniary claim shall bind all persons liable in respect thereof:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s25_6_proviso">Provided that a payment made after the expiration of the period of limitation prescribed for the bringing of an action to recover the debt or other claim shall not bind any person other than the person making the payment and his successors, and shall not bind any successor on whom the liability devolves on the determination of a preceding estate or interest in property under a settlement taking effect before the date of the payment.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035940_004" name="7" temporalId="s25_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>An acknowledgment by one of several personal representatives of any claim to the personal estate of a deceased person, or to any share or interest therein, or a payment by one of several personal representatives in respect of any such claim shall bind the estate of the deceased person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412035940_012" name="8" temporalId="s25_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><def name="Successor">In this section the expression
                    <term>successor</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">繼承人</term>), in relation to any mortgagee or person
                liable in respect of any debt or claim, means his personal representatives and any
                other person on whom the rights under the mortgage or, as the case may be, the
                liability in respect of the debt or claim devolve, whether on death or bankruptcy or
                the disposition of property or the determination of a limited estate or interest in
                settled property or otherwise.</def><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 25 U.K.]</referenceNote></subsection></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Fraud,
        Concealment
        and
        Mistake</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039720_003" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Postponement of limitation period in case of fraud, concealment or
            mistake</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412035987_033" name="1" temporalId="s26_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (4), where in the case of any action for which a period of
                limitation is prescribed by this Ordinance, either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412035987_041" name="a" temporalId="s26_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the action is based upon the fraud of the defendant;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412035987_049" name="b" temporalId="s26_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any fact relevant to the plaintiff’s right of action has been deliberately
                    concealed from him by the defendant; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036003_006" name="c" temporalId="s26_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the action is for relief from the consequences of a mistake,</content></paragraph><continued>the period of limitation shall not begin to run until the plaintiff has
                discovered the fraud, concealment or mistake (as the case may be) or could with
                reasonable diligence have discovered it.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036003_019" name="2" temporalId="s26_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>References in subsection (1) to the defendant include references to the
                defendant’s agent and to any person through whom the defendant claims and his
                agent.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036003_027" name="3" temporalId="s26_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (1), deliberate commission of a breach of duty
                in circumstances in which it is unlikely to be discovered for some time amounts to
                deliberate concealment of the facts involved in that breach of duty.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036003_035" name="4" temporalId="s26_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Nothing in this section shall enable any action—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036003_043" name="a" temporalId="s26_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to recover, or recover the value of, any property; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036003_051" name="b" temporalId="s26_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to enforce any charge against, or set aside any transaction affecting,
                    any
                    property,</content></paragraph><continued>to be brought against the purchaser of the property or any person claiming
                through him in any case where the property has been purchased for valuable
                consideration by an innocent third party since the fraud or concealment or (as the
                case may be) the transaction in which the mistake was made took place.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036003_064" name="5" temporalId="s26_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>A purchaser is an innocent third party for the purposes of this
                section—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036018_006" name="a" temporalId="s26_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of fraud or concealment of any fact relevant to the plaintiff’s
                    right of action, if he was not a party to the fraud or (as the case may be) to
                    the concealment of that fact and did not at the time of the purchase know or
                    have reason to believe that the fraud or concealment had taken place;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036018_014" name="b" temporalId="s26_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of mistake, if he did not at the time of the purchase know or
                    have reason to believe that the mistake had been made.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036018_021" name="6" temporalId="s26_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content><ref>Sections 31</ref> and <ref>32</ref> shall not apply to any action to which
                subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref> applies (and accordingly the period of limitation
                referred to in that subsection, in any case to which either of those sections would
                otherwise apply, is the period applicable under <ref>section 4(1)</ref>).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 12</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1980 c. 58 s. 32 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Special
        Provisions
        Applicable
        to
        Certain Actions
        in
        respect of
        Personal
        Injuries</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039735_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Time limit for personal injuries</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036065_018" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies to any action for damages for negligence, nuisance or
                breach of duty (whether the duty exists by virtue of a contract or of provision made
                by or under an Ordinance or imperial enactment or independently of any contract or
                any such provision) where the damages claimed by the plaintiff for the negligence,
                nuisance or breach of duty consist of or include damages in respect of personal
                injuries to the plaintiff or any other person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036065_026" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Section 4</ref> shall not apply to an action to which this section
                applies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036081_005" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to <ref>section 30</ref>, an action to which this section applies shall
                not be brought after the expiration of the period specified in subsections (4) and
                (5).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036081_013" name="4" temporalId="s27_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Except where subsection (5) applies, the said period is 3 years from—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036081_021" name="a" temporalId="s27_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the date on which the cause of action accrued; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036081_029" name="b" temporalId="s27_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the date (if later) of the plaintiff’s knowledge.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036081_036" name="5" temporalId="s27_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>If the person injured dies before the expiration of the period in subsection
                (4), the period as respects the cause of action surviving for the benefit of the
                estate of the deceased by virtue of <ref>section 20</ref> of the Law Amendment and
                Reform (Consolidation) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap23">Cap. 23</ref>) shall be 3
                years from—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036081_044" name="a" temporalId="s27_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the date of death; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036081_052" name="b" temporalId="s27_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the date of the personal representative’s knowledge,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the later.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036081_065" name="6" temporalId="s27_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>In this section, and in <ref>section 28</ref>, references to a person’s date of
                knowledge are references to the date on which he first had knowledge of the
                following facts—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036081_073" name="a" temporalId="s27_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the injury in question was significant; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036081_081" name="b" temporalId="s27_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that that injury was attributable in whole or in part to the act or
                    omission which is alleged to constitute negligence, nuisance or breach of duty;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036096_006" name="c" temporalId="s27_6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the identity of the defendant; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036096_014" name="d" temporalId="s27_6_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if it is alleged that the act or omission was that of a person other than
                    the defendant, the identity of that person and the additional facts supporting
                    the bringing of an action against the defendant,</content></paragraph><continued>and knowledge that any acts or omissions did or did not, as a matter of law,
                involve negligence, nuisance or breach of duty is irrelevant.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036096_027" name="7" temporalId="s27_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>For the purposes of this section an injury is significant if the plaintiff
                would reasonably have considered it sufficiently serious to justify his instituting
                proceedings for damages against a defendant who did not dispute liability and was
                able to satisfy a judgment.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036096_035" name="8" temporalId="s27_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section and <ref>section 28</ref> a person’s knowledge
                includes knowledge which he might reasonably have been expected to acquire—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036096_043" name="a" temporalId="s27_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>from facts observable or ascertainable by him; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036096_051" name="b" temporalId="s27_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>from facts ascertainable by him with the help of medical or other
                    appropriate expert advice which it is reasonable for him to seek,</content></paragraph><continued>but a person shall not be fixed under this subsection with knowledge of a
                fact ascertainable only with the help of expert advice so long as he has taken all
                reasonable steps to obtain (and, where appropriate, to act on) that
                advice.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036112_011" name="9" temporalId="s27_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><def name="PersonalRepresentative">For the purposes of this section
                    <term>personal
                    representative</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">遺產代理人</term>) includes any person who is or has
                been a personal representative of the deceased, including an executor who has not
                proved the will (whether or not he has renounced probate); and regard shall be had
                to any knowledge acquired by any such person while a personal representative or
                previously.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036112_018" name="10" temporalId="s27_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>If there is more than one personal representative, and their dates of knowledge
                are different, subsection <ref>(5)(b)</ref> shall be read as referring to the
                earliest of those dates.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1975 c. 54 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039751_002" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Time limit for actions under Fatal Accidents
            Ordinance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036159_004" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section has effect subject to <ref>section 30</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036159_012" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An action under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap.
                    22</ref>) shall not be brought if the death occurred when the person injured
                could no longer maintain an action and recover damages in respect of the injury
                (whether because of a time limit in this Ordinance or in any other Ordinance, or any
                other reason); and where any such action by the injured person would have been
                barred by the time limit in <ref>section 27</ref>, no account shall be taken of the
                possibility of that time limit being overridden under <ref>section
                30</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036174_005" name="3" temporalId="s28_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>An action under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap.
                    22</ref>) shall not be brought after the expiration of 3 years from—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036174_013" name="a" temporalId="s28_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the date of death; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036174_021" name="b" temporalId="s28_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the date of knowledge of the person for whose benefit the action is
                    brought,</content></paragraph><continued>whichever is the later.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036174_034" name="4" temporalId="s28_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subsection (3) shall not apply to an action for which a period of limitation is
                prescribed by or under any Ordinance other than this Ordinance, and <ref>section
                    27</ref> shall not apply to an action under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036190_005" name="5" temporalId="s28_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>An action under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap.
                    22</ref>) shall be one to which <ref>section 22</ref> applies, but otherwise
                    <ref>sections 22 to 26</ref>, inclusive, and Part IV shall not apply to the
                    action.<inline class="width_3"> </inline></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1975 c. 54 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039766_001" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Dependants subject to different time limits</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036221_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>This section applies where there is more than one person for whose benefit an action under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>) is brought.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036221_012" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><ref>Section 28(3)(b)</ref> shall be applied separately to each of them, and if that would debar one or more of them, but not all, the court shall direct that any person who would be so debarred shall be excluded from those for whom the action is brought unless it is shown that if the action were brought exclusively for the benefit of that person it would not be defeated by a defence of limitation (whether in consequence of <ref>section 22</ref>, or an agreement between the parties not to raise the defence, or otherwise).</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1975 c. 54 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039766_003" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Court’s power to override time limits</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036252_004" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If it appears to the court that it would be equitable to allow an action to proceed having regard to the degree to which—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/ln307">L.N. 307 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036252_012" name="a" temporalId="s30_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the provisions of <ref>section 27</ref> or <ref>28</ref> prejudice the plaintiff or any person whom he represents; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036252_020" name="b" temporalId="s30_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any decision of the court under this subsection would prejudice the defendant or any person whom he represents,</content></paragraph><continued>the court may direct that those provisions shall not apply to the action, or shall not apply to any specified cause of action to which the action relates.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036252_033" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The court shall not under this section disapply <ref>section 28(2)</ref> except where the reason why the person injured could no longer maintain an action was because of the time limit in <ref>section 27</ref>; so that if, for example, the person injured could at his death no longer maintain an action under the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>) because of the time limit under the Carriage by Air Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap500">Cap. 500</ref>), the court has no power to direct that <ref>section 28(2)</ref> shall not apply.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/13">13 of 1997 s. 20</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036268_005" name="3" temporalId="s30_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>In acting under this section the court shall have regard to all the circumstances of the case and in particular to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036268_013" name="a" temporalId="s30_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the length of, and the reasons for, the delay on the part of the plaintiff;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036268_021" name="b" temporalId="s30_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the extent to which, having regard to the delay, the evidence adduced or likely to be adduced by the plaintiff or the defendant is or is likely to be less cogent than if the action had been brought within the time allowed by <ref>section 27</ref> or <ref>28</ref>, as the case may be;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036283_006" name="c" temporalId="s30_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the conduct of the defendant after the cause of action arose, including the extent, if any, to which he responded to requests reasonably made by the plaintiff for information or inspection for the purpose of ascertaining facts which were or might be relevant to the plaintiff’s cause of action against the defendant;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036283_014" name="d" temporalId="s30_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the duration of any disability of the plaintiff arising after the date of the accrual of the cause of action;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036283_022" name="e" temporalId="s30_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the extent to which the plaintiff acted promptly and reasonably once he knew whether or not the act or omission of the defendant, to which the injury was attributable, might be capable at that time of giving rise to an action for damages;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036299_006" name="f" temporalId="s30_3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the steps, if any taken by the plaintiff to obtain medical, legal or other expert advice and the nature of any such advice he may have received.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036299_013" name="4" temporalId="s30_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In a case where the person injured died when, because of <ref>section 27</ref>, he could no longer maintain an action and recover damages in respect of the injury, the court shall have regard in particular to the length of, and the reasons for, the delay on the part of the deceased.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036299_021" name="5" temporalId="s30_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In a case under subsection (4), or any other case where the time limit, or one of the time limits, depends on the date of knowledge of a person other than the plaintiff, subsection (3) shall have effect with appropriate modifications, and shall have effect in particular as if references to the plaintiff included references to any person whose date of knowledge is or was relevant in determining a time limit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036315_005" name="6" temporalId="s30_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>A direction by the court disapplying the provisions of <ref>section 28(2)</ref> shall operate to disapply the provisions to the same effect in <ref>section 3</ref> of the Fatal Accidents Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap22">Cap. 22</ref>).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036315_013" name="7" temporalId="s30_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><def name="TheCourt">In this section
                    <term>the
                    court</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">法院</term>) means the court in which the action has
                been brought.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036315_020" name="8" temporalId="s30_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>References in this section to <ref>section 27</ref> include references to that section as extended by any provision of this Part and Part IV.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1975 c. 54 s. 1 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><crossHeading class="tied-tag-crossHeading-center add-toc">Actions in respect of
        Latent Damage
        not
        Involving
        Personal
        Injuries</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438403039782_002" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Special time limit for negligence actions where facts relevant to cause of action
            are not known at date of accrual</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036361_018" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>This section applies to any action for damages for negligence, other than one to
                which <ref>section 27</ref> applies, where the earliest date on which the plaintiff
                or any person in whom the cause of action was vested before him first had
                both—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036361_026" name="a" temporalId="s31_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the knowledge required for bringing an action for damages in respect of the
                    relevant damage; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036361_034" name="b" temporalId="s31_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a right to bring such an action,</content></paragraph><continued>(referred to in this section as the
                    <term>date
                    of
                knowledge</term>)
                falls after the date on which the cause of action accrued.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036377_004" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The period of limitation prescribed by <ref>section 4(1)</ref> in respect of
                actions founded on tort shall not apply to an action to which this section
                applies.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036377_012" name="3" temporalId="s31_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>An action to which this section applies shall not be brought after the
                expiration of the period applicable in accordance with subsection (4).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036377_020" name="4" temporalId="s31_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>That period is either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036377_028" name="a" temporalId="s31_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>6 years from the date on which the cause of action accrued; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036377_036" name="b" temporalId="s31_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>3 years from the date of knowledge, if that period expires later than the
                    period mentioned in paragraph (a).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036377_043" name="5" temporalId="s31_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="TheKnowledgeRequiredForBringingAnActionForDamagesInRespectOfTheRelevantDamage">
                <leadIn>In subsection (1)
                        <term>the
                        knowledge required for bringing an action for damages in respect of the
                        relevant
                    damage</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">就有關損害而提出損害賠償訴訟所需的知悉</term>) means
                    knowledge—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412036377_051" name="a" temporalId="s31_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>of such facts about the damage in respect of which damages are claimed
                        as would lead a reasonable person who had suffered such damage to consider
                        it sufficiently serious to justify his instituting proceedings for damages
                        against a defendant who did not dispute liability and was able to satisfy a
                        judgment;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412036393_006" name="b" temporalId="s31_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that the damage was attributable in whole or in part to the act or
                        omission which is alleged to constitute negligence;</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412036393_014" name="c" temporalId="s31_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>of the identity of the defendant; and</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412036393_022" name="d" temporalId="s31_5_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>if it is alleged that the act or omission was that of a person other
                        than the defendant, of the identity of that person and the additional facts
                        supporting the bringing of an action against the defendant.</content></paragraph>
            </def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036393_029" name="6" temporalId="s31_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Knowledge that any acts or omissions did or did not, as a matter of law,
                involve negligence is irrelevant for the purposes of subsection (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036393_037" name="7" temporalId="s31_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section or <ref>section 33</ref> a person’s knowledge
                includes knowledge which he might reasonably have been expected to acquire—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036393_045" name="a" temporalId="s31_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>from facts observable or ascertainable by him; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036393_053" name="b" temporalId="s31_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>from facts ascertainable by him with the help of appropriate expert advice
                    which it is reasonable for him to seek,</content></paragraph><continued>but a person shall not be taken by virtue of this subsection or <ref>section
                    33</ref> to have knowledge of a fact ascertainable only with the help of expert
                advice so long as he has taken all reasonable steps to obtain (and, where
                appropriate, to act on) that advice.</continued></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 13</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1980 c. 58 s. 14A U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039798_002" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Overriding time limit for negligence actions not involving personal injuries</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036439_004" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An action for damages for negligence, other than one to which <ref>section 27</ref> applies, shall not be brought after the expiration of 15 years from the date (or, if more than one, from the last of the dates) on which there occurred any act or omission—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036439_012" name="a" temporalId="s32_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>which is alleged to constitute negligence; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036439_020" name="b" temporalId="s32_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to which the damage in respect of which damages are claimed is alleged to be attributable (in whole or in part).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036439_027" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>This section bars the right of action in a case to which subsection (1) applies notwithstanding that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036439_035" name="a" temporalId="s32_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the cause of action has not yet accrued; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036439_043" name="b" temporalId="s32_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where <ref>section 31</ref> applies to the action, the date which is for the purposes of that section the date of knowledge has not yet occurred,</content></paragraph><continued>before the end of the period of limitation prescribed by this section.</continued></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 13</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1980 c. 58 s. 14B U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039798_004" name="s33" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403039813_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>General</heading><section id="ID_1438403039829_001" name="s34" reason="repealed" startPeriod="2011-06-01" status="repealed" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2010/17">17 of 2010 s. 112</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039829_003" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>New claims in pending actions: rules of court</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036486_004" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this Ordinance, any new claim made in the course of any
                action shall be deemed to be a separate action and to have been commenced—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036486_012" name="a" temporalId="s35_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a new claim made in or by way of third party proceedings, on
                    the date on which those proceedings were commenced; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036502_006" name="b" temporalId="s35_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of any other new claim, on the same date as the original
                    action.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036502_013" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>In this section a new claim means any claim by way of set-off or counterclaim,
                and any claim involving either—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036502_021" name="a" temporalId="s35_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the addition or substitution of a new cause of action; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036502_029" name="b" temporalId="s35_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the addition or substitution of a new party,
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/58">L.N. 446 of
                        1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued name="ThirdPartyProceedings">and
                    <term>third
                    party
                proceedings</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第三方法律程序</term>) means any proceedings brought in
                the course of any action by any party to the action against a person not previously
                a party to the action, other than proceedings brought by joining any such person as
                defendant to any claim already made in the original action by the party bringing the
                proceedings.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036502_042" name="3" temporalId="s35_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Except as provided by <ref>section 30</ref> or by rules of court, the court
                shall not allow a new claim within subsection <ref>(1)(b)</ref>, other than an
                original set-off or counterclaim, to be made in the course of any action after the
                expiry of any time limit under this Ordinance which would affect a new action to
                enforce that claim.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036517_005" name="4" temporalId="s35_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the purposes of subsection (3), a claim is an original set-off or an
                original counterclaim if it is a claim made by way of set-off or (as the case may
                be) by way of counterclaim by a party who has not previously made any claim in the
                action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036517_013" name="5" temporalId="s35_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Rules of court may provide for allowing a new claim to which subsection (3)
                applies to be made as there mentioned, but only if the conditions specified in
                subsection (6) are satisfied, and subject to any further restrictions the rules may
                impose.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036517_021" name="6" temporalId="s35_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>The conditions referred to in subsection (5) are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036517_029" name="a" temporalId="s35_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of a claim involving a new cause of action, if the new cause of
                    action arises out of the same facts or substantially the same facts as a cause
                    of action in respect of which relief has already been claimed in the action by
                    the party applying for leave to make the amendment; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036533_006" name="b" temporalId="s35_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of a claim involving a new party, if the addition or
                    substitution of the new party is necessary for the determination of the original
                    action.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036533_013" name="7" temporalId="s35_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>The addition or substitution of a new party shall not be regarded for the
                purposes of subsection <ref>(6)(b)</ref> as necessary for the determination of the
                original action unless either—
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/58">L.N. 446 of
                1994</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036533_021" name="a" temporalId="s35_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the new party is substituted for a party whose name was given in any claim
                    made in the original action in mistake for the new party’s name; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036533_029" name="b" temporalId="s35_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any claim already made in the original action cannot be maintained by or
                    against an existing party unless the new party is joined or substituted as
                    plaintiff or defendant in that action.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1984/58">L.N. 446 of
                        1994</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036533_036" name="8" temporalId="s35_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Subject to subsection (5), rules of court may provide for allowing a party to
                any action to claim relief in a new capacity in respect of a new cause of action
                notwithstanding that he had no title to make that claim at the date of the
                commencement of the action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036533_044" name="9" temporalId="s35_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Subsection (8) shall not be taken as prejudicing the power of rules of court to
                provide for allowing a party to claim relief in a new capacity without adding or
                substituting a new cause of action.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036549_005" name="10" temporalId="s35_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Subsections (3) to (9) shall apply in relation to a new claim made in the
                course of third party proceedings as if those proceedings were the original action,
                and subject to such other modifications as may be prescribed by rules of court in
                any case or class of case.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036549_013" name="11" temporalId="s35_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content>The power to make rules of court under <ref>section 54</ref> of the Supreme
                Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>) shall include power to make
                rules of court for the purposes of this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036549_021" name="12" temporalId="s35_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>Rules of court made before the
                    commencement<sup>#</sup>
                of the Limitation (Amendment) Ordinance 1984 (<ref href="/hk/1984/58">58 of
                    1984</ref>) which would have been validly made had this section been in
                operation when they were made shall have effect as from the
                    commencement<sup>#</sup>
                of the Limitation (Amendment) Ordinance 1984 (<ref href="/hk/1984/58">58 of
                    1984</ref>) as if made by virtue of this section.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1984/58">58 of 1984 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1980 c. 58 s. 35 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1589340409975_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><sup>#</sup> Commencement date: 27 July 1984.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039844_002" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Acquiescence</heading><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect any equitable jurisdiction to refuse relief on the ground of acquiescence or otherwise.</content><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 29 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039844_004" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Application to the Crown</heading><leadIn>Save as in this Ordinance otherwise expressly provided and without prejudice to the provisions of <ref>section 40</ref>, this Ordinance shall apply to proceedings by or against the Crown in like manner as it applies to proceedings between subjects:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s37_proviso">Provided that this Ordinance shall not apply to any proceedings by the Crown for the recovery of any tax or duty or interest thereon or to any forfeiture proceedings under the Dutiable Commodities Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap109">Cap. 109</ref>) or any Ordinance relating to duties of excise or to any proceedings in respect of the forfeiture of a ship.</proviso><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 30(1) U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039860_002" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Transitional provisions and provisions as to actions already barred</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036642_004" name="1" temporalId="s38_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><ref>Sections 22(2)</ref> and (2A), 27, 28, 29 and 30 shall have effect in
                relation to causes of action which accrued before, as well as causes of action which
                accrue on or after, 1 February 1977 and shall have effect in relation to any cause
                of action which accrued before 1 February 1977 notwithstanding that an action in
                respect thereof has been commenced and is pending on 1 February 1977.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of
                        1976 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036642_012" name="2" temporalId="s38_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this section an action shall not be taken to be pending at
                any time if a final order or judgment has been made or given therein,
                notwithstanding that an appeal is pending or that the time for appealing has not
                    expired.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036658_005" name="3" temporalId="s38_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A decision taken at any time by a court to grant, or not to grant, leave under
                the former <ref>sections 27 to 33</ref> inclusive (which, so far as they relate to
                leave, are repealed by the Limitation (Amendment) Ordinance 1976 (<ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976</ref>)) does not affect the determination of any
                question in proceedings under the Limitation (Amendment) Ordinance 1976 (<ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976</ref>), but in such proceedings account may be
                taken of evidence admitted in proceedings under the said sections repealed by the
                Limitation (Amendment) Ordinance 1976 (<ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of
                    1976</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s.
                    6</ref>. Amended <ref href="hk/1995/ln587">L.N. 587 of
                    1995</ref>)</sourceNote><inline class="width_3"> </inline></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036673_005" name="3A" temporalId="s38_3A"><num value="3A">(3A)</num><def name="Action">In this section
                    <term>action</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">訴訟</term>) includes any proceedings in a court of
                law, an arbitration and a claim by way of set-off or counterclaim.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976
                        s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036673_012" name="4" temporalId="s38_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Save as aforesaid, nothing in this Ordinance shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036673_020" name="a" temporalId="s38_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>affect any action or arbitration commenced before the
                        commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance or
                    the title to any property which is the subject of any such action or
                    arbitration; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036673_028" name="b" temporalId="s38_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>enable any action to be brought which, immediately before the
                        commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this Ordinance, was
                    then barred by the provision of any imperial enactment or Ordinance which ceases
                    to apply in the Colony by virtue of or, as the case may be, is repealed by
                        <ref>section 39</ref>, except in so far as the cause of action or right of
                    action may be revived by an acknowledgment or part payment made in accordance
                    with the provisions of this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><referenceNote>[cf. 1939 c. 21 s. 33
                    U.K.]</referenceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036689_005" name="5" temporalId="s38_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of <ref>section 6</ref> and subsection (4) of this
                section, the time for bringing proceedings in respect of a cause of action which
                accrued before the commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of this
                Ordinance shall, if it has not then already expired, expire at a time when it would
                have expired apart from the provisions of this Ordinance or at any time when it
                would have expired if the provisions of this Ordinance had at all material times
                been in force, whichever is the later:</leadIn><proviso>Provided that where a cause of action, for which a period of limitation is
                prescribed by this Ordinance, has accrued before the commencement of this Ordinance
                in any case in which, but for the provisions of this Ordinance, no time for bringing
                proceedings in respect thereof is limited, the time for bringing such proceedings,
                as limited by the provisions of this Ordinance, shall commence to run from the date
                of the coming into operation of this Ordinance. <referenceNote>[cf. 1954 c. 36 s.
                    7(1) U.K.]</referenceNote></proviso></subsection><referenceNote>[cf. 1975 c. 54 s. 3 U.K.]</referenceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1589340467041_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 11 June
                1965.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039876_001" name="s38A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s38A"><num value="38A">38A.</num><heading>Transitional provisions relating to 1991 amendments</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412036751_004" name="1" temporalId="s38A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The time for bringing proceedings in respect of a cause of action—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036751_012" name="a" temporalId="s38A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to recover any land;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036751_020" name="b" temporalId="s38A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to redeem mortgaged land;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036751_028" name="c" temporalId="s38A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to recover any principal sum of money secured by a mortgage or other charge on property, or to recover proceeds of the sale of land; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036751_036" name="d" temporalId="s38A_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to foreclose on mortgaged personal property,</content></paragraph><continued>which accrued before 1 July 1991 shall, if it has not then already expired, expire at the time when it would have expired apart from the provisions of the Limitation (Amendment) Ordinance 1991 (<ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991</ref>).</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036751_049" name="2" temporalId="s38A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Nothing in <ref>section 22A</ref>, <ref>31</ref> or <ref>32</ref> shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412036751_057" name="a" temporalId="s38A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>enable any action to be brought which was barred by this Ordinance before 1 July 1991; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412036751_065" name="b" temporalId="s38A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>affect any action commenced before 1 July 1991.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412036751_072" name="3" temporalId="s38A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subsection (2), <ref>sections 22A</ref>, <ref>31</ref> and <ref>32</ref> shall have effect in relation to causes of action accruing before, as well as in relation to causes of action accruing on or after, 1 July 1991.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1991/31">31 of 1991 s. 14</ref>)</sourceNote><referenceNote>[cf. 1980 c. 58 s. 4 U.K.]</referenceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403039876_003" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Cessations of application</heading><content>The imperial enactments set out in the first column of the <ref>Schedule</ref> shall, to the extent specified in the second column thereof, cease to apply in the Colony.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403039891_002" name="s40" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="s40"><num value="40">40.</num><heading>Saving</heading><content>This Ordinance shall not apply to any action or arbitration for which a period of limitation is prescribed by or under any other Ordinance or any imperial enactment, or to any action or arbitration to which the Crown is a party and for which, if it were between subjects, a period of limitation would be prescribed by or under any other enactment.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1976/67">67 of 1976 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><schedule id="ID_1438403039891_004" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-07-09" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap347/s39">s. 39</ref>]</note><heading>Cessation
            of Application
            of
            Enactments</heading><text>
            
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void">
                <col width="70%"></col>
                
                
                <col width="2%"></col>
                
                
                
                <col width="28%"></col>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <th class="align_top">
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><inline class="not_bold">Imperial enactments</inline></center>
                        </th>
                        
                        
                        <th></th>
                        
                        
                        <th class="align_top">
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><inline class="not_bold">Extent of cessation
                                    <br></br>of
                                    application</inline></center>
                        </th>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8">An Act concerning Informers (1588 c. 5
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                            5</ref></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8">The Limitation Act 1623 (1623 c. 16
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Sections
                                3</ref>, <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">4</ref>
                            and <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">7</ref></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td>An Act for the amendment of the Law and the better Advancement of
                            Justice (1705 c. 3
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Sections 17 to
                                19</ref></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8">The Crown Suits Act 1769 (1769 c. 16
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8">The whole Act</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td>The Statute of Frauds Amendment Act 1828 (1828 c. 14
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        
                        <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Sections 1</ref>,
                                <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">3</ref>, <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">4</ref> and <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">8</ref></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td>The Real Property Limitation Act 1833 (1833 c. 27
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8">The whole Act</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8">The Civil Procedure Act 1833 (1833 c. 42
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Sections 3 to
                                7</ref></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td>The Real Property Limitation Act 1837 (1837 c. 28
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8">The whole Act</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td>The Limitations of Actions and Costs Act 1842 (1842 c. 97
                            U.K.)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        
                        
                        <td></td>
                        
                        
                        <td class="first_line_indent_-12 left_indent_12 align_justified cellpadding_right_8"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                            5</ref></td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
        </text></schedule></main></ordinance>