<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 448</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>448</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap448!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2020-03-19</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403207186_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2020-03-19">
            <content>An Ordinance to repeal and re-enact with appropriate modifications certain
                provisions relating to civil aviation.</content>
            <content>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
                <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            </content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[13 May 1994]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><enactingFormula>
            <content><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of
                        2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content>
        </enactingFormula><section id="ID_1438403207201_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Civil Aviation Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403207201_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412535406_011" name="1" temporalId="s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance—</leadIn><def name="Aerodrome">
                <leadIn><term>aerodrome</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機場</term>) means any area of land or water
                    designed, equipped, set apart or commonly used for affording facilities for the
                    landing and taking off of aircraft and includes—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412535406_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any area or space, whether on the ground, on the roof of a building or
                        elsewhere, which is designed, equipped or set apart for affording facilities
                        for the landing and taking off of aircraft capable of descending or climbing
                        vertically; and</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438412535406_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any such area of land or water or any such area or space the management
                        of which is vested in the Government or in the Chief Executive,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                <continued>but does not include any area the use of which for affording facilities
                    for the landing and taking off of aircraft has been abandoned and has not been
                        resumed;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued>
            </def><def name="ChicagoConvention"><term>Chicago
                    Convention</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">《芝加哥公約》</term>)
                means the Convention on International Civil Aviation which, on 7 December 1944, was
                opened for signature at the International Civil Aviation Conference held at
                    Chicago;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s.
                    2</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of
                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Grant"><term>grant</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">批給</term>) includes issue;</def><def name="HongKongPermanentResident"><term>Hong Kong permanent
                resident</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">香港永久性居民</term>) means a person who is such a
                resident within the meaning of the Immigration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap115">Cap. 115</ref>);</def><def name="Land"><term>land</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地</term>) includes buildings and other structures,
                land covered with water, and any estate, interest, easement or right in or over
                land;</def><def name="Licence"><term>licence</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">牌照</term>) includes a permit or certificate.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535422_039" name="2" temporalId="s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="LossOrDamage">For the avoidance of doubt it is hereby declared that in this
                Ordinance
                    <term>loss or
                damage</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">損失或損毀</term>) includes, in relation to persons,
                loss of life and personal injury.</def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535422_046" name="3" temporalId="s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any reference in this Ordinance to goods includes a reference to mails and a
                reference to animals.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/28">28 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403207217_002" name="s2A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s2A"><num value="2A">2A.</num><heading>Power to give effect to Chicago Convention and regulate air navigation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412535453_004" name="1" temporalId="s2A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may by order make such provision as appears to the Chief Executive in Council to be necessary or expedient—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535453_012" name="a" temporalId="s2A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>for carrying out the Chicago Convention, any Annex thereto relating to international standards and recommended practices (being an Annex adopted in accordance with the Convention) and any amendment of the Convention or any such Annex made in accordance with the Convention;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535453_020" name="b" temporalId="s2A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>generally for regulating air navigation,</content></paragraph><continued>provided that such provision deals only with the routine business and technical management of civil aviation including—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_012" name="i" temporalId="s2A_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the management of aerodromes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_020" name="ii" temporalId="s2A_1_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the provision of air traffic services within the flight information region of Hong Kong; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_028" name="iii" temporalId="s2A_1_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the discharge of other responsibilities allocated to Hong Kong under the regional air navigation procedures of the International Civil Aviation Organization.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535469_035" name="2" temporalId="s2A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may by order make provision—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_043" name="a" temporalId="s2A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>as to the registration of aircraft in Hong Kong;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_051" name="b" temporalId="s2A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>for prohibiting aircraft from flying unless certificates of airworthiness issued or validated under the order are in force with respect to them and except upon compliance with such conditions as to maintenance or repair as may be specified either in the order or by the Chief Executive;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_059" name="c" temporalId="s2A_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>for the licensing, inspection and regulation of aerodromes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_067" name="d" temporalId="s2A_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>for access to aerodromes and places where aircraft have landed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535469_075" name="e" temporalId="s2A_2_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>for access to aircraft factories for the purpose of inspecting work therein carried on in relation to aircraft or parts thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535484_006" name="f" temporalId="s2A_2_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>for prohibiting or regulating the use of unlicensed aerodromes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535484_014" name="g" temporalId="s2A_2_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>for prohibiting persons from engaging in, or being employed in or (except in the maintenance at unlicensed aerodromes of aircraft not used for or in connection with commercial, industrial or other gainful purposes) in connection with, air navigation in such capacities as may be specified either in the order or by the Chief Executive except in accordance with provisions in that behalf contained in the order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535484_022" name="h" temporalId="s2A_2_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>for the licensing of persons employed in the inspection or supervision of aircraft at aerodromes licensed under the order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535484_030" name="i" temporalId="s2A_2_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>as to the conditions under which, and in particular the aerodromes to or from which, aircraft entering or leaving Hong Kong may fly;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535484_038" name="j" temporalId="s2A_2_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>as to the conditions under which aircraft may fly from one part of Hong Kong to another;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535500_006" name="k" temporalId="s2A_2_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><leadIn>as to the conditions under which—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535500_014" name="i" temporalId="s2A_2_k_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>passengers and goods may be carried by air; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535500_022" name="ii" temporalId="s2A_2_k_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>aircraft may be used for other commercial, industrial or gainful purposes;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535500_029" name="l" temporalId="s2A_2_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>for prohibiting the carriage by air of goods of such classes as may be specified either in the order or by the Chief Executive;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535500_037" name="m" temporalId="s2A_2_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>for minimizing or preventing interference with the use or effectiveness of apparatus used in connection with air navigation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535500_045" name="n" temporalId="s2A_2_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><leadIn>for prohibiting or regulating—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535500_053" name="i" temporalId="s2A_2_n_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the use of apparatus used in connection with air navigation; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535500_061" name="ii" temporalId="s2A_2_n_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the display of signs and lights liable to endanger aircraft;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535500_068" name="o" temporalId="s2A_2_o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content>generally for securing the safety, efficiency and regularity of air navigation and the safety of aircraft and of persons and property carried therein, for preventing aircraft endangering other persons and property and, in particular, for the detention of aircraft for any of the purposes specified in this paragraph;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535515_006" name="p" temporalId="s2A_2_p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content>for requiring persons engaged in, or employed in or in connection with, air navigation to supply meteorological information for the purposes of air navigation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535515_014" name="q" temporalId="s2A_2_q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content>for regulating the making of signals and other communications by or to aircraft and persons carried therein;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535515_022" name="r" temporalId="s2A_2_r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content>for regulating the use of the civil air ensign and any other ensign established by the Chief Executive in Council for purposes connected with air navigation;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535515_030" name="s" temporalId="s2A_2_s"><num value="s">(s)</num><content>subject to subsections (3) and (4), for prohibiting aircraft from flying over such areas in Hong Kong as may be specified either in the order or by the Chief Executive;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535515_038" name="t" temporalId="s2A_2_t"><num value="t">(t)</num><content>for applying, adapting or modifying, or enabling the Chief Executive to apply, adapt or modify, in relation to aerodromes and to aircraft and to persons and property carried therein, any law in force in Hong Kong relating to customs;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535515_046" name="u" temporalId="s2A_2_u"><num value="u">(u)</num><content>for preventing smuggling by air;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535515_054" name="v" temporalId="s2A_2_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>for permitting, or enabling the Chief Executive to permit, in connection with air navigation, subject to such conditions as appear to the Chief Executive in Council, or to the Chief Executive, as the case may be, to be necessary or expedient for the protection of the revenue, the importation of goods into Hong Kong without payment of duty;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535531_006" name="w" temporalId="s2A_2_w"><num value="w">(w)</num><content>as to the manner and conditions of the issue, validation, renewal, extension or variation of any licence or other document required by the order (including the examinations and tests to be undergone) and as to the form, custody, production, cancellation, suspension, endorsement and surrender of any such document;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535531_014" name="x" temporalId="s2A_2_x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content>subject to subsection (5), for regulating, or enabling the Chief Executive to regulate, the charges that may be made for the use of aerodromes licensed under the order and for services provided at such aerodromes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535531_022" name="y" temporalId="s2A_2_y"><num value="y">(y)</num><content>for prescribing, or enabling the Chief Executive to prescribe, the fees to be paid in respect of the issue, validation, renewal, extension or variation of any licence or other document or the undergoing of any examination or test required by, or in pursuance of, the order and in respect of any other matter in respect of which it appears to the Chief Executive in Council to be expedient for the purposes of the order to charge fees;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535547_006" name="z" temporalId="s2A_2_z"><num value="z">(z)</num><content>for exempting from the provisions of the order, or any of them, any aircraft or persons or classes of aircraft or persons.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535547_013" name="3" temporalId="s2A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>No order may be made under subsection <ref>(2)(s)</ref> for prohibiting aircraft from flying over any area in Hong Kong—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535547_021" name="a" temporalId="s2A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by reason of national defence; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535547_029" name="b" temporalId="s2A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>during a state of emergency or state of war,</content></paragraph><continued>except on an instruction of the Central People’s Government issued as described in subsection (4).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535547_042" name="4" temporalId="s2A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Where the Central People’s Government, by reason of national defence, or at any time during a state of emergency or state of war, issues an instruction to the Chief Executive—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535562_005" name="a" temporalId="s2A_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that an order be made under subsection <ref>(2)(s)</ref> in accordance with
                    the instruction;
                    or<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535562_013" name="b" temporalId="s2A_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that an order made under subsection <ref>(2)(s)</ref> be repealed or amended in accordance with the instruction,</content></paragraph><continued>then the Chief Executive in Council shall comply with that instruction.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535562_026" name="5" temporalId="s2A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>No order may be made under subsection <ref>(2)(x)</ref> for regulating, or enabling the Chief Executive to regulate, the charges that may be made in relation to any matter for which charges may be determined by the Airport Authority under <ref>section 7</ref> or <ref>34</ref> of the Airport Authority Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap483">Cap. 483</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535562_034" name="6" temporalId="s2A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>An order under this section may make different provision with respect to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535562_042" name="a" temporalId="s2A_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>different classes of aircraft, aerodromes, persons or property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535562_050" name="b" temporalId="s2A_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>different circumstances; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535578_006" name="c" temporalId="s2A_6_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>different parts of Hong Kong,</content></paragraph><continued>but shall, so far as practicable, be so framed as not to discriminate in like circumstances between aircraft registered in Hong Kong operated on charter terms by one air transport undertaking and such aircraft so operated by another air transport undertaking.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535578_019" name="7" temporalId="s2A_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>An order under this section may, for the purpose of securing compliance with the order or any regulation or other instrument made thereunder—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535578_027" name="a" temporalId="s2A_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>create offences and provide for the imposition of penalties on conviction but not exceeding a fine at level 6 or imprisonment for a term of 2 years or both such fine and such imprisonment;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535578_035" name="b" temporalId="s2A_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of any provision having effect by virtue of subsection <ref>(2)(s)</ref>, provide for the taking of such steps (including firing on aircraft) as may be specified in the order.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535578_042" name="8" temporalId="s2A_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="StateOfEmergency"><term>state of
                emergency</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">緊急狀態</term>) means a state of emergency in Hong
                Kong declared by the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress for the
                purposes of this Ordinance by reason of turmoil within Hong Kong which endangers
                national unity or security and is beyond the control of the Government of the Hong
                Kong Special Administrative Region;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="StateOfWar"><term>state of
                war</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">戰爭狀態</term>) means a state of war declared in
                accordance with the law of the People’s Republic of China.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403207248_001" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Investigation of accidents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412535687_011" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations providing for the
                investigation of any accident arising out of or in the course of air navigation and
                occurring in or over Hong Kong, or occurring elsewhere to aircraft registered in
                Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535687_019" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Regulations under this section may contain provisions—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535687_027" name="a" temporalId="s3_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>requiring notice to be given of any such accident as aforesaid in such
                    manner and by such persons as may be specified;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535687_035" name="b" temporalId="s3_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>applying, with or without modification, for the purpose of investigations
                    held with respect to any such accidents any of the provisions of any law in
                    force in Hong Kong relating to the investigation of deaths or
                    accidents;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535703_006" name="c" temporalId="s3_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>prohibiting, pending investigation, access to or interference with aircraft
                    to which an accident has occurred, and authorizing any person, so far as may be
                    necessary for the purposes of an investigation, to have access to, examine,
                    remove, take measures for the preservation of, or otherwise deal with, any such
                    aircraft or any other aircraft;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535703_014" name="d" temporalId="s3_2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>authorizing or requiring the cancellation, suspension, endorsement or
                    surrender of any licence or other document granted in Hong Kong under
                    regulations or orders made under this Ordinance or regulations specified in
                        <ref>section 13(6)</ref>, or the withdrawal or suspension of any validation
                    conferred in Hong Kong of a licence granted by a competent authority elsewhere,
                    where it appears on an investigation that the licence or other document ought to
                    be cancelled, suspended, endorsed or surrendered, or the validation withdrawn or
                    suspended, as the case may be, and requiring the production of any such licence
                    or other document for the purpose of being so dealt with. <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535718_005" name="3" temporalId="s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A person who contravenes or fails to comply with any regulation under this
                section commits a summary offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                at
                level 6, or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 3 months or
                to both such fine and such imprisonment.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403207248_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Dangerous flying</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412535749_034" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an aircraft is flown in such a manner as to be the cause of
                                unnecessary danger to any person or property on land or water, the
                                pilot or the person in charge of the aircraft, and also the owner
                                thereof unless he proves to the satisfaction of the court that the
                                aircraft was so flown without his actual fault or privity, commits a
                                summary offence and shall be liable on conviction to a fine
                                at
                                level 6, or to imprisonment for a term not
                                exceeding 6 months or to both such fine and such imprisonment.
                                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of
                                        2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535765_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><def name="Owner">In this section
                    <term>owner</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機主</term>), in relation to an aircraft used in the
                commission of an offence under subsection (1), includes any person by whom the
                aircraft is hired at the time of the offence.</def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403207264_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Air transport licensing</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412535781_033" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535796_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>to secure that aircraft shall not be used in Hong Kong by any
                    person—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535796_013" name="i" temporalId="s5_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>for flying, while carrying passengers or goods for hire or reward, on
                        such journeys or classes of journeys (whether beginning and ending at the
                        same point or at different points) as may be specified in the regulations;
                        or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535796_021" name="ii" temporalId="s5_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>for such flying undertaken for the purpose of any trade or business as
                        may be so specified,</content></subparagraph><continued>except under the authority of, and in accordance with, a licence issued
                    to the person by the authority specified in the regulations;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535796_034" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535796_037" name="i" temporalId="s5_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>as to the circumstances in which a licence under the regulations may or
                        shall be issued, refused, revoked, varied, transferred or suspended, and in
                        particular as to the matters to which the authority specified in the
                        regulations is to have regard in deciding whether to issue such a
                        licence;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535796_044" name="ii" temporalId="s5_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>enabling any such licence (as distinct from the conditions attached to
                        it), or any such licence (as so distinct) which is of a specified class or
                        description, to be varied if, subject to subparagraph (i), the authority
                        which issued the licence thinks fit, such variation to be in accordance with
                        an application in that behalf by the holder of the licence and made to that
                        authority;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535812_006" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>as to appeals by persons interested in the grant, refusal, revocation,
                    variation, transfer, or suspension of any licence under the regulations or the
                    extension of the period during which such licence is to be in force;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535812_014" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>as to the conditions which may be attached to such a licence (including
                    conditions as to the fares, freight or other charges and conditions relating to
                    specified services or specified classes of service (being in all cases services
                    to be provided in or in relation to civil aviation)), and for securing
                    compliance with any conditions so attached;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535827_006" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>as to the extension of the period during which such a licence is to be in
                    force or to variation of the conditions attached to such a licence;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535827_014" name="f" temporalId="s5_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>as to information to be furnished by an applicant for, or the holder of,
                    such a licence to such authorities as may be specified in the
                    regulations;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535827_022" name="g" temporalId="s5_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>prescribing the fees to be paid in respect of the issue or transfer of any
                    licence under the regulations, or the variation of the conditions attached to
                    such a licence or the extension of the period during which such a licence is to
                    remain in force, or enabling such fees to be fixed by any authority or other
                    person specified in that behalf by the regulations,</content></paragraph><continued>and such regulations may make different provision as respects different
                classes of aircraft and different classes of licences.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535843_004" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Regulations made under this section may, for the purpose of securing compliance
                with the regulations, create offences and provide for the imposition of the
                following penalties on conviction, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535843_012" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in the case of summary conviction, a fine not exceeding
                    level
                    6 or imprisonment for a term not exceeding 3 months or both
                    such fine and such imprisonment; and
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of
                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535843_020" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of conviction on indictment, a fine not exceeding $5,000,000 or
                    imprisonment for a term not exceeding 2 years or both such fine and such
                    imprisonment.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403207311_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Information regarding air transport undertakings and use of customs
            aerodromes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412535874_047" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Chief Executive in Council may make regulations—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412535874_055" name="a" temporalId="s6_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>requiring any person—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535890_006" name="i" temporalId="s6_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>who carries on the business of carrying passengers or goods in aircraft
                        for hire or reward on such journeys or classes of journeys (whether
                        beginning and ending at the same point or at different points) as may be
                        specified in the regulations; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412535890_014" name="ii" temporalId="s6_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>who is the holder of a licence in respect of a customs aerodrome
                        (whether the licence was issued before or after the
                        commencement*
                        of this section),</content></subparagraph><continued>to furnish to such authorities as may be specified in the regulations
                    such information relating to the use of aircraft for the purpose of his said
                    business and to the persons employed in connection with that use, or, as the
                    case may be, relating to the use of the aerodrome and to the persons employed in
                    aircraft arriving thereat or departing therefrom, as may be prescribed by the
                    regulations;</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535890_027" name="b" temporalId="s6_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>requiring the owner, or the pilot or other person in charge, of any
                    aircraft arriving at, or departing from, any customs aerodrome to furnish to the
                    holder of the licence in respect of that aerodrome such information as may be
                    necessary to enable the holder of the said licence to comply with such of the
                    provisions of the regulations as relate to him;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412535905_006" name="c" temporalId="s6_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>prescribing
                    the times at which, and the form and manner in which, any information required
                    under the regulations is to be furnished:
                    
                </content></paragraph><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_1_c_proviso">Provided that a person carrying on
                such a business as is mentioned in paragraph <ref>(a)(i)</ref> shall not be required
                to furnish information relating to the use of aircraft on journeys wholly outside
                Hong Kong, or relating to persons exclusively employed outside Hong Kong, unless the
                person carrying on the business is either a Hong Kong permanent resident or a
                Chinese citizen or a body corporate incorporated under the law of Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/28">28 of
                        1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535921_004" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Regulations under this section may create summary offences and provide for
                imposing on any person who contravenes or fails to comply with any provision of the
                regulations such penalties (not exceeding a fine
                at
                level 6 and a further fine (not exceeding in all $500,000) not
                exceeding $50,000 for every day on which the contravention or non-compliance
                continues after conviction therefor) as may be specified in the regulations.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535921_012" name="3" temporalId="s6_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subsection (4), no information with respect to any particular
                undertaking which has been obtained by virtue of regulations under this section
                shall, without the consent of the person carrying on that undertaking, be disclosed
                otherwise than in connection with the execution of such regulations, and if any
                person discloses any such information in contravention of this subsection, he shall
                be guilty of an offence and be liable, on summary conviction, to a fine
                at
                level 6, or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 3 months or
                to both such fine and such imprisonment or, on conviction on indictment, to a fine
                not exceeding $5,000,000, or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding 2 years or to
                both such fine and such imprisonment.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2020/er2">E.R. 2 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535952_005" name="4" temporalId="s6_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall apply to the disclosure of any information for
                the purposes of any legal proceedings which may be taken by virtue of this
                subsection or of regulations made under this section, or for the purposes of any
                report of any such proceedings, but, save as aforesaid, the restriction imposed by
                subsection (3) shall, in relation to any legal proceedings (including arbitrations),
                extend so as to prohibit and prevent any person who is in possession of any such
                information so obtained from disclosing, and from being required by any court or
                arbitrator to disclose, that information (whether as a witness or otherwise) except
                with the consent of the person carrying on the undertaking to which the information
                relates.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412535983_005" name="5" temporalId="s6_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="CustomsAerodrome">In this section
                    <term>customs
                    aerodrome</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">設有海關的機場</term>) means an aerodrome for the time
                being appointed as a place of landing or taking off of aircraft for the purposes of
                the enactments relating to customs.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s.
                    5</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1583455679013_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 13 May
                1994.</content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403207326_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Marking of aircraft wreck in Hong Kong waters</heading><content>Where any aircraft, part of an aircraft or equipment for an aircraft is sunk, stranded or abandoned in the waters of Hong Kong in such a manner as in the opinion of the Director of Marine is, or is likely to become, an obstruction or a danger to marine navigation in those waters pending the raising, removal or destruction thereof, the Director of Marine may cause such aircraft, part or equipment to be lighted or buoyed in such manner as he considers appropriate.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403207326_003" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Liability in respect of trespass, nuisance or surface damage in certain circumstances</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536030_025" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>No action shall lie in respect of trespass or in respect of nuisance, by reason only of the flight of an aircraft over any property at a height above the ground, which, having regard to wind, weather and all the circumstances of the case, is reasonable, or the ordinary incidents of such flight so long as such of the provisions of orders made under <ref>section 2A</ref>, of regulations made under <ref>section 3</ref> or of an enactment specified in <ref>section 13(6)</ref> which are applicable in the particular case are complied with and there has been no breach of <ref>section 4</ref>. <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536061_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsection (3), where material loss or damage is caused to any person or property on land or water by, or by a person in, or an article or person falling from, an aircraft while in flight, taking off or landing, then unless the loss or damage was caused or contributed to by the negligence of the person by whom it was suffered, damages in respect of the loss or damage shall be recoverable without proof of negligence or intention or other cause of action, as if the loss or damage had been caused by the wilful act, neglect, or default of the owner of the aircraft.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536077_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where material loss or damage is caused as described in subsection (2) and in circumstances in which—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536077_013" name="a" temporalId="s8_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>damages are recoverable in respect of the said loss or damage by virtue only of subsection (2); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536077_021" name="b" temporalId="s8_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a legal liability is created in some person other than the owner of an aircraft to pay damages in respect of the said loss or damage,</content></paragraph><continued>such owner shall be entitled to be indemnified by that other person against any claim in respect of the said loss or damage.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536077_034" name="4" temporalId="s8_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (5), in this section—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536077_042" name="a" temporalId="s8_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="Owner"><term>owner</term>
                                                  (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">機主</term>), in
                                                  relation to an aircraft, includes the operator of
                                                  the aircraft; and</def></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536077_049" name="b" temporalId="s8_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="Operator"><term>operator</term>
                                                  (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經營人</term>) means the
                                                  person having the management of an aircraft for
                                                  the time being or, in relation to a time, at that
                                                  time.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/2006/2">2 of 2006 s.
                                                  2</ref>)</sourceNote></def></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536077_055" name="5" temporalId="s8_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>A person is not the owner of an aircraft within the meaning of this section if, at the time the material loss or damage mentioned in subsection (2) was caused—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536077_063" name="a" temporalId="s8_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the aircraft had been bona fide demised,
                                                  let or hired out by such person
                                                  (<b><i>the
                                                  lessor</i></b>)
                                                  to any other person
                                                  (<b><i>the
                                                  lessee</i></b>)
                                                  under a lease or other arrangement for a term
                                                  exceeding 14 days;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536077_071" name="b" temporalId="s8_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>under the lease or arrangement, the lessee was responsible for ensuring the airworthiness of the aircraft; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536093_006" name="c" temporalId="s8_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>no member of the crew of the aircraft was in the employment of the lessor.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2006/2">2 of 2006 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403207342_002" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Application of law of salvage and wreck salvage to aircraft</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536124_041" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438412536139_001" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Any services rendered in assisting, or in saving life from, or in saving
                    the cargo or apparel of, an aircraft in, on or over the sea or any tidal water,
                    or on or over the shore of the sea or any tidal water, shall be deemed to be
                    salvage services in all cases in which they would have been salvage services if
                    they had been rendered in relation to a vessel; and where salvage services are
                    rendered by an aircraft to any property or person, the owner of the aircraft
                    shall be entitled to the same reward for those services as he would have been
                    entitled to if the aircraft had been a vessel.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536139_007" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Paragraph (a) shall have effect notwithstanding that the aircraft concerned
                    is not for the time being registered in Hong Kong, and notwithstanding that the
                    services in question are rendered elsewhere than within the limits of the waters
                    of Hong Kong.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536155_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may by regulations direct that any provisions of
                any law of Hong Kong for the time being in force which relate to wreck, to salvage
                of life or property or to the duty of rendering assistance to vessels in distress
                shall, with such exceptions, adaptations and modifications, if any, as may be
                specified in the regulations, apply in relation to aircraft as those provisions
                apply in relation to vessels.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536155_013" name="3" temporalId="s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of this section, any provisions of any law of Hong Kong which
                relate to vessels laid by or neglected as unfit for sea service shall be deemed to
                be provisions relating to wreck.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403207357_001" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Exemption of aircraft and parts thereof from seizure on patent claims</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536202_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any lawful entry into Hong Kong or any lawful transit across Hong Kong, with or
                without landings, of an aircraft to which this section applies shall not entail any
                seizure or detention of the aircraft or any proceedings being brought against the
                owner or operator thereof or any other interference therewith by or on behalf of any
                person in Hong Kong, on the ground that the construction, mechanism, parts,
                accessories or operation of the aircraft is or are an infringement of any patent,
                design or model.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536217_005" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The importation into, and storage in, Hong Kong of spare parts and spare
                equipment for an aircraft to which this section applies and the use and installation
                thereof in the repair of such an aircraft shall not entail any seizure or detention
                of the aircraft or of the spare parts or spare equipment or any proceedings being
                brought against the owner or operator of the aircraft or the owner of the spare
                parts or spare equipment or any other interference with the aircraft by or on behalf
                of any person in Hong Kong on the ground that the spare parts or spare equipment or
                their installation are or is an infringement of any patent, design or
                model.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536233_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subsection (2) shall not apply in relation to any spare parts or spare
                equipment which are sold or distributed in Hong Kong or are exported from Hong Kong
                for sale or distribution.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536233_013" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>This section applies—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536233_021" name="a" temporalId="s10_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to an aircraft, other than an aircraft used in military, customs or police
                    services, registered in any country or territory in the case of which there is
                    for the time being in force a declaration made by the Central People’s
                    Government, with a view to the fulfilment of the provisions of the Chicago
                    Convention which relate to matters to which subsection (1) or (2) extends, that
                    the benefits of those provisions apply to that country or territory;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536249_006" name="b" temporalId="s10_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to such other aircraft as the Central People’s Government may
                        specify.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536249_013" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403207373_002" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Extraterritoriality</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536280_011" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>A regulation or order made under this Ordinance or an enactment specified in
                    <ref>section 13(6)</ref> shall not, on the ground that it would have effect
                outside Hong Kong, be deemed to be invalid in so far as it applies to aircraft
                registered in Hong Kong wherever they may be, or prohibits, requires or
                regulates—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536280_019" name="a" temporalId="s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the doing of anything by persons in, or any of the personnel of, such
                    aircraft, wherever they may be; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536280_027" name="b" temporalId="s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the doing of anything in relation to such aircraft by other persons being
                    Hong Kong permanent residents or Chinese citizens, wherever they may be.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/28">28 of
                            1998 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536280_034" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the avoidance of doubt and for the purpose of conferring jurisdiction as
                regards proceedings for an offence under regulations or orders under this Ordinance
                or an enactment specified in <ref>section 13(6)</ref>, the alleged offence may be
                treated as having been committed in any place where the person against whom the
                proceedings are instituted may for the time being be. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536295_005" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of this section the personnel of an aircraft shall be deemed
                to include the commander or other person in charge of the aircraft, and all other
                members of the crew of the aircraft.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403207389_002" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Regulations and
            orders—supplementary
            provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536311_055" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Regulations or orders under this Ordinance or an enactment specified in
                    <ref>section 13(6)</ref> which relate to aircraft may provide for the detention
                of aircraft to secure compliance with the regulations or orders or with any
                provision of this Ordinance in connection with which the regulations or orders are
                made, and such regulations or orders may make such further provision as appears to
                the Chief Executive in Council to be necessary or expedient for securing such
                detention.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536327_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Regulations or orders under this Ordinance, an enactment specified in
                    <ref>section 13(6)</ref>, or instructions given by the Chief Executive under any
                such regulations, orders or enactment, may contain such incidental and supplementary
                provisions as appear to the Chief Executive in Council, or to the Chief Executive,
                as may be appropriate, to be necessary or expedient for the purposes of the
                regulations, orders, enactment or instructions; and any such regulations, orders or
                enactment may authorize the Chief Executive to give instructions for the purposes of
                the regulations, orders or enactment in respect of such matters as may be therein
                specified.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536358_005" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any reference in this Ordinance to any regulations or orders made under this
                Ordinance, or to an enactment, includes where the context admits a reference to the
                provisions of any instructions given under the regulations or orders or
                enactment.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 9</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403207404_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Savers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536373_026" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall apply to aircraft belonging to or exclusively employed for the time being in the service of the Central People’s Government, the Chinese People’s Liberation Army or the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536389_005" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may by order apply to any aircraft described in subsection (1), with or without modification, any provision of this Ordinance or any regulations made thereunder or any enactment specified in subsection (6).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/2">2 of 2012 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536389_013" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this Ordinance shall be construed as affecting any provision relating to marine navigation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536389_021" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Each of the enactments specified in subsection (6) (being enactments in force
                immediately before the
                commencement*
                of this section) shall notwithstanding <ref>section 14</ref> continue in force, and
                such enactments shall be deemed to include such adaptations and modifications (if
                any) as are necessary or expedient to enable this subsection to have full
                effect.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536389_029" name="5" temporalId="s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may by regulations amend or revoke any enactment specified in subsection (6).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536405_005" name="6" temporalId="s13_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>The enactments referred to in subsection (4) are—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536405_013" name="a" temporalId="s13_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Air Transport (Licensing of Air Services) Regulations (App.
                    I,
                    p.
                    G1)**;
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536405_021" name="b" temporalId="s13_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Hong Kong Civil Aviation (Investigation of Accidents) Regulations (App.
                    I,
                    p.
                    L1)***.
                </content></paragraph></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1577949502824_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline><inline class="width_12"> </inline>Commencement date: 13 May 1994.</content>
            
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">**</inline><inline class="width_6"> </inline>
                Now
                    <ref href="/hk/cap448A">Cap. 448 sub. leg.
                    A.</ref></content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">***</inline>
                Now
                    <ref href="/hk/cap448B">Cap. 448 sub. leg.
                    B.</ref></content>
        </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438403207420_002" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Repeals</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536436_004" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The following provisions of the Civil Aviation Act 1949 (1949 c. 67 U.K.), in so far as they apply to Hong Kong, are repealed, namely, <ref>sections 10</ref>, <ref>11</ref>, <ref>13</ref>, <ref>14</ref>, <ref>40</ref>, <ref>41</ref>, <ref>51</ref>, <ref>53</ref>, <ref>57</ref>, <ref>58</ref>, <ref>59</ref> and <ref>61</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536436_012" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536436_020" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Section 23</ref> of the Interpretation and General Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>) shall apply to each of the repeals effected by subsection (1) as it applies in relation to a repeal described in that section.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403207435_002" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-03-19" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Repeals and savings</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412536467_009" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Civil Aviation Act 1949 (1949 c. 67 U.K.), in so far as it applies to Hong
                Kong, is repealed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536467_017" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The following, in so far as they apply to Hong Kong, are repealed,
                namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536467_025" name="a" temporalId="s15_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the
                    Civil Aviation Act 1971 (Overseas Territories) Order 1973 (App. III, p.
                    DG1);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536467_033" name="b" temporalId="s15_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Air Corporations (Dissolution) Order 1973 (App. III, p. DH1);
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536467_041" name="c" temporalId="s15_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Civil Aviation Act 1971 (Overseas Territories) Order 1976 (App. III, p.
                    DM1).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536467_048" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><ref>Sections 23 to 25</ref> of the Interpretation and General Clauses
                Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>) apply to each of the repeals effected
                by subsections (1) and (2) as they apply in relation to the repeal of a provision of
                an Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412536467_056" name="4" temporalId="s15_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Notwithstanding the repeal effected by subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412536467_064" name="a" temporalId="s15_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Air Navigation (Hong Kong) Order 1995
                        (<ref href="/hk/1995/ln561">L.N. 561 of
                    1995</ref>)*,
                    as amended by the Civil Aviation (Amendment) Ordinance 1997 (<ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997</ref>), shall continue in force under this
                    Ordinance and shall be deemed for all purposes to have been made by the Chief
                    Executive in Council under <ref>sections 2A</ref>, <ref>12</ref> and
                        <ref>13(2)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412536483_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any
                    regulation**,
                    direction, rule, licence or other instrument made, issued or continued under the
                    Air Navigation (Hong Kong) Order 1995
                        (<ref href="/hk/1995/ln561">L.N. 561 of
                    1995</ref>)
                    shall, if in force on the
                    commencement***
                    of this section, continue in force and shall be deemed for all purposes to have
                    been made, issued or continued under an order made by the Chief Executive in
                    Council under <ref>sections 2A</ref>, <ref>12</ref> and <ref>13(2)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/36">36 of
                            1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/66">66 of 1997 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1583456374001_001">
            <content>Editorial Note:</content>
            <content></content>
            
            
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline><inline class="width_11"> </inline>Now <ref href="/hk/cap448C">Cap. 448 sub. leg. C</ref>.</content>
            <content class="align_justified left_indent_52 first_line_indent_-16"><inline class="force_orig_font">**</inline><inline class="width_4"> </inline>See the
                Hong Kong Air Navigation (Fees) Regulations (<ref href="/hk/cap448D">Cap. 448 sub.
                    leg. D</ref>).</content>
            <content><inline class="force_orig_font">***</inline> Commencement date: 13 June
                1997.</content>
            
        </editorialNote></section></main></ordinance>