<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 405 sub. leg. A</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>405A</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap405A!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2022-10-27</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403160557_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2022-10-27">Drug
                                    Trafficking (Recovery
                                    of
                                    Proceeds)
                                    (Designated Countries
                                    and
                                    Territories)
                                    Order</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap405/s28">Cap.
                                                405, section
                                    28</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted— <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                                                2022</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker>[18
                                    January 1991]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes— <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                                    2022</ref>)</sourceNote><section name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="regulation" status="operational" id="ID_1438403160573_002" temporalId="s1" startPeriod="2022-10-27"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Citation</heading><content>This
            Order
            may be cited as the Drug Trafficking (Recovery of Proceeds) (Designated Countries and
            Territories) Order.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403160589_001" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this
                Order—<inline> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of
                2022</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><def name="AppropriateAuthority">
            <leadIn><term>appropriate
                    authority</term>
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關當局</term>), in relation to a designated country,
                means—</leadIn>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412405676_026" name="a" temporalId="s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an authority specified opposite that country in <ref>Schedule
                    1</ref>;</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ID_1438412405676_034" name="b" temporalId="s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>where either—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412405676_042" name="i" temporalId="s2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>no authority is so specified; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412405676_050" name="ii" temporalId="s2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>that country is a designated country by virtue of <ref>paragraph
                            3(1)(b)</ref>,</content></subparagraph><continued>the authority appearing to the court to be the appropriate authority of
                    that country for the purposes of <ref>sections 28</ref> and <ref>29</ref> of the
                    Ordinance, and of the other provisions of the Ordinance as applied under
                        <ref>paragraph 3(2)</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln308">L.N. 308 of
                            1997</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></paragraph>
            
        </def><def name="CourtInADesignatedCountry"><term>court
                in a designated
            country</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指定國家的法院</term>) includes a court in any state or
            territory of a designated country;</def><def name="DesignatedCountry"><term>designated
                country</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">指定國家</term>) means a country, territory or place
            designated under <ref>paragraph 3(1)</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1999/15">15 of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)</sourceNote></def></section><section id="ID_1438403160589_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Designation of and application of the Ordinance to countries, territories and places</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412405708_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Each of the countries, territories and places—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412405708_012" name="a" temporalId="s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405708_020" name="b" temporalId="s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to which the 1988 United Nations Convention against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances is applicable (and whether or not such country, territory or place is specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>),</content></paragraph><continued>is designated for the purposes of <ref>sections 28</ref> and <ref>29</ref> of the Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln308">L.N. 308 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/15">15 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405708_033" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In relation to a designated country, the Ordinance as modified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> shall apply to external confiscation orders and to proceedings (whether criminal or civil in nature, and whether those proceedings are in the form of proceedings against a person or against property) which have been or are to be instituted in the designated country and which may result in an external confiscation order being made there.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403160604_002" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Proof of orders and judgments of court in a designated country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412405739_011" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>sections 28</ref> and <ref>29</ref> of the Ordinance, and of the other provisions of the Ordinance as applied under <ref>paragraph 3(2)</ref>—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412405739_019" name="a" temporalId="s4_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any order made or judgment given by a court in a designated country purporting to bear the seal of that court or to be signed by any person in his capacity as a judge, magistrate or officer of the court, shall be deemed without further proof to have been duly sealed or, as the case may be, to have been signed by that person; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405739_027" name="b" temporalId="s4_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a document, duly authenticated, which purports to be a copy of any order made or judgment given by a court in a designated country shall be deemed without further proof to be a true copy.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405754_005" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A document purporting to be a copy of any order made or judgement given by a court in a designated country is duly authenticated for the purpose of subparagraph <ref>(1)(b)</ref> if it purports to be certified by any person in his capacity as a judge, magistrate or officer of the court in question or by or on behalf of the appropriate authority of the designated country.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403160620_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Evidence in relation to proceedings and orders in a designated country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412405770_048" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of <ref>sections 28</ref> and <ref>29</ref> of the Ordinance,
                and of the other provisions of the Ordinance as applied under <ref>paragraph
                    3(2)</ref>, a certificate purporting to be issued by or on behalf of the
                appropriate authority of a designated country stating—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412405786_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that proceedings have been instituted and have not been concluded, or that
                    proceedings are to be instituted, there;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405786_013" name="b" temporalId="s5_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that an external confiscation order is in force and is not subject to
                    appeal;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405786_021" name="c" temporalId="s5_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that all or a certain amount of the sum payable under an external
                    confiscation order remains unpaid in the designated country, or that other
                    property recoverable under an external confiscation order remains unrecovered
                    there;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405786_029" name="d" temporalId="s5_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that any person has been notified of any proceedings in accordance with the
                    law of the designated country; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405786_037" name="e" temporalId="s5_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><leadIn>that an order (however described) made by a court in the designated country
                    has the purpose of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412405786_045" name="i" temporalId="s5_1_e_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><leadIn>recovering (including forfeiting and confiscating)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412405786_052" name="A" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s5_1_e_i_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>payments or other rewards received in connection with drug
                            trafficking or their value;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412405786_060" name="B" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s5_1_e_i_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>property derived or realised, directly or indirectly, from payments
                            or other rewards received in connection with drug trafficking or the
                            value of such property; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412405801_007" name="C" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="s5_1_e_i_C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content>property used or intended to be used in connection with drug
                            trafficking or the value of such property; or</content></subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412405801_015" name="ii" temporalId="s5_1_e_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>depriving a person of a pecuniary advantage obtained in connection with
                        drug trafficking,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/87">87 of 1997
                                s.
                                36</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><continued>shall, in any proceedings in the Court of First Instance, be admissible as
                evidence of the facts so stated.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405801_027" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In any such proceedings a statement contained in a document, duly
                authenticated, which purports to have been received in evidence or to be a copy of a
                document so received, or to set out or
                summarise
                evidence given in proceedings in a court in a designated country, shall be
                admissible as evidence of any fact stated therein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405801_035" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A document is duly authenticated for the purposes of subparagraph (2) if it
                purports to be certified by any person in his capacity as a judge, magistrate or
                officer of the court in the designated country, or by or on behalf of the
                appropriate authority of the designated country, to have been received in evidence
                or to be a copy of a document so received or, as the case may be, to be the original
                document containing or summarising the evidence or a true copy of that
                document.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405817_005" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Nothing in this paragraph shall prejudice the admission of any evidence,
                whether contained in any document or otherwise, which is admissible apart from this
                paragraph.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403160635_002" name="s5A" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s5A"><num value="5A">5A.</num><heading>Certificate as to appropriate authority of designated country, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412405848_027" name="1" temporalId="s5A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412405848_035" name="a" temporalId="s5A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to a designated country no authority is specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405848_043" name="b" temporalId="s5A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a designated country is such a country by virtue of <ref>paragraph 3(1)(b)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>a certificate signed by the Secretary for Justice certifying that the authority specified in the certificate is the appropriate authority for the purposes of <ref>sections 28</ref> and <ref>29</ref> of the Ordinance, and of the other provisions of the Ordinance as applied under <ref>paragraph 3(2)</ref>, shall be evidence of that fact.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405864_011" name="2" temporalId="s5A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a designated country is such a country by virtue of <ref>paragraph 3(1)(b)</ref>, a certificate signed by the Secretary for Justice, certifying that the 1988 United Nations Convention against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances is applicable to that country shall be evidence of that fact.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln308">L.N. 308 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403160651_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Representation of government of designated country</heading><text>A request for assistance sent to the Secretary for Justice by the appropriate
            authority of a designated country shall, unless the contrary is shown, be deemed to
            constitute the authority of the government of that country for the Secretary for Justice
            to act on its behalf in any proceedings in the Court of First Instance under
                <ref>section 29</ref> of the Ordinance or any other provision of the Ordinance as
            applied by <ref>paragraph 3(2)</ref>.</text><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25
                of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403160682_001" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Satisfaction of confiscation order in a designated country</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412405910_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412405910_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a confiscation order has been made under <ref>section 3</ref> of the Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405910_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a request has been sent by the Secretary for Justice to the appropriate authority of a designated country for assistance in enforcing that order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412405910_028" name="c" temporalId="s7_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in execution of that request property is recovered in that country,</content></paragraph><continued>the amount payable under the confiscation order shall be treated as reduced by the value of property so recovered.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405910_041" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this paragraph, and without prejudice to the admissibility of any evidence which may be admissible apart from this subparagraph, a certificate purporting to be issued by or on behalf of the appropriate authority of a designated country stating that property has been recovered there in execution of a request by the Secretary for Justice, stating the value of the property so recovered and the date on which it was recovered shall, in any proceedings in a court in Hong Kong, be admissible as evidence of the facts so stated.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403160698_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Currency conversion</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412405942_047" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the value of property recovered as described in <ref>paragraph 7(1)</ref>
                is expressed in a currency other than that of Hong Kong, the extent to which the
                amount payable under the confiscation order is to be reduced under that paragraph
                shall be calculated on the basis of the exchange rate prevailing on the date on
                which the property was recovered in the designated country concerned.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405957_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an amount of money payable or remaining to be paid under an external
                confiscation order registered in the Court of First Instance under <ref>section
                    29</ref> of the Ordinance is expressed in a currency other than that of Hong
                Kong, for the purpose of any action taken in relation to that order under the
                Ordinance as applied under <ref>paragraph 3(2)</ref> the amount shall be converted
                into the currency of Hong Kong on the basis of the exchange rate prevailing on the
                date of registration of the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                    2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412405973_005" name="3" temporalId="s8_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>For the purposes of this paragraph a certificate purporting to be signed by or
                on behalf of the Monetary Authority and stating the exchange rate prevailing on a
                specified date shall be admissible in any proceedings as evidence of the facts so
                    stated.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1992/82">82
                        of 1992 s. 45</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403160698_003" name="s9" reason="repealed" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2003-01-01" status="repealed" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403160807_001" name="s10" reason="omittedAsSpent" role="paragraph" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="omitted" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><sourceNote>(Omitted as spent— <ref href="/hk/2022/er5">E.R. 5 of 2022</ref>)</sourceNote></section><schedule id="ID_1438403160838_002" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap405A/s2">paras. 2</ref>, <ref href="/hk/cap405A/s3">3</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/cap405A/s5A">5A</ref>]</note><content>
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="repeat_header" width="446">
                <col width="50%"></col>
                <col width="50%"></col>
                
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Designated
                                country</center>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Appropriate
                                authority</center>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Afghanistan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Algeria</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Anguilla</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of
                            Anguilla</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Antigua and
                            Barbuda</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Argentina</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Ministry of Foreign
                            Affairs</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Armenia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Australia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">The Attorney
                            General’s Department</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Austria</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Azerbaijan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">The Bahamas</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of the
                            Bahamas</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bahrain</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bangladesh</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Barbados</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">The Attorney
                            General</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Belarus</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Belgium</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Belize</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bermuda</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">The Attorney
                            General of Bermuda</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td></td>
                    <td></td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bhutan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bolivia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bosnia and
                            Herzegovina</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Brazil</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">British Virgin
                            Islands</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of the
                            British Virgin Islands</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Brunei
                            Darussalam</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Bulgaria</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Burkina
                            Faso</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Burundi</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Cameroon</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Canada</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Minister of Justice or
                            an official designated by that Minister</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Cape Verde</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Cayman
                            Islands</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of the
                            Cayman Islands</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Chad</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Chile</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    
                    <td class="cellpadding_right_5">
                        
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-10">China
                            (except Hong Kong)<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/1999/15">15 of 1999 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Colombia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Costa Rica</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Cote
                            d’Ivoire</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Croatia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Cuba</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Cyprus</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Czech
                            Republic</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Denmark</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Dominica</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Dominican
                            Republic</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Ecuador</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Egypt</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">El Salvador</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">England and
                            Wales</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Home Office</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Ethiopia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Fiji</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Finland</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">France</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Gambia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Germany</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Ghana</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Gibraltar</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of
                            Gibraltar</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Greece</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Grenada</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">The Ministry of
                            External Affairs</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Guatemala</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Guernsey</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">Her Majesty’s Attorney
                            General for the Bailiwick of Guernsey</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Guinea</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Guinea-Bissau</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Guyana</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Haiti</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Honduras</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">India</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Iran</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Isle of Man</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">Her Majesty’s Attorney
                            General for the Isle of Man</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Italy</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p>The Ministry of Justice</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Jamaica</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Japan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Jersey</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">Her Majesty’s Attorney
                            General for the Bailiwick of Jersey</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Jordan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Kenya</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Kingdom of
                            Thailand</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of the
                            Kingdom of Thailand or a person designated by him</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Kyrgyzstan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Latvia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Lesotho</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Lithuania</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Luxembourg</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-10">Macedonia,
                            The Former
                            Yugoslav
                            Republic of</p>
                        
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Madagascar</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Malawi</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Malaysia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Inspector General of
                            Police or a person designated by him</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Mali</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Malta</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Mauritania</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Moldova</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Monaco</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Montserrat</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of
                            Montserrat</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Morocco</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Myanmar</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Nepal</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Netherlands</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Nicaragua</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Niger</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Nigeria</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Northern
                            Ireland</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Home Office</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Norway</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Oman</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Pakistan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Panama</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Paraguay</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Peru</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Poland</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Portugal</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Qatar</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Romania</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">The Russian
                            Federation</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Saint Kitts and
                            Nevis</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Saint Lucia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Saint Vincent
                            and the Grenadines</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Sao Tome and
                            Principe</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Saudi
                            Arabia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Scotland</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Home Office</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Senegal</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Seychelles</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Sierra
                            Leone</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Slovakia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Slovenia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">South
                            Africa</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Spain</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Sri Lanka</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Sudan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Suriname</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Swaziland</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Sweden</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Switzerland</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Syrian Arab
                            Republic</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Tajikistan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Togo</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Trinidad and
                            Tobago</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Tunisia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Turkey</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Turkmenistan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Turks and
                            Caicos Islands</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Uganda</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Ukraine</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">United Arab
                            Emirates</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">United Mexican
                            States</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">United States
                            of America</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-12">The Attorney General of the
                            United States of America or a person designated by him</p>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Uruguay</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Uzbekistan</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Venezuela</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Yemen</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_12 first_line_indent_-10">Yugoslavia
                            (Serbia and
                            Montenegro,
                            Federal Republic of)</p>
                        
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Zambia</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <p class="align_justified left_indent_2 first_line_indent_0">Zimbabwe</p>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </content><sourceNote>(<ref>Schedule 1</ref> replaced <ref href="/hk/1997/ln308">L.N. 308 of
            1997</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403160932_001" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
            2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap405A/s3">para. 3(2)</ref>]<sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of
                    2002 s.
            4</ref>)</sourceNote></note><heading>Drug
            Trafficking (Recovery
            of
            Proceeds) Ordinance
            as
            Modified</heading><section id="ID_1438412406160_004" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><heading><inline class="not_bold width_72">.............................</inline></heading></section><section id="ID_1438412406160_012" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406160_021" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s2_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="AuthorizedOfficer">
                    <leadIn><term>authorized
                            officer</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">獲授權人</term>) means—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406160_038" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any police officer;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406160_047" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any member of the Customs and Excise Service established by
                                <ref>section 3</ref> of the Customs and Excise Service Ordinance
                                (<ref href="/hk/cap342">Cap. 342</ref>); and</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406160_056" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any other person authorized in writing by the Secretary for Justice
                            for the purposes of this Ordinance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                                    1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                </def><def name="CorrespondingLaw"><term>corresponding
                        law</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">相應的法律</term>) has the same meaning as in
                        <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>);</def><def name="DangerousDrug"><term>dangerous
                        drug</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">毒品</term>) has the same meaning as in
                        <ref>section 2(1)</ref> of the Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>);</def><def name="Dealing">
                    <leadIn><term>dealing</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">處理</term>), in relation to property
                        referred to in the definition of
                            <term>drug
                            trafficking</term>
                        or <ref>section 10(1)</ref>, includes—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406160_088" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>receiving or acquiring the property;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406160_097" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>concealing or disguising the property (whether by concealing or
                            disguising its nature, source, location, disposition, movement or
                            ownership or any rights with respect to it or otherwise);</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406176_007" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>disposing of or converting the property;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406176_016" name="d" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>bringing into or removing from Hong Kong the property;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406176_025" name="e" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>using the property to borrow money, or as security (whether by way
                            of charge, mortgage or pledge or otherwise);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                                    33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
                </def><def name="DrugTrafficking">
                    <leadIn><term>drug
                            trafficking</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">販毒</term>) means doing or being concerned
                        in, whether in Hong Kong or elsewhere, any act constituting—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406176_041" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an offence specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref>; or</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406176_050" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s2_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an offence punishable under a corresponding law, </content></paragraph>
                    <continued>and includes dealing, whether in Hong Kong or elsewhere, with any
                        property which in whole or in part directly or indirectly represents any
                        person’s proceeds of drug trafficking;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                                33</ref>)</sourceNote></continued>
                </def><def name="Interest"><term>interest</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">權益</term>) in relation to property, includes
                    right;</def><def name="Property"><term>property</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">財產</term>) includes both movable and immovable
                    property within the meaning of <ref>section 3</ref> of the Interpretation and
                    General Clauses Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap1">Cap. 1</ref>);</def><def name="Registrar"><term>Registrar</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">司法常務官</term>) means the Registrar of the High
                        Court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s. 33</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def><marker role="section-break"></marker></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406176_089" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s2_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The expressions listed in the left hand column below are respectively
                    defined or (as the case may be) fall to be construed in accordance with the
                    provisions of this Ordinance listed in the right hand column in relation to
                    those
                    expressions.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></leadIn><continued>
                    <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="cellpadding_bottom_3 align_justified left_indent_60">
                        <col width="73%"></col>
                        <col width="3%"></col>
                        <col width="24%"></col>
                        <tr>
                            <td>
                                <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Expression</center>
                            </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td>
                                <center xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Relevant
                                    provision</center>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Charging order (抵押令) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                    11(2)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Defendant (被告) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                    3(3)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">External confiscation order (外地沒收令) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                    3(1)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Gift caught by this Ordinance (受本條例囿制的饋贈)</td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"><br></br>Section
                                    7(9)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Making a gift (作出饋贈) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                    7(10)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Realisable property (可變現財產) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                    7(1)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Restraint order (限制令) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                    10(1)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Value of gift, payment or reward (饋贈、付款或酬賞的價值) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td class="valign_bottom"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                7</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td class="leaders_.">Value of property (財產的價值) </td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Section
                                    7(4)</ref></td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                </continued></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                33</ref>)</sourceNote><subsection id="ID_1438412406191_013" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s2_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>This Ordinance applies to property whether it is situated in Hong Kong or
                    elsewhere.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406191_022" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s2_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content><fillIn class=" width_80">.</fillIn></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406191_031" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s2_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>References in this Ordinance to property received in connection with drug
                    trafficking include a reference to property received both in that connection and
                    in some other connection, and whether received before or after the
                        commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of the Drug Trafficking
                    (Recovery of Proceeds) (Designated Countries and Territories) Order (<ref href="/hk/cap405A">Cap. 405 sub. leg. A</ref>) and whether received in
                    connection with drug trafficking carried on by the recipient or some other
                    person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406207_006" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s2_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Subsections (7) to (13) shall have effect for the interpretation of this
                    Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406207_015" name="7" temporalId="sch2_s2_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Property is held by any person if he holds any interest in it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406207_024" name="8" temporalId="sch2_s2_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>References to property held by a person include a reference to property
                    vested in his trustee in bankruptcy or in a liquidator.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406207_033" name="9" temporalId="sch2_s2_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>References to an interest held by a person beneficially in property
                    include, where the property is vested in his trustee in bankruptcy or in a
                    liquidator, a reference to an interest which would be held by him beneficially
                    if the property were not so vested.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406222_006" name="10" temporalId="sch2_s2_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Property is transferred by one person to another if the first person
                    transfers or grants to the other any interest in the property.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406222_015" name="11" temporalId="sch2_s2_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><leadIn>Proceedings are instituted in a designated country when—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406222_024" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s2_11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>under the law of the designated country concerned one of the steps
                        specified in relation to that country in column 2 of <ref>Schedule 1A</ref>
                        has been taken there in respect of alleged drug trafficking by the
                        defendant; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406222_033" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s2_11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an application has been made to a court in a designated country for an
                        external confiscation order, </content></paragraph><continued>and where the application of this subsection would result in there being
                    more than one time for the institution of proceedings, they shall be taken to
                    have been instituted at the earliest of those times.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406222_048" name="12" temporalId="sch2_s2_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><leadIn>Proceedings are concluded—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406222_057" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s2_12_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>when, disregarding any power of a court to grant leave to appeal out of
                        time, there is no further possibility of an external confiscation order
                        being made in the proceedings;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406238_006" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s2_12_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on the satisfaction of an external confiscation order made in the
                        proceedings (whether by the recovery of all property liable to be recovered,
                        or the payment of any amount due, or otherwise).</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406238_014" name="13" temporalId="sch2_s2_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>An order is subject to appeal until (disregarding any power of a court to
                    grant leave to appeal out of time) there is not further possibility of an appeal
                    on which the order could be varied or set
                    aside.</content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1660549813761_001">
                <content>Editorial Note:</content>
                <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 18 January
                    1991.</content>
            </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406238_021" name="s3" temporalId="sch2_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>External confiscation
                orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406238_030" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>An order made by a court in a designated country for the purpose
                    of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406238_039" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s3_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>recovering (including forfeiting and confiscating)—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406238_048" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s3_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>payments or other rewards received in connection with drug
                            trafficking or their value;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406238_057" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s3_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>property derived or realised, directly or indirectly, from payments
                            or other rewards received in connection with drug trafficking or the
                            value of such property; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406238_066" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_s3_1_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>property used or intended to be used in connection with drug
                            trafficking or the value of such property; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1513670367087_001" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s3_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>depriving a person of a pecuniary advantage obtained in connection with
                        drug trafficking,</content></paragraph><continued>and whether the proceedings which gave rise to the order are criminal or
                    civil in nature, and whether those proceedings are in the form of proceedings
                    against a person or property, is referred to in this Ordinance as an
                        <term>external
                        confiscation
                    order</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">外地沒收令</term>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/87">87 of 1997 s.
                        36</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406254_013" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>In subsection (1) the reference to an order includes any order, decree,
                    direction or judgment, or any part thereof, however described.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406254_022" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s3_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="TheDefendant">A person (however described in the proceedings in the
                    designated country) against whom, or in relation to whose property, an external
                    confiscation order has been, or may be, made is referred to in this Ordinance as
                        <term>the
                        defendant</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">被告</term>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote alignTo="zh-Hant-HK">(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of
                        1993</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406254_029" name="s4...6" temporalId="sch2_s4...6" class="no_header"><num value="4...6">4-6.</num><heading><inline class="not_bold width_72">.............................</inline></heading></section><section id="ID_1438412406254_037" name="s6A" temporalId="sch2_s6A" class="no_header"><num value="6A">6A.</num><heading>Interest on amounts to be recovered under external confiscation
                orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406254_054" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s6A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where a fixed amount is payable under an external confiscation order, that
                    amount shall be treated as a judgment debt for the purposes of <ref>section
                        49</ref> of the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>)
                    and, for those purposes, the date on which the external confiscation order was
                    registered under <ref>section 29</ref> of the Drug Trafficking (Recovery of
                    Proceeds) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap405">Cap. 405</ref>) shall be treated as
                    the date of the judgment debt.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406269_006" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s6A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where by virtue of subsection (1) any interest accrues on the amount
                    payable under an external confiscation order, the defendant shall be liable to
                    pay that interest and the amount of the interest shall for the purposes of
                    enforcement be treated as part of the amount payable under the external
                    confiscation order.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                33</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406269_021" name="s7" temporalId="sch2_s7" class="no_header"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Definition of principal terms
                used</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406285_005" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><def name="RealisableProperty">
                    <leadIn>In this Ordinance,
                            <term>realisable
                            property</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">可變現財產</term>) means, subject to subsection
                        (2)—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406285_014" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>in relation to an external confiscation
                            order—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406285_023" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s7_1_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>made in respect of specified property, the property which is
                                specified in the order;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406285_032" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s7_1_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>which may be made as the result of proceedings which have been,
                                or are to be, instituted in a designated country, the property which
                                may be specified in the order; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247
                                        of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406285_040" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in any other case—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406285_049" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s7_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>any property held by the defendant;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995
                                        s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406285_058" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s7_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any property held by a person to whom the defendant has
                                directly or indirectly made a gift caught by this Ordinance;
                                    and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                                33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406285_067" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_s7_1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>any property that is subject to the effective control of the
                                    defendant.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                                33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph>
                </def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406300_006" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Property is not realisable property if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406300_015" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an order under <ref>section 102</ref> or <ref>103</ref> of the Criminal
                        Procedure Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap221">Cap. 221</ref>); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406300_024" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>an order under <ref>section 38F</ref> or <ref>56</ref> of the Dangerous
                        Drugs Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>),</content></paragraph><continued>is in force in respect of the property.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406300_039" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><fillIn class=" width_80">.</fillIn></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406300_048" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Subject to the following subsections, for the purposes of this Ordinance the
                    value of property (other than cash) in relation to any person holding the
                    property—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406300_057" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>where any other person holds an interest in the property, is—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406300_066" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s7_4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the market value of the first mentioned person’s beneficial
                            interest in the property, less</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406300_075" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s7_4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the amount required to discharge any incumbrance (other than a
                            charging order) on that interest; and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406300_083" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in any other case, is its market value.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406300_091" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s7_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><def name="TheMaterialTime">
                    <leadIn>Subject to subsection (10), references in this Ordinance to the value at
                        any time (referred to in subsection (6) as
                            <term>the
                            material
                        time</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">關鍵時間</term>)) of a gift caught by this
                        Ordinance or of any payment or reward are references to—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406300_100" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the value of the gift, payment or reward to the recipient when he
                            received it adjusted to take account of subsequent changes in the value
                            of money; or</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406316_008" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where subsection (6) applies, the value there mentioned,</content></paragraph>
                    <continued>whichever is the greater.</continued>
                </def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406316_023" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s7_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (10), if at the material time the recipient
                    holds—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406316_032" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the property which he received (not being cash); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406316_041" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>property which, in whole or in part, directly or indirectly represents
                        in his hands the property which he received,</content></paragraph><continued>the value referred to in subsection <ref>(5)(b)</ref> is the value to him
                    at the material time of the property mentioned in paragraph (a) or, as the case
                    may be, of the property mentioned in paragraph (b) so far as it so represents
                    the property which he received, but disregarding in either case any charging
                    order.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406316_056" name="7...8" temporalId="sch2_s7_7...8"><num value="7...8">(7)-(8)</num><content><fillIn class=" width_80">.</fillIn></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406316_065" name="9" temporalId="sch2_s7_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>A gift (including a gift made before the
                        commencement<inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> of the Drug Trafficking
                    (Recovery of Proceeds) (Designated Countries and Territories) Order (<ref href="/hk/cap405A">Cap. 405 sub. leg. A</ref>)) is caught by this Ordinance
                    if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406316_074" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>it was made by the defendant at any time since the beginning of the
                        period of 6 years ending when the proceedings were instituted against him;
                        or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406332_007" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>it was made by the defendant at any time and was a gift of
                        property—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406332_016" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s7_9_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>received by the defendant in connection with drug trafficking
                            carried on by him or another; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406332_025" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s7_9_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>which in whole or in part directly or indirectly represented in the
                            defendant’s hands property received by him in that connection.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406332_032" name="10" temporalId="sch2_s7_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406332_041" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_10_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the circumstances in which the defendant is to be treated as making a
                        gift include those where he transfers property to another person directly or
                        indirectly for a consideration the value of which is significantly less than
                        the value of the consideration provided by the defendant; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406332_050" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_10_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in those circumstances, the preceding provisions of this section shall
                        apply as if the defendant had made a gift of such share in the property as
                        bears to the whole property the same proportion as the difference between
                        the values referred to in paragraph (a) bears to the value of the
                        consideration provided by the defendant.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406347_006" name="11" temporalId="sch2_s7_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of subsection (1)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406347_015" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>property, or an interest in property, may be subject to the effective
                        control of the defendant whether or not the defendant has—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406347_024" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a legal or equitable estate or interest in the property;
                            or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406347_033" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a right, power or privilege in connection with the
                            property;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406347_041" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>without limiting the generality of any other provision of this
                        Ordinance, in determining—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406347_050" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>whether or not property, or an interest in property, is subject to
                            the effective control of the defendant; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406347_059" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>whether or not there are reasonable grounds to believe that
                            property, or an interest in property, is subject to the effective
                            control of the defendant, </content></subparagraph><continued>regard may be had to—</continued><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406347_075" name="A" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_b_A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content>shareholdings in, debentures over or directorships of a company
                            that has an interest (whether direct or indirect) in the
                            property;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406363_008" name="B" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_b_B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content>a trust that has a relationship to the property; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406363_017" name="C" temporalId="sch2_s7_11_b_C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content>family, domestic and business relationships between persons having
                            an interest in the property, or in companies of the kind referred to in
                            subparagraph (A) or trusts of the kind referred to in subparagraph (B),
                            and other persons.
                            <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995
                                    s.</ref> 33)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406363_024" name="12" temporalId="sch2_s7_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>Where a person obtains a pecuniary advantage referred to in <ref>section
                        3(1)(b)</ref>, he is to be treated for the purposes of this Ordinance as if
                    he had obtained in connection with the drug trafficking to which the advantage
                    relates a sum of money equal to the value of the advantage, and the other
                    provisions of this Ordinance shall be construed accordingly.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/87">87 of 1997 s.
                            36</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1660549814017_002">
                <content>Editorial Note:</content>
                <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 18 January
                    1991.</content>
            </editorialNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406363_031" name="s8" temporalId="sch2_s8" class="no_header"><num value="8">8.</num><heading><inline class="not_bold width_72">.............................</inline></heading></section><section id="ID_1438412406363_039" name="s9" temporalId="sch2_s9" class="no_header"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Cases in which restraint orders and charging orders may be
                made</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406378_013" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The powers conferred on the Court of First Instance by <ref>sections
                        10(1)</ref> and <ref>11(1)</ref> are exercisable where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406378_022" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>proceedings have been instituted in a designated country;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406378_031" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the proceedings have not been concluded; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406378_040" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>either an external confiscation order has been made in the proceedings
                        or it appears to the Court of First Instance that there are reasonable
                        grounds for believing that an external confiscation order may be made in
                        them.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406378_048" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Those powers are also exercisable where the Court of First Instance is
                    satisfied that proceedings are to be instituted in a designated country or
                    territory and it appears to the court that an external confiscation order may be
                    made in them.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406378_057" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s9_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><fillIn class=" width_80">.</fillIn></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406378_066" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s9_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the Court of First Instance has made an order under <ref>section
                        10(1)</ref> or <ref>11(1)</ref> by virtue of subsection (2), it shall
                    discharge the order if the proposed proceedings are not instituted within such
                    time as the Court of First Instance considers reasonable.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406394_012" name="s10" temporalId="sch2_s10" class="no_header"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Restraint
                orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406394_021" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Court of First Instance may by order (in this Ordinance referred to as
                    a
                        <term>restraint
                        order</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">限制令</term>)) prohibit any person
                    from dealing with any realisable property, subject to such conditions and
                    exceptions as may be specified in the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406394_030" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A restraint order may apply to any realisable property, including property
                    transferred to a person after the making of the order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of
                            1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406394_039" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>This section shall not have effect in relation to any property for the time
                    being subject to a charge under <ref>section 11</ref>. </content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406394_048" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>A restraint order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406394_057" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s10_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may be made only on an application by or on behalf of the government of
                        a designated country or, in a case where an external confiscation order has
                        been registered under <ref>section 29</ref> of the Drug Trafficking
                        (Recovery of Proceeds) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap405">Cap. 405</ref>), by
                        a receiver appointed under <ref>section 12</ref> or the Secretary for
                            Justice;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of 1993</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406410_007" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s10_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may be made on an ex parte application to a judge in chambers;
                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406410_016" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s10_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>may, notwithstanding anything in Order 11 of the Rules of the High
                        Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg. A</ref>), provide for service
                        on, or the provision of notice to, persons affected by the order in such
                        manner as the Court of First Instance may direct.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                                2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406410_024" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>A restraint order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406410_033" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s10_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may be discharged or varied in relation to any property; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406410_042" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s10_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>shall be discharged when the proceedings in relation to which the order
                        was made are concluded.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406425_006" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s10_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>An application for the discharge or variation of a restraint order may be
                    made by any person affected by it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406425_015" name="7" temporalId="sch2_s10_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>Where the Court of First Instance has made a restraint order, the Court of
                    First Instance may at any time appoint a receiver—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406425_024" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s10_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to take possession of any realisable property; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406425_033" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s10_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in accordance with the directions of the Court of First Instance, to
                        manage or otherwise deal with any property in respect of which he is
                        appointed,</content></paragraph><continued>subject to such exceptions and conditions as may be specified by the
                    Court of First Instance; and may require any person having possession of
                    property in respect of which a receiver is appointed under this section to give
                    possession of it to the receiver.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406425_048" name="8" temporalId="sch2_s10_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406425_057" name="9" temporalId="sch2_s10_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>Where the Court of First Instance has made a restraint order, an authorized
                    officer may, for the purpose of preventing any realisable property being removed
                    from Hong Kong, seize the property.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/1994/ln650">L.N. 650 of 1994</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406425_066" name="10" temporalId="sch2_s10_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>Property seized under subsection (9) shall be dealt with in accordance with
                    the directions of the Court of First Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/5">25
                            of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406441_006" name="11" temporalId="sch2_s10_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><leadIn>Where any property specified in a restraint order is immovable property the
                    order shall, for the purposes of the Land Registration Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap128">Cap. 128</ref>)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406441_015" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s10_11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>be deemed to be an instrument affecting land; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406441_024" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s10_11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be registrable as such in the Land Registry under that Ordinance in
                        such manner as the Land Registrar thinks fit.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/8">8 of 1993 s.
                            30</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406441_032" name="12" temporalId="sch2_s10_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>An authorized officer may, by notice in writing served on a person who
                    holds any realisable property the subject of a restraint order, require the
                    person to deliver to the authorized officer, to the extent that it is
                    practicable to do so, documents, or copies of documents, or any other
                    information (in whatever form), in his possession or control which may assist
                    the authorized officer to determine the value of the property.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                            4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406456_006" name="13" temporalId="sch2_s10_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>A person who receives a notice under subsection (12) shall, as soon as is
                    practicable after receipt of the notice, comply with the notice to the extent
                    that it is practicable to do so taking into account the nature of the realisable
                    property the subject of the restraint order concerned.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406456_015" name="14" temporalId="sch2_s10_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><leadIn>A disclosure made in order to comply with a requirement under subsection
                    (12)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406456_024" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s10_14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall not be treated as a breach of any restriction upon the disclosure
                        of information imposed by contract or by any enactment, rule of conduct or
                        other provision;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406456_033" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s10_14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>shall not render the person who made it liable in damages for any loss
                        arising out of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406456_042" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s10_14_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the disclosure;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406456_051" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s10_14_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any act done or omitted to be done in relation to the property
                            concerned in consequence of the disclosure.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406456_058" name="15" temporalId="sch2_s10_15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content>Any person who contravenes subsection (13) commits an offence and is liable
                    on conviction to a fine at level 5 and to imprisonment for 1 year.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                            4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406472_006" name="16" temporalId="sch2_s10_16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content>A person who knowingly deals in any realisable property in contravention of
                    a restraint order commits an offence.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406472_015" name="17" temporalId="sch2_s10_17"><num value="17">(17)</num><leadIn>A person who commits an offence under subsection (16) is liable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406472_024" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s10_17_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on conviction upon indictment to a fine of $500,000 or to the value of
                        the realisable property the subject of the restraint order concerned which
                        has been dealt with in contravention of that order, whichever is the
                        greater, and to imprisonment for 5 years; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406472_033" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s10_17_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on summary conviction to a fine of $250,000 and to imprisonment for 2
                            years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406472_039" name="s11" temporalId="sch2_s11" class="no_header"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Charging orders in respect of land, securities,
                etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406472_049" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Court of First Instance may make a charging order on realisable property
                    for securing the payment to the Government—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406472_058" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s11_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where a fixed amount is payable under an external confiscation order,
                        of an amount not exceeding the amount so payable; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406488_008" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s11_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in any other case, of an amount equal to the value from time to time of
                        the property charged.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406488_016" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For the purposes of this Ordinance, a
                        <term>charging
                        order</term>
                    is an order made under this section imposing on any such realisable property as
                    may be specified in the order a charge for securing the payment of money to the
                    Government.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406488_025" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>A charging order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406488_034" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s11_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>may be made only on an application by or on behalf of the government of
                        a designated country or, in a case where an external confiscation order has
                        been registered under <ref>section 29</ref> of the Drug Trafficking
                        (Recovery of Proceeds) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap405">Cap. 405</ref>), by
                        a receiver appointed under <ref>section 12</ref> or the Secretary for
                            Justice;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of 1993</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406503_007" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s11_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>may be made on an ex parte application to a judge in
                        chambers;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406503_016" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s11_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>may, notwithstanding anything in Order 11 of the Rules of the High
                        Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub. leg. A</ref>), provide for service
                        on, or the provision of notice to, persons affected by the order in such
                        manner as the Court of First Instance may direct; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406503_025" name="d" temporalId="sch2_s11_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>may be made subject to such conditions as the Court of First Instance
                        thinks fit and, without prejudice to the generality of this paragraph, such
                        conditions as it thinks fit as to the time when the charge is to become
                            effective.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406503_033" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (6), a charge may be imposed by a charging order only
                    on—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406503_042" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s11_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>any interest in realisable property, being an interest held beneficially
                        by the defendant or by a person to whom the defendant has directly or
                        indirectly made a gift caught by this Ordinance—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406503_050" name="i" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch2_s11_4_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in any asset of a kind specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>;
                            or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406503_059" name="ii" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch2_s11_4_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>under any trust; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406503_068" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s11_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any interest in realisable property held by a person as trustee of a
                        trust if the interest is in such an asset or is an interest under another
                        trust and a charge may by virtue of paragraph (a) be imposed by a charging
                        order on the whole beneficial interest under the first mentioned
                        trust.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406519_007" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s11_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In any case where a charge is imposed by a charging order on any interest
                    in an asset of a kind specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>, the Court of First
                    Instance may provide for the charge to extend to any interest,
                    dividend
                    or other distribution payable and any bonus issue in respect of the
                        asset.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406519_016" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s11_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Court of First Instance may make an order discharging or varying the
                    charging order and shall make an order discharging the charging order if the
                    proceedings in the designated country or territory are concluded or the amount
                    payment of which is secured by the charge is paid into the Court of First
                        Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406534_007" name="7" temporalId="sch2_s11_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>An application for the discharge or variation of a charging order may be
                    made by any person affected by it.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406534_016" name="8" temporalId="sch2_s11_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, a charge imposed by a charging
                    order shall have the like effect and shall be enforceable in the same manner as
                    an equitable charge created by the person holding the beneficial interest or, as
                    the case may be, the trustee, by writing under his hand.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406534_025" name="9" temporalId="sch2_s11_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>An authorized officer may, by notice in writing served on a person who
                    holds any realisable property the subject of a charging order, require the
                    person to deliver to the authorized officer, to the extent that it is
                    practicable to do so, documents, or copies of documents, or any other
                    information (in whatever form), in his possession or control which may assist
                    the authorized officer to determine the value of the property.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                            4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406550_007" name="10" temporalId="sch2_s11_10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content>A person who receives a notice under subsection (9) shall, as soon as is
                    practicable after receipt of the notice, comply with the notice to the extent
                    that it is practicable to do so taking into account the nature of the realisable
                    property the subject of the charging order concerned.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406550_016" name="11" temporalId="sch2_s11_11"><num value="11">(11)</num><leadIn>A disclosure made in order to comply with a requirement under subsection
                    (9)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406550_025" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s11_11_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>shall not be treated as a breach of any restriction upon the disclosure
                        of information imposed by contract or by any enactment, rule of conduct or
                        other provision;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406550_034" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s11_11_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>shall not render the person who made it liable in damages for any loss
                        arising out of—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406550_042" name="i" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch2_s11_11_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the disclosure;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406550_051" name="ii" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch2_s11_11_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>any act done or omitted to be done in relation to the property
                            concerned in consequence of the disclosure.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406566_007" name="12" temporalId="sch2_s11_12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content>Any person who contravenes subsection (10) commits an offence and is liable
                    on conviction to a fine at level 5 and to imprisonment for 1 year.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                            4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406566_016" name="13" temporalId="sch2_s11_13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content>A person who knowingly deals in any realisable property in contravention of
                    a charging order commits an offence.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s.
                        4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406566_025" name="14" temporalId="sch2_s11_14"><num value="14">(14)</num><leadIn>A person who commits an offence under subsection (13) is liable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406566_034" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s11_14_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>on conviction upon indictment to a fine of $500,000 or to the value of
                        the realisable property the subject of the charging order concerned which
                        has been dealt with in contravention of that order, whichever is the
                        greater, and to imprisonment for 5 years; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406566_043" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s11_14_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on summary conviction to a fine of $250,000 and to imprisonment for 2
                            years.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote>
                        </content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406566_048" name="s11A" temporalId="sch2_s11A" class="no_header"><num value="11A">11A.</num><heading>Applications for restraint and charging
                orders</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406566_057" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s11A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Order 115 of the Rules of the High Court (<ref href="/hk/cap4A">Cap. 4 sub.
                        leg. A</ref>) shall apply to applications made under this Ordinance subject
                    to the modifications set out in subsections (1A) to (7).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s. 33</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406581_006" name="1A" temporalId="sch2_s11A_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content><ref>Rule 2A</ref> shall be omitted.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                        33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406581_015" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s11A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>For <ref>rule 3(2)</ref> there shall be substituted—</content><quotedStructure>
                    <subsection><num value="2">“(2)</num><leadIn>An application under <ref>section 10(4)</ref> or <ref>11(3)</ref>
                            shall be supported by an affidavit which shall—</leadIn></subsection>
                    
                    
                    
                    <paragraph><paragraph><num value="a">(a)</num><content>state, where applicable, the grounds for believing that an
                                external confiscation order may be made in the proceedings
                                instituted or to be instituted in the designated country
                                concerned;</content></paragraph></paragraph>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    <paragraph><paragraph><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to the best of the deponent’s ability, give particulars of the
                                realisable property in respect of which the order is sought and
                                specify the person or persons holding such property;</content></paragraph></paragraph>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    <paragraph><paragraph><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in a case to which <ref>section 9(2)</ref> applies, indicate
                                when it is intended that proceedings should be instituted in the
                                designated country concerned.”.</content></paragraph></paragraph>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                </quotedStructure></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406581_058" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s11A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406581_067" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s11A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>For the <ref>rule 5(3)</ref> there shall be substituted—</content><quotedStructure>
                    <subsection><num value="3">“(3)</num><content>Upon the Court being notified that proceedings have been concluded
                            any restraint or charging order shall be discharged.”.</content></subsection>
                </quotedStructure></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406597_013" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s11A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>In <ref>rule 7(3)</ref> for everything after “such property” there shall be
                    substituted a full stop.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406597_022" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s11A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In <ref>rule 8(3)</ref> before the words “confiscation order” there shall
                    be added “external”.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406597_031" name="7" temporalId="sch2_s11A_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content><ref>Rules 9 to 23</ref> shall be omitted.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of
                1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406597_046" name="s12" temporalId="sch2_s12" class="no_header"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Realisation of
                property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406597_055" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where an external confiscation order has been registered in the Court of
                    First Instance under <ref>section 29</ref> of the Drug Trafficking (Recovery of
                    Proceeds) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap405">Cap. 405</ref>), the Court of First
                    Instance may, on an application by the Secretary for Justice, exercise the
                    powers conferred by subsections (2) to (6).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of
                            1993</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                        1997</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406612_006" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Court of First Instance may appoint a receiver in respect of realisable
                    property.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406612_015" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>The Court of First Instance may empower a receiver appointed under
                    subsection (2), under <ref>section 10</ref> or in pursuance of a charging
                    order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406612_024" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s12_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to enforce any charge imposed under <ref>section 11</ref> on realisable
                        property or on any interest, dividend or other distribution payable and any
                        bonus issue in respect of such property; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406612_033" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s12_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in relation to any realisable property other than property for the time
                        being subject to a charge under <ref>section 11</ref>, to take possession of
                        the property subject to such conditions or exceptions as may be specified by
                        the Court of First Instance.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406612_041" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Court of First Instance may order any person having possession of
                    realisable property to give possession of it to any such receiver.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406612_050" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s12_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Court of First Instance may empower any such receiver to realise any
                    realisable property in such manner as the Court of First Instance may
                    direct.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406628_006" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s12_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>The Court of First Instance may order any person holding an interest in
                    realisable property to make such payment to the receiver in respect of any
                    beneficial interest held by the defendant or, as the case may be, the recipient
                    of a gift caught by this Ordinance as the Court of First Instance may direct and
                    the Court of First Instance may, on the payment being made, by order transfer,
                    grant or extinguish any interest in the property.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406628_015" name="7" temporalId="sch2_s12_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Subsections (4) to (6) do not apply to property for the time being subject
                    to a charge under <ref>section 11</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406628_024" name="8" temporalId="sch2_s12_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>The Court of First Instance shall not in respect of any property exercise
                    the powers conferred by subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref>, (5) or (6) unless a
                    reasonable opportunity has been given for persons holding any interest in the
                    property to make representations to the Court of First Instance.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406644_012" name="s13" temporalId="sch2_s13" class="no_header"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Application of proceeds of realisation and other
                sums</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406644_021" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsection (2), the following sums in the hands of a receiver
                    appointed under <ref>section 10</ref> or <ref>12</ref> or in pursuance of a
                    charging order, that is—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406644_030" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s13_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the proceeds of the enforcement of any charge imposed under
                            <ref>section 11</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406644_039" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s13_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the proceeds of the realisation, other than by
                        the
                        enforcement of such a charge, of any property under
                            <ref>section 10</ref> or
                            <ref>12</ref>;
                        and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406644_048" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s13_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any other sums, being property held by the defendant,</content></paragraph><continued>shall first be applied in payment of such expenses incurred by a person
                    acting as an insolvency officer as are payable under <ref>section 18(2)</ref>
                    and then shall, after such payments (if any) as the Court of First Instance may
                    direct have been made out of those sums be paid to the Registrar and applied for
                    the purposes specified in subsections (4) to (6) and in the order so
                        specified.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406644_063" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where a fixed amount is payable under the external confiscation order and,
                    after that amount has been fully paid, any such sums remain in the hands of such
                    a receiver, the receiver shall distribute those sums—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406659_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s13_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>among such of those who held property which has been realised under
                        this Ordinance; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406659_015" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s13_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in such proportions,</content></paragraph><continued>as the Court of First Instance may direct after giving a reasonable
                    opportunity for such persons to make representations to the Court of First
                        Instance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406659_030" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content><fillIn class=" width_80">.</fillIn></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406659_039" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any sums paid to the Registrar under subsection (1) or otherwise in
                    satisfaction of an external confiscation order shall be first applied to pay any
                    expenses incurred by a person acting as an insolvency officer and payable under
                        <ref>section 18(2)</ref> but not already paid under subsection
                    (1).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406659_048" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s13_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If the sum was paid to the Registrar by a receiver appointed under
                        <ref>section 10</ref> or <ref>12</ref> or in pursuance of a charging order
                    the Registrar shall next pay the receiver’s remuneration and expenses.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406675_006" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s13_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>After making—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406675_015" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s13_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any payment required by subsection (4); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406675_024" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s13_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in a case to which subsection (5) applies, any payment required by that
                        subsection,</content></paragraph><continued>the Registrar shall reimburse any amount paid under <ref>section
                        19(2)</ref>.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406675_039" name="7" temporalId="sch2_s13_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><leadIn>Subject to subsections (8) and (9)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406675_048" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s13_7_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any balance in the hands of the Registrar after he has made all
                        payments required by the foregoing subsections shall be deposited in an
                        interest-bearing account;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406675_057" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s13_7_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>upon the expiration of 5 years beginning with the day on which such
                        balance was so deposited, the Registrar shall arrange for such balance,
                        together with any interest earned thereon, to be paid into the general
                            revenue.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406675_065" name="8" temporalId="sch2_s13_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>On an application made by or on behalf of the government of a designated
                    country before the expiration of the period referred to in subsection
                        <ref>(7)(b)</ref> in respect of any balance referred to in that subsection,
                    the Secretary for Justice may direct the Registrar to pay to that government
                    such proportion of that balance as is specified in the direction and the
                    Registrar shall, as soon as is reasonably practicable after the receipt of that
                            direction—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                            1997</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406690_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s13_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>comply with the direction; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406690_015" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s13_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>pay any remainder of that balance, together with any interest earned on
                        that balance, into the general revenue.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                                33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406690_023" name="9" temporalId="sch2_s13_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content>The Registrar shall not comply with subsection <ref>(7)(b)</ref> in respect
                    of any balance referred to in that subsection (including any interest earned
                    thereon) until any application referred to in subsection (8) made in respect of
                    that balance has been determined, whether by a direction under subsection (8) or
                        otherwise.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
                    33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406690_030" name="s14" temporalId="sch2_s14" class="no_header"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Exercise of powers by Court of First Instance or
                receiver</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406690_039" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The following subsections apply to the powers conferred on the Court of
                    First Instance by <ref>sections 10 to 13</ref>, or on a receiver appointed under
                        <ref>section 10</ref> or <ref>12</ref> or in pursuance of a charging
                        order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406706_006" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Subject to subsections (3), (4), (5) and (6), the powers shall be exercised
                    with a view to recovering property which is liable to be recovered under an
                    external confiscation order registered in the Court of First Instance under
                        <ref>section 29</ref> of the Drug Trafficking (Recovery of Proceeds)
                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap405">Cap. 405</ref>) or, as the case may be, with a
                    view to making available for recovery property which may become liable to be
                    recovered under any external confiscation order which may be made.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247
                            of 1993</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406722_006" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>In the case of realisable property held by a person to whom the defendant
                    has directly or indirectly made a gift caught by this Ordinance, the powers
                    shall be exercised with a view to realising no more than the value for the time
                    being of the gift.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406722_015" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>In the case of realisable property other than realisable property referred
                    to in <ref>section 7(1)(a)</ref>, the powers shall be exercised with a view to
                    allowing any person other than the defendant or the recipient of any such gift
                    to retain or recover the value of any property held by him.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406722_024" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s14_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>An order may be made or other action taken in respect of a debt owed by the
                    Government.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406722_033" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s14_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>In exercising those powers, no account shall be taken of any obligations of
                    the defendant or of the recipient of any such gift which conflict with the
                    obligation to satisfy the external confiscation
                    order.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406737_004" name="s15" temporalId="sch2_s15" class="no_header"><num value="15">15.</num><heading><inline class="not_bold width_72">.............................</inline></heading></section><section id="ID_1438412406737_012" name="s16" temporalId="sch2_s16" class="no_header"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Bankruptcy of defendant, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406737_022" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a person who holds realisable property is adjudged bankrupt—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406737_031" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s16_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>property for the time being subject to a restraint order made before
                        the order adjudging him bankrupt; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406737_040" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s16_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any proceeds of property realised by virtue of <ref>section 10(7)</ref>
                        or <ref>12(5)</ref> or (6) for the time being in the hands of a receiver
                        appointed under <ref>section 10</ref> or <ref>12</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>are excluded from the property of the bankrupt for the purposes of the
                    Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>).</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406737_055" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where a person has been adjudged bankrupt, the powers conferred on the Court
                    of First Instance by <ref>sections 10 to 13</ref> shall not be exercised in
                    relation to—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                        2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406737_064" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s16_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>property for the time being comprised in the property of the bankrupt
                        for the purposes of the Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap.
                            6</ref>); and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406737_073" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s16_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>property which is to be applied for the benefit of creditors of the
                        bankrupt by virtue of a condition imposed under <ref>section 30A(9)</ref> of
                        the Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/87">87 of
                                1997 s. 36</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406753_007" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s16_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in the Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>)
                    shall be taken as restricting, or enabling the restriction of, the exercise of
                    the powers conferred on the Court of First Instance by <ref>sections 10 to
                        13</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406753_016" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s16_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Subsection (2) does not affect the enforcement of a charging order—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406753_025" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s16_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>made before the order adjudging the person bankrupt; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406753_034" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s16_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>on property which was subject to a restraint order when the order
                        adjudging him bankrupt was made.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406753_042" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s16_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where, in the case of a debtor, an interim trustee stands appointed under
                        <ref>section 13</ref> of the Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap.
                        6</ref>) and any property of the debtor is subject to a restraint order, the
                    powers conferred on the interim trustee by virtue of that Ordinance do not apply
                    to property for the time being subject to the restraint order.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/18">18 of 2005 s.
                            48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406768_007" name="6" temporalId="sch2_s16_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>Where a person is adjudged bankrupt and has directly or indirectly made a
                    gift caught by this Ordinance—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406768_016" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s16_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><leadIn>a court shall not make an order under—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406768_024" name="i" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch2_s16_6_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content><ref>section 49</ref> or <ref>50</ref> of the Bankruptcy Ordinance
                                (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>); or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1997/87">87 of 1997 s.
                                    36</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406768_033" name="ii" role="subSubParagraph" temporalId="sch2_s16_6_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content><ref>section 60</ref> of the Conveyancing and Property Ordinance
                                (<ref href="/hk/cap219">Cap. 219</ref>), </content></subparagraph><continued>in respect of the making of the gift at any time when property of the
                        person to whom the gift was made is subject to a restraint order or charging
                        order; and</continued></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406768_049" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s16_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any order made under any of those sections after the discharge of the
                        restraint order or charging order shall take into account any realisation
                        under this Ordinance of property held by the person to whom the gift was
                        made.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406768_054" name="s17" temporalId="sch2_s17" class="no_header"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Winding up of company holding realisable
                property</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406784_005" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where realisable property is held by a company and an order for the winding
                    up of the company has been made or a resolution has been passed by the company
                    for the voluntary winding up, the functions of the liquidator (or any
                    provisional liquidator) shall not be exercisable in relation to—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406784_014" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s17_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>property for the time being subject to a restraint order made before
                        the relevant time; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406784_023" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s17_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any proceeds of property realised by virtue of <ref>section 10(7)</ref>
                        or <ref>12(5)</ref> or (6) for the time being in the hands of a receiver
                        appointed under <ref>section 10</ref> or <ref>12</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406784_031" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where, in the case of a company, such an order has been made or such a
                    resolution has been passed, the powers conferred on the Court of First Instance
                    by <ref>sections 10 to 13</ref> shall not be exercised in relation to any
                    realisable property held by the company in relation to which the functions of
                    the liquidator are exercisable—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406784_040" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s17_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>so as to inhibit him from exercising those functions for the purpose of
                        distributing any property held by the company to the company’s creditors;
                        or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406784_049" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s17_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>so as to prevent the payment out of any property of expenses (including
                        the remuneration of the liquidator or any provisional liquidator) properly
                        incurred in the winding up in respect of the property.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406800_006" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>)
                    or the Companies (Winding Up and Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>) shall be taken as restricting, or enabling
                    the restriction of, the exercise of the powers conferred on the Court of First
                    Instance by <ref>sections 10 to 13</ref>.
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                            912
                            &amp;
                        920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406800_015" name="3A" temporalId="sch2_s17_3A"><num value="3A">(3A)</num><content>Subsection (3) shall apply to any proceedings relating to an appeal,
                    further appeal or review against any exercise of the powers referred to in that
                    subsection as if the court hearing the appeal, further appeal or review, as the
                    case may be, were the Court of First Instance. <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s. 33</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406800_024" name="4" temporalId="sch2_s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subsection (2) does not affect the enforcement of a charging order made
                    before the relevant time or on property which was subject to a restraint order
                    at the relevant time.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406815_006" name="5" temporalId="sch2_s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="Company"><term>company</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">公司</term>) means any company which may be wound
                    up under the Companies (Winding Up and Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>);
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                            912
                            &amp;
                        920</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TheRelevantTime">
                    <leadIn><term>the
                            relevant
                        time</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關時間</term>) means—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406815_031" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s17_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where no order for the winding up of the company has been made, the
                            time of the passing of the resolution for voluntary winding
                            up;</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406815_040" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s17_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where such an order has been made and, before the presentation of
                            the petition for the winding up of the company by the Court of First
                            Instance, such a resolution had been passed by the company, the time of
                            the passing of the resolution; and</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406815_049" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s17_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in any other case where such an order has been made, the time of
                            the making of the order.</content></paragraph>
                </def></subsection><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2014/er2">E.R. 2 of
                2014</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406815_063" name="s18" temporalId="sch2_s18" class="no_header"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Insolvency officers dealing with property subject to restraint
                order</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406815_080" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of any provision contained in the
                    Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>), the Companies (Winding
                    Up and Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>)
                    or any other Ordinance, where—  <sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012
                            ss.
                            912
                            &amp;
                        920</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406831_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s18_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any insolvency officer seizes or disposes of any property in relation
                        to which his functions are not exercisable because it is for the time being
                        subject to a restraint order; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406831_015" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s18_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>at the time of the seizure or disposal he believes, and has reasonable
                        grounds for believing, that he is entitled (whether in pursuance of an order
                        of a court or otherwise) to seize or dispose of that property, </content></paragraph><continued>he shall not be liable to any person in respect of any loss or damage
                    resulting from the seizure or disposal except in so far as the loss or damage is
                    caused by his negligence; and the insolvency officer shall have a lien on the
                    property, or the proceeds of its sale, for such of his expenses as were incurred
                    in connection with the liquidation, bankruptcy or other proceedings in relation
                    to which the seizure or disposal purported to take place and for so much of his
                    remuneration as may reasonably be assigned for his acting in connection with
                    those proceedings. </continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406831_030" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any insolvency officer who incurs expenses—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406846_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s18_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in respect of such property as is mentioned in subsection
                            <ref>(1)(a)</ref> and in so doing does not know and has no reasonable
                        grounds to believe that the property is for the time being subject to a
                        restraint order; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406846_015" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s18_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>other than in respect of such property as is so mentioned, being
                        expenses which, but for the effect of a restraint order, might have been met
                        by taking possession of and realising the property, </content></paragraph><continued>shall be entitled (whether or not he has seized or disposed of that
                    property so as to have a lien under that subsection) to payment of those
                    expenses under <ref>section 13(1)</ref> or (3).</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406846_030" name="3" temporalId="sch2_s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><def name="InsolvencyOfficer">
                    <leadIn>In this section
                            <term>insolvency
                            officer</term>
                            (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">債務處理人</term>) means—</leadIn>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406846_039" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s18_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Official Receiver; or</content></paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ID_1438412406846_048" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s18_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>any person acting as—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406846_057" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s18_3_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>a trustee (including provisional trustee), interim trustee or
                                special manager appointed under the Bankruptcy Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap6">Cap. 6</ref>); or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2005/18">18 of 2005
                                        s. 48</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438412406862_008" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s18_3_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>a liquidator, provisional liquidator or special manager
                                appointed under the Companies (Winding Up and Miscellaneous
                                Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                                        912
                                        &amp;
                                    920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph>
                </def></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406862_013" name="s19" temporalId="sch2_s19" class="no_header"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Receivers: supplementary
                provisions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438412406862_022" name="1" temporalId="sch2_s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a receiver appointed under <ref>section 10</ref> or <ref>12</ref> or
                    in pursuance of a charging order takes any action—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438412406862_031" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s19_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in relation to property which is not realisable property, being action
                        which he would be entitled to take if it were such property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438412406862_040" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s19_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>believing, and having reasonable grounds for believing, that he is
                        entitled to take that action in relation to that property,</content></paragraph><continued>he shall not be liable to any person in respect of any loss or damage
                    resulting from his action except in so far as the loss or damage is caused by
                    his negligence.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406862_055" name="2" temporalId="sch2_s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any amount due in respect of the remuneration and expenses of a receiver so
                    appointed shall, if no sum is available to be applied in payment of it under
                        <ref>section 13(5)</ref>, be paid by the person on whose application the
                    receiver was appointed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of
                    1993</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406878_004" name="s20...28" temporalId="sch2_s20...28" class="no_header"><num value="20...28">20-28.</num><heading><inline class="not_bold width_72">.............................</inline></heading></section><section id="ID_1438412406878_012" name="s29" temporalId="sch2_s29" class="no_header"><num value="29">29.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1993/ln247">L.N. 247 of
                1993</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438412406878_020" name="s30" temporalId="sch2_s30" class="no_header"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Evidence of corresponding
                law</heading><content><ref>Section 43</ref> of the Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>) shall apply in relation to proceedings under this Ordinance as
                it applies in relation to proceedings for an offence under that
                Ordinance.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412406878_036" name="s31" temporalId="sch2_s31" class="no_header"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Amendment of
                <ref>Schedules</ref></heading><content>The Chief Executive in Council may, by order, amend <ref>Schedule 1</ref>,
                    <ref>1A</ref> or <ref>2</ref>.</content><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s. 33</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/15">15
                    of 1999 s.
                3</ref>)<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></sourceNote></section><crossHeading>Schedule
            1</crossHeading><note class="align_right">[<ref>s.
            2</ref>]</note><crossHeading>Drug
            Trafficking
            Offences<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text class="left_indent_0 align_left"><table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="447" class="repeat_header">
                
                <col width="11%"></col>
                
                <col width="7%"></col>
                
                <col width="41%"></col>
                
                <col width="5%"></col>
                
                <col width="35%"></col>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <th colspan="2"><span class="not_bold">Item</span><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></th>
                        <th class="align_center"><span class="not_bold">Offence</span><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></th>
                        <th></th>
                        <th class="align_center"><span class="not_bold">Description*</span><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></th>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">1.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9 align_justified"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 4(1)</ref>,
                            Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap.
                            134</ref>)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">trafficking
                            in a dangerous drug</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">2.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 4A</ref>,
                            Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap.
                            134</ref>)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">trafficking
                            in purported dangerous drug</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">3.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 5(1)</ref>,
                            Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>)</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">supplying or
                            procuring a dangerous drug to or for unauthorized
                            persons<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">4.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 6(1)</ref>,
                            Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap.
                            134</ref>)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">manufacturing
                            a dangerous drug</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">5.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 9(1)</ref>,
                            (2) and (3), Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>)</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">cultivating,
                            supplying, procuring, dealing in, importing, exporting, or possessing
                            cannabis plant or opium
                            poppy<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">6.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section 35</ref>,
                            Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>)</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">keeping or
                            managing a divan for the taking of dangerous
                            drugs<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">7.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            37</ref>,
                            Dangerous
                            Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap. 134</ref>)</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">permitting
                            premises to be used for unlawful trafficking, manufacturing or storage
                            of dangerous
                            drugs<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td class="align_right">7A.</td>
                        <td class="left_indent_9"></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9"><ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                40(1)(c)</ref>, Dangerous Drugs Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap134">Cap.
                            134</ref>)<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">aiding,
                            etc. offence under a corresponding
                            law<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">8.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td><fillIn xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class=" width_85">.</fillIn><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">9.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">conspiracy to
                            commit any of the offences specified in items 1 to
                            7<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center valign_center">—</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">10.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">inciting
                            another to commit any of the offences specified in items 1 to
                            7<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center valign_center">—<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">11.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">attempting to
                            commit any of the offences specified in items 1 to
                            7<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center valign_center">—<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_right">12.</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_justified left_indent_9 first_line_indent_-9">aiding,
                            abetting, counselling or procuring the commission of any of the offences
                            specified in items 1 to
                            7<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td class="align_center valign_center">—<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        
                        <td class="align_right">* Note:</td>
                        
                        <td colspan="4" class="align_justified left_indent_9 ">The
                            short description of offences in this <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">Schedule</ref> is for
                            ease of reference only.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table><sourceNote class="align_right">(<ref href="/hk/1995/89">89 of 1995 s.
            33</ref>)</sourceNote><marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="section-break"></marker></text><crossHeading>Schedule
            1A</crossHeading><note class="align_right">[<ref>s.
            2(11)</ref>]</note><crossHeading>Institution
            of
            Proceedings<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></crossHeading><text>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" frame="void" width="445" class="repeat_header">
                <col width="29%"></col>
                <col width="2%"></col>
                <col width="6%"></col>
                <col width="63%"></col>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <th class="align_center"><span class="not_bold">Designated
                            country</span><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></th>
                        <th></th>
                        <th colspan="2" class="align_center valign_bottom"><span class="not_bold">Point at which proceedings are
                            instituted</span><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></th>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1">Australia</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">where an information has been laid before a
                            justice of the peace;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a person is charged with the offence after
                            having been taken into custody without a warrant; or</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(c)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a bill of indictment is
                            preferred.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Canada</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified">When an information has been laid or
                            an indictment is
                            preferred.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1">England
                            and Wales</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when an information has been laid before a
                            justice of the peace;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a person is charged with an offence;
                            or</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(c)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a bill of indictment is
                            preferred.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Gibraltar</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified">When a person is charged with an
                            offence, whether by the laying of an information or otherwise.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/1991/ln446">L.N. 446 of
                            1991</ref>)</sourceNote><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Guernsey</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified">When a person is charged with an
                            offence.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1">Isle of Man</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">where a justice of the peace issues a summons
                            under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                13</ref> of the Petty Sessions and Summary Jurisdiction Act 1927,
                            when the complaint in relation to the offence is made to him;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">where a justice of the peace issues a warrant
                            for the arrest of any person under that section, when the complaint in
                            relation to the offence is made to him;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(c)</td>
                        
                        <td class="align_justified">where a person is charged with the offence after
                            being taken into custody without a warrant, when he is taken into
                            custody; or</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(d)</td>
                        
                        <td class="align_justified">where an information is preferred by the
                            Secretary for Justice in a case where there have been no committal
                            proceedings,
                            when
                            the information is lodged in the General Registry in accordance with
                                <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                4(1)</ref> of the Criminal Code Amendment Act 1917.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of
                            1997</ref>)</sourceNote><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1">Jersey</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td colspan="1" class="align_justified">when the Bailiff issues a warrant in
                            respect of an offence for the arrest of a person who is out of the
                            island;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a person is arrested and charged with an
                            offence;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(c)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a summons in respect of an offence is
                            served on a person at the instance of the Secretary for Justice;
                                or<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/1997/ln362">L.N. 362 of 1997</ref>)</sourceNote></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(d)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a summons in respect of the offence is
                            served on a person in accordance with the provisions of Article 8 of the
                            Police Court (Miscellaneous Provisions) (Jersey) Law
                            1949.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Kingdom of Thailand</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified">When a complaint or a denunciation
                            is lodged with the inquiry official or other competent official, whether
                            or not the suspect has been identified.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/1996/ln282">L.N. 282 of
                            1996</ref>)</sourceNote><marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1">Malaysia</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when an action that may lead to the making of an
                            order for the purpose of confiscating the proceeds or instrumentalities
                            of drug trafficking is commenced in a court; or</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a person is charged with an offence after
                            having been taken into custody without a warrant.<inline xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(<ref href="/hk/1993/ln12">L.N. 12 of 1993</ref>)</sourceNote></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Northern Ireland</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a summons or warrant is issued under
                            Article 20 of the Magistrates’ Courts (Northern Ireland) Order
                            1981;</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a person is charged with an offence after
                            being taken into custody without a warrant; or</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(c)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when an indictment is presented under <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                            2(2)(c)</ref>, (e) or (f) of the Grand Jury (Abolition) Act (Northern
                            Ireland)
                            1969.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1">Scotland</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(a)</td>
                        <td>when a petition warrant is granted; or</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td></td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td>(b)</td>
                        <td class="align_justified">when a person has been charged with an offence
                            after having been arrested without a
                            warrant.<marker xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" role="blank-line"></marker></td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>United States of America</td>
                        <td></td>
                        <td colspan="2" class="align_justified">When an indictment, information or
                            complaint has been filed against a person in respect of an offence.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <marker role="section-break"></marker>
        </text><crossHeading>Schedule
            2</crossHeading><note class="align_right">[<ref>s.
            11</ref>]</note><crossHeading>Assets
            on which a Charging Order may be
            Imposed</crossHeading><section id="ID_1438412406893_028" name="s1" temporalId="sch2_s1" class="no_header"><num value="1">1.</num><content>Land in Hong
                Kong.</content></section><section id="ID_1438412406893_036" name="s2" temporalId="sch2_s2" class="no_header"><num value="2">2.</num><leadIn>Securities of any of the following kinds—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412406909_006" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Government stock;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406909_015" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>stock of any body incorporated in Hong Kong;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406909_024" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>stock of any body incorporated outside Hong Kong or of any state or
                    territory outside Hong Kong, being stock registered in a register kept at any
                    place within Hong Kong;</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406909_033" name="d" temporalId="sch2_s2_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>units of any unit trust in respect of which a register of the unit holders
                    is kept at any place within Hong
                    Kong.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438412406909_039" name="s3" temporalId="sch2_s3" class="no_header"><num value="3">3.</num><leadIn>In this <ref>Schedule</ref>—</leadIn><subsection id="ID_1438412406909_049" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="GovernmentStock,Land">the terms
                        <term>Government
                        stock</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">政府證券</term>) and
                        <term>land</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">土地</term>) have the same meaning as in
                        <ref>section 2</ref> of the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap.
                        4</ref>);<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438412406909_057" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><def name="Stock,UnitTrust">the terms
                        <term>stock</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">股份</term>) and
                        <term>unit
                        trust</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">單位信託基金</term>) have the same meaning as in
                        <ref>section 20A</ref> of that Ordinance.</def></subsection></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403160979_002" name="sch3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2022-10-27" status="operational" temporalId="sch3"><num value="3">Schedule
            3</num><heading>Drug
            Trafficking (Recovery
            of
            Proceeds) Ordinance
            as
            Modified</heading><editorialNote id="ID_1660274782939_001">
            <content>(<ref>Schedule 3</ref> was renumbered as <ref>Schedule 2</ref> - see <ref href="/hk/2002/26">26 of 2002 s. 4</ref> &amp; Sch. 3 (ss. 2 &amp; 3(a)). The
                content of which has been moved to <ref>Schedule 2</ref> from then on.)</content>
        </editorialNote></schedule></main></subLeg>