<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ordinance xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 332</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>332</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap332!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-03-23</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><longTitle id="ID_1438403018316_001" name="longTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="longTitle" startPeriod="2020-04-23">
            <content>To make provision for the registration and better control of trade unions, and
                matters ancillary
                thereto.<marker role="blank-line"></marker><marker role="blank-line"></marker></content>
        </longTitle><commencementNote>[1 April 1962]
            <sourceNote><ref href="/hk/1962/gna14">G.N.A. 14 of 1962</ref></sourceNote></commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote><part id="ID_1438403018316_003" name="P1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P1"><num value="1">Part
            I</num><heading>Preliminary</heading><section id="ID_1438403018332_002" name="s1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Short title</heading><content>This Ordinance may be cited as the <shortTitle>Trade Unions
            Ordinance</shortTitle>.</content><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s.
            2</ref>; <ref href="hk/1991/ln16">L.N. 16 of 1991</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018332_004" name="s2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In this Ordinance, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Branch"><term class="">branch</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">分會</term>) means any number of members of a trade union
            who have in accordance with the constitution of the trade union appointed their own
            management committee but who are under the control of the executive committee of such
            trade union and are bound by the constitution of the trade union to contribute to its funds;
            <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="ElectoralFund"><term class="">electoral
            fund</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">選舉經費</term>) means a fund established under
                <ref>section 33A</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s.
                    2</ref>)<marker role="section-break"></marker></sourceNote></def><def name="Employee"><term class="">employee</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">僱員</term>) means any person who has entered into or
            works under, or, in the case of a contract which has been terminated, worked under, a
            contract with an employer, whether the contract is by way of manual labour, clerical
            work or otherwise, is express or implied, oral or in writing, and whether it is a
            contract of service or apprenticeship or a contract personally to execute any work or labour;
            <sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Executive"><term class="">executive</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">理事會</term>、理事) means the body to which the management
            of the affairs of a trade union or a branch of a trade union or a trade union
            federation, as the case may be, is entrusted by the members and also means any person
            for the time being carrying out the functions of a president, chairman, vice-chairman,
            secretary or treasurer thereof;</def><def name="Funds"><term class="">funds</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">經費</term>), in relation to a trade union or a branch of
            a trade union, or a trade union federation, includes money, whether in an electoral or
            welfare fund or not, and all other property or assets, whether real or personal, held,
            collected, received or controlled by or on behalf of the trade union or the branch of
            the trade union or the trade union federation, as the case may be;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s.
                2</ref>; <ref href="hk/1991/ln16">L.N. 16 of 1991</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Injury"><term class="">injury</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">損害</term>), for the purposes of Part VII, includes
            injury to a person in respect of his business, occupation, employment or other source of
            income, and includes any actionable wrong;</def><def name="Intimidation"><term class="">intimidation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">恐嚇</term>),
            for the purposes of Part VII, means to cause in the mind of a person a reasonable
            apprehension of injury to himself or to any member of his family or to any of his
            dependants or of violence or damage to any person or
            property;<marker role="section-break"></marker></def><def name="Lockout"><term class="">lock-out</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">閉廠</term>) means the closing of a place of employment,
            or the suspension of work, or the refusal by an employer to continue to employ any
            number of persons employed by him in consequence of a dispute, done with a view to
            compelling those persons, or to aiding another employer in compelling persons employed
            by him, to accept terms or conditions of or affecting employment;</def><def name="Officer"><term class="">officer</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">職員</term>), in relation to a trade union or a branch of
            a trade union or a trade union federation, includes any member of the executive thereof,
            but does not include an auditor;</def><def name="PaidStaff"><term class="">paid
            staff</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">受薪人員</term>) in relation to a trade union or a branch
            of a trade union or a trade union federation, means a clerk or other person appointed
            by, and acting under the instructions of, the executive thereof and paid from the funds
            of the trade union or the branch of the trade union or the trade union federation, as
            the case may be;
            <sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="Register"><term class="">register</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">登記冊</term>) means the register of trade unions to be
            maintained by the Registrar in accordance with <ref>section 4</ref>;</def><def name="Registered"><term class="">registered</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已登記</term>、登記) means registered under this
            Ordinance;</def><def name="RegisteredOffice"><term class="">registered
            office</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">已登記辦事處</term>), in relation to a trade union or a
            branch of a trade union or a trade union federation, means the office, if any, which is
            registered under this Ordinance as the head office thereof;</def><def name="Registrar"><term class="">Registrar</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">局長</term>) means the Registrar of Trade Unions
            appointed under <ref>section 3</ref>;</def><def name="Strike"><term class="">strike</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">罷工</term>) means the cessation of work by a body of
            persons employed acting in combination, or a concerted refusal, or a refusal under a
            common understanding, of any number of persons employed, to continue to work for an
            employer in consequence of a dispute, done as a means of compelling their employer or
            the employer of any other person or body of persons, or any person or body of persons
            employed, to accept or not to accept terms or conditions of or affecting
            employment;</def><def name="StrikeBenefit"><term class="">strike
            benefit</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">罷工利益</term>) means any financial or other benefit given
            by a trade union to any member of the trade union in consideration of a strike or
            lock-out;</def><def name="TradeDispute"><term class="">trade
            dispute</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">勞資糾紛</term>) means any dispute or difference between
            employers and employees, or between employees and employees, connected with the
            employment or
            non-employment,
            or the terms of employment, or with the conditions of or affecting employment, of any person;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TradeUnion"><term class="">trade
            union</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">職工會</term>) means any combination the principal objects
            of which are under its constitution the regulating of relations between employees and
            employers, or between employees and employees, or between employers and employers,
            whether such combination would or would not, if this Ordinance had not been enacted,
            have been deemed to have been an unlawful combination by reason of some one or more of
            its purposes being in restraint of trade;
            <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></def><def name="TradeUnionFederation"><term class="">trade union
            federation</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">職工會聯會</term>) means a trade union which is wholly an
            association or combination of other registered trade unions;</def><def name="VotingMember"><term class="">voting
            member</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有表決權會員</term>) means any member of a registered trade
            union entitled to vote for any purposes under the rules of the trade union;</def><def name="WelfareFund"><term class="">welfare
            fund</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">福利經費</term>) means trade union funds allocated or set
            apart for payment to members or the families of members of the trade union of any
            assurance or benefit, other than strike benefit, or for the provision for such members
            or such families of educational, recreational or medical facilities.</def></section></part><part id="ID_1438403018363_001" name="P2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P2"><num value="2">Part
            II</num><heading>Appointments</heading><section id="ID_1438403018363_003" name="s3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Appointment of Registrar, etc.</heading><text>The Chief Executive shall appoint such person as he may think fit to be Registrar of
            Trade Unions and may appoint a deputy registrar, assistant registrars and such other
            officers as may from time to time appear to him necessary for carrying out the purposes
            of this Ordinance.</text><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403018379_001" name="P3" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P3"><num value="3">Part
            III</num><heading>Registration</heading><section id="ID_1438403018379_003" name="s4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Register of trade unions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966551_004" name="1" temporalId="s4_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar shall keep a register in which shall be recorded such particulars relating to trade unions and trade union federations as may be prescribed by regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966551_012" name="2" temporalId="s4_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A copy of an entry in the register certified under the hand of the Registrar
                shall, until the contrary is shown, be received in evidence as proof of the facts
                specified therein
                as at the date
                of such certified copy.</content><content></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018394_001" name="s5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Trade unions to be registered, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966567_026" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every trade union shall be registered under this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966582_005" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An application for the registration of a trade union shall be made to the Registrar in the prescribed form within 30 days of the establishment thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966582_013" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Every such application shall be signed by not less than 7 voting members of the trade union, any of whom may be officers thereof.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966582_021" name="4" temporalId="s5_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Upon receipt of any such application in the prescribed form, the Registrar shall issue to the trade union a certificate in the prescribed form acknowledging receipt of such application, and every such certificate or a copy thereof certified under the hand of the Registrar shall, until the contrary is proved, be received in evidence as proof of the facts specified therein.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966582_029" name="5" temporalId="s5_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content><leadIn>Any person who is an officer, or who acts as an officer, or who takes any part in the
                    management or administration, of a trade union that is not registered under this
                    Ordinance shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary
                    conviction to a fine at level 1 and to imprisonment for 6 months:
                        <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s5_5_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that this subsection shall not apply to any person who is an officer, or who acts as an officer, or who takes any part in the management or administration, of any such trade union so long as—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966598_005" name="a" temporalId="s5_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>an application for the registration of the trade union has been made in accordance with this section and the Registrar has not refused to register such trade union; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966598_013" name="b" temporalId="s5_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the only acts performed by such person, and the only acts performed by or on behalf of the trade union, are acts for the purposes of, or in connection with, its establishment and its registration under this Ordinance.</content></paragraph></proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018394_003" name="s6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966614_058" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Whenever he has registered a<inline class="width_3"> </inline>trade union, the Registrar shall issue to the trade union a certificate of registration in the prescribed form, and such certificate, or a copy thereof certified under his hand shall, unless proved to have been cancelled, be conclusive evidence for all purposes that such trade union has been duly registered under this Ordinance:<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s6_1_proviso">Provided that if any of the purposes of such trade union be unlawful such registration shall be void.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966629_011" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Registrar may, before registering a trade union, direct that the applicants shall produce any documents or provide any such particulars concerning such trade union as he may require in order to satisfy himself that such trade union is entitled to registration under this Ordinance.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018410_002" name="s7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Refusal of registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966645_004" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Registrar may in his discretion refuse to register a trade union if—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966645_012" name="a" temporalId="s7_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any of the provisions of this Ordinance or the regulations have not been complied with; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966645_020" name="b" temporalId="s7_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any of the purposes of such trade union is unlawful; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966645_028" name="c" temporalId="s7_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the name under which it is proposed to register the trade union is identical with that by which any other trade union, whether existing or having ceased to exist, has been registered, or so nearly resembles such name as to be likely to deceive the public or the members of such trade union or of any other existing trade union; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966645_036" name="d" temporalId="s7_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>he is of the opinion that the trade union applying for registration is
                    substantially a trade union the certificate of registration of which has been
                    cancelled under
                        <ref>section 10(1)</ref>;
                    but the Registrar shall not refuse registration solely on the ground that the
                    membership of the trade union applying for registration includes members of the
                    trade union the certificate of registration of which has been cancelled.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of
                            1971 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966660_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Registrar refuses to register a trade union, he shall forthwith serve upon the applicants for registration thereof a notice in writing to that effect and shall specify therein the ground for his refusal.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018426_001" name="s8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Appeals against refusal of Registrar to register trade union</heading><leadIn>Where the Registrar refuses to register a trade union, any of the applicants for the
            registration thereof who considers that the refusal of the Registrar to register the
            trade union on the ground specified in the notice of refusal to register was wrong in
            that, as the case may be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966692_019" name="a" temporalId="s8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the provisions of this Ordinance and the regulations had been complied
                with;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966692_027" name="b" temporalId="s8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the purposes of the trade union were not unlawful;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966692_035" name="c" temporalId="s8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the name under which registration of the trade union was sought was not such a
                name as is specified in <ref>section 7(1)(c)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966692_043" name="d" temporalId="s8_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the trade union was not such a trade union as is specified in <ref>section
                    7(1)(d)</ref>,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>may, within 28 days after the service of such notice, appeal to the Court of
            First Instance, which may, if it finds that the refusal of the Registrar to register the
            trade union was wrong as aforesaid, so declare and thereupon the Registrar shall
            register the trade union, but, save as hereinbefore provided, the appeal shall be
            dismissed.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 7</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018426_003" name="s9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Effect of application to register</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966707_063" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>The provisions of this Ordinance, other than the provisions of <ref>section 45</ref>, shall apply to a trade union in respect of which application for registration has been made in accordance with <ref>section 5</ref> in like manner as if the trade union had been duly registered:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_1_proviso">Provided that, upon service by the Registrar upon any of the applicants for registration of a notice of refusal to register, the provisions of this Ordinance shall cease so to apply to the trade union.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966723_011" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content><leadIn>A trade union in respect of which application for registration has been made in accordance with <ref>section 5</ref> shall, for the purposes of the Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap151">Cap. 151</ref>), be deemed to have been duly registered under this Ordinance:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s9_2_proviso">Provided that, upon service by the Registrar upon any of the applicants for registration of a notice of refusal to register, the trade union shall cease to be deemed to have been so registered.</proviso></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018441_002" name="s10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Cancellation of registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966785_004" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The registration of a trade union shall not be cancelled otherwise than by order of the Registrar and in the following cases—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966785_012" name="a" temporalId="s10_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>at the request of the trade union, to be verified in such manner as the Registrar may require; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966785_020" name="b" temporalId="s10_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>where—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411966785_028" name="i" temporalId="s10_1_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the certificate of registration of the trade union has been obtained by fraud or mistake; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411966785_036" name="ii" temporalId="s10_1_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the registration of the trade union has become void under the proviso to <ref>section 6(1)</ref>; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411966785_044" name="iii" temporalId="s10_1_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>the trade union is being used, or has at any time since registration been used, for any unlawful purpose or for any purpose inconsistent with its objects or rules; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411966785_052" name="iv" temporalId="s10_1_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>the trade union has wilfully and after notice in writing from the
                        Registrar contravened this Ordinance, or has allowed any rule which is
                        inconsistent with this Ordinance to continue in force, or has rescinded any
                        rule providing for any matter for which provision is required by
                            <ref>section 18</ref>;
                        or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411966801_007" name="v" temporalId="s10_1_b_v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content>the funds of the trade union have been expended in an unlawful manner or for an unlawful purpose or for any purpose not authorized by the rules of the trade union; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411966801_015" name="vi" temporalId="s10_1_b_vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content>any funds of the trade union that have been utilized for any purpose connected with the trade union, or any members thereof, have wilfully and after notice in writing from the Registrar requiring the same to be entered in the accounts of such trade union been omitted from the accounts thereof; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411966801_023" name="vii" temporalId="s10_1_b_vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content>the trade union has ceased to exist.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966801_029" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where an appeal has been duly brought under <ref>section 12(1)</ref>, the Registrar shall not cancel the registration of the trade union before the appeal has been determined.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018457_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Notice of cancellation</heading><leadIn>Before cancelling the registration of a registered trade union, the Registrar shall give to the trade union not less than 2 months’ previous notice in writing specifying the ground upon which he intends to cancel its registration:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s11_proviso"><leadIn>Provided that no such notice shall be required—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966832_035" name="a" temporalId="s11_proviso_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>where the trade union has ceased to exist; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966832_043" name="b" temporalId="s11_proviso_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>where cancellation is at the request of the trade union.</content></paragraph></proviso></section><section id="ID_1438403018457_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Appeals in relation to cancellation by Registrar of registration of trade
            union</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966879_011" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Any voting member of a trade union that has received from the Registrar notice
                in writing of his intention to cancel its registration who considers that the
                Registrar is not entitled to cancel its registration on the ground specified in the
                notice in that, as the case may be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966879_019" name="a" temporalId="s12_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the certificate of registration of the trade union was not obtained by
                    fraud or mistake;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966879_027" name="b" temporalId="s12_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the registration of the trade union has not become void under the proviso
                    to <ref>section 6(1)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966879_035" name="c" temporalId="s12_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the trade union was not being used, nor has at any time since its
                    registration been used, for any unlawful purpose or for any purpose inconsistent
                    with its objects or rules;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966879_043" name="d" temporalId="s12_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the trade union has not wilfully and after notice in writing from the
                    Registrar contravened this Ordinance nor allowed any rule which is inconsistent
                    with this Ordinance to continue in force nor rescinded any rule providing for
                    any matter for which provision is required by <ref>section 18</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966894_006" name="e" temporalId="s12_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the funds of the trade union have not been expended in any way specified in
                        <ref>section 10(1)(b)(v)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966894_014" name="f" temporalId="s12_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>any such funds as are specified in <ref>section 10(1)(b)(vi)</ref> have not
                    wilfully and after notice in writing from the Registrar requiring the same to be
                    entered in the accounts of the trade union been omitted from such
                    accounts,</content></paragraph><continued>may, within 28 days after the service of such notice upon the trade union,
                appeal to the Court of First Instance, which may, if it finds that the Registrar is
                not entitled as aforesaid to cancel the registration of the trade union, so declare,
                but, save as hereinbefore provided, the appeal shall be dismissed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of
                        1971 s. 8</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s.
                2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966894_027" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Any voting member of a trade union the registration of which has been cancelled
                who considers that the cancellation of its registration was wrong in that, as the
                case may be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966894_035" name="a" temporalId="s12_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>notice was not given by the Registrar in accordance with <ref>section
                        11</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966894_043" name="b" temporalId="s12_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the trade union had not requested cancellation of its
                    registration;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966894_051" name="c" temporalId="s12_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the trade union had not ceased to exist,</content></paragraph><continued>may, within 14 days after the cancellation of its registration, appeal to the
                Court of First Instance, which may, if it finds that the cancellation of the
                registration of the trade union was wrong as aforesaid, so declare and thereupon the
                Registrar shall restore the registration of the trade union, but, save as
                hereinbefore provided, the appeal shall be dismissed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 8</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018472_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Effect of registration</heading><content>The registration of a trade union shall render it a body corporate by the name under which it is registered, and, subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, with perpetual succession and with power to hold property movable or immovable and to enter into contracts, to institute and defend suits and other legal proceedings and to do all things necessary for the purposes of its constitution.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018488_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Effect of cancellation of registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411966957_011" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Save where, under subsection (2), the cancellation of the registration of a trade union does not take effect immediately in which case this subsection shall apply when the cancellation takes effect for the purposes thereof, a trade union whose registration has been cancelled under this Ordinance shall in addition to any other disability—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966972_005" name="a" temporalId="s14_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>cease to exist as a corporate body, and the Registrar may, notwithstanding anything contained in the rules of such trade union, forthwith appoint one or more persons to be liquidators thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966972_013" name="b" temporalId="s14_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>cease to enjoy any of the rights, immunities or privileges of a registered trade union, but without prejudice to any liability incurred by the trade union, which may be enforced against the trade union or its assets, whether such liability is incurred before, on or after the date of the cancellation of registration;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966972_021" name="c" temporalId="s14_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>forthwith be dissolved and no person shall, except for the purpose of defending proceedings against the trade union or of dissolving it and disposing of its funds in accordance with the rules thereof and the provisions of this Ordinance, take any part in its management or organization or act or purport to act on behalf of the trade union or as an officer thereof.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411966988_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Where the registration of a trade union is cancelled on the ground that it had requested cancellation of the registration or had ceased to exist, the cancellation shall not take effect for the purposes of subsection (1) or for the purposes of the Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap151">Cap. 151</ref>) prior to the expiry of the period limited by <ref>section 12(2)</ref> for the bringing of an appeal and then—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411966988_013" name="a" temporalId="s14_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>if no appeal is brought under <ref>section 12(2)</ref> within that period, the cancellation shall take effect for those purposes at the commencement of the day following the day on which that period expired; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411966988_021" name="b" temporalId="s14_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if an appeal is so brought within that period, the cancellation shall not take effect for the purposes of subsection (1) or for the purposes of the Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap151">Cap. 151</ref>) prior to the determination of the appeal, but, if the appeal is dismissed, shall take effect for those purposes on the determination thereof.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018488_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Power of liquidator and Registrar in winding up of affairs of a trade union</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967019_012" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a liquidator is appointed under <ref>section 14</ref>, all of the property of whatsoever description (including books and documents) belonging to the trade union, or held by trustees on its behalf, shall vest in the liquidator by his official name with effect from the date of his appointment, and the liquidator, after giving such indemnity, if any, as the Registrar may direct, may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967019_020" name="a" temporalId="s15_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>bring or defend in his official name any action or other legal proceeding that relates to the property of the trade union or is necessary to bring or defend for the purpose of effectually winding up the trade union and recovering its property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967035_006" name="b" temporalId="s15_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>take possession of any books, documents or property of whatsoever description belonging to the trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967035_014" name="c" temporalId="s15_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>sell the real and personal property and
                    choses
                    in action of the trade union by public auction or private contract, with power
                    to transfer the whole thereof to any person or company or to sell the same in
                    parcels;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967035_022" name="d" temporalId="s15_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>appoint a solicitor or agent to assist him in his duties;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967035_030" name="e" temporalId="s15_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>pay any creditors or classes of creditors of the trade union in full or in part;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967035_038" name="f" temporalId="s15_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>compromise any debts or liabilities of the trade union and any liabilities capable of resulting in debts and any claims, present or future, certain or contingent, ascertained or sounding only in damages, that subsist, or are supposed to subsist, between the trade union and any member thereof or any other debtor or person apprehending liability to the trade union and any questions in any way relating to or affecting the assets or winding up of the affairs of the trade union on such terms as may be agreed, and take any security for the discharge of any such debt, liability or claim and give complete discharge in respect thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967050_006" name="g" temporalId="s15_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>make any compromise with creditors of the trade union or persons claiming to be creditors or having or alleging themselves to have any claim, present or future, certain or contingent, ascertained or sounding only in damages, against the trade union or whereby the trade union may be rendered liable; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967066_006" name="h" temporalId="s15_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>prepare a scheme of distribution of the assets of the trade union available for distribution and, subject to the approval of the same by the Registrar, distribute the assets accordingly.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967066_013" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The exercise by the liquidator of any of the powers conferred by this section shall be subject to the control of the Registrar, and any creditor or member of the trade union may apply to the Registrar with respect to any exercise or proposed exercise of any of those powers.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967066_021" name="3" temporalId="s15_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (2), the Registrar may—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967066_029" name="a" temporalId="s15_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>rescind or vary any order made by a liquidator or substitute therefor a new order;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967066_037" name="b" temporalId="s15_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>remove a liquidator from office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967066_045" name="c" temporalId="s15_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>make an order upon the assets of the trade union for the remuneration of any liquidator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967082_006" name="d" temporalId="s15_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>call for and inspect the books, documents or assets of a trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967082_014" name="e" temporalId="s15_3_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>by order in writing limit or restrict the powers of a liquidator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967082_022" name="f" temporalId="s15_3_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>at any time require accounts to be rendered to him by a liquidator;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967082_030" name="g" temporalId="s15_3_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>refer any subject of dispute between a liquidator and any third party to arbitration, subject to the consent in writing of such third party;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967082_038" name="h" temporalId="s15_3_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>summon such meetings of the members of the trade union as may appear to him convenient for the purpose of winding up the affairs of the trade union.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967082_045" name="4" temporalId="s15_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A liquidator appointed under <ref>section 14</ref> or the Registrar shall, in so far as such powers are necessary for the carrying out of the purposes of this section, have power to summon and enforce the attendance of parties and witnesses and to compel the production of documents by the same means and (so far as may be) in the same manner as is provided in the case of a magistrate.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018504_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Closure of liquidation on appointment of liquidator by Registrar</heading><leadIn>Where a liquidator has been appointed under <ref>section 14</ref> for the liquidation of a registered trade union the registration of which has been cancelled, then, notwithstanding anything contained in the rules of the trade union—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967128_036" name="a" temporalId="s16_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all of the funds (including welfare funds, if any) and assets of what description soever belonging to the trade union shall be realized and converted into money and shall be applied first to the cost of the liquidation, then to the discharge of the liabilities of the trade union, then to the payment of share capital, if any, and then in such manner as may be provided by the rules of the trade union or, failing provision therefor, in such manner as the Registrar may direct;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967144_006" name="b" temporalId="s16_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>when the liquidation of the trade union has been closed and any creditor
                thereof has not claimed or received what is due to him under the scheme of
                distribution, notice of the closing of the liquidation shall be published in the
                Gazette, and all claims against the funds of the trade union shall be prescribed
                when 2 years shall have elapsed from the date of such publication;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1979/ln20">L.N. 20
                        of 1979</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967160_006" name="c" temporalId="s16_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any surplus remaining after the application of the funds to the purposes specified in paragraph (a) and the payment of any claims under paragraph (b) shall be paid into the general revenue of Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section></part><part id="ID_1438403018519_002" name="P4" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P4"><num value="4">Part
            IV</num><heading>Constitution</heading><section id="ID_1438403018519_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Officers and members of trade unions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967191_011" name="1" temporalId="s17_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to subsection (1A), no person shall be a member of a registered trade
                union unless he is ordinarily resident in Hong Kong and engaged or employed in a
                trade, industry or occupation with which the trade union is directly
                    concerned.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967191_019" name="1A" temporalId="s17_1A"><num value="1A">(1A)</num><content>Any person who has lawfully been a member of a registered trade union may, upon
                his retirement on account of age or ill-health from the trade, industry or
                occupation in which he was engaged or employed and by virtue of which he was a
                member of the trade union, remain a member thereof, but shall not be a voting
                    member.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967206_005" name="1B" temporalId="s17_1B"><num value="1B">(1B)</num><content>No person shall be refused membership of a trade union solely on the ground
                that he is casually or seasonally engaged or employed in the trade, industry or
                occupation with which the trade union is directly concerned.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967206_013" name="2" temporalId="s17_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>No person shall, without the consent in writing of the Registrar, be an officer
                of a registered trade union unless he is ordinarily resident in Hong Kong and is or
                has been engaged or employed in a trade, industry or occupation with which the trade
                union is directly concerned.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s. 3</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of
                        1997 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967206_021" name="3" temporalId="s17_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Save with the consent of the Chief Executive in Council, no person who has been
                convicted of any offence specified in <ref>Schedule 1</ref> shall, within the period
                of 5 years from the date of his conviction or discharge from prison, whichever is
                the later, be an officer of a registered trade union.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 9</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967222_005" name="3A" temporalId="s17_3A"><num value="3A">(3A)</num><content>The Chief Executive in Council may, by order published in the Gazette, amend
                    <ref>Schedule 1</ref>.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 9</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56
                        of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967222_013" name="4" temporalId="s17_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A person under the age of 16 years may be a member of a registered trade union,
                unless provision is made in the rules thereof to the contrary, but shall not be a
                voting member or a member of the executive of a registered trade union.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967222_021" name="5" temporalId="s17_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>A person under the age of 18 years, but of or over the age of 16 years, may be
                a member of a registered trade union, unless provision is made in the rules thereof
                to the contrary, and may, subject to the rules of the trade union, enjoy all the
                rights of a member and execute all instruments and give all acquittances necessary
                to be executed or given under the rules, but shall not be a member of the executive
                of a registered trade union.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967238_005" name="6" temporalId="s17_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Any person who is an officer of a registered trade union in contravention of
                this section shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction
                to a fine
                at
                level 1 and to imprisonment for 6 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018535_002" name="s17A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s17A"><num value="17A">17A.</num><heading>Powers of Registrar in respect of union elections and membership</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967300_005" name="1" temporalId="s17A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Registrar may, if he is of the opinion that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967300_013" name="a" temporalId="s17A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>a person is an officer of a registered trade union in contravention of
                        <ref>section 17</ref> or any of the rules of the trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967300_021" name="b" temporalId="s17A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>a candidate for election as an officer of a registered trade union is
                    ineligible to be so elected by virtue of <ref>section 17</ref> or any of the
                    rules of the trade union; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967300_029" name="c" temporalId="s17A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>a person is a member of a registered trade union in contravention of
                        <ref>section 17</ref> or any of the rules of the trade union,</content></paragraph><continued>serve upon such officer, candidate or person, and upon the trade union, a
                notice in writing requiring the officer, candidate or person to cease holding office
                or to cease being a candidate for election as an officer or to cease being a member
                of the trade union.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967300_042" name="2" temporalId="s17A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>If the officer, candidate or person fails within 14 days of service to satisfy
                the Registrar that he has complied with a notice under subsection (1) the Court of
                First Instance may, on the application of the Registrar—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967300_050" name="a" temporalId="s17A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>grant an injunction prohibiting such officer, candidate or person from
                    holding office or being a candidate for election as an officer or being a member
                    of the trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967316_006" name="b" temporalId="s17A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>make a declaration that such officer, candidate or person no longer holds
                    office in the trade union or is no longer a candidate for election as an officer
                    or a member of the trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967316_014" name="c" temporalId="s17A_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>make an order directing the trade union to hold, in such manner as the
                    court may direct, a fresh election if an officer has ceased to hold office or a
                    candidate for election as an officer has ceased to be a candidate by virtue of
                    this section.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018550_002" name="s17B" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-10-31" status="repealed" temporalId="s17B"><num value="17B">17B.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 14</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018566_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967362_004" name="1" temporalId="s18_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every registered trade union shall have, and every trade union which is applying for registration shall make, rules that, in the opinion of the Registrar, provide adequately for each and all of the matters specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967362_012" name="2" temporalId="s18_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438411967362_016" name="a" temporalId="s18_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>Where application is being made for the registration of a trade union, the rules of the trade union shall be sent to the Registrar, in the manner prescribed by regulations, at the same time as the application for registration.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967362_022" name="b" temporalId="s18_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>If the Registrar is satisfied that—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967362_030" name="i" temporalId="s18_2_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>such rules have been duly made;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967362_038" name="ii" temporalId="s18_2_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>such rules make adequate provision for each and all of the matters specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967362_046" name="iii" temporalId="s18_2_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>no such rule is inconsistent with any of the provisions of this Ordinance or the regulations or with any other such rule or with the principal objects of the trade union or is contradictory, imprecise or incomprehensible; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967378_007" name="iv" temporalId="s18_2_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>where any such rule relates to the taking of decisions by secret ballot, every voting member of the trade union has an equal right and, so far as practicable, a reasonable opportunity of voting and that the secrecy of the ballot is ensured,</content></subparagraph><continued>he shall register such rules, but if he is not so satisfied he shall refuse to register the rules.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967378_019" name="3" temporalId="s18_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>No alteration or amendment of or addition to any of the registered rules of a registered trade union shall be made the effect of which is that the rules no longer provide adequately for each and all of the matters specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967378_027" name="4" temporalId="s18_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where any registered rule of a registered trade union has been altered or amended or any rule has been added to the registered rules thereof and where the registered rules of a registered trade union have been wholly rescinded or otherwise cancelled and replaced by new rules, the rule so amended or altered or the rule so added or the new rules, as the case may be, shall, within 30 days of the making thereof, be sent to the Registrar in the manner prescribed by regulations.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967394_005" name="5" temporalId="s18_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>If the Registrar is satisfied that—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967394_013" name="a" temporalId="s18_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>such alteration, amendment or addition has, or such new rules have, been duly made; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967394_021" name="b" temporalId="s18_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>in the case of an altered or amended rule or a rule which has been so added—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967394_029" name="i" temporalId="s18_5_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the effect of the alteration, amendment or addition is not such that the rules of the trade union no longer make adequate provision for each and all of the matters specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967394_037" name="ii" temporalId="s18_5_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>the altered or amended rule or the rule so added is not inconsistent with any of the provisions of this Ordinance or the regulations or with any other rule of the trade union or with the principal objects of the trade union or contradictory, imprecise or incomprehensible;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967409_007" name="iii" temporalId="s18_5_b_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>where the altered or amended rule or the rule so added relates to the taking of decisions by secret ballot, every voting member of the trade union has an equal right and, so far as practicable, an equal opportunity of voting and that the secrecy of the ballot is ensured; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967409_015" name="iv" temporalId="s18_5_b_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>where the rule has been amended or altered or the rule has been added for the purpose of compliance by such trade union with the provisions of subsection (1), the rule, either by itself or in conjunction with other registered rules, makes adequate provision for the matter specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref> to which it relates; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967425_006" name="c" temporalId="s18_5_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>in the case of new rules—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967425_014" name="i" temporalId="s18_5_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>such rules make adequate provision for each and all of the matters specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967425_022" name="ii" temporalId="s18_5_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>no such rule is inconsistent with any of the provisions of this Ordinance or the regulations or with any other such rule or with the principal objects of the trade union or is contradictory, imprecise or incomprehensible; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411967425_030" name="iii" temporalId="s18_5_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>where any such rule relates to the taking of decisions by secret ballot, every voting member of the trade union has an equal right and, so far as practicable, an equal opportunity of voting and that the secrecy of the ballot is ensured,</content></subparagraph></paragraph><continued>he shall register the altered or amended rule or the rule so added or the new rules, as the case may be, but if he is not so satisfied he shall refuse to register the rule or rules.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967425_042" name="6" temporalId="s18_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>No new rule, no alteration or amendment of any registered rule and no rule added to the registered rules of a registered trade union shall take effect until the same has been registered under this section.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967440_004" name="7" temporalId="s18_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>If a registered trade union contravenes subsection (1), the trade union shall
                be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine at level
                1. <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967440_012" name="8" temporalId="s18_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>In the event of a contravention of subsection (3), (4) or (6), the registered
                trade union shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction
                to a fine at level 1. <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018597_001" name="s18A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s18A"><num value="18A">18A.</num><heading>Refusal by Registrar to register rules under <ref>section 18</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967487_004" name="1" temporalId="s18A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the Registrar refuses to register the rules of a trade union sent to him under <ref>section 18(2)(a)</ref> in connection with an application for registration of the trade union he shall, upon such refusal, serve on the applicants for registration of the trade union a notice in writing to that effect and shall specify in the notice the ground of his refusal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967487_012" name="2" temporalId="s18A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the Registrar refuses to register a rule or rules in relation to a
                registered trade union sent to him under
                    <ref>section 18(4)</ref>
                he shall, upon such refusal, serve on the union a notice in writing to that effect
                and shall specify in the notice the ground of his refusal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967503_005" name="3" temporalId="s18A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Any person who is aggrieved by the refusal of the Registrar—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967503_013" name="a" temporalId="s18A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>under <ref>section 18(2)(b)</ref> to register the rules of a trade union sent to him under <ref>section 18(2)(a)</ref>; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967503_021" name="b" temporalId="s18A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>under <ref>section 18(5)</ref> to register any rule of a registered trade union sent to him under <ref>section 18(4)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>may, at any time before the expiry of 28 days after service by the Registrar of the notice required under subsection (1) or (2), as the case may be, appeal to the Court of First Instance against such refusal.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967503_034" name="4" temporalId="s18A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>On the hearing of an appeal under subsection (3) the Court of First Instance
                may, if it finds that the requirements of
                    <ref>section 18(2)(b)</ref>
                or (5), as the case may be, have been complied with, direct the Registrar to
                register the rule or rules under that subsection, but unless the court so finds it
                shall dismiss the appeal.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018597_003" name="s19" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Copies of rules</heading><content>A copy of the rules of a registered trade union shall be delivered by the trade union to any person demanding the same and tendering payment in advance of a sum not exceeding $2.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018613_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Registered office</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967550_004" name="1" temporalId="s20_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every registered trade union shall have a registered office situate in Hong Kong and a postal address to which all communications and notices may be addressed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967550_012" name="2" temporalId="s20_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of the situation of the registered office and of the postal address, and of any change therein, shall, within 2 weeks of the registration of the trade union or of such change, as the case may be, be given to the Registrar and shall be registered by him, and the trade union shall not be deemed to have complied with this Ordinance until such notice has been given.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967565_005" name="3" temporalId="s20_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Any registered trade union that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967565_013" name="a" temporalId="s20_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>operates without having a registered office or without giving notice of the situation of its registered office; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967565_021" name="b" temporalId="s20_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>operates at any place to which its registered office may have been removed without having given notice of the change in the situation thereof to the Registrar; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967565_029" name="c" temporalId="s20_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>operates without having a postal address or without giving notice of its postal address; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967565_037" name="d" temporalId="s20_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>fails to give notice to the Registrar of a change in its postal address,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine at
                level 1. <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018644_001" name="s20A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s20A"><num value="20A">20A.</num><heading>Seal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967581_058" name="1" temporalId="s20A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered trade union shall have a common seal bearing its registered name in legible characters.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967581_066" name="2" temporalId="s20A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The common seal of a trade union shall only be used by the authority of the executive of the union and every instrument to which the common seal shall be affixed shall be signed by an officer or a member appointed by the executive for that purpose and countersigned by the chairman, treasurer or secretary.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967596_005" name="3" temporalId="s20A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A trade union which fails to comply with subsection (1) shall be guilty of an
                offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967596_013" name="4" temporalId="s20A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>An officer of a trade union, or any person on its behalf, who uses or
                authorizes the use of any seal which falsely purports to be the seal of the trade
                union shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a
                fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 12</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018644_003" name="s21" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Branches and various undertakings of trade unions to be reported to the Registrar</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967612_042" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Notification of—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967612_050" name="a" temporalId="s21_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>every branch of a registered trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967612_058" name="b" temporalId="s21_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>every business or charitable, cultural, educational or medical undertaking which is operated by or in the name of a trade union; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967628_006" name="c" temporalId="s21_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any change in the address of such branch, or business or charitable, cultural, educational or medical undertaking,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be made to the Registrar in writing, together with such particulars as the Registrar may require, by the trade union within 14 days after the establishment of or change of address of such branch, or business or charitable, cultural, educational or medical undertaking.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 13</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967628_019" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If a branch of a registered trade union or such a business or charitable, cultural, educational or medical undertaking as is mentioned in subsection (1) ceases after notification to the Registrar, to exist or to be operated by or in the name of a registered trade union, the trade union shall report the fact to the Registrar in writing within 30 days thereafter.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967628_027" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A registered trade union that contravenes this section shall be guilty of an
                offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018660_001" name="s22" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Notification of officers, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967659_004" name="1" temporalId="s22_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A notice giving the names (including any alias) of all officers and their titles shall be prominently exhibited in the registered office of every registered trade union and in every office of any branch of a registered trade union.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967659_012" name="2" temporalId="s22_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notice of every change of officers or of the title of any officer of a registered trade union shall, within 14 days thereof, be sent by the trade union to the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967659_020" name="3" temporalId="s22_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Registrar may require a registered trade union to furnish, in respect of any officer specified in any notice given under subsection (2), such particulars as he may consider necessary, and such trade union shall furnish such particulars within 14 days of the date of such request.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967674_005" name="4" temporalId="s22_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A registered trade union that contravenes subsection (2) or fails to furnish,
                within the period specified therein, any particulars which the Registrar may have
                required under subsection (3) shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
                summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018660_003" name="s23" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s23"><num value="23">23.</num><heading>Change of name</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967690_019" name="1" temporalId="s23_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered trade union may agree to change its name by secret ballot of a
                majority of its voting members present at a general meeting or of a majority of
                members’ representatives present at a general meeting where the rules of the trade
                union allow voting by members’ representatives.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s.
                    3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967690_027" name="2" temporalId="s23_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where a registered trade union has so agreed to change its name, application
                for the registration of the change of name shall be made to the Registrar within 14
                days thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967706_005" name="3" temporalId="s23_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>If—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967706_013" name="a" temporalId="s23_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the proposed name is identical with that under which any other trade union,
                    whether existing or not, is or has been registered or so nearly resembles such
                    name as to be likely to deceive the public or the members of such trade union or
                    of any other trade union; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967706_021" name="b" temporalId="s23_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the provisions of this Ordinance in respect of change of name have not been
                    complied with,</content></paragraph><continued>the Registrar shall refuse to register the change of name.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967706_034" name="4" temporalId="s23_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Save as provided in subsection (3), the Registrar shall register the change of
                name.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967706_042" name="5" temporalId="s23_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><leadIn>Any person who considers that the Registrar was wrong in refusing to register a
                change of the name of any registered trade union in that, as the case may
                be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967706_050" name="a" temporalId="s23_5_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the proposed name was not such a name as is specified in subsection
                        <ref>(3)(a)</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967706_058" name="b" temporalId="s23_5_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the provisions of this Ordinance in respect of change of name had been
                    complied with,</content></paragraph><continued>may, within 14 days after the refusal of the Registrar to register the change
                of name, appeal to the Court of First Instance, which may, if it finds that the
                refusal of the Registrar to register the change of name was wrong as aforesaid, so
                declare and thereupon the Registrar shall register the change of name, but, save as
                hereinbefore provided, the appeal shall be dismissed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 14</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967721_004" name="6" temporalId="s23_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>No change of name of a registered trade union shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967721_012" name="a" temporalId="s23_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>take effect until the same has been registered under this
                    section;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967721_020" name="b" temporalId="s23_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>affect any right or obligation of the trade union or any member
                    thereof.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967721_027" name="7" temporalId="s23_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>Where, in respect of any registered trade union that has changed its name, any
                proceeding or cause of action was pending or existed at the time of the change of
                name, the same may be continued or enforced by or against the trade union as it
                might have been continued or enforced by or against the trade union if the change of
                name had not taken place.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967721_035" name="8" temporalId="s23_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content>A registered trade union which fails to comply with subsection (2) shall be
                guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s.
                    14</ref>. Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of
                    2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018675_002" name="s24" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s24"><num value="24">24.</num><heading>Consent of Registrar required to amalgamation of trade unions</heading><content>Save with the consent of the Registrar, no registered trade unions shall amalgamate as one trade union.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018691_001" name="s25" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s25"><num value="25">25.</num><heading>Application for consent to amalgamation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967784_004" name="1" temporalId="s25_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where 2 or more registered trade unions desire to amalgamate as one trade union, an application shall be made to the Registrar for his consent to the amalgamation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967784_012" name="2" temporalId="s25_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every application under subsection (1) shall be made in the prescribed form and shall be signed by the chairman and one other officer of each trade union and shall be accompanied by 3 copies of the proposed rules of the trade union to be formed by the intended amalgamation.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018691_003" name="s26" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s26"><num value="26">26.</num><heading>Vote on application for consent to amalgamation</heading><content>No application under <ref>section 25</ref> for the consent of the Registrar to the amalgamation of any registered trade unions shall be made unless, in the case of each trade union, a majority of the executive thereof has voted in favour of the making of the application.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018706_002" name="s27" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s27"><num value="27">27.</num><heading>Grounds for refusal to consent to amalgamation and procedure in such
            cases</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967815_011" name="1" temporalId="s27_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The Registrar may refuse to give his consent to an intended amalgamation of
                registered trade unions where—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967815_019" name="a" temporalId="s27_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any of the provisions of this Ordinance in respect of the making of the
                    application for his consent have not been complied with;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967815_027" name="b" temporalId="s27_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the proposed rules of the trade union to be formed by the amalgamation will
                    not make adequate provision for each and all of the matters specified in
                        <ref>Schedule 2</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967815_035" name="c" temporalId="s27_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any of the purposes of such trade union will be unlawful;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967815_043" name="d" temporalId="s27_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the name by which it is proposed that such trade union will be known is
                    identical with that under which any other trade union, whether existing or not,
                    is or has been registered or so nearly resembles such name as to be likely to
                    deceive the public or the members of such trade union or of any other trade
                    union.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967830_005" name="2" temporalId="s27_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where, under subsection (1) of this section or <ref>section 28(2)</ref>, the
                Registrar refuses to give his consent to the amalgamation of any registered trade
                unions, he shall, in writing, notify the trade unions of his refusal and shall
                specify therein the ground for his refusal.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967830_013" name="3" temporalId="s27_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Any person who considers that the Registrar was wrong in refusing under
                subsection (1) to give his consent to an intended amalgamation of registered trade
                unions on the ground specified in the notice given pursuant to subsection (2) in
                that, as the case may be—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967830_021" name="a" temporalId="s27_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the provisions of this Ordinance in respect of the making of the
                    application for his consent had been complied with;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967830_029" name="b" temporalId="s27_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the proposed rules of the trade union to be formed by the amalgamation
                    would have made adequate provision for each and all of the matters specified in
                        <ref>Schedule 2</ref>;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967830_037" name="c" temporalId="s27_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>none of<inline class="width_3"> </inline>the purposes of such trade union
                    will be unlawful;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967846_006" name="d" temporalId="s27_3_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the name by which it was proposed that such trade union would be known was
                    not such a name as is specified in subsection <ref>(1)(d)</ref>,</content></paragraph><continued>may, within 14 days after the Registrar has given such notice, appeal to the
                Court of First Instance, which may, if it finds that the refusal of the Registrar to
                give his consent to the intended amalgamation was wrong as aforesaid, so declare and
                thereupon the Registrar shall, subject to the provisions of <ref>section 28</ref>,
                give his consent to the amalgamation, but, save as hereinbefore provided, the appeal
                shall be dismissed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 15</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018722_001" name="s28" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s28"><num value="28">28.</num><heading>Application for consent to be referred to Chief Executive in certain
            cases</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967877_011" name="1" temporalId="s28_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the Registrar has received an application under
                    <ref>section 25(1)</ref>
                for his consent to the amalgamation of any registered trade unions and any of such
                trade unions is a member of any kind of a trade union or other organization
                established outside Hong Kong, he shall, if, but for the provisions of this section,
                he would have given his consent to the amalgamation, refer such application to the
                Chief Executive.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967877_019" name="2" temporalId="s28_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where, under subsection (1), the Registrar has referred an application to the
                Chief Executive, he shall refuse to give his consent to the amalgamation unless the
                Chief Executive consents to the same.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1973/72">72 of 1973 s. 2</ref>; <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018722_003" name="s29" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s29"><num value="29">29.</num><heading>Notice in writing to be given of consent to amalgamation, and saving of powers of Registrar in relation to registration of trade union formed by amalgamation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967908_004" name="1" temporalId="s29_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the Registrar gives his consent to the amalgamation of any registered
                trade unions, he shall send to each of the trade unions a notice in writing thereof
                and shall supply to each of the trade unions such additional copies of such notice
                as may be necessary to enable the trade union to comply with
                    <ref>section 30(1)(a)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967908_012" name="2" temporalId="s29_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The giving by the Registrar of his consent to the amalgamation of any registered trade unions shall not prejudice or affect in any way the powers vested in him by this Ordinance to refuse to register the trade union formed by such amalgamation or the exercise of any powers so vested in him in connection with the registration thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018738_002" name="s30" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s30"><num value="30">30.</num><heading>Procedure for amalgamation, etc.</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967924_019" name="1" temporalId="s30_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No registered trade unions shall be amalgamated as one trade union unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411967924_027" name="a" temporalId="s30_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the notice in writing of the consent of the Registrar to the amalgamation has been posted at the registered office of each of the trade unions party to the amalgamation and in every branch thereof for a period of not less than 14 days; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411967940_006" name="b" temporalId="s30_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>in the case of each such trade union, on a vote being taken in secret ballot, the votes of at least 50% of the voting members thereof are recorded and of the votes recorded those in favour of the amalgamation exceed by not less than 20% those against the same.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 16</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967940_013" name="2" temporalId="s30_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An amalgamation of registered trade unions may take place with or without any dissolution or division of the funds of the trade unions.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018753_001" name="s31" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s31"><num value="31">31.</num><heading>Transfer of liabilities, etc. to trade union formed by amalgamation</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967955_034" name="1" temporalId="s31_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All deeds, bonds, agreements and instruments to which any registered trade union that is amalgamated with any other registered trade union was a party that are subsisting at the time of the amalgamation shall be of as full force and effect against or in favour of the trade union formed by the amalgamation as if, instead of such registered trade union, the trade union so formed had been named therein or had been a party thereto.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411967971_005" name="2" temporalId="s31_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where, in respect of any registered trade union that has amalgamated with any other registered trade union, any proceeding or cause of action was pending or existed at the time of the amalgamation, the same may be continued or enforced by or against the trade union formed by the amalgamation as it might have been continued or enforced by or against such registered trade union if the amalgamation had not taken place.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018753_003" name="s32" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s32"><num value="32">32.</num><heading>Notification of dissolution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411967986_019" name="1" temporalId="s32_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>When a registered trade union is dissolved, notice of the dissolution thereof,
                signed by the secretary of the trade union and 7 persons who were voting members
                thereof at the date of the dissolution, shall,
                within
                14
                days after the dissolution, be sent to the Registrar by the trade union, and upon
                the registration by the Registrar of such dissolution, the trade union shall cease
                to be a body corporate.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968002_005" name="2" temporalId="s32_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A registered trade union that contravenes subsection (1) and every officer of a
                registered trade union, or other person, bound by the rules thereof to give or send
                the notice required by that subsection who fails to give or send the same shall be
                guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403018769_001" name="P5" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P5"><num value="5">Part
            V</num><heading>Funds,
            Accounts and Returns</heading><section id="ID_1438403018769_003" name="s33" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s33"><num value="33">33.</num><heading>Application of funds</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968049_004" name="1" temporalId="s33_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The funds, other than the welfare and electoral funds (if any), of a registered
                trade union may, subject to the rules thereof and to the provisions of this
                Ordinance and the regulations, be expended only for the following
                    purposes—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s.
                    4</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968049_012" name="a" temporalId="s33_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the payment to officers and paid staff of the trade union of salaries,
                    allowances and expenses incurred in dealing with the affairs of the trade
                        union;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 17</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of
                            1977 s. 4</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968049_020" name="b" temporalId="s33_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the payment of expenses for the administration of the trade union,
                    including audit of the accounts of the funds thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968049_028" name="c" temporalId="s33_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the prosecution or defence of any legal proceeding to which the trade union
                    or any member thereof is a party, when such prosecution or defence is undertaken
                    for the purpose of securing or protecting any rights of the trade union as such
                    or any rights arising out of the relations of any member with his employer or
                    with a person whom such member employs;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968064_006" name="d" temporalId="s33_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the conduct of trade disputes on behalf of the trade union or any member
                    thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968064_014" name="e" temporalId="s33_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the compensation of members for loss arising out of trade
                    disputes;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968064_022" name="f" temporalId="s33_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the allocation of moneys for the provision and maintenance of a welfare
                    fund;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968064_030" name="g" temporalId="s33_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>purchase of bonds, securities or property;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968064_038" name="h" temporalId="s33_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>payment of subscriptions, fees, contributions or donations to a registered
                    trade union or other lawful association or combination established within Hong
                        Kong;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968064_046" name="i" temporalId="s33_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the promotion of entertainments;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968064_054" name="j" temporalId="s33_1_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content>subject to the approval of the Chief Executive, contributions or donations
                    to a trade union or other similar organization established outside Hong Kong
                    whether or not such registered trade union is affiliated therewith;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of
                            1971 s. 17</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 3</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s. 4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135
                            of 1997 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968080_006" name="k" temporalId="s33_1_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>the payment of fines imposed on the trade union for any offence of which it
                    is convicted under this or any other Ordinance;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s.
                        17</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968080_014" name="l" temporalId="s33_1_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>any other purpose which the Chief Executive may approve.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15
                            of 1971 s. 17</ref>. Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s.
                            4</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s.
                    8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968080_021" name="2" temporalId="s33_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to <ref>section 49</ref>, a registered trade union that
                contravenes subsection (1) shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
                summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018784_002" name="s33A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s33A"><num value="33A">33A.</num><heading>Electoral fund</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968111_040" name="1" temporalId="s33A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>If authorized by secret ballot of a majority of its voting members, a registered trade union may establish an electoral fund out of which may be paid—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968111_048" name="a" temporalId="s33A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>expenses incurred directly or indirectly by a candidate or prospective candidate for election to a District Council or the Legislative Council;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968127_006" name="b" temporalId="s33A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>expenses for the holding of a meeting or the preparation and distribution of literature or documents in support of a candidate or prospective candidate for election to a District Council or the Legislative Council; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968127_014" name="c" temporalId="s33A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>expenses related to the registration of electors or the selection of a candidate for election to a District Council or the Legislative Council.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1999/8">8 of 1999 s. 89</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1999/78">78 of 1999 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968127_021" name="2" temporalId="s33A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A registered trade union shall not compel a member to contribute to the electoral fund and the union shall not make contribution to the fund a condition for admission to the union or continuing as a member with full membership rights in the union.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968127_029" name="3" temporalId="s33A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>A registered trade union shall not pay money out of an electoral fund until
                rules under paragraph <ref>(j)(iii)</ref> of
                    <ref>Schedule
                    2</ref> have been registered by the Registrar under <ref>section
                18</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968127_037" name="4" temporalId="s33A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A registered trade union that contravenes this section commits an offence and
                is liable to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018800_002" name="s33B" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s33B"><num value="33B">33B.</num><heading>Electoral expenses resolution</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968158_004" name="1" temporalId="s33B_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where no electoral fund is established under <ref>section 33A</ref>, a registered trade union, if authorized by secret ballot of a majority of its voting members present at a general meeting or of a majority of members’ representatives present at a general meeting where the rules of the trade union allow voting by members’ representative, may pay for expenses referred to in <ref>section 33A(1)</ref>.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968158_012" name="2" temporalId="s33B_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An authorization under this section must limit the expenditures to a specific election and specify the maximum amount authorized.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018800_004" name="s34" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s34"><num value="34">34.</num><heading>Use of funds for political purposes</heading><leadIn>Except as permitted under <ref>sections 33A</ref> and <ref>33B</ref>, the funds of a
            registered trade union shall not, whether in Hong Kong or elsewhere—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968189_012" name="a" temporalId="s34_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>be applied either directly or indirectly for any political purpose;
                or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968189_020" name="b" temporalId="s34_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>be paid or transferred to any person or body of persons in furtherance of any
                political purpose.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018816_002" name="s35" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s35"><num value="35">35.</num><heading>Treasurer to render accounts to members</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968205_047" name="1" temporalId="s35_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The treasurer of a registered trade union and every other officer thereof who is responsible for the accounts of the trade union or for collection, disbursement, custody or control of the funds or moneys thereof shall, upon resigning or vacating his office and at least once in every year at such time as may be specified in the rules of the trade union and at any other times at which he may be required to do so by a resolution of the voting members of the trade union or by the rules thereof, render to the trade union and its members a just and true account of all moneys received and paid by him during the period that has elapsed since his assuming office or, if he has previously rendered an account, since the last date upon which he rendered such account, and of the balance remaining in his custody at the time of rendering such account and of all bonds, securities or other property of the trade union entrusted to his custody or under his control.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968252_005" name="2" temporalId="s35_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The form of account may be prescribed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968252_013" name="3" temporalId="s35_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The trade union shall cause the account to be audited by some person approved for that purpose by the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968252_021" name="4" temporalId="s35_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>After the account has been audited, the treasurer or other officer referred to in subsection (1) shall, if he is resigning or vacating his office or if so required by resolution of the voting members of the trade union or by the rules thereof, as the case may be, hand over to the trade union such balance as appears to be due from him and all bonds, securities, effects, books, papers and property of the trade union in his custody or otherwise under his control.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968267_005" name="5" temporalId="s35_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>If the treasurer or other officer referred to in
                subsection (1)
                fails to hand over such balance or such other things as are referred to in
                subsection (4) in accordance with that subsection, the trade union or any voting
                member thereof may sue him in any competent court for the balance appearing to have
                been due from him upon the account last rendered by him and for all moneys since
                received by him on account of the trade union and for the securities and effects,
                books, papers and property in his custody, leaving him to set off in such action the
                sums, if any, that he may have since paid on account of the trade union, and in any
                such action the plaintiff shall be entitled to recover full costs of the suit to be
                taxed as between solicitor and client.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018831_001" name="s36" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s36"><num value="36">36.</num><heading>Annual statement of account and returns to be rendered to Registrar</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968314_004" name="1" temporalId="s36_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Every registered trade union shall furnish annually to the Registrar, not more than 3 months after the termination of each financial year of the trade union as specified in the rules thereof or within such further period as the Registrar may on application in writing grant, a statement of account, audited by an auditor approved by the Registrar, of all receipts and expenditures during that financial year and of the assets and liabilities of the trade union. The statement shall be accompanied by a copy of the auditor’s report and shall be prepared in such form and shall contain such particulars as may be prescribed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 18</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968330_005" name="2" temporalId="s36_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Every registered trade union shall furnish to the Registrar on or before 31 March in each year, or within such further period as the Registrar may on application in writing grant, a return in the form prescribed showing the membership of the trade union and the names of the officers thereof on 31 December in the preceding year and containing such other particulars as may be prescribed.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 18</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968345_005" name="3" temporalId="s36_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Every member of a registered trade union shall be entitled to receive free of charge a copy of the statement of account referred to in subsection (1) and the secretary or other officer thereof specified in the rules of the trade union shall deliver a copy of such statement to every member of the trade union who makes application to him therefor.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968345_013" name="4" temporalId="s36_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>A registered trade union that contravenes subsection (1) or (2) shall be guilty
                of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018831_003" name="s37" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s37"><num value="37">37.</num><heading>Inspection of accounts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968376_004" name="1" temporalId="s37_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The account books of a registered trade union and the register of the members thereof shall be open to inspection by any officer or member of the trade union or any authorized agent thereof at such times and in such place as may be specified in the rules thereof and shall be open to inspection at any time by the Registrar or any person authorized in writing by him in that behalf and the Registrar or such person may for that purpose enter any premises occupied by the trade union or any branch thereof.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968376_012" name="2" temporalId="s37_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any person who opposes, obstructs or impedes the Registrar, or any person
                authorized by him under subsection (1), in the carrying out of such inspection shall
                be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1 and to imprisonment for 3 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018847_002" name="s38" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s38"><num value="38">38.</num><heading>Power to require detailed accounts</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968408_004" name="1" temporalId="s38_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Without prejudice to any other provisions relating to the rendering of accounts, the Registrar may, at any time, call upon a registered trade union to render, in respect of any particular period, an account of the funds of the trade union or any branch thereof, or both, together with a statement of the assets and liabilities thereof, and such account shall show in particular such information, and shall be vouched in such manner, as the Registrar may require and shall be delivered to him within such period as he may specify.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968423_005" name="2" temporalId="s38_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any registered trade union that fails to comply with a request made by the
                Registrar under subsection (1) shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on
                summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403018847_004" name="P6" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P6"><num value="6">Part
            VI</num><heading>Rights
            and Liabilities of Trade Unions</heading><section id="ID_1438403018862_002" name="s39" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s39"><num value="39">39.</num><heading>Disabilities of unregistered union</heading><content>Subject to <ref>section 9</ref>, no trade union shall enjoy any of the rights, immunities or privileges of a registered trade union until it is registered.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018862_004" name="s40" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s40"><num value="40">40.</num><heading>Registered trade union not criminal</heading><content>The purposes of any registered trade union shall not, by reason merely that they are in restraint of trade, be deemed to be unlawful so as to render any member of such registered trade union liable to criminal prosecution for conspiracy or otherwise.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018878_002" name="s41" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s41"><num value="41">41.</num><heading>Registered trade union not unlawful for civil purposes</heading><content>The purposes of any registered trade union shall not, by reason merely that they are in restraint of trade, be unlawful so as to render void or voidable any agreement or trust.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018894_001" name="s42" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s42"><num value="42">42.</num><heading>Immunity from civil suit in certain cases</heading><content>No suit or other legal proceeding shall be maintained in any civil court against a registered trade union in respect of any act done in contemplation or furtherance of a trade dispute to which a member of such trade union is a party on the ground only that such act induces some other person to break a contract of employment or that it is an interference with the trade, business or employment of some other person or with the right of some other person to dispose of his capital or of his labour as he wills.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403018894_003" name="s43" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s43"><num value="43">43.</num><heading>Prohibition of actions in tort against registered trade unions</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968486_011" name="1" temporalId="s43_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An action against a registered trade union, whether of employees or employers, in respect of any tortious act alleged to have been committed in contemplation or furtherance of a trade dispute by or on behalf of such trade union shall not be entertained by any court.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 19</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968501_005" name="2" temporalId="s43_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall affect the liability of a registered trade union, or any trustees thereof, to be sued in any court touching and concerning any property, or any right or claim to property, of such trade union, except in respect of any tortious act committed by or on behalf of such trade union in contemplation or furtherance of a trade dispute.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403018909_001" name="s43A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s43A"><num value="43A">43A.</num><heading>Protection from civil suit for acts done in contemplation or furtherance of trade
            dispute</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968532_004" name="1" temporalId="s43A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>No suit or other legal proceeding shall be maintained in any civil court against
                an employer, an employee or a member or officer of a registered trade union, in
                respect of any act done in contemplation or furtherance of a trade dispute—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968532_012" name="a" temporalId="s43A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to which such employer or employee is a party;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968532_020" name="b" temporalId="s43A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to which such member is a party; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968532_028" name="c" temporalId="s43A_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in the case of an officer of a registered trade union, to which a member of
                    that trade union is a party,</content></paragraph><continued>on the ground only that such act induces some other person to break a
                contract of employment or that it is an interference with the trade, business or
                employment of some other person or with the right of some other person to dispose of
                his capital or of his labour as he wills.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968532_041" name="2" temporalId="s43A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>This section applies to an act done on or after the day this section comes into
                operation*.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/77">77 of 1997 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1583985122534_001">
        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
        <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 27 June
            1997.</content>
    </editorialNote><section id="ID_1438403018925_002" name="s44" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1998-09-04" status="operational" temporalId="s44"><num value="44">44.</num><heading>Trade union contracts</heading><leadIn>Nothing in this Ordinance shall enable any court to entertain any legal proceeding instituted with the object of directly enforcing or recovering damages for the breach of any of the following agreements, namely—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968564_012" name="a" temporalId="s44_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any agreement between members of a trade union as such concerning the conditions on which any members for the time being of such trade union shall or shall not sell their goods, transact business, employ or be employed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968564_020" name="b" temporalId="s44_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any agreement for the payment by any person of any subscription or penalty to a trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968564_028" name="c" temporalId="s44_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>any agreement for the application of the funds of a trade union—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411968564_036" name="i" temporalId="s44_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>to provide benefits for members; or</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411968564_044" name="ii" temporalId="s44_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>to furnish contributions to any employer or employee not a member of such trade union, in consideration of such employer or employee acting in conformity with the rules or resolutions of such trade union; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 20</ref>; <ref href="/hk/1998/ln307">L.N. 307 of 1998</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411968564_052" name="iii" temporalId="s44_c_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>to discharge any fine imposed on any person by sentence of a court of justice; or</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968564_059" name="d" temporalId="s44_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>any agreement made between one trade union and another; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968564_067" name="e" temporalId="s44_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>any bond to secure the performance of any of the above mentioned agreements,</content></paragraph><continued>but nothing in this section shall be deemed to constitute any of the above mentioned agreements unlawful.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403018940_002" name="s45" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s45"><num value="45">45.</num><heading>Affiliation with organizations in foreign countries</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968595_018" name="1" temporalId="s45_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A registered trade union may be or may become a member of an organization of
                workers or employers, or a relevant professional organization, which is established
                in a foreign country if, and only if, it is so authorized by secret ballot of a
                majority of the voting members of the union present at a general meeting.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968595_026" name="2" temporalId="s45_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>A registered trade union shall, within 1 month after becoming a member of an
                organization which is established in a foreign country as provided in subsection
                (1), notify the Registrar in writing of the fact.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968610_005" name="3" temporalId="s45_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Except as provided in subsection (1), a registered trade union shall not be or
                become a member of an organization which is established in a foreign country
                unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968610_013" name="a" temporalId="s45_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the consent of the Chief Executive has been obtained; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968610_021" name="b" temporalId="s45_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>it is so authorized by secret ballot of a majority of the voting members of
                    the union present at a general meeting.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968610_028" name="4" temporalId="s45_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Any consent given under subsection <ref>(3)(a)</ref> may be withdrawn at the
                discretion of the Chief Executive.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968610_036" name="5" temporalId="s45_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a registered trade union is or becomes a member of an organization which
                is established in a foreign country as provided in subsection (1) or (3), it shall
                not be necessary for the union to obtain the consent of the Chief Executive for the
                purposes of <ref>section 33(1)(j)</ref> in respect of the payment of any
                contribution by way of a membership fee to that organization.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968626_005" name="6" temporalId="s45_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><paragraph id="ID_1438411968626_009" name="a" temporalId="s45_6_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>In subsection (1), reference to an organization of workers or employers, or
                    a relevant professional organization, which is established in a foreign country
                    does not include reference to a political organization or body established in a
                    foreign country.</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968626_015" name="b" temporalId="s45_6_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>Nothing in subsection (3) shall be construed as allowing or providing for a
                    registered trade union to be or become a member of a political organization or
                    body established in a foreign country.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/23">23 of 1998 s.
                            2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968626_022" name="7" temporalId="s45_7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content>A registered trade union that contravenes subsection (2) or (3) commits an
                offence and is liable to a fine at level 1.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968626_030" name="8" temporalId="s45_8"><num value="8">(8)</num><leadIn>In proceedings for an offence under this section, a certificate signed by an
                officer of an organization which is established in a foreign country and
                stating—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968626_038" name="a" temporalId="s45_8_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the objects and qualification for membership of the organization;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968626_046" name="b" temporalId="s45_8_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the place of establishment of the organization; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968626_054" name="c" temporalId="s45_8_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that a registered trade union is or was at a date or for a period specified
                    in the certificate a member of the organization,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/23">23 of 1998 s.
                            2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>shall be admissible in evidence as proof of the matters so stated; and a
                certificate purporting to be signed by an officer of an organization which is
                established in a foreign country shall in the absence of evidence to the contrary be
                deemed to be such a certificate for the purposes of this section.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968642_011" name="9" temporalId="s45_9"><num value="9">(9)</num><leadIn>In this section, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968642_019" name="a" temporalId="s45_9_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><def name="RelevantProfessionalOrganization"><term>relevant
                        professional
                    organization</term>
                        (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關專業組織</term>), in relation to a registered
                    trade union, means an organization the objects of which are to promote the
                    interests of persons engaged or employed in a trade, industry or occupation
                    which is the same as, or similar to, the trade, industry or occupation with
                    which the registered trade union is directly concerned;</def></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968642_026" name="b" temporalId="s45_9_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>reference to an organization of workers, an organization of employers or a
                    relevant professional organization includes reference to a federation of
                    organizations of that particular type.</content></paragraph></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018956_002" name="s45A" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s45A"><num value="45A">45A.</num><heading>Transitional provision in relation to <ref>section 45</ref></heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968704_004" name="1" temporalId="s45A_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn><ref>Section 45</ref> does not apply in relation to a registered trade union’s
                being a member of an organization which is established in a foreign country in the
                case where the trade union—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968704_012" name="a" temporalId="s45A_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>became a member of the organization during the period beginning with the
                    commencement*
                    of the Trade Unions (Amendment) (No. 2) Ordinance 1997 and ending with the
                    commencement^
                    of the Legislative Provisions (Suspension of Operation) Ordinance 1997
                        (<ref>section 3(1)</ref> of which suspends the operation of that Ordinance);
                    and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968704_020" name="b" temporalId="s45A_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has remained a member of the organization continuously since so becoming a
                    member.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968704_027" name="2" temporalId="s45A_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn><ref>Section 45</ref> does not apply in relation to a registered trade union’s
                being a member of an organization which is established in a foreign country in the
                case where the trade union—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968704_035" name="a" temporalId="s45A_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>was, immediately before the
                    commencement*
                    of the Trade Unions (Amendment) (No. 2) Ordinance 1997, a member of the
                    organization in accordance with
                        <ref>section 45</ref>
                    as then in force; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968720_006" name="b" temporalId="s45A_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has remained a member of the organization continuously ever
                    since,</content></paragraph><continued>and <ref>section 45</ref> as in force immediately before the
                commencement*
                of the Trade Unions (Amendment)
                (No. 2)
                Ordinance 1997 shall continue to apply in relation to the trade union’s being a
                member of the organization as if that Ordinance and the Employment and Labour
                Relations (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 1997 had not been
                enacted.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968720_019" name="3" temporalId="s45A_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn><ref>Section 45</ref> does not apply in relation to a registered trade union’s
                being a member of an organization which is established in a foreign country in the
                case where the trade union—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968720_027" name="a" temporalId="s45A_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>was, immediately before the
                        commencement<sup>#</sup>
                    of the Employment and Labour Relations (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance
                    1997, a member of the organization in accordance with <ref>section 45</ref> as
                    then in force; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968720_035" name="b" temporalId="s45A_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>has remained a member of the organization continuously ever
                    since,</content></paragraph><continued>and <ref>section 45</ref> as in force immediately before the
                    commencement<sup>#</sup>
                of the Employment and Labour Relations (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 1997
                shall continue to apply in relation to the trade union’s being a member of the
                organization as if that Ordinance had not been enacted.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968735_004" name="4" temporalId="s45A_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>To avoid doubt, it is declared that for the purposes of the continued
                application of <ref>section 45</ref> as in force immediately before the commencement
                of the Trade Unions (Amendment) (No. 2) Ordinance
                1997*
                or the Employment and Labour Relations (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance
                    1997<sup>#</sup>,
                as provided in subsections (2) and (3)—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968735_012" name="a" temporalId="s45A_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any reference in that section to the Governor shall be read as reference to
                    the Chief Executive;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968735_020" name="b" temporalId="s45A_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any reference in that section to a fine of $500 shall be read as reference
                    to a fine at level 1.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968735_027" name="5" temporalId="s45A_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Reference in subsections (3) and (4) to <ref>section 45</ref> as in force
                immediately before the
                    commencement<sup>#</sup>
                of the Employment and Labour Relations (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 1997 is
                a reference to that section as so in force by virtue of <ref>section 3(1)</ref> of
                the Legislative Provisions (Suspension of Operation) Ordinance 1997.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968751_005" name="6" temporalId="s45A_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><leadIn>In this section—</leadIn><def name="EmploymentAndLabourRelationsMiscellaneousAmendmentsOrdinance1997"><term>Employment
                    and Labour Relations (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance
                1997</term>
                    (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">1997年僱傭及勞資關係(雜項修訂)條例</term>》)
                means the Employment and Labour Relations (Miscellaneous Amendments) Ordinance 1997
                    (<ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997</ref>);</def><def name="LegislativeProvisionsSuspensionOfOperationOrdinance1997"><term>Legislative
                    Provisions (Suspension of Operation) Ordinance
                1997</term>
                    (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">1997年法律條文(暫時終止實施)條例</term>》)
                means the Legislative Provisions (Suspension of Operation) Ordinance 1997 (<ref href="/hk/cap538">Cap. 538</ref>);</def><def name="TradeUnionsAmendmentNo2Ordinance1997"><term>Trade
                    Unions (Amendment) (No. 2) Ordinance
                1997</term>
                    (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">1997年職工會(修訂</term>)
                    (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">第 2 號)條例</term>》) means the Trade Unions
                (Amendment) (No. 2) Ordinance 1997 (<ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of
                1997</ref>).</def></subsection><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 10</ref>)</sourceNote></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1583993684323_001">
        <content>Editorial Note:</content>
        <content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement date: 30 June
            1997.</content>
        <content>^ Commencement date: 18 July 1997.</content>
        <content><sup>#</sup> Commencement date: 31 October 1997.</content>
    </editorialNote></part><part id="ID_1438403018972_002" name="P7" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P7"><num value="7">Part
            VII</num><heading>Picketing,
            Intimidation and Conspiracy</heading><section id="ID_1438403018987_001" name="s46" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s46"><num value="46">46.</num><heading>Peaceful picketing</heading><leadIn>Notwithstanding anything in this Ordinance, it shall be lawful for one or more
            persons, acting on their own behalf or on behalf of a registered trade union or of an
            individual employer or firm, in contemplation or furtherance of a trade dispute, to
            attend at or near a place where a person works or carries on business, if they so attend
            merely for the purpose of peacefully obtaining or communicating information or of
            peacefully persuading any person to work or abstain from working:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s46_proviso">Provided that it shall not be lawful if
            they so attend in such numbers, or otherwise in such manner, as to be calculated to
            intimidate any person in that place, or to obstruct the approach thereto or egress
            therefrom, or to lead to a breach of the peace, and any person who acts in contravention
            of this proviso shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction
            to a fine
            at
            level 1 and to imprisonment for 6 months.</proviso><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s.
            21</ref>; <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403018987_003" name="s47" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s47"><num value="47">47.</num><heading>Intimidation and annoyance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968829_025" name="1" temporalId="s47_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every person who, with a view to compelling any person to abstain from doing or to do any act that such other person has a legal right to do or abstain from doing, wrongfully and without legal authority—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968829_033" name="a" temporalId="s47_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>uses violence to or intimidates such other person or his wife or children, or injures his property; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968829_041" name="b" temporalId="s47_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>persistently follows such other person about from place to place; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968829_049" name="c" temporalId="s47_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>hides any tools, clothes or other property owned or used by such other person, or deprives him of the same or hinders him in the use thereof; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968829_057" name="d" temporalId="s47_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>watches or besets the house or other place where such other person resides or works or carries on business or happens to be or the approach to such house or place; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968844_006" name="e" temporalId="s47_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>follows such other person in a disorderly manner in or through any street or road,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1 and to imprisonment for 6 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968844_019" name="2" temporalId="s47_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Attending at or near any place in such numbers, or otherwise in such manner, as
                is by the proviso to <ref>section 46</ref> declared to be unlawful shall be deemed
                to be a watching or
                besetting
                of that place within the meaning of this section.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s.
                    22</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019003_002" name="s48" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-03-23" status="operational" temporalId="s48"><num value="48">48.</num><heading>Conspiracy in relation to trade disputes</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968876_004" name="1" temporalId="s48_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An agreement or combination of 2 or more persons to do or procure to be done any act in contemplation or furtherance of a trade dispute shall not be triable as a conspiracy if such act committed by one person would not be punishable as a crime.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968891_005" name="2" temporalId="s48_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An act done in pursuance of an agreement or combination by 2 or more persons shall, if done in contemplation or furtherance of a trade dispute, not be actionable unless the act, if done without any such agreement or combination, would be actionable.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968891_013" name="3" temporalId="s48_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall exempt from punishment any person guilty of a conspiracy for which a punishment is awarded by any enactment in force in Hong Kong.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s. 3</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968891_021" name="4" temporalId="s48_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall affect the law relating to riot, unlawful
                assembly, breach of the peace or
                any
                offence endangering national
                    security.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2024/6">6 of 2024
                        s. 155</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968891_029" name="5" temporalId="s48_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where a person is convicted of any such agreement or combination as is referred to in subsection (1) to do or procure to be done any act that is punishable on summary conviction, and is sentenced to imprisonment, the imprisonment shall not exceed 3 months, or such longer term, if any, as may have been prescribed by the law for the punishment of such act when committed by one person.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968907_005" name="6" temporalId="s48_6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed in any way to limit or prejudice any of the provisions of the Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap151">Cap. 151</ref>).</content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403019018_001" name="P8" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P8"><num value="8">Part
            VIII</num><heading>Miscellaneous
            Offences relating to Registered Trade Unions</heading><section id="ID_1438403019018_003" name="s49" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s49"><num value="49">49.</num><heading>Punishment for withholding money or property of a registered trade union</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411968938_004" name="1" temporalId="s49_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>If any officer or any other person being or representing himself to be a member of a registered trade union or the nominee, executor, administrator or assignee of a member thereof or any person whatsoever, by false representation or imposition, obtains possession of any moneys, securities, books, papers or other effects of such trade union, or having the same in his possession, wilfully withholds or fraudulently misapplies the same, or wilfully applies any part of the same to purposes other than those expressed or directed in the rules of such trade union, the District Court, upon application made by such trade union or by any voting member of such trade union or by the Registrar, may make an order requiring such officer, member or other person to deliver up to the trade union all such moneys, securities, books, papers, or other effects of the trade union, or to repay the amount of the moneys applied improperly, and to pay to the trade union, if the District Court thinks fit, a further sum of money not exceeding $200 together with the costs of the application, and, in default of delivery of such effects, or repayment of such amount of money, or payment of such penalty and costs aforesaid, the said court may order such officer, member or person to be imprisoned for any time not exceeding 3 months:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s49_1_proviso">Provided that nothing in this subsection shall prevent any criminal proceedings being taken against such officer, member or other person in relation to any matter in respect of which an order was made under this subsection.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411968938_018" name="2" temporalId="s49_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Without prejudice to the provisions of subsection (1), any registered trade union or any voting member of a registered trade union or the Registrar may apply to the District Court for an injunction restraining an officer of the trade union from holding office or controlling trade union funds, and the District Court, if satisfied that there is a prima facie case against such officer for the fraudulent misuse of the funds of the trade union, may grant such injunction.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019034_001" name="s50" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s50"><num value="50">50.</num><heading>Circulating false copies of rules, etc.</heading><leadIn>Any person who, with intent to mislead or defraud—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411968969_047" name="a" temporalId="s50_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>gives to any member of a registered trade union or to any person intending or
                applying to become a member of such trade union a copy of any rules, or of any
                alterations or amendments of any rules, other than those that have been registered
                for the time being under this Ordinance, on the pretence that such rules are
                registered or that there are no other rules of such trade union; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968985_006" name="b" temporalId="s50_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>gives a copy of any document purporting to be rules on the pretence that such
                document contains the rules of a trade union registered under this Ordinance, that
                is not so registered; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411968985_014" name="c" temporalId="s50_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>uses any sign, seal or stationery of any unregistered trade union on the
                pretence that such trade union is registered,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
            at
            level 1 and to imprisonment for 3 months.</continued><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019034_003" name="s51" reason="repealed" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="repealed" temporalId="s51"><num value="51">51.</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s. 5</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019050_002" name="s52" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s52"><num value="52">52.</num><heading>Contravention of rules</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969016_004" name="1" temporalId="s52_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If it appears to the Registrar that any registered trade union or any officer thereof has contravened or is about to contravene any of the rules of the trade union respecting any of the matters specified in <ref>Schedule 2</ref>, the Registrar may serve upon the trade union or upon such officer, as the case may be, a notice in writing requiring the trade union or such officer to comply with such rule.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 23</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969016_012" name="2" temporalId="s52_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any registered trade union upon which, or any officer of a registered trade
                union upon whom, a notice has been served under subsection (1) fails to comply with
                such notice, the trade union or such officer, as the case may be, shall be guilty of
                an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403019050_004" name="P9" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P9"><num value="9">Part
            IX</num><heading>Trade
            Union Federations</heading><section id="ID_1438403019065_002" name="s53" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s53"><num value="53">53.</num><heading>Application to trade union federations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969047_004" name="1" temporalId="s53_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content><leadIn>Save as hereinafter expressly provided, this Ordinance shall apply, in so far as applicable, to a trade union federation as if the component trade unions comprising such trade union federation were individual members of a trade union:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s53_1_proviso">Provided that the Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap151">Cap. 151</ref>) shall not apply to a trade union federation so as to penalize any individual member of a registered trade union merely by reason of his being a member of such registered trade union.</proviso></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969047_018" name="2" temporalId="s53_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Save as otherwise provided, every notice, copy of rules or other document required by this Ordinance to be signed, in the case of a trade union, by the secretary or voting members thereof, or both, shall, in the case of a trade union federation, be signed by the chairman and one other officer thereof.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019081_001" name="s54" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s54"><num value="54">54.</num><heading>Provisions as to application for registration of trade union federation</heading><content>In the case of a trade union federation, an application for registration in accordance with <ref>section 5</ref> shall be signed by the chairman and one other officer of each of the registered trade unions comprised therein, and shall be accompanied by a declaration from each of such trade unions, signed by 7 voting members thereof, that the application is made with the consent of the voting members thereof as declared by a majority of votes taken by secret ballot at a general meeting of the trade union.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019081_003" name="s55" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s55"><num value="55">55.</num><heading>Trade union federation not to be registered unless component trade unions
            registered</heading><content>No trade union federation shall be registered by the Registrar unless each of the
            component trade unions comprising such trade union federation is a registered trade
            union.</content><sourceNote>(Amended  <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s. 7</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019096_001" name="s56" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s56"><num value="56">56.</num><heading>Additions to membership of trade union federations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969110_004" name="1" temporalId="s56_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Where a trade union federation has been registered under this Ordinance, no
                trade union shall subsequently enter into any agreement for membership thereof or be
                a member of such registered trade union federation unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969110_012" name="a" temporalId="s56_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s. 8</ref>)</sourceNote></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969110_020" name="b" temporalId="s56_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>application for membership of such registered trade union federation has
                    been submitted to the Registrar in the prescribed form, which shall be signed by
                    the secretary and not less than 7 voting members of the trade union applying for
                    such membership, any of whom may be officers thereof, and contain a declaration
                    that such application is made with the consent of the voting members of the
                    trade union as declared by a majority of the votes taken by secret ballot at a
                    general meeting thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969125_006" name="c" temporalId="s56_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>there has been submitted to the Registrar a declaration signed by all of
                    the officers of such registered trade union federation signifying consent;
                        and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1995/13">13 of 1995 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969125_014" name="d" temporalId="s56_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the Registrar, having satisfied himself that all of the requirements of
                    this Ordinance have been complied with, has signified his consent in writing to
                    such trade union joining in membership with such trade union
                    federation.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969125_021" name="2" temporalId="s56_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any registered trade union, being a member of a registered trade union
                federation, shall cease to be registered, such trade union shall forthwith cease to
                be a member of such registered trade union federation.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969141_005" name="3" temporalId="s56_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Where, under subsection <ref>(1)(d)</ref>, the Registrar has signified his
                consent to any registered trade union joining in membership with a trade union
                federation and, in respect of any declaration made for the purposes of subsection
                    <ref>(1)(b)</ref> or (c), there has been a contravention of <ref>section
                    58(3)</ref>, the Registrar may forthwith withdraw such consent.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969141_013" name="4" temporalId="s56_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>If any trade union, or any person acting for or on behalf of or in the name of
                a trade union with the consent of the trade union, takes any part in the affairs or
                business of a registered trade union federation of which such trade union is not a
                properly constituted member in accordance with this Ordinance and the rules of such
                registered trade union federation, such trade union or person, as the case may be,
                shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of
                2020</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019096_003" name="s57" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s57"><num value="57">57.</num><heading>Officers of trade union federations</heading><leadIn>No person shall be an officer of a registered trade union federation
            unless—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969188_012" name="a" temporalId="s57_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969188_015" name="i" temporalId="s57_a_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>he is an officer of one of the component registered trade unions comprising
                    such trade union federation; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969188_022" name="ii" temporalId="s57_a_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>he is ordinarily resident in Hong Kong; or<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s.
                            9</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969188_030" name="iii" temporalId="s57_a_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><sourceNote>(Repealed <ref href="/hk/1997/102">102 of 1997 s. 9</ref>)</sourceNote></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969188_037" name="b" temporalId="s57_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>he is a voting member of one of the component registered trade unions
                comprising such trade union
                federation.<marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s. 6</ref>)</sourceNote></section></part><part id="ID_1438403019112_002" name="P10" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P10"><num value="10">Part
            X</num><heading>Forms
            and Regulations</heading><section id="ID_1438403019128_001" name="s58" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s58"><num value="58">58.</num><heading>Forms and offences in relation thereto</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969219_004" name="1" temporalId="s58_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The Registrar may prescribe all such forms as may, in his opinion, be required for the carrying out of this Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969219_012" name="2" temporalId="s58_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any form prescribed under subsection (1) shall be published in the Gazette.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969219_020" name="3" temporalId="s58_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969234_005" name="a" temporalId="s58_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in any form prescribed by the Registrar under subsection (1), or in any declaration accompanying any such form, makes any statement or furnishes any information that he knows to be false or has reason to believe to be false;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969234_013" name="b" temporalId="s58_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>causes or procures any such statement to be made or any such information to be furnished in any such form or in any such declaration; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969234_021" name="c" temporalId="s58_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>in any such form or in any such declaration makes any statement or furnishes any information recklessly,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1 and to imprisonment for 3 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969234_034" name="4" temporalId="s58_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Any person who—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969234_042" name="a" temporalId="s58_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>signs any form prescribed by the Registrar under subsection (1) knowing that it contains any false statement or any statement that he has reason to believe to be false; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969234_050" name="b" temporalId="s58_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>signs any such form recklessly,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be guilty of an offence and shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine
                at
                level 1 and to imprisonment for 3 months.
                <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></continued></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019128_003" name="s59" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s59"><num value="59">59.</num><heading>Regulations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969266_011" name="1" temporalId="s59_1" class="section"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Save as provided in <ref>section 58</ref> and notwithstanding anything in the
                rules of any registered trade union, the Chief Executive in Council may by
                regulation provide for—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2000/56">56 of 2000 s.
                        3</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969266_019" name="a" temporalId="s59_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>all matters stated or required in this Ordinance to be
                    prescribed;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969266_027" name="b" temporalId="s59_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>books, registers and forms to be used for the purposes of this
                    Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969266_035" name="c" temporalId="s59_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the manner in which the accounts of registered trade unions shall be
                    audited and the qualifications of persons by whom they may be audited;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969266_043" name="d" temporalId="s59_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the seal, if any, to be used by the Registrar for the purpose of
                    registration of trade unions;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969266_051" name="e" temporalId="s59_1_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>inspection of registers and documents kept by the Registrar and the making
                    of copies of entries therein;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969266_059" name="f" temporalId="s59_1_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>fees to be charged for inspection and any other service or matter
                    prescribed or permitted by this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969281_006" name="g" temporalId="s59_1_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>the due disposal and safe custody of the funds and moneys of a registered
                    trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969281_014" name="h" temporalId="s59_1_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content>the creation, administration, protection, control and disposal of the
                    welfare and electoral funds of registered trade unions and all matters connected
                    therewith or incidental thereto;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s.
                            7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969281_022" name="i" temporalId="s59_1_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>generally for giving effect to the principles and provisions of this
                    Ordinance.</content><content><marker role="section-break"></marker></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969281_029" name="2" temporalId="s59_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Regulations made under this section may be of general application or limited to
                any particular registered trade union or class of registered trade unions.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969281_037" name="3" temporalId="s59_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>
                <leadIn>Regulations made under this section may provide that any person who, or any
                    registered trade union that, contravenes any of the provisions of such
                    regulations shall be guilty of an offence and may prescribe penalties
                    therefor:</leadIn>
                <proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s59_3_proviso">Provided that no penalty so
                    prescribed shall exceed a fine
                    at
                    level 1.
                    <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="hk/2020/er3">E.R. 3 of 2020</ref>)</sourceNote></proviso>
            </content></subsection></section></part><part id="ID_1438403019143_002" name="P11" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="P11"><num value="11">Part
            XI</num><heading>Miscellaneous</heading><section id="ID_1438403019159_001" name="s60" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s60"><num value="60">60.</num><heading>Delegation of powers</heading><leadIn>The Registrar may delegate to any officer of the Registry of Trade Unions, either generally or particularly, such of his powers, functions or duties under this Ordinance as he may consider expedient:</leadIn><proviso name="proviso" temporalId="s60_proviso">Provided that no delegation made hereunder shall preclude the Registrar from exercising or performing at any time any of the powers, functions or duties so delegated.</proviso><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1994/ln446">L.N. 446 of 1994</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019159_003" name="s61" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s61"><num value="61">61.</num><heading>Liability of officers thereof where offence committed by trade union</heading><content>Where any offence against this Ordinance or any regulations made thereunder has been committed by any registered trade union, every officer of the trade union shall be guilty of the like offence unless he proves to the satisfaction of the court that the act constituting the offence took place without his knowledge or consent.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019174_002" name="s62" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s62"><num value="62">62.</num><heading>Limit of time for complaints or information</heading><content>Notwithstanding anything contained in the Magistrates Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap227">Cap. 227</ref>), a complaint made or information laid in respect of an offence under this Ordinance or the regulations shall be made or laid within 2 years from the time when the matter of such complaint or information respectively arose.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403019174_004" name="s63" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s63"><num value="63">63.</num><heading>Service of legal process and notices issued by Registrar</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969359_011" name="1" temporalId="s63_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Every—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969359_019" name="a" temporalId="s63_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>summons, notice or other document required to be served on a registered trade union in any civil or criminal proceeding; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969359_027" name="b" temporalId="s63_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>notice or other document issued by the Registrar under this Ordinance and required to be served on a registered trade union,</content></paragraph><continued>shall be deemed to be duly served if it is delivered at or sent by registered post addressed to the registered office of the trade union or if it is served personally on any officer of the trade union, provided that such service is otherwise in compliance with the requirements of any relevant Ordinance.</continued></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969359_040" name="2" temporalId="s63_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1), whenever the Registrar is required under <ref>section 11</ref> to give notice to a trade union, he may in addition publish such notice in the Gazette and such publication shall be deemed to be good and effective notice to the trade union.</content></subsection><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 26</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019190_002" name="s64" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-07-01" status="operational" temporalId="s64"><num value="64">64.</num><heading>Procedure, etc. upon appeal under Ordinance to Court of First Instance and Court of
            Appeal</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969390_011" name="1" temporalId="s64_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, the practice and procedure upon
                and in connection with any appeal under this Ordinance to the Court of First
                Instance shall be subject to any rules of court made under the High Court Ordinance
                    (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s.
                    27</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969390_019" name="2" temporalId="s64_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>An appeal shall be from a decision of the Court of First Instance under this
                Ordinance to the Court of Appeal in accordance with <ref>section 14</ref> of the
                High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Replaced <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s.
                    27</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1998/25">25 of 1998 s. 2</ref>)</sourceNote></section><section id="ID_1438403019206_001" name="s65" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s65"><num value="65">65.</num><heading>Ordinance not to affect certain agreements</heading><leadIn>Nothing in this Ordinance shall affect—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969406_041" name="a" temporalId="s65_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>any agreement between partners as to their own business;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969422_006" name="b" temporalId="s65_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>any agreement between an employer and those employed by him as to such employment; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969422_014" name="c" temporalId="s65_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any agreement in consideration of the sale of the goodwill of a business or of instruction in any profession, trade or handicraft.</content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403019206_003" name="s66" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="1997-06-30" status="operational" temporalId="s66"><num value="66">66.</num><heading>Notification in the Gazette</heading><leadIn>The Registrar shall notify the following facts in the Gazette—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969437_012" name="a" temporalId="s66_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the fact that a trade union has applied for registration under this Ordinance;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969437_020" name="b" temporalId="s66_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the fact that a trade union has been registered under this Ordinance or that registration has been refused;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969437_028" name="c" temporalId="s66_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the fact that the registration of a trade union has been cancelled;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969437_036" name="d" temporalId="s66_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>the fact that any change of name, amalgamation or federation relating to any trade union has been registered;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969437_044" name="e" temporalId="s66_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>the fact that any registered trade union has been dissolved; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969437_052" name="f" temporalId="s66_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>the fact that a trade union has withdrawn its application for registration under this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 28</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section><section id="ID_1438403019221_001" name="s67" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2014-03-03" status="operational" temporalId="s67"><num value="67">67.</num><heading>Provisions of certain Ordinances not to apply to trade unions or trade union federations</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969468_004" name="1" temporalId="s67_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>Subject to the provisions of this Ordinance, the following Ordinances do not
                apply to a trade union or a trade union federation—  <sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969468_012" name="a" temporalId="s67_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969468_020" name="b" temporalId="s67_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Co-operative Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap33">Cap.
                    33</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969468_028" name="c" temporalId="s67_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Companies (Winding Up and Miscellaneous Provisions) Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss.
                            912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969468_035" name="2" temporalId="s67_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The registration of a trade union or a trade union federation under any of the following Ordinances is void and of no effect—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969468_043" name="a" temporalId="s67_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>);</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969468_051" name="b" temporalId="s67_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Co-operative Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap33">Cap.
                        33</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403019237_002" name="s68" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="s68"><num value="68">68.</num><heading>Result of registration</heading><subsection id="ID_1438411969484_063" name="1" temporalId="s68_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If a trade union is registered under the relevant Ordinance and the same shall
                become registered under this Ordinance, all of the property and assets of what
                description soever vested in the trade union by virtue of registration under the
                relevant Ordinance together with all rights and liabilities, whether present,
                future, certain or contingent, shall forthwith be deemed vested in the trade union
                by virtue of its registration under this Ordinance, and all causes of action
                subsisting, or suits or other legal proceedings pending, by or against the trade
                union by reason of or arising out of its registration under the relevant Ordinance
                shall subsist or be continued by or against such trade union by virtue of its
                registration under this Ordinance.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28 of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969515_005" name="2" temporalId="s68_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If any unincorporated association, being a trade union within the meaning of
                this Ordinance, shall become registered thereunder, all of the property and assets
                of what description soever belonging to the members of such association by virtue of
                membership thereof or vested in trustees for the members of such association shall
                become vested in the registered trade union upon registration together with all
                rights and liabilities, whether present, future, certain or contingent, and all
                causes of action subsisting, or suits or other legal proceedings pending, by or
                against any trustees for the members of such association or any officer or member on
                behalf of himself and all other members of such association shall subsist or
                continue by or against such registered trade union in the name under which it is
                registered.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438411969546_005" name="3" temporalId="s68_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>For the purposes of this section—</leadIn><def name="RelevantOrdinance">
                <leadIn><term>relevant Ordinance</term> (《<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">有關條例</term>》)
                    means—</leadIn>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411969546_020" name="a" temporalId="s68_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap32">Cap. 32</ref>) as in
                        force from time to time before the commencement date* of <ref>section 2 of
                            Schedule 9</ref> to the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap.
                            622</ref>);</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411969546_028" name="b" temporalId="s68_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the Co-operative Societies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap33">Cap.
                            33</ref>); or</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID_1438411969562_006" name="c" temporalId="s68_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the Companies Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap622">Cap. 622</ref>).<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/2012/28">28
                                of 2012 ss. 912</ref> &amp; <ref href="/hk/2012/28">920</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph>
            </def></subsection></section><editorialNote type="footnote" id="ID_1583987639020_001">
        <content>Editorial Note:<content><inline class="force_orig_font">*</inline> Commencement
                date : 3 March 2014.</content></content>
    </editorialNote></part><schedule id="ID_1438403019252_002" name="sch1" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch1"><num value="1">Schedule
            1</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap332/s17">s.
            17</ref>]</note><section class="no_header" id="ID_1582691421929_001" name="s0" temporalId="sch1_s0"><leadIn>Any offence involving—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969593_081" name="a" temporalId="sch1_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>fraud;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969593_090" name="b" temporalId="sch1_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>dishonesty;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969609_007" name="c" temporalId="sch1_s0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>extortion;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969609_016" name="d" temporalId="sch1_s0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>membership of a triad society.</content></paragraph><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of 1971 s. 29</ref>)</sourceNote></section></schedule><schedule id="ID_1438403019268_001" name="sch2" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2020-04-23" status="operational" temporalId="sch2"><num value="2">Schedule
            2</num><note class="align_right" role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap332/s18">s. 18</ref>]</note><heading>Matters
            for which Provision must be Made in the Rules of Every Registered Trade
            Union</heading><section id="ID_1560226298474_001" name="s0" temporalId="sch2_s0" class="no_header"><leadIn>The rules of every registered trade union shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438411969624_022" name="a" temporalId="sch2_s0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>contain a statement of the name of the trade union and the address of its
                    registered office;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969624_031" name="b" temporalId="sch2_s0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>declare the whole of the objects for which the trade union is
                    established;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969624_040" name="c" temporalId="sch2_s0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><leadIn>subject to the provisions of <ref>section 17</ref>, declare the conditions
                    under which persons may enjoy—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969624_049" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s0_c_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>voting membership; and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969624_058" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s0_c_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>non-voting membership;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969624_066" name="d" temporalId="sch2_s0_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969624_069" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s0_d_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>provide for the keeping of a register of members of the trade union;
                        and</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969624_077" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s0_d_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>make provision for the maintenance of discipline within the trade
                        union, including provision for appeal to the voting members at a general
                        meeting of the trade union against any decision of the executive cancelling
                        the membership of any member or dismissing any officer;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969624_085" name="e" temporalId="sch2_s0_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>specify the method of convening and conducting annual general meetings and
                    extraordinary general meetings, and the matters to be presented to the members
                    of the trade union at such meetings, including in the case of annual general
                    meetings the presentation of audited accounts;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969640_007" name="f" temporalId="sch2_s0_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>provide for the appointment and replacement of officers of the trade
                    union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969640_016" name="g" temporalId="sch2_s0_g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content>provide that every voting member of the trade union shall have a reasonable
                    opportunity of voting;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969640_025" name="h" temporalId="sch2_s0_h"><num value="h">(h)</num><leadIn>provide that all decisions in respect of the following matters be taken by
                    decision of the voting members of the trade union by means of secret
                    ballot—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969640_034" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s0_h_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the appointment of members of the executive;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1977/18">18 of 1977 s.
                                7</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969640_043" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s0_h_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>change of name of the trade union;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969640_052" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_s0_h_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>amalgamation of the trade union with any other trade union;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969640_061" name="iiia" temporalId="sch2_s0_h_iiia"><num value="iiia">(iiia)</num><content>establishing an electoral fund;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s.
                                11</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969640_070" name="iiib" temporalId="sch2_s0_h_iiib"><num value="iiib">(iiib)</num><content>the payment of any expenses of a kind mentioned in <ref>section
                            33A(1)</ref>;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s. 11</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969640_079" name="iiic" temporalId="sch2_s0_h_iiic"><num value="iiic">(iiic)</num><content>being or becoming a member of an organization which is established in a
                        foreign country; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1997/135">135 of 1997 s.
                        11</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969656_008" name="iv" temporalId="sch2_s0_h_iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content>federation of the trade union with any other trade union or with a
                        trade union federation;</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969656_016" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s0_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>specify the amount and manner of payment of subscriptions, fees and
                    contributions payable by members of the trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969656_025" name="j" temporalId="sch2_s0_j"><num value="j">(j)</num><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969656_028" name="i" temporalId="sch2_s0_j_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>subject to the provisions of <ref>section 33</ref>, specify the
                        purposes to which the funds of the trade union may be applied;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969656_036" name="ii" temporalId="sch2_s0_j_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>provide for the creation, administration, protection, disbursement and
                        disposal of the welfare fund (if any) and declare the conditions under which
                        any member, or the family of any member, of the trade union may become
                        entitled to any benefit assured thereby;</content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438411969656_045" name="iii" temporalId="sch2_s0_j_iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content>provide for the administration, protection, disbursement and disposal
                        of the electoral fund, if one is established, and declare the conditions
                        under which money in the fund may be spent.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1988/47">47 of 1988 s.
                                8</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969671_007" name="k" temporalId="sch2_s0_k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content>provide for the custody and investment of the funds (if any) of the trade
                    union, the designation of the officer or officers responsible therefor, the
                    keeping of accounts and the annual, or more frequent periodic, auditing
                    thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969671_016" name="l" temporalId="sch2_s0_l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content>specify the commencement and termination of the financial year of the trade
                    union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969671_025" name="m" temporalId="sch2_s0_m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content>ensure reasonable opportunity for the inspection by members of the trade
                    union of the rules of the trade union, its account books and the registers of
                    the names of the members thereof;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969671_034" name="n" temporalId="sch2_s0_n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content>provide for the making, altering, amending and rescinding of the rules of
                    the trade union;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969671_043" name="o" temporalId="sch2_s0_o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content>provide for the method of dissolution of the trade union and the manner in
                    which the funds thereof shall be disposed of upon
                        dissolution;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Amended <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of
                            1971 s. 30</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438411969671_052" name="p" temporalId="sch2_s0_p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content>provide for the safe custody of the common seal of the trade union.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(Added <ref href="/hk/1971/15">15 of
                            1971 s. 30</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph></section></schedule></main></ordinance>