<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><subLeg xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd" xml:lang="en"><meta><docName>Cap. 547 sub. leg. C</docName><docType>cap</docType><docNumber>547C</docNumber><docStatus>In effect</docStatus><dc:identifier>/hk/cap547C!en</dc:identifier><dc:date>2024-01-01</dc:date><dc:subject>legislation</dc:subject><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>DoJ</dc:publisher><dc:rights>the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region</dc:rights></meta><main xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0 https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/schemas/hklm.xsd"><docTitle id="ID_1438403414741_001" name="shortTitle" reason="inEffect" status="operational" temporalId="shortTitle" startPeriod="2019-06-20">District
            Councils
            (Election
            Petition)
            Rules</docTitle><enactingFormula role="empoweringSection">(<ref href="/hk/cap547/s52">Cap. 547, section
                52(3)</ref>)</enactingFormula><sourceNote>(Enacting provision omitted—<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of
            2019</ref>)</sourceNote><commencementNote>[4 June 1999]</commencementNote><sourceNote>(Format changes—<ref href="/hk/2019/er2">E.R. 2 of 2019</ref>)</sourceNote><section id="ID_1438403414757_001" name="s1" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s1"><num value="1">1.</num><heading>Interpretation</heading><leadIn>In these Rules, unless the context otherwise requires—</leadIn><def name="Registrar"><term>Registrar</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">司法常務官</term>) means the Registrar of the High
            Court;</def><def name="Respondent"><term>respondent</term>
                (<term xml:lang="zh-Hant-HK">答辯人</term>) means a respondent within the meaning of
                <ref>section 51</ref> of the Ordinance.</def></section><section id="ID_1438403414757_003" name="s2" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s2"><num value="2">2.</num><heading>General practice and procedure</heading><content>Subject to <ref>Division 4</ref> of Part V of the Ordinance and to these Rules, the practice and procedure of the High Court, including the rules relating to the discovery and inspection of documents and the delivery of interrogatories, shall apply to an election petition as nearly as circumstances permit as if it were an ordinary action within the jurisdiction of the High Court.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403414772_002" name="s3" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s3"><num value="3">3.</num><heading>Filing of documents</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413215656_004" name="1" temporalId="s3_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Any document required to be filed in proceedings relating to any election petition shall be filed in the Registry of the High Court.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215656_012" name="2" temporalId="s3_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The High Court Fees Rules (<ref href="/hk/cap4D">Cap. 4 sub. leg. D</ref>) shall, subject to any necessary modifications, apply in respect of all proceedings relating to election petitions.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414772_004" name="s4" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2024-01-01" status="operational" temporalId="s4"><num value="4">4.</num><heading>Form and substance of election petition</heading><leadIn>An election petition shall be in the form set out in the <ref>Schedule</ref>, or a
            form to the like effect with such variations as the circumstances may require, and shall
            state—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413215672_027" name="a" temporalId="s4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>in which of the capacities mentioned in <ref>section 50</ref> of the Ordinance
                the petitioner, or each of the petitioners, lodges the election petition;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215687_006" name="b" temporalId="s4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><leadIn>the date of declaration of result of the election and the person declared to be
                elected by the Returning Officer—</leadIn><subparagraph id="ID_1438413215687_014" name="i" temporalId="s4_b_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>in the case of an election which was not contested, in a notice containing
                    a declaration for the purposes of <ref>section
                    39(1)</ref>
                    or <ref>(2)(a)</ref> of the Ordinance published in accordance
                    with regulations in force under the Electoral Affairs Commission Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap541">Cap. 541</ref>); or
                    <sourceNote>(<ref href="hk/2023/19">19 of 2023 s.
                    91</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID_1438413215687_022" name="ii" temporalId="s4_b_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>in the case of a contested election, in a notice of result of election
                    published in accordance with regulations in force under the Electoral Affairs
                    Commission Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap541">Cap. 541</ref>); and</content></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215687_029" name="c" temporalId="s4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>the ground under <ref>section 49(1)</ref> of the Ordinance on which the
                election is questioned and on which relief is to be sought, setting out with
                sufficient particularity the facts relied on but not the evidence by which they are
                to be proved,</content></paragraph><continued>and shall conclude with a request setting out the particulars of the relief
            sought.</continued></section><section id="ID_1438403414788_002" name="s5" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s5"><num value="5">5.</num><heading>Signature and lodgement of election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413215734_011" name="1" temporalId="s5_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An election petition shall be signed by the petitioner or by each petitioner if
                there is more than one and shall be lodged in the Court by filing the election
                petition, together with 4 copies thereof, with the Registrar who shall give a
                receipt therefor, if required so to do.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215734_019" name="2" temporalId="s5_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>The Registrar shall, immediately after the lodgement of the election
                petition—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413215734_027" name="a" temporalId="s5_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>send a certified true copy thereof to the Director of Home Affairs, who
                    shall, forthwith upon receipt thereof, cause that copy to be displayed in a
                    conspicuous place on or near the outer door of any regular place of meetings of
                    the District Council concerned and to the Secretary for Constitutional and
                    Mainland Affairs and to the Electoral Affairs Commission;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                            2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215750_006" name="b" temporalId="s5_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>cause a certified true copy thereof to be displayed in a conspicuous place
                    in the High Court; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215750_014" name="c" temporalId="s5_2_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>cause a notice, which shall state that such an election petition has been
                    lodged and specify the parties thereto, to be published in the
                    Gazette.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215750_021" name="3" temporalId="s5_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The Registrar shall cause a list of the election petitions to be displayed in a
                conspicuous place in the High Court.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414803_001" name="s6" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s6"><num value="6">6.</num><heading>Notice of lodgement of election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413215781_004" name="1" temporalId="s6_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The petitioner shall, within 2 days of the lodgement of the election petition or such other period as the Court may direct, serve on the respondent and the Secretary for Justice, notice of the lodgement of the election petition and the nature of the security for costs which the petitioner proposes to give in accordance with <ref>section 54</ref> of the Ordinance, together with a copy of the election petition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215797_005" name="2" temporalId="s6_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Service shall be effected in the manner in which a writ of summons is served and an affidavit of service shall be filed as soon as possible after service has been effected.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414803_003" name="s7" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s7"><num value="7">7.</num><heading>Manner of application for directions in chambers</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413215812_018" name="1" temporalId="s7_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Application to the Court for directions under <ref>section 54(2)</ref> of the Ordinance shall be made by the petitioner by summons to a judge in chambers at the time of lodging the election petition, or within 2 days thereafter or such other period as the Court may direct.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215828_005" name="2" temporalId="s7_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The summons under subrule (1) shall be issued by the Registrar forthwith upon being filed.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215828_013" name="3" temporalId="s7_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to subrule (4), all applications under subrule (1) shall be made by inter partes summons, the return day of which shall be not later than 5 days after the lodgement of the election petition or the expiry of such other period as the Court may direct for giving security under <ref>section 54(1)</ref> of the Ordinance.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215828_021" name="4" temporalId="s7_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Where the petitioner proposes to give the maximum amount of security that may be directed under <ref>section 54(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, and proposes to give such amount by the deposit of money to that extent, an application for directions that the security be given in such maximum amount and by the deposit of money, may be made by ex parte summons, and the Registrar shall, by endorsement on the summons, order the petitioner to appear at the time and place directed by the Registrar, being not later than 5 days after the lodgement of the election petition.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414819_002" name="s8" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s8"><num value="8">8.</num><heading>Affidavit of proposed surety to be filed and served on respondent</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413215875_004" name="1" temporalId="s8_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where the petitioner proposes to give security under <ref>section 54</ref> of the Ordinance wholly or partly by recognizance entered into by a surety or sureties, the petitioner shall, together with the summons referred to in <ref>rule 7(1)</ref>, file an affidavit sworn by the proposed surety or each proposed surety, which shall specify the sum in which it is proposed the surety should be bound by a recognizance and shall state that after payment of all his debts the value of all his assets is not less than the sum so specified.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215890_005" name="2" temporalId="s8_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The petitioner shall, forthwith upon the affidavit being filed in accordance with subrule (1), serve or cause to be served on the respondent the summons issued under <ref>rule 7(2)</ref>, together with a copy of the affidavit.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414835_001" name="s9" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s9"><num value="9">9.</num><heading>Grounds of objection to recognizance</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413215921_004" name="1" temporalId="s9_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><leadIn>The respondent to an election petition may, at the hearing of the summons issued under <ref>rule 7(2)</ref>, object to any recognizance on the grounds—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413215921_012" name="a" temporalId="s9_1_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>that the amount of any security is insufficient;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215921_020" name="b" temporalId="s9_1_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>that any surety is dead;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215921_028" name="c" temporalId="s9_1_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>that any surety cannot be found; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215921_036" name="d" temporalId="s9_1_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>that any surety cannot be ascertained for want of a sufficient description in the notice served under <ref>rule 6</ref> or in the copy of the affidavit served under <ref>rule 8(2)</ref>.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215937_005" name="2" temporalId="s9_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>The Court may, at any time during the hearing of an election petition, increase the amount of security ordered on an application under <ref>rule 7(1)</ref>, subject to the maximum amount specified in <ref>section 54(2)</ref> of the Ordinance, and give directions as to the manner and form of giving such increased security.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414835_003" name="s10" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s10"><num value="10">10.</num><heading>Time and place for trial of election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413215968_011" name="1" temporalId="s10_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The petitioner shall, within 28 days of giving security in accordance with
                    <ref>section 54</ref> of the Ordinance and these Rules, apply by summons to a
                judge for a time and place to be fixed for the trial of the election
                petition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215968_019" name="2" temporalId="s10_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If the petitioner fails to make an application under subrule (1) within the
                period specified under that subrule, any respondent may, within 7 days of the expiry
                of such period, apply by summons to a judge for a time and place to be fixed for the
                trial of the election petition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215984_005" name="3" temporalId="s10_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>If no application to fix the time and place for the trial of the election
                petition is made in accordance with subrule (1) or (2), the Registrar shall refer
                the matter to a judge, who shall thereupon fix such a time and place.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215984_013" name="4" temporalId="s10_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Not less than 7 days before the day so fixed the Registrar shall cause a notice
                of the time and place of the trial to be displayed in a conspicuous place in the
                High Court, and cause a copy of that notice to be sent—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413215984_021" name="a" temporalId="s10_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>to the petitioner;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215984_029" name="b" temporalId="s10_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>to the respondent;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215984_037" name="c" temporalId="s10_4_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>to the Secretary for Justice;</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215984_045" name="d" temporalId="s10_4_d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content>to the Secretary for Constitutional and Mainland Affairs;<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130
                            of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215999_006" name="e" temporalId="s10_4_e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content>to the Electoral Affairs Commission; and</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413215999_014" name="f" temporalId="s10_4_f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content>to the Director of Home Affairs.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413215999_021" name="5" temporalId="s10_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>The Director of Home Affairs shall, forthwith upon receipt of the notice under
                subrule (4), cause it to be displayed in the same manner as provided under <ref>rule
                    5(2)(a)</ref> in respect of a copy of an election petition.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414850_001" name="s11" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s11"><num value="11">11.</num><heading>Trial of election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216031_027" name="1" temporalId="s11_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>The trial of an election petition shall be proceeded with notwithstanding that the respondent has ceased to hold the office his election to which is questioned by the election petition.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216046_005" name="2" temporalId="s11_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where more election petitions than one are lodged relating to the same election, the Court may, upon its own motion or application by a party to any such election petition, order those election petitions to be consolidated on such terms as it thinks fit or order them to be tried at the same time or one immediately after another.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216046_013" name="3" temporalId="s11_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>On the trial of an election petition, unless the Court otherwise directs, any charge of corrupt or illegal conduct may be inquired into, and evidence in relation thereto may be received, before any proof has been given of agency on behalf of any candidate in respect of the corrupt or illegal conduct.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/10">10 of 2000 s. 47</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216062_005" name="4" temporalId="s11_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Subject to <ref>rule 12(4)(a)</ref>, on the trial of an election petition complaining that a person was not duly elected and claiming the office for some other person, the respondent may give evidence to prove that that other person was not duly elected in his place, in the same manner as if he had lodged an election petition questioning the election of that person.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414850_003" name="s12" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s12"><num value="12">12.</num><heading>Lists of objections in recriminatory case</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216093_004" name="1" temporalId="s12_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Where on the trial of an election petition complaining that a person was not duly elected and claiming the office for some other person, the respondent intends to give evidence in accordance with <ref>rule 11(4)</ref> to prove that that other person was not duly elected in his place, the respondent shall, not less than 7 days before the day fixed for the trial of the election petition, file a list of his objections to the election of that other person on which he intends to rely and serve a copy of the list on the petitioner and the Secretary for Justice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216109_005" name="2" temporalId="s12_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Where the election petition claims the office for an unsuccessful candidate on the ground that that person who is a candidate at an election had the number of valid votes that entitled him to claim the office, every party shall, not less than 7 days before the day fixed for the trial of the election petition, file a list of the votes which that party contends were wrongly admitted or wrongly rejected, stating in respect of each such vote the grounds for his contention, and serve a copy of the list on every other party and the Secretary for Justice.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216124_005" name="3" temporalId="s12_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Any party to an election petition may inspect and obtain a copy of any list filed in accordance with subrule (1) or (2).</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216140_005" name="4" temporalId="s12_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><leadIn>Except by leave of the Court, and upon such terms as the Court may order, no evidence shall be given—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413216140_013" name="a" temporalId="s12_4_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by a respondent of any objection to the election of any person which is not specified in a list filed by him in accordance with subrule (1); or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413216140_021" name="b" temporalId="s12_4_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>by a party against the admission or rejection of any vote, or as to any ground of contention, which is not specified in a list filed by him in accordance with subrule (2).</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414866_002" name="s13" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s13"><num value="13">13.</num><heading>Application for leave to withdraw election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216187_011" name="1" temporalId="s13_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An application for leave to withdraw or abandon or cease to prosecute an
                election petition shall be made by motion to the Court at such time and place as the
                Court may appoint.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216187_019" name="2" temporalId="s13_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Not less than 7 days before the day so appointed, the petitioner shall—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413216187_027" name="a" temporalId="s13_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>serve a notice of the intended motion on the respondent, the Secretary for
                    Justice, the Secretary for Constitutional and Mainland Affairs, the Electoral
                    Affairs Commission and the Director of Home Affairs, and file a copy with the
                    Registrar; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413216187_035" name="b" temporalId="s13_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>publish a notice of the intended motion in at least 2 newspapers
                    circulating in Hong Kong, one being published in English and the other one being
                    published in Chinese.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216202_004" name="3" temporalId="s13_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The notice of the intended motion shall state the grounds on which the
                application is made to withdraw or abandon or cease to prosecute the election
                petition, and shall contain a statement to the effect that at the hearing of the
                application any person who could have lodged an election petition in respect of the
                election or the Secretary for Justice may apply to the Court to be substituted as a
                petitioner.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216202_012" name="4" temporalId="s13_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>The Director of Home Affairs shall, forthwith upon receipt of the notice under
                subrule <ref>(2)(a)</ref>, cause it to be displayed in the same manner as provided
                under <ref>rule 5(2)(a)</ref> in respect of a copy of an election
                petition.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414881_001" name="s14" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s14"><num value="14">14.</num><heading>Evidence required for withdrawal of election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216233_028" name="1" temporalId="s14_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>Before leave to withdraw or abandon or cease to prosecute an election petition is granted, there shall be produced affidavits by all parties to the election petition and their solicitors (if any) and by the election agents (if any) of all the parties who were candidates at the election, but the Court may dispense with the affidavit of any particular person if it seems to the Court on special grounds to be just so to do.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216249_005" name="2" temporalId="s14_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Each affidavit shall state that, to the best of the knowledge and belief of the deponent, no agreement of any kind whatsoever has been made, and no undertaking has been entered into, in relation to withdrawing or abandoning or ceasing to prosecute the election petition, but if any agreement has been made with respect to withdrawing or abandoning or ceasing to prosecute the election petition, the affidavit shall set forth that agreement and shall make the foregoing statement subject to what appears from the affidavit.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216265_005" name="3" temporalId="s14_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>The affidavits of the applicant and his solicitor (if any) shall further state the grounds on which the election petition is sought to be withdrawn or abandoned or no longer prosecuted.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216265_013" name="4" temporalId="s14_4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content>Copies of the affidavits shall be delivered to the Secretary for Justice not less than 7 days before the day appointed for the hearing of the application for leave to withdraw or abandon or cease to prosecute the election petition, and the Court may hear the Secretary for Justice or his representative in opposition to the application for leave to withdraw or abandon or cease to prosecute the election petition, and shall have power to receive the evidence on oath of any person or persons whose evidence the Secretary for Justice or his representative may consider material.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216296_005" name="5" temporalId="s14_5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content>Where more than one solicitor is concerned for the petitioner or respondent, whether as agent for another solicitor or otherwise, the affidavit shall be made by all such solicitors.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414881_003" name="s15" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s15"><num value="15">15.</num><heading>Application to stay or dismiss election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216327_011" name="1" temporalId="s15_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>An application by a respondent to stay or dismiss an election petition before
                the day fixed for the trial shall be made by motion to the Court at such time and
                place as the Court may appoint.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216327_019" name="2" temporalId="s15_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Not less than 7 days before the day so appointed, the respondent shall serve a
                notice of the intended motion, stating the grounds thereof, on the petitioner, any
                other respondent, the Secretary for Justice, the Secretary for Constitutional and
                Mainland Affairs, the Electoral Affairs Commission and the Director of Home Affairs,
                and file a copy with the Registrar.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of
                    2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414897_002" name="s16" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s16"><num value="16">16.</num><heading>Notice of termination of election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216358_004" name="1" temporalId="s16_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>If an election petition is lodged by one petitioner and the election petition is terminated by the death of that petitioner, the solicitor acting for him in the proceedings at the date of his death or, if he had no such solicitor, any respondent learning of his death shall file a notice to that effect with the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216358_012" name="2" temporalId="s16_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>If an election petition is lodged by 2 or more petitioners and the election petition is terminated because the last remaining petitioner dies, the solicitor acting for such petitioner in the proceedings at the date of his death or, if he had no such solicitor, any respondent learning of his death shall file a notice to that effect with the Registrar.</content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414897_004" name="s17" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s17"><num value="17">17.</num><heading>Notice of death, etc. of respondent</heading><content>On the happening of any event mentioned in <ref>section 58(1)(a)</ref> of the Ordinance, the respondent concerned, or, in the case of the death of a respondent, the solicitor acting for him in the proceedings at the date of his death or, if he had no such solicitor, any petitioner learning of his death shall file a notice to that effect with the Registrar.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403414913_002" name="s18" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s18"><num value="18">18.</num><heading>Filing copy particulars</heading><content>A party giving particulars in accordance with an order or otherwise shall file a copy within 24 hours after delivering the particulars to the party requiring them.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403414913_004" name="s19" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s19"><num value="19">19.</num><heading>Notice of respondent’s solicitor and service of notices</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216436_011" name="1" temporalId="s19_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>A solicitor appointed to act for a respondent in proceedings on an election
                petition shall forthwith give notice of his appointment to the petitioner and file a
                copy of the notice with the Registrar.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216436_019" name="2" temporalId="s19_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><leadIn>Subject to <ref>rule 6(2)</ref>, any notice required to be served on a
                respondent to an election petition may be served—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413216436_027" name="a" temporalId="s19_2_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>by delivering or sending it by post to any solicitor who has given notice
                    under subrule (1) that he is acting for the respondent; or</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413216436_035" name="b" temporalId="s19_2_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>if no notice under subrule (1) has been given, by delivering it to the
                    respondent or by leaving it at, or sending it by post or by recorded delivery or
                    by a registered letter to, his last known place of abode in Hong Kong, or, if
                    the proceedings are before the Court, in such manner as the Court may
                    direct.</content></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216452_005" name="3" temporalId="s19_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content>Subject to <ref>rule 6(2)</ref>, any notice required to be served on the
                Secretary for Justice, the Secretary for Constitutional and Mainland Affairs, the
                Electoral Affairs Commission and the Director of Home Affairs in proceedings on any
                election petition may be served by delivering or sending it by post to that
                    person.<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2007/ln130">L.N. 130 of 2007</ref>)</sourceNote></content></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414928_002" name="s20" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s20"><num value="20">20.</num><heading>Witnesses’ expenses</heading><content>The reasonable expenses incurred by any person in appearing to give evidence at the trial of an election petition, equal to such sum of money as would be allowed to such person under <ref>section 52</ref> of the High Court Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap4">Cap. 4</ref>) if he were a witness in any civil proceedings, may be allowed to him by a certificate of the Court or of the Registrar, and shall be deemed to be costs of the election petition.</content></section><section id="ID_1438403414944_001" name="s21" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s21"><num value="21">21.</num><heading>Costs of election petition</heading><subsection id="ID_1438413216514_004" name="1" temporalId="s21_1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>All costs of, or incidental to, the lodgement of an election petition and the proceedings consequent thereon, except such as are otherwise provided for under subrule (3), shall be defrayed by the parties to the election petition in such manner and in such proportions as the Court may determine.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216530_002" name="2" temporalId="s21_2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content>Any costs which in the opinion of the Court have been caused by vexatious conduct, unfounded allegations or unfounded objections on the part either of the petitioner or of the respondent, and any needless expenses incurred or caused on the part either of the petitioner or of the respondent, may be ordered to be defrayed by the parties by whom those costs or expenses have been incurred or caused whether or not those parties are on the whole successful.</content></subsection><subsection id="ID_1438413216530_010" name="3" temporalId="s21_3"><num value="3">(3)</num><leadIn>Where upon the trial of an election petition it appears to the Court that—</leadIn><paragraph id="ID_1438413216530_018" name="a" temporalId="s21_3_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content>corrupt conduct has not been proved to have been engaged in in reference to the election by or with the knowledge and consent of the respondent to the election petition; and<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/10">10 of 2000 s. 47</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413216545_006" name="b" temporalId="s21_3_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content>the respondent took all reasonable means to prevent corrupt conduct being engaged in on his behalf; but<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/10">10 of 2000 s. 47</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413216545_014" name="c" temporalId="s21_3_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content>any person or persons is or are proved, whether by providing money or otherwise, to have been extensively engaged in corrupt conduct, or to have encouraged or promoted extensive corrupt conduct, in reference to the election,<inline class="width_3"> </inline><sourceNote>(<ref href="/hk/2000/10">10 of 2000 s. 47</ref>)</sourceNote></content></paragraph><continued>the Court may, after giving that person or those persons an opportunity of being heard by counsel or solicitor and examining and cross-examining witnesses to show cause why an order should not be made, order—</continued><paragraph id="ID_1438413216545_028" name="i" temporalId="s21_3_i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content>the whole or part of the costs to be paid by that person or those persons or any of them; but</content></paragraph><paragraph id="ID_1438413216545_036" name="ii" temporalId="s21_3_ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content>if the costs cannot be, or are unlikely to be, so recovered from one or more of those persons, that they shall be paid by some other of those persons or by the petitioner or petitioners or the respondent or respondents.</content></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID_1438403414944_003" name="s22" reason="inEffect" role="rule" startPeriod="2019-06-20" status="operational" temporalId="s22"><num value="22">22.</num><heading>Forfeiture of recognizance</heading><content>If a petitioner neglects or refuses for 3 months after demand to pay to any person summoned as a witness on his behalf or to the respondent any sum due to him or his costs, and the neglect or refusal is, within 1 year after the demand, proved to the satisfaction of the Court, every person who under these Rules entered into a recognizance relating to the election petition shall be held to have made default in the recognizance, and the Court shall thereupon certify the recognizance to be forfeited.</content></section><schedule id="ID_1438403414959_002" name="sch0" reason="inEffect" startPeriod="2024-01-01" status="operational" temporalId="sch0"><num value="0">Schedule</num><note role="crossReferences" type="inline">[<ref href="/hk/cap547C/s4">r.
            4</ref>]</note><heading>Election Petition</heading><content>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%">
                <colgroup>
                    <col width="100%"></col>
                </colgroup>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                            <p class="above_space_between_line_12 align_center">IN THE HIGH COURT OF
                                HONG KONG</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left cellpadding_left_5 cellpadding_right_5">
                            <p class="align_center above_space_between_line_12">ORIGINAL
                                JURISDICTION</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%">
                <colgroup>
                    <col width="8%"></col>
                    <col width="8%"></col>
                    <col width="7%"></col>
                    <col width="77%"></col>
                </colgroup>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left cellpadding_right_2" colspan="4">
                            <p class="first_line_indent_24 ">In the Matter of the District Councils
                                Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap547">Cap. 547</ref>)</p>
                            <p class="align_center">and</p>
                            <p class="first_line_indent_24 align_justified">In the Matter of a
                                District Council election for the *<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of District
                                    Committees constituency)</i> District Committees Constituency/<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of District
                                    Council geographical constituency)</i> District Council
                                Geographical Constituency held on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(date of
                                    election)</i>.</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr class="break_rows">
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">1.</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <p class="right_indent_2 align_justified below_space_between_line_4">The
                                Election Petition of <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of
                                    Petitioner or names of Petitioners)</i> states—</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_right">*</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_-24 below_space_between_line_4 align_justified" id="ID_1687938232090_001" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content class="font_size_11">that the Petitioner was a candidate at
                                    the above election;</content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(or)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_right">*</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_-24 below_space_between_line_4 align_justified" id="ID_1687938232090_002" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content class="font_size_11">that the Petitioners are electors who
                                    were entitled to vote at the above election;</content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_right">*</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(b)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="right_indent_2 align_justified">in an election which was not
                                contested, that *<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of candidate)</i> was a candidate at the election/<i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of each
                                    candidate)</i> were candidates at the election, and on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(date on which
                                    that candidate was declared elected or those candidates were
                                    declared elected)</i> the Returning Officer for the
                                above-mentioned Constituency declared, for the purposes of <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">section
                                    39(1)</ref> or <ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(2)(a)</ref> of
                                the District Councils Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap547">Cap. 547</ref>), *that candidate/those candidates to be elected
                                for the above-mentioned Constituency in a notice published in the
                                Gazette on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(date
                                    of publication in Gazette of that notice)</i> in accordance with
                                regulations in force under the Electoral Affairs Commission
                                Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap541">Cap. 541</ref>); and</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(or)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_right">*</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(b)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left cellpadding_right_2">
                            <p class="align_justified">in a contested election, that the poll was
                                held on the above day, that <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of each
                                    candidate)</i> were candidates at the election, and on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(date on which
                                    the successful candidate was declared elected or successful
                                    candidates were declared elected)</i> the Returning Officer for
                                the above-mentioned Constituency declared <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of
                                    successful candidate or names of successful candidates)</i> to
                                be elected for the above-mentioned Constituency in a notice of
                                result of election prepared in accordance with regulations in force
                                under the Electoral Affairs Commission Ordinance (<ref xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" href="/hk/cap541">Cap. 541</ref>), and that that notice was published in the
                                Gazette on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(date
                                    of publication in Gazette of notice of result of election)</i>
                                in accordance with regulations in force under that Ordinance;
                                and</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(c)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left cellpadding_bottom_5">
                            <p class="align_justified right_indent_1">that <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(ground under
                                        <ref>section 49(1)</ref></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0"> of the District
                                    Councils Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap547">Cap. 547</ref></i><i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">) on which the
                                    election is questioned and on which relief is to be sought and
                                    the facts on which the Petitioner relies or the Petitioners
                                    rely)</i>.</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">*2.</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <p class="align_justified">The *Petitioner/Petitioners therefore
                                *requests/request, in the case of an election which was not
                                contested, the Court to determine—</p>
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_-24 below_space_between_line_4 align_justified" id="ID_1687938232090_003" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content class="font_size_11">whether any decision of the District
                                    Council Eligibility Review Committee as to the validity of any
                                    nomination in the notice of nominations published in accordance
                                    with regulations in force under the Electoral Affairs Commission
                                    Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap541">Cap. 541</ref>) (as read with
                                    the definition of <b><i>election</i></b> in <ref>section
                                        49(3)</ref> of the District Councils Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap547">Cap. 547</ref>)) was correct;</content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_-24 below_space_between_line_4 align_justified" id="ID_1687938232090_004" name="b" temporalId="sch0_b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content class="font_size_11">if the Court determines that the
                                    decision of the District Council Eligibility Review Committee
                                    was not correct, whether the *candidate/candidates declared by
                                    the Returning Officer to have been elected for the
                                    above-mentioned Constituency in the notice published for the
                                    purposes of <ref>section 39(1)</ref> or <ref>(2)(a)</ref> of the
                                    District Councils Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap547">Cap.
                                        547</ref>) in accordance with regulations in force under the
                                    Electoral Affairs Commission Ordinance (<ref href="/hk/cap541">Cap. 541</ref>) *was/were duly elected; and</content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_-24 below_space_between_line_4 align_justified" id="ID_1687938232090_005" name="c" temporalId="sch0_c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content class="font_size_11">any further or other relief as may be
                                    just.</content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p>(or)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">*2.</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <p class="align_justified">The Petitioner therefore requests, in the
                                case of a contested election, the Court to determine—</p>
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_-24 below_space_between_line_4 align_justified" id="ID_1687938232090_006" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content class="font_size_11">whether *the candidate <i>(to be
                                        named)</i>/some other candidate <i>(to be named)</i>
                                    declared by the Returning Officer for the above-mentioned
                                    Constituency to be elected in the notice was duly
                                    elected;</content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(b)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">if the Court determines that that person was
                                not duly elected, whether *the Petitioner/some other candidate <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(to be named)</i>
                                was duly elected in that person’s place; and</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(c)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left cellpadding_bottom_5">
                            <p class="align_justified">any further or other relief as may be
                                just.</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(or)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">*2.</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="2">
                            <p class="align_justified">The Petitioners therefore request, in the
                                case of a contested election, the Court to determine—</p>
                            <paragraph xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0" class="left_indent_24 first_line_indent_-24 below_space_between_line_4 align_justified" id="ID_1687938232090_007" name="a" temporalId="sch0_a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content class="font_size_11">whether *the candidate <i>(to be
                                        named)</i>/some other candidate <i>(to be named)</i>/the
                                    candidates <i>(to be named)</i> declared by the Returning
                                    Officer for the above-mentioned Constituency to be elected in
                                    the notice *was/were duly elected;</content></paragraph>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(b)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">if the Court determines that *that
                                person/those persons *was/were not duly elected, whether *the other
                                candidate <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(to be
                                    named)</i>/some other candidate <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(to be
                                named)</i>/the candidates <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(to be named)</i>
                                *was/were duly elected in *his/her/their place; and</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(c)</p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">any further or other relief as may be
                                just.</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="3">
                            <p></p>
                            <p class="align_justified">Dated this .............. day of
                                .................. 20 .......</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            
            
            
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            <marker role="blank-line"></marker>
            
            
            <table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" width="100%">
                <colgroup>
                    <col width="24%"></col>
                    <col width="8%"></col>
                    <col width="14%"></col>
                    <col width="8%"></col>
                    <col width="10.02%"></col>
                    <col width="35.98%"></col>
                </colgroup>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">Signed</p>
                            <p></p>
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">*Petitioner/Petitioners</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">(or)</p>
                            <p></p>
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                        <td class="align_left">
                            <p class="align_justified">*Solicitors</p>
                            <p></p>
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="6">
                            <p class="align_justified first_line_indent_24">*This Election Petition
                                is lodged by the *Petitioner/Petitioners.</p>
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left cellpadding_right_2" colspan="6">
                            <p class="align_justified">(or) *This Election Petition is lodged by <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of
                                    solicitors)</i>, Solicitors acting for and on behalf of the
                                *Petitioner/Petitioners.</p>
                            <p></p>
                            <p class="align_justified left_indent_24">The address for service is <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(address to be
                                    stated)</i>.</p>
                            <p></p>
                            <p class="first_line_indent_24 align_justified">It is proposed to serve
                                a copy of this Election Petition on <i xmlns="http://www.xml.gov.hk/schemas/hklm/1.0">(name of
                                    Respondent or names of Respondents)</i> and on the Secretary for
                                Justice.</p>
                            <p></p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td class="align_left" colspan="6">
                            <p class="align_justified"><span class="font_size_9">* Delete whichever
                                    is inapplicable.</span></p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </content><sourceNote>(<ref>Schedule </ref>replaced <ref href="hk/2023/19">19 of 2023 s.
                92</ref>)</sourceNote></schedule></main></subLeg>